<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1121.08</num>
  <heading>Deposit of rents, fees, taxes, assessments, sewer and water charges; payment of expenditures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided by subsection (b) of this section, all collections, including rents and fees, received by the District under this subchapter shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States in a trust fund, from which may be paid, in the same manner as is provided by law for other expenditures of the District, such expenditures as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, including necessary expenses connected with the operation, maintenance, and disposition of property coming into the possession of the District by reason of a default under a lease entered into under this subchapter. The unobligated balance in such trust fund in excess of $100,000 as of the end of any fiscal year shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of such special funds or the General Fund of the District in such proportions as the Mayor may determine.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Taxes (including payments in lieu of taxes), special assessments, and sanitary sewer and water service charges shall be deposited directly to the respective funds to which such revenues are normally deposited.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-598" type="History" path="§9">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1168, Pub. L. 90-598, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-948.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1038.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
