<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1121.10</num>
  <heading>Rules; enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A violation of this subchapter or a rule issued in accordance with this subchapter may be punished by imprisonment of not more than 90 days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may maintain an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to enjoin any continuing violation of this subchapter or a rule issued in accordance with this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Civil fines and penalties may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this subchapter or any rules promulgated under the authority of this subchapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-1801.01">2-1801.01</cite> et seq.] (“Civil Infractions Act”). Enforcement and adjudication of an infraction shall be pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may also enforce this subchapter or a rule issued in accordance with this subchapter pursuant to §  50-921.19(a), (c), (d), (e), and (f).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-598" type="History">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1168, Pub. L. 90-598, § 11</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 571, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(27)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-42" type="History">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 428, 32 DCR 4450</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-207" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-207, § 7, 61 DCR 12690</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1040.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-950.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</law-cite> rewrote this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</law-cite>: Section 12(a) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</law-cite> provided that §§ 2(a), 2(b)(1), 2(b)(2)(A), 2(b)(2)(B), 2(b)(2)(C), 2(c), 3, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and 11 shall apply as of March 11, 2015.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
