<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1102.03</num>
  <heading>Use of property subject to the requirements of § 9-113.04.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor is authorized, with respect to property subject to the requirements of § <cite path="§9-113.04">9-113.04</cite> [repealed], to allow the same use to be made of such property as, under the authority of this part, he allows to be made of the public space abutting such property. Any such use of such property shall be subject to the same conditions as are applicable to the use of the abutting public space, with the exception of the payment of rent.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-596" type="History">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1158, Pub. L. 90-596, title II, § 203</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 7-1006.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 7-907.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 9-113.04, referred to in the first sentence was repealed, effective March 10, 1983, by <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-201">D.C. Law 4-201</cite>, § 713. For present provisions regarding the naming of public places, see subchapter IV of Chapter 2 of Title 9.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
