<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1101.03</num>
  <heading>Minor uses without rental payments authorized.</heading>
  <text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subchapter, the Mayor is authorized, in his judgment and pursuant to regulations adopted and promulgated by the Council of the District of Columbia, to permit the occupancy of public space for minor uses without requiring rental payments when the fixing and collection of rental charges would not be feasible.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-596">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1157, Pub. L. 90-596, title I, § 105</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Procurement, source selection and contract formation, exemptions, see § <cite path="§2-303.20">2-303.20</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 7-1003.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 7-904.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
