<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1803</num>
  <heading>Creation of the Waterfront Park Maintenance Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Waterfront Park Maintenance Fund (“Fund”), which shall be used solely to pay the expenses of maintaining, operating, and improving the Waterfront Park and the expenses of events held in the Waterfront Park. The Chief Financial Officer shall deposit into the Fund the sales tax revenues attributable to the Waterfront Park Retail Area and revenue from the Waterfront Park Special Assessment. All monies in the Fund shall be paid by the Chief Financial Officer to the Capital Riverfront Business Improvement District pursuant to the terms set forth in the Maintenance Agreement. The payments from the Fund shall be an authorized expenditure by the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-105" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-105, § 4, 57 DCR 11</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 8042(b), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-895.24">47-895.24</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8042(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8042(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 8041 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle E of Title VIII of the act may be cited as the “Waterfront Park at the Yards Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 8044 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that §§ 8042 and 8043 of the act shall apply as of March 3, 2010.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
