<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1202.15a</num>
  <heading>Redevelopment of existing convention center site.</heading>
  <text>Any proposed exclusive right agreement to redevelop the existing convention center site, which is legally described as Square 374 and Lot 848 and excluding Lot 829, shall be submitted with a proposed resolution by the Mayor to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed resolution within the 30-day period of review, the proposed resolution and exclusive right agreement shall be deemed approved.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History" path="§215a">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 215a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-286" type="History">as added Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-286, § 2, 50 DCR 944</annotation>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 16-165, the “Revised Old Convention Center Site Disposition Approval Resolution of 2005”, was approved effective June 7, 2005.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 16-166, the “Revised Old Convention Center Site Exclusive Right Agreement Approval Resolution of 2005”, was approved effective June 7, 2005.</text>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority to Execute Exclusive Rights Agreements, Land Disposition Agreements, Deeds and Associated Documents with Respect to Certain Real Estate, see Mayor’s Order 2005-28, February 2, 2005 ( 52 DCR 2848).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§10-1202.15a">10-1202.15a</cite>, see § 2 of Council Review of Existing Convention Center Site Redevelopment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-539, December 2, 2002,  49 DCR 11655).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§10-1202.15a">10-1202.15a</cite>, see § 2 of Council Review of Existing Convention Center Site Redevelopment Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-425, July 17, 2002,  49 DCR 7629).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Council Review of Existing Convention Center Site Redevelopment Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-224">D.C. Law 14-224</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2737).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
