<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1601.01</num>
  <heading>Findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council finds that:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The ownership, construction, development, or renovation of a publicly financed stadium in the District of Columbia, after October 1, 2004, for use primarily for professional athletic team events is a municipal use that is in the interest of, and for the benefit of, the citizens of the District of Columbia because such a publicly-owned stadium or arena will contribute to the social and economic well-being of the citizens of the District of Columbia and significantly enhance the economic development and employment opportunities within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To further that interest, it is appropriate for the District of Columbia to pay all or a portion of the cost of constructing, developing, or renovating a stadium and, to that end, to impose a ballpark fee based upon the gross receipts of certain persons doing business within the District of Columbia; to impose a tax on the sales of tickets, or rights to admission, to certain events at the stadium; to impose a tax on sales of personal property and certain services at the stadium and to utilize the revenues derived from such fees and taxes to pay all or a portion of the cost of development, construction, or renovation of the stadium or the debt service on bonds or other evidence of indebtedness issued to finance all or a portion of the cost of the development, construction, or renovation of the stadium; to acquire real property in furtherance of these public purposes; to lease the stadium to one or more professional baseball clubs; and for the District of Columbia and any duly designated District government agency or instrumentality to enter into binding and enforceable contracts to further these purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-320" type="History" path="§101">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-320, § 101, 52 DCR 1757</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority Pursuant to the Ballpark Omnibus Financing and Revenue Act of 2004, <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-320">D.C. Law 15-320</cite>, effective April 8, 2005, see Mayor’s Order 2005-120, August 19, 2005, ( 52 DCR 8662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority for Acquisition of Real Property for Baseball Stadium, see Mayor’s Order 2005-130, September 20, 2005 ( 53 DCR 144).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
