<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-150</num>
  <heading>Potomac Park — Temporary occupancy by Department of Agriculture.</heading>
  <text>The Director of the National Park Service is authorized to grant permission to the Department of Agriculture for the temporary occupation of such area or areas of Potomac Park, not exceeding a total of 75 acres in extent, as may not be needed in any one season for the reclamation or park improvement, the said areas to be used by the Department of Agriculture as testing grounds; provided, that nothing herein contained shall be construed to change the essential character of the lands so used, which lands shall continue to be a public park, as provided in § <cite path="§10-147">10-147</cite>;   and provided further, that said area or areas shall be vacated by the Department of Agriculture at the close of any season upon the request of the said Director; and provided further, that the entire Park shall remain under the charge of the said Director.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 55-3-ch458" path="§2">Mar. 3, 1899, 30 Stat. 1378, ch. 458, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 8-150.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 8-156.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Director of the National Park Service relating to public buildings were transferred to the Federal Works Administrator by § 303 (b) of  Reorganization Plan No. I, July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2729, 53 Stat. 1427. All functions of all officers of the Department of the Interior (including the Director of the National Park Service) and all functions of all agencies and employees of such Department were, with 2 exceptions, transferred to the Secretary of the Interior, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or the performance of any of his functions by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 3, §§ 1, 2, 15 F.R. 3174, 64 Stat. 1262. All functions of the Federal Works Agency and of all agencies thereof, together with all functions of the Federal Works Administrator, and all functions of the Commissioner of Public Buildings and the Public Buildings Administration, were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380, ch. 288. The Federal Works Agency, the Office of Federal Works Administrator, the Office of Commissioner of Public Buildings, and the Public Buildings Administration, were abolished by § 103(b) of said Act. All functions with respect to acquiring space in buildings by lease and all functions with respect to assigning and reassigning space in buildings for use by agencies (including both space acquired by lease and space in government-owned buildings), were, with certain exceptions, transferred from the respective agencies in which theretofore vested to the Administrator of General Services by §  1 of 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 18, 15 F.R. 3177, 64 Stat. 1270.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
