<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-152</num>
  <heading>Parkway connecting Potomac Park with Zoological and Rock Creek Parks — Acquisition of land authorized; reimbursement of costs.</heading>
  <text>For the purpose of preventing the pollution and obstruction of Rock Creek and of connecting Potomac Park with the Zoological Park and Rock Creek Park, a commission, to be composed of the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Agriculture, is authorized and directed to acquire, by purchase, condemnation or otherwise, such land and premises as were not, on March 4, 1913, the property of the United States in the District of Columbia shown on the map on file in the Office of the Mayor of the District of Columbia, dated May 17, 1911, and lying on both sides of Rock Creek, including such portion of the creek bed as may be in private ownership, between the Zoological Park and Potomac Park; and the sum of $1,300,000 is hereby authorized to be expended toward the acquirement of such lands. All lands belonging, on March 4, 1913, to the United States or to the District of Columbia lying within the exterior boundaries of the land to be acquired by this section as shown and designated on said map are appropriated to and made a part of the parkway herein authorized to be acquired. One-half of the cost of the said lands shall be reimbursed to the Treasury of the United States out of the revenues of the District of Columbia in 8 equal annual installments, with interest at the rate of 3 per centum per annum, upon the deferred payments.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 62-3-ch147" path="§22">Mar. 4, 1913, 37 Stat. 885, ch. 147, § 22</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Lands reincluded within parkway: Act of September 1, 1916, 39 Stat. 689, ch. 433, provided certain described lands were reincluded as a part of the connecting parkway between Potomac Park, the Zoological Park and Rock Creek Park.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 8-158.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 8-152.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-153">10-153</cite> and § <cite path="§10-154">10-154</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
