<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1601.04</num>
  <heading>Local, small, and disadvantaged business enterprises, First Source employment, and apprentice requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “ballpark” shall have the meaning specified in § <cite path="§47-2002.05">47-2002.05</cite>(a)(1).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mayor shall take all measures as shall be reasonably necessary to assure that all contracts entered into by the District or any agency or instrumentality of the District with respect to the ballpark shall comply with the requirements of subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2 [repealed].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall take all measures as shall be reasonably necessary to assure that all contracts entered into by the District or any agency or instrumentality of the District with respect to each major phase of the development and construction of the ballpark, including contracts for architectural, engineering, and construction services, shall provide that at least 50% of the work in the aggregate under such contracts shall be awarded to local business enterprises, local small business enterprises, or local disadvantaged business enterprises, as such terms are defined in § <cite path="§2-218.02">2-218.02</cite>; provided, that of the percentage of the work required by this section to be awarded to local business enterprises, local small business enterprises, or local disadvantaged business enterprises, 35% of the work shall be awarded to local small business enterprises or local disadvantaged business enterprises, as such terms are defined in § <cite path="§2-218.02">2-218.02</cite>; provided further, that if the 35% requirement is unattainable, the Mayor shall report this to the Council for reconsideration. Of the percentage of the work required by this section to be awarded to local small business enterprises or local disadvantaged business enterprises, not less than 20% of the work shall be awarded to local disadvantaged business enterprises.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mayor shall take all measures as shall be reasonably necessary to assure that all contracts entered into by the District or any agency or instrumentality of the District with respect to the development and construction of the ballpark shall comply with First Source Employment requirements of subchapter X of Chapter 2 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-219.01">2-219.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mayor shall take all measures as shall be reasonably necessary to assure that all contracts entered into by the District or any agency or instrumentality of the District with respect to the development and construction of the ballpark shall comply with the requirements of subchapter I of Chapter 14 of Title 32 [§ <cite path="§32-1401">32-1401</cite> et seq.].</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, 50% of all apprenticeship hours performed pursuant to apprenticeship programs related to the construction and operation of the ballpark shall be performed by District of Columbia residents.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any prime contractor or subcontractor that fails to make a good faith effort to comply with the requirements of this paragraph shall be subject to a monetary fine in the amount of 5% of the direct or indirect labor costs of the contract. Fines shall be imposed by the Contracting Officer and remitted to the Department of Employment Services to be applied to job training programs, subject to appropriations by Congress.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall encourage the owner of any professional baseball franchise that operates in the ballpark to enter into broadcast media rights agreements with broadcast media companies that are local business enterprises and disadvantaged business enterprises as such terms are defined in § <cite path="§2-218.02">2-218.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-320" type="History" path="§104">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-320, § 104, 52 DCR 1757</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 38, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-1601.06">10-1601.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</law-cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of Title 2” for “subchapter IX of Chapter 2 of Title 2”; and, in subsecs. (c) and (f), substituted “§ <cite path="§2-218.02">2-218.02</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§2-217.01">2-217.01</cite>”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
