<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1401</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “plat” means the plat filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia under S.O. 92-252.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Islands” means Heritage Island and all of that portion of Kingman Island located south of Benning Road and within the District of Columbia and the Anacostia River, being a portion of United States Reservation 343, Section F, as specified and legally described on the Survey.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “National Children’s Island” means a cultural, educational, and family-oriented recreation park, together with a children’s playground, to be developed and operated in accordance with <cite path="10|14|II">subchapter II of this chapter</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “playground” means the children’s playground that is part of National Children’s Island and includes all lands on the Islands located south of East Capitol Street.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “recreation park” means the cultural, educational, and family-oriented recreation park that is part of National Children’s Island.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The term “Survey” means the ALTA/ACSM Land Title Survey prepared by Dewberry &amp; Davis and dated February 12, 1994.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 104-163" type="History" path="§2">July 19, 1996, 110 Stat. 1416, Pub. L. 104-163, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of §§ <cite path="§10-1503">10-1503</cite> to <cite path="§10-1505">10-1505</cite>, see § 2(a) to (c) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-13, January 27, 2003,  50 DCR 1488).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-901.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
