<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1505</num>
  <heading>Allocation of R13BA property sales and lease proceeds.</heading>
  <text>The proceeds from the lease or sale of any property in the R13BA, which includes all structures of a permanent character erected on or affixed to, any natural resources located on or under, all riparian rights attached to, or any air space located above or below the property or any street or alley, owned, controlled, or administered by the District, shall be applied in the following order:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To fund infrastructure improvements related to a proposed development; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To be deposited in the Fund into a dedicated R13BA Health Care account to be used for the purpose of providing health care to the uninsured residents of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-300" type="History">Apr. 11, 2003, D.C. Law 14-300, § 6, 50 DCR 406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-69" type="History">Feb. 6, 2004, D.C. Law 15-69, § 2(c), 50 DCR 9824</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-69">D.C. Law 15-69</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-3">D.C. Law 15-3</cite>, May 3, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 3783).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-13, January 27, 2003,  50 DCR 1488).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Draft Master Plan for Public Reservation 13 Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-273, December 18, 2003,  51 DCR 40).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
