<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-163</num>
  <heading>Bathing pools and beaches — Construction authorized; appropriations.</heading>
  <text>The Director of the National Park Service is authorized and directed to locate and construct in the District of Columbia, subject to the approval of the National Capital Planning Commission, and after consultation with the Commission on the Arts and Humanities, as appropriations shall be provided therefor, artificial bathing pools or beaches, not exceeding 6 in number, with suitable buildings, shower baths, lockers, provisions for the use of filtered water, purification of the water, and all things necessary for the proper conduct of such pools or beaches, and to conduct and maintain the same. The cost of construction of any of these pools or beaches, with buildings and equipment, shall not exceed $150,000 each, and the appropriation of the sums necessary for the purposes named is hereby authorized to be paid in like manner as other appropriations for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 69-1-ch234" path="">May 4, 1926, 44 Stat. 394, ch. 234</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 28, 1929, 45 Stat. 1412, ch. 384, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-165">10-165</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 8-163.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 8-169.</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Director of the National Park Service relating to public buildings were transferred to the Federal Works Administrator by § 303 (b) of  Reorganization Plan No. I, July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2729, 53 Stat. 1427. All functions of all officers of the Department of the Interior (including the Director of the National Park Service) and all functions of all agencies and employees of such Department were, with 2 exceptions, transferred to the Secretary of the Interior, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or the performance of any of his functions by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 3, §§ 1, 2, 15 F.R. 3174, 64 Stat. 1262. All functions of the Federal Works Agency and of all agencies thereof, together with all functions of the Federal Works Administrator, and all functions of the Commissioner of Public Buildings and the Public Buildings Administration, were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380, ch. 288. The Federal Works Agency, the Office of Federal Works Administrator, the Office of Commissioner of Public Buildings, and the Public Buildings Administration, were abolished by § 103(b) of said Act. All functions with respect to acquiring space in buildings by lease and all functions with respect to assigning and reassigning space in buildings for use by agencies (including both space acquired by lease and space in government-owned buildings), were, with certain exceptions, transferred from the respective agencies in which theretofore vested to the Administrator of General Services by §  1 of 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 18, 15 F.R. 3177, 64 Stat. 1270.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The functions, powers and duties of the National Capital Park and Planning Commission were transferred to the National Capital Planning Commission by the Act of June 6, 1924, 43 Stat. 463, ch. 270, § 9, as added by the Act of July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 790, ch. 949, § 1.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
