<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1181.04</num>
  <heading>Dangerous Structures on Public Space Fund.</heading>
  <text>There is established a fund designated as the Dangerous Structures on Public Space Fund, which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used for defraying the Department’s costs for repairing or removing dangerous structures in public space and all associated administrative costs. The fund shall be funded by taxes collected or property collected under this chapter along with any additional funds that may be lawfully appropriated for this purpose at the discretion of the Director. All monies collected under this chapter, and all interest earned, shall be deposited into the fund without regard to any fiscal year limitation, pursuant to an act of Congress. All monies deposited into the fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this chapter, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History" path="§6025">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 6025, 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6025 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6025 of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
