<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1202.23a</num>
  <heading>Use of new convention center vault space.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to the airspace located below the portion of N Street, N.W., between 7th and 9th Streets, N.W., the portion of 9th Street, N.W., between and including N Street, N.W., and Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., and the adjoining sidewalks abutting the new convention center in which the Authority was permitted to construct, and has constructed, a portion of the new convention center, including loading docks, access ramps, and associated driveways, the Authority may enter into one or more agreements with Marriott International, Inc., or its designee, to permit Marriott International, Inc., or its designee to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Use the new convention center’s access ramp and associated driveways and entrances thereto for such purposes as may be authorized by the Authority;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Construct, operate, and maintain within the airspace an access way from the new convention center’s access ramp and associated driveways for the purpose of entering and exiting from the proposed loading docks of the new convention center hotel and such other purposes as may be authorized by the Authority; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Construct, operate, and maintain within such airspace a pedestrian connector between the new convention center hotel and the new convention center and for such other purposes as may be authorized by the Authority.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The agreement regarding the pedestrian connector authorized under subsection (a) of this section may provide that Marriott International, Inc., or its designee, shall be responsible for the operation and maintenance of the pedestrian connector and, if so provided, that the Authority shall pay 50% of the costs to operate and maintain the pedestrian connector.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History" path="§703a">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 703a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-339" type="History">as added Mar. 21, 2009, D.C. Law 17-339, § 2(c), 56 DCR 947</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-294">D.C. Law 17-294</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 703a. Use of new convention center vault space.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to the airspace located below the portion of N Street, N.W., between 7th and 9th Streets, N.W., and 9th Street, N.W., between and including N Street, N.W., and Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., and the adjoining sidewalks abutting the new convention center in which the Authority was permitted to construct, and has constructed, a portion of the new convention center, including loading docks, access ramps, and associated driveways, the Authority may enter into one or more agreements with Marriott International, Inc., or its designee, to permit Marriott International, Inc., or its designee to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Use the new convention center’s access ramp and associated driveways;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Construct and maintain within such airspace access ways from the new convention center’s access ramp and associated driveways for the purpose of entering and exiting from the proposed loading docks of the new convention center hotel and such other purposes as may be authorized by the Authority; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Construct, operate, and maintain within such airspace a pedestrian connector between the new convention center hotel and the new convention center.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The agreement regarding the pedestrian connector authorized under subsection (a) of this section may provide that Marriott International, Inc., or its designee, shall be responsible for the operation and maintenance of the pedestrian connector and, if so provided, that the Authority shall pay 50% of the costs to operate and maintain the pedestrian connector.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-294">D.C. Law 17-294</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(a) of New Convention Center Hotel Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-556, October 27, 2008,  55 DCR 12004).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(c) of New Convention Center Hotel Combined Technical Amendments Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-604, December 16, 2008,  56 DCR 17).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
