<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1203.05</num>
  <heading>Audit of accounts and operations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>At least once every 3 fiscal years the District of Columbia Auditor, pursuant to the Auditor’s duties under § <cite path="§1-204.55">1-204.55</cite>(b), shall audit the accounts and operations of the Authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On or before July 15 of each year in which there is outstanding any indebtedness issued by the Authority pursuant to this chapter, the District of Columbia Auditor shall prepare and deliver to the Mayor, the Council, the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, and the Chairman of the Authority a certification relating to the upcoming fiscal year of the District as to the sufficiency of the sum of the projected revenues from the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The taxes imposed pursuant to §§ <cite path="§47-2002.02">47-2002.02</cite> and <cite path="§47-2202.01">47-2202.01</cite> and transferred to the Authority by the Mayor pursuant to §§ <cite path="§47-2002.03">47-2002.03</cite> and <cite path="§47-2202.02">47-2202.02</cite>, as such tax revenues are estimated by the Office of Tax and Revenue for such upcoming fiscal year, which estimates shall be delivered by the Office of Tax and Revenue to the Authority on or prior to July 1 of such year, excluding from such estimate any amounts relating to any surtax imposed pursuant to subsection (c) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The projected operating revenues of the Authority for such upcoming fiscal year contained in the most recent multiyear financial plan of the Board submitted pursuant to § <cite path="§10-1202.06">10-1202.06</cite>(g); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any amounts on deposit in any reserve fund or account (other than any debt service reserve fund or account for indebtedness of the Authority), which are in excess of the required minimum balance for such fund or account, as certified by the Authority, to meet the sum of (i) projected operating and debt service expenditures and reserve requirements (other than amounts included in clause (ii) below) of the Authority for the upcoming fiscal year contained in the most recent multiyear financial plan of the Board submitted pursuant to § <cite path="§10-1202.06">10-1202.06</cite>(g), and (ii) any amounts required, as certified by the Authority, to restore any reserves relating to indebtedness of the Authority to their required minimum balance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the certification delivered pursuant to subsection (b) of this section indicates that such projected revenues for the upcoming fiscal year are insufficient to meet such projected expenditures and reserve requirements (other than amounts included in clause (ii) of subsection (b)(3) of this section) and payments required to restore reserves relating to indebtedness of the Authority to their minimum required balance for the upcoming fiscal year, the Mayor shall impose a surtax, to become effective on or before the first day of the upcoming fiscal year, on the tax imposed pursuant to §§ <cite path="§47-2002.02">47-2002.02</cite>(1) and <cite path="§47-2202.01">47-2202.01</cite>(1) in an amount equal to the difference between (i) the sum of the projected operating and debt service expenditures and reserve requirements (other than amounts included in clause (ii) of subsection (b)(3) of this section) and payments required to restore any reserves relating to indebtedness of the Authority to their minimum required balance, and (ii) the projected revenues described in subsection (b) of this section. Such surtax shall be effective only for such upcoming fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 305, 41 DCR 5333</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-142" type="History">Aug. 12, 1998, D.C. Law 12-142, § 2(k), 45 DCR 4826</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1192(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-831.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “At least once every 3 fiscal years” for “On or before July 1 of each year,”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effective Dates">For effective date of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-142">D.C. Law 12-142</cite>, see Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§10-1202.01">10-1202.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2(k) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-142">D.C. Law 12-142</cite>, effective August 12, 1998, pursuant to § 2 of Pub. L. 105-227, 112 Stat. 1515, recodified and amended § 305 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-188">D.C. Law 10-188</cite> to be this section.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 12-142: Section 4 of Law 12-142 provided that § 2(k) of the act shall apply as of October 1, 1998.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
