<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-115</num>
  <heading>Whitehaven Parkway — Exchange authorized with property owners.</heading>
  <text>Upon the dedication by the lawful owner or owners of the land contained in the parcel designated “C” and the transfer by plat as provided herein and/or the conveyance by deed of the land contained in the parcel designated “D,” in accordance with map showing said parcels filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia, numbered as map 1817, the said parcel “C” to be dedicated to the District of Columbia for street purposes and the said parcel “D” transferred by plat and/or conveyed by deed to the United States, to be under the jurisdiction of the Director of the National Park Service, then the said Director, with the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, acting for and in behalf of the United States of America, is authorized and directed to transfer by plat as provided herein and/or convey by deed all the land comprised in the parcel designated “E” as shown on said map filed in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia and numbered as map 1817, said transfer and/or conveyance to be made to the owner or owners making the transfer and/or conveyance of said parcel designated “D” to the United States, such transfers and/or deeds of conveyance to pass title in fee simple to the said land, and any and all of such transfers when duly executed and consummated shall constitute legal conveyances of the parcels herein described to the parties in interest; provided, however, that good and sufficient title, satisfactory to the Mayor of the District of Columbia and the Director of the National Park Service, shall be given with respect to the land contained in said parcels “C” and “D,” respectively; and provided further, that upon the transfer by plat and/or the conveyance by deed of the said parcel designated “E,” as provided herein, the land contained in said parcel shall be subject to assessment and taxation the same in all respects as other private property in the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Apr. 13, 1934, 48 Stat. 575, ch. 114, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 8-115.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 8-119.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Director of the National Park Service relating to public buildings were transferred to the Federal Works Administrator by § 303 (b) of  Reorganization Plan No. I, July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2729, 53 Stat. 1427. All functions of all officers of the Department of the Interior (including the Director of the National Park Service) and all functions of all agencies and employees of such Department were, with 2 exceptions, transferred to the Secretary of the Interior, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or the performance of any of his functions by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 3, §§ 1, 2, 15 F.R. 3174, 64 Stat. 1262. All functions of the Federal Works Agency and of all agencies thereof, together with all functions of the Federal Works Administrator, and all functions of the Commissioner of Public Buildings and the Public Buildings Administration, were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380, ch. 288. The Federal Works Agency, the Office of Federal Works Administrator, the Office of Commissioner of Public Buildings, and the Public Buildings Administration, were abolished by § 103(b) of said Act. All functions with respect to acquiring space in buildings by lease and all functions with respect to assigning and reassigning space in buildings for use by agencies (including both space acquired by lease and space in government-owned buildings), were, with certain exceptions, transferred from the respective agencies in which theretofore vested to the Administrator of General Services by §  1 of 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 18, 15 F.R. 3177, 64 Stat. 1270.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
