<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-1202.33</num>
  <heading>Eminent domain.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may exercise eminent domain in accordance with the procedures set forth in <cite path="16|13|II">subchapter II of Chapter 13 of Title 16</cite> to acquire properties in the New Convention Center Hotel Site to construct and develop the New Convention Center Hotel and such other real properties that the Mayor determines are necessary or convenient to construct a connection between the New Convention Center Hotel and the New Convention Center.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The New Convention Center Hotel shall be constructed for the purpose of enhancing the New Convention Center and, to the extent the Mayor determines feasible, shall be physically connected to the New Convention Center, above or below grade, to permit direct access between the New Convention Center Hotel and the New Convention Center. The New Convention Center Hotel shall be located adjacent to or in close proximity to the New Convention Center and shall have approximately 1,100 rooms and suites, together with meeting and ballroom space, and other ancillary facilities, including retail, customarily found in similar convention center hotels.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-188" type="History" path="§233">Sept. 28, 1994, D.C. Law 10-188, § 233, formerly § 803</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-163" type="History">as added Sept. 19, 2006, D.C. Law 16-163, § 201, 53 DCR 5430</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-144" type="History">Apr. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-144, § 3(h), 55 DCR 2527</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">renumbered Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 122(i), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 201 of New Convention Center Hotel Omnibus Financing and Development Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-404, June 26, 2006,  53 DCR 5404).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in the credit, renumbered the section designation from § 803 to § 233.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-144">D.C. Law 17-144</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
