<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-304</num>
  <heading>Park adoptions and sponsorships.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Individuals, associations, corporations, partnerships, neighborhood and civic groups, nonprofit organizations, or other governmental entities may adopt or sponsor Departmental programs, sites, facilities, fields, or operations. The form of such adoption or sponsorship may be made by a donation of funds to the Fund, services, equipment, or any other asset with intrinsic value. The Department may form partnerships with any of the above stated groups to accomplish a stated goal or mission of the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall, within 1 year from March 23, 1995, promulgate regulations appropriate for the full implementation of this chapter including regulations related to park adoptions and sponsorships, vending and concessions fees, and permits.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-246" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-246, § 5, 42 DCR 452</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-110" type="History">Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 20(b), 43 DCR 530</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-68" type="History">Feb. 26, 2016, D.C. Law 21-68, § 3, 62 DCR 16266</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-303">10-303</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 8-304.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-68">D.C. Law 21-68</law-cite> substituted “neighborhood and civic groups, nonprofit organizations, or other governmental entities may adopt or sponsor Departmental programs, sites, facilities, fields, or operations” for “neighborhood and civic groups or other governmental entities may adopt or sponsor Departmental programs, sites, or operations” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§10-301">10-301</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 3 of the Athletic Field Naming and Sponsorship Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-201, Nov. 23, 2015,  62 DCR 15274).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 3 of the Athletic Field Naming and Sponsorship Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-302, Feb. 18, 2016,  63 DCR 2171).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
