<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-509.05</num>
  <heading>Reciprocal agreements with states.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia may enter into agreements with any of the states, or any political subdivision thereof, where any such institution mentioned in § <cite path="§10-509.01">10-509.01</cite> is located, for such governmental services as the Mayor shall deem necessary to the efficient and proper government of such institution, and they may, from time to time, agree to modifications in any such agreement; provided, that where the charge for any such service is established by the laws of the state within whose territorial limits such institution is situated, the Mayor may not pay for such service an amount in excess of the charge so established. There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the making of payment for services under any such agreement.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 84-2-ch508" path="§5">July 3, 1956, 70 Stat. 488, ch. 508, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 9-138.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-134.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
