<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-551.07</num>
  <heading>Representative program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Director may contract for the services of a representative to provide real estate brokerage or real estate consulting services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each contract for the services of a representative shall be awarded on a competitive basis to a qualified real estate professional in accordance with applicable procurement regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The representative shall perform an analysis of all aspects of the proposed contract or real estate transaction, including the costs and benefits, and shall negotiate on behalf of the District; provided, that the representative shall not bind the District, and the terms of the contract shall be approved by the Director and, if applicable, by the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Fees paid for the services of a representative may be paid by either party in a transaction, either as a percentage of the total contract value or a fixed dollar amount, according to the terms of the contract as negotiated between the District and the representative.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§1028">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1028, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1008 of Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-93, June 29, 2011,  58 DCR 5599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1022 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 1022 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
