<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-551.02</num>
  <heading>Organization.</heading>
  <text>There are established 6 primary organizational functions in the Department as follows:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Agency Management, which shall include the staff and organizational units needed to carry out the overall plan and direction for the Department, including coordination and management for information technology, resource allocation, human resources, procurement, fixed-cost forecasting for District facilities, and the administrative functions of the Department;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Capital Construction, which shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Implement and oversee the Department’s capital improvement program for District government facilities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Execute the capital budget program, which includes the rehabilitation of existing real property facilities and construction of new facilities supporting the District;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Portfolio Management, which shall coordinate:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Lease administration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Allocation of owned and leased properties to District agencies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Property acquisition and disposition; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Rent collection from entities leasing District-owned or leased properties;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Facilities Management, which shall coordinate the day-to-day operations of District-owned properties by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Maintaining building assets and equipment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Performing various repairs and non-structural improvements; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Providing janitorial, trash and recycling pickup, postal, and engineering services; provided, that the District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”) shall remain responsible for providing janitorial services at DCPS facilities;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Contracting and Procurement, which shall provide services and support in procuring for the District:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The construction, architecture, and engineering services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The facilities maintenance and operation services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The real estate asset management services, including leasing and auditing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The utility contracts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>The security services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Such other services necessary or desirable to improve the effectiveness of the Department and advance the purposes of this chapter; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Protective Services Division, which shall coordinate, manage, and provide security services for District government facilities through the use of special police officers and security officers, as defined in § <cite path="§47-2839.01">47-2839.01</cite>, civilian employees, or contractors.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§1023">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 1023, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 70(a), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1022, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “this subtitle” for “this act” [translated as “this chapter”] in (5)(F).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> rewrote (6).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1003 of Fiscal Year 2012 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-93, June 29, 2011,  58 DCR 5599).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1022 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1022 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 1021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle C of Title I of the act may be cited as the “Department of General Services Protective Services Division Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
