<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-603</num>
  <heading>Public buildings — Loans for construction authorized; projects enumerated.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized to borrow for the District of Columbia from the Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works created by the National Industrial Recovery Act (which, for the purposes of §§ <cite path="§10-603">10-603</cite> to 10-606, shall be construed to include any agency created or designated by the President for similar purposes under the Emergency Relief Appropriation Act of 1935); and said Administration is authorized to lend to said Mayor the sum of $10,750,000, or any part thereof, out of funds authorized by law for said Administration, for the acquisition, purchase, construction, establishment, and development of a tuberculosis hospital, a sewage-disposal plant, an extension of or addition to Gallinger Municipal Hospital, a jail or other enclosure for prisoners at Lorton, Virginia, and a building or buildings for the Police Court, the Municipal Court, the Recorder of Deeds, and the Juvenile Court, or any of them, said court buildings to be located on such portions or parts of Judiciary Square, or the area bounded by 4th and 5th Streets, D and G Streets, Northwest, as shall be approved by said Mayor, and the National Capital Planning Commission, or any one or more of said projects as the said Mayor may determine; and to advance to the Children’s Hospital of the District of Columbia in compensation for clinical examination of tubercular children, the sum of $100,000 or so much thereof as may be necessary for alterations and enlargement of building, equipment, and accessories.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 73-2-ch743" path="§1">June 25, 1934, 48 Stat. 1215, ch. 743, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 6, 1935, 49 Stat. 174, ch. 91, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-604">10-604</cite>, § <cite path="§10-605">10-605</cite>, § <cite path="§10-606">10-606</cite>, § <cite path="§10-611">10-611</cite>, and § <cite path="§10-612">10-612</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-203.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 9-204.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Act of April 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1, consolidated the Police Court and the Municipal Court into a single court, to be known as “The Municipal Court for the District of Columbia”. Act of July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1, changed the name of the court to the “District of Columbia Court of General Sessions”. Act of July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, § 155(a), changed the name of the court to Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works was consolidated into the Federal Works Agency to be administered by the Public Works Administration by 1939 Reorganization Plan No. 1, §§ 301, 305, 4 F.R. 2729, 53 Stat. 1426. All functions of the Public Works Administration and the Commissioner of Public Works, in the Federal Works Agency, were transferred to the  Federal Works Administrator by Executive Order No. 9357, June 30, 1943, 8 F.R. 9041. All functions of the Federal Works Agency and of all agencies thereof, together with all functions of the Federal Works Administrator, were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380, ch. 288. Both the Federal Works Agency and the Office of Federal Works Administrator were abolished by § 103(b) of the Act of June 30, 1949.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The functions, powers and duties of the National Capital Park and Planning Commission were transferred to the National Capital Planning Commission by the Act of June 6, 1924, ch. 270, § 9, as added by the Act of July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 790, ch. 949, § 1.</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
