<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-607</num>
  <heading>Authorization to borrow money from the United States for public works.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized to accept advancements for the District of Columbia from the Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works, created by the National Industrial Recovery Act, and said Administration with the approval of the President is authorized to advance to said Mayor the sum of $18,150,000, or any part thereof, in addition to any sums heretofore advanced to the District of Columbia by said Administration, out of funds authorized by law for said Administration, for the acquisition, purchase, construction, establishment, and development of public works, including among others a building or buildings for the Municipal Court, the Recorder of Deeds, and the Juvenile Court, or any of them, said buildings to be located on such portions or parts of Judiciary Square, or the area bounded by 4th and 5th Streets, D and G Streets, Northwest, or upon such other area or areas as shall be approved by said Mayor and the National Capital Planning Commission and the making of such advances is hereby included among the purposes for which funds heretofore appropriated or authorized for said Administration, including funds appropriated by the Public Works Administration Appropriation Act of 1938, may be used, in addition to the other purposes specified in the respective acts appropriating or authorizing said funds.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>June 25, 1938, 52 Stat. 1203, ch. 704, § 1</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-608">10-608</cite>, § <cite path="§10-609">10-609</cite>, and § <cite path="§10-610">10-610</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 9-207.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 9-208.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
      <annotation>The Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works was consolidated into the Federal Works Agency to be administered by the Public Works Administration by 1939 Reorganization Plan No. 1, §§ 301, 305, 4 F.R. 2729, 53 Stat. 1426. All functions of the Public Works Administration and the Commissioner of Public Works, in the Federal Works Agency, were transferred to the  Federal Works Administrator by Executive Order No. 9357, June 30, 1943, 8 F.R. 9041. All functions of the Federal Works Agency and of all agencies thereof, together with all functions of the Federal Works Administrator, were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380, ch. 288. Both the Federal Works Agency and the Office of Federal Works Administrator were abolished by § 103(b) of the Act of June 30, 1949.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
