<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-619</num>
  <heading>Program of construction to meet capital needs authorized; contents.</heading>
  <text>A program of construction to meet capital needs of the government of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized. Such program shall include, without limitation, projects relating to activities to meet the needs of the public in the fields of education, health, welfare, public safety, recreation, and other general government activities.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-451" type="History" path="§1">June 6, 1958, 72 Stat. 183, Pub. L. 85-451, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-104" type="History">Aug. 27, 1963, 77 Stat. 130, Pub. L. 88-104, § 2(a), (b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-173" type="History">Sept. 8, 1965, 79 Stat. 665, Pub. L. 89-173, § 5(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-610" type="History">Sept. 30, 1966, 80 Stat. 857, Pub. L. 89-610, title VI, § 601</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-791" type="History">Nov. 7, 1966, 80 Stat. 1434, Pub. L. 89-791, title III, § 301(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-120" type="History">Nov. 3, 1967, 81 Stat. 339, Pub. L. 90-120, title II, §§ 201, 202</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Dec. 9, 1969, 83 Stat. 321, Pub. L. 91-143, § 4(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-650" type="History">Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1930, Pub. L. 91-650, title I, § 103(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-349" type="History">July 13, 1972, 86 Stat. 466, Pub. L. 92-349, title II, § 201(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-517" type="History">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1002, Pub. L. 92-517, title II, § 201(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 832, Pub. L. 93-198, title VII,§ 743(a)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Appropriations, public higher educational institutions, see § <cite path="§38-1106">38-1106</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Multiyear capital improvements plan, see § <cite path="§1-204.44">1-204.44</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-1106">38-1106</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-219.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 9-220.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Appropriations authorized: Public Law 103-334, 108 Stat. 2581, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1995, provided for construction projects $5,600,000, as authorized by §§ <cite path="§34-2405.01">34-2405.01</cite> through <cite path="§34-2405.08">34-2405.08</cite>; the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954, approved May 18, 1954 (68 Stat. 101; Public Law 83-364 [34-2413.08 and 34-2413.10] ); §§ <cite path="§10-610">10-610</cite> and <cite path="§47-3404">47-3404</cite>) [section 3(g) of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Parking Facility Act of 1942, approved August 20, 1958 (72 Stat. 686; Public Law 85-692; D.C. Code, sec 40-805(7)); and the National Capital Transportation Act of 1969, approved December 9, 1969 (83 Stat. 320; Public Law 91-143;  D.C. Code, secs. 9-1111.01,  9-1111.02,  9-1111.03,  9-1111.04 and  9-1111.05)]; including acquisition of sites, preparation of plans and specifications, conducting preliminary surveys, erection of structures, including building improvement and alteration and treatment of grounds, to remain available until expended: Provided, That $140,000 shall be available for project management and $110,000 shall be available for design by the Director of the Department of Public Works or by contract for architectural engineering services, as may be determined by the Mayor: Provided further, That funds for use of each capital project implementing agency shall be managed and controlled in accordance with all procedures and limitations established under the Financial Management System: Provided further, That all funds provided by this appropriation title shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended: Provided further, That notwithstanding the foregoing, all authorizations for capital outlay projects, except those projects covered by the first sentence of section 23(a) of the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1968, approved August 23, 1968 (82 Stat. 827; Public Law 90-495;  D.C. Code, sec. 9-107.01, note), for which funds are provided by this appropriation title, shall expire on September 30, 1996, except authorizations for projects as to which funds have been obligated in whole or in part prior to September 30, 1996: Provided further, That upon expiration of any such project authorization the funds provided herein for the project shall lapse.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Appropriations authorized: Public Law 104-194, 110 Stat. 2362, the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 1997, provided for construction projects an increase of $46,923,000 (including an increase of $34,000,000 for the highway trust fund, reallocations and rescissions for a net rescission of $120,496,000 from local funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years and an additional $133,419,000 in Federal funds), as authorized by §§ <cite path="§34-2405.01">34-2405.01</cite> through <cite path="§34-2405.08">34-2405.08</cite>; §§ <cite path="§34-2413.08">34-2413.08</cite>, <cite path="§34-2413.10">34-2413.10</cite> and <cite path="§34-2304">34-2304</cite>; and §§ <cite path="§10-619">10-619</cite> and <cite path="§47-3404">47-3404</cite>; including acquisition of sites, preparation of plans and specifications, conducting preliminary surveys, erection of structures, including building improvement and alteration and treatment of grounds, to remain available until expended: Provided, That funds for use of each capital project implementing agency shall be managed and controlled in accordance with all procedures and limitations established under the Financial Management System: Provided further, That all funds provided by this appropriation title shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended: Provided further, That notwithstanding the foregoing, all authorizations for capital outlay projects, except those projects covered by the first sentence of section 23(a) of the Federal-Aid Highway Act of 1968, approved August 23, 1968 (82 Stat. 827; Public Law 90-495;  D.C. Code, sec. 9-107.01, note), for which funds are provided by this appropriation title, shall expire on September 30, 1998, except authorizations for projects as to which funds have been obligated in whole or in part prior to September 30, 1998: Provided further, That upon expiration of any such project authorization the funds provided herein for the project shall lapse.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
