<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-616</num>
  <heading>Repayment of advancements; interest.</heading>
  <text>The Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works, or its successor, shall be repaid 55 per centum of any moneys advanced under § <cite path="§10-614">10-614</cite> in annual instalments over a period of not to exceed 25 years with interest thereon at such rate as is agreed upon by the Mayor of the District and the Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works, or its successor, for the period of amortization; provided, that such sums as may be necessary for the reimbursement herein required of the District of Columbia, and for the payment of interest, shall be included in the annual estimates of the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the 1st reimbursement with interest to be made not later than June 30, 1944; provided further, that whenever the District of Columbia is under obligation by virtue of the provisions of § 4 of Public Act No. 284, 71st Congress, 46 Stat. 482, ch. 354, reimbursement under that Act shall not be less than $300,000 in any 1 fiscal year.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 11, 1940, 54 Stat. 757, ch. 583, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-216.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 9-217.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">The Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works was consolidated into the Federal Works Agency to be administered by the Public Works Administration by 1939 Reorganization Plan No. 1, §§ 301, 305, 4 F.R. 2729, 53 Stat. 1426. All functions of the Public Works Administration and the Commissioner of Public Works, in the Federal Works Agency, were transferred to the  Federal Works Administrator by Executive Order No. 9357, June 30, 1943, 8 F.R. 9041. All functions of the Federal Works Agency and of all agencies thereof, together with all functions of the Federal Works Administrator, were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380, ch. 288. Both the Federal Works Agency and the Office of Federal Works Administrator were abolished by § 103(b) of the Act of June 30, 1949.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
