<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-833</num>
  <heading>Minimum standards for disposition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A request for proposals issued pursuant to this subchapter shall contain the following provisions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No person shall be eligible to purchase a property disposed of pursuant to this subchapter unless the person first signs a first source employment agreement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No person shall be eligible to purchase a property disposed of pursuant to this subchapter unless the person first signs a certificate evidencing the person’s intent to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Department of Small and Local Business Development, established by § <cite path="§2-218.11">2-218.11</cite>, to make a good-faith effort to contract with, and procure from, local, small, and disadvantaged business enterprises (“LSDBE MOUs”). The contents of the certificate and the memorandum shall be determined by the Department of Small and Local Business Development, established by § <cite path="§2-218.11">2-218.11</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each property disposed of pursuant to the RFP shall be rehabilitated and offered for sale or rental to the public in no more than 12 months, or such shorter period determined by the Mayor, after the disposition of the property.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish other minimum standards as part of the RFP.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall list all known minimum requirements as part of the RFP.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-267" type="History">Apr. 2, 2003, D.C. Law 14-267, § 4, 50 DCR 420</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-119" type="History">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-119, § 3(c), 53 DCR 2609</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 42, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-835">10-835</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-119">D.C. Law 16-119</cite>, in par. (a)(3), substituted “offered for sale or rental” for “offered for sale”; and repealed pars. (a)(4) and (a)(5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in subsec. (a)(2), substituted “Department of Small and Local Business Development, established by § <cite path="§2-218.11">2-218.11</cite>” for “Office of Local Business Development”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 4 of Abandoned and Vacant Properties Community Development Disposition, and Disapproval of Disposition of Certain Scattered Vacant and Abandoned Properties Temporary of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-203">D.C. Law 14-203</cite>, October 17, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 10021).</text>
    </annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
