<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-831</num>
  <heading>Properties subject to disposition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may dispose of real property that is, or has previously been determined to be, abandoned or deteriorated property, as those terms are defined in § <cite path="§42-3171.01">42-3171.01</cite>, under this subchapter if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The property is owned or acquired by the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The property is suitable for, and the Mayor proposes construction, reconstruction, or rehabilitation as, a single-household property or a multi-household property containing 25 or fewer single-household dwelling units; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The property is listed in § <cite path="§10-839">10-839</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Disposition of the property pursuant to this subchapter is approved by the Council pursuant to a proposed resolution transmitted by the Mayor for a 5-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess. If no Councilmember introduces a disapproval resolution within the 5-day period, the resolution shall be deemed approved at the end of the 5-day period. If a resolution of disapproval is introduced by at least 3 Councilmembers within the 5-day period, the Council review period shall be 45 days from the date the Mayor transmitted the proposed resolution to the Council, excluding days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve the disapproval resolution within the 45-day period, the resolution shall be deemed approved.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The authority of the Mayor under this subchapter shall expire on September 30, 2011.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The process for disposing of any property pursuant to this subchapter shall be conducted solely pursuant to the requirements set forth in this subchapter and shall not be subject to any other statutory provision governing the process for the disposition of real property, nor shall any property disposed of pursuant to this subchapter be subject to the prerequisites to disposition of property set forth in § <cite path="§42-3171.03">42-3171.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-267" type="History">Apr. 2, 2003, D.C. Law 14-267, § 2, 50 DCR 420</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 2002(a), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-119" type="History">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-119, § 3(a), 53 DCR 2609</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§10-839">10-839</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</law-cite> rewrote pars. (1) and (2) of subsec. (a); in subsec. (b), substituted “2006” for “2004”; and added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-119">D.C. Law 16-119</law-cite>, in par. (a)(2), substituted “a single-household property or a multi- household property containing 25 or fewer single-household dwelling units” for “a single-household residence or a multi-household residence of 5 or fewer units”; and in subsec. (b), substituted “2011” for “2006”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Abandoned and Vacant Properties Community Development Disposition, and Disapproval of Disposition of Certain Scattered Vacant and Abandoned Properties Temporary of 2002 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-203">D.C. Law 14-203</law-cite>, October 17, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 10021).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(a) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(a) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle A of title II of Law 15-205: Section 2001 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</law-cite> provided that subtitle A of title II of the act may be cited as the Vacant and Abandoned Properties Amendment Act of 2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of the Mayor’s Disposition Authority to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development to Dispose of Certain Vacant and Abandoned Real Property in the District of Columbia, see Mayor’s Order 2005-189, December 2, 2005 ( 53 DCR 693).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority to the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development, see Mayor’s Order 2007-209, September 27, 2007 ( 55 DCR 133).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 16-204, the “Vacant and Abatement Properties Community Development Disposition Approval Resolution of 2005”, was approved effective June 13, 2005.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 11 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-267">D.C. Law 14-267</law-cite> provided: “The Disposition of Certain Scattered Vacant and Abandoned Properties Approval Resolution of 2002, introduced on March 1, 2002 (P.R. 14-585), is disapproved.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
