<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>10-801</num>
  <heading>Authorization; description of property; submission and approval of resolution; reacquisition rights; notice.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except for real property disposed of pursuant to <cite path="§6-1005|(c)">§ 6-1005(c)</cite>, the Mayor is authorized and empowered, in his discretion, for the best interests of the District of Columbia (“District”), and with the approval of the Council by resolution, to sell, convey, lease (inclusive of options) for a period of greater than 20 years, exchange, or otherwise dispose of real property, in whole or in part, now or hereafter owned in fee simple by the District, whether purchased with appropriated, grant, or other funds, the proceeds of general obligation bonds or tax revenue anticipation notes issued by the District government, or United States Treasury Notes, or obtained by any other means including exchange, condemnation, eminent domain, gift, dedication, donation, devise or assignment, for municipal, community development, or other public purpose, which the Council finds to be no longer required for public purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall submit separate resolutions for the determination that the real property is no longer required for public purposes pursuant to subsection (a-1) of this section and for the approval of its disposition pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Mayor believes that real property is no longer required for public purposes, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a proposed resolution which includes a finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes. In the proposed resolution submitted to the Council, the Mayor shall also provide a description of the real property and a detailed explanation as to why the real property is no longer required for public purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The proposed resolution shall be accompanied by an analysis setting forth:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Whether the real property has any necessary use by the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Why the determination that the real property is no longer required for public purposes is in the best interests of the District; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A summary of public comments received at the public hearing required under paragraph (4) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The proposed resolution shall be submitted to the Council for a 90-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed resolution within the 90-day period, the proposed resolution shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Before submitting a proposed resolution pursuant to this subsection, the Mayor shall hold at least one public hearing on the finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes. The hearing shall be held at an accessible evening or weekend time and in an accessible location in the vicinity of the real property. The Mayor shall provide at least 30 days notice to Advisory Neighborhood Commissions of the public hearing and shall publicize the hearing by placing a notice in the District of Columbia Register at least 15 days before the hearing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall be deemed to have met the requirements of paragraphs (2)(C) and (4) of this subsection if, prior to April 19, 2010, the Mayor submitted the proposed resolution pursuant to this subsection to the Council and, prior to March 10, 2010, the Mayor engaged in community outreach efforts regarding the real property’s proposed redevelopment; provided, that the community outreach:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Occurred in an accessible location, or accessible locations, in the vicinity of the real property; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Involved a discussion of the proposed redevelopment plan for real property.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-2)</num>
    <text>If the Council determines that the real property is no longer required for public purposes pursuant to subsection (a-1) of this section, the Mayor shall attempt to dispose of the real property for a use with a direct public benefit as described in a specific government plan adopted by the Mayor or Council, including the Community Development Plan, the Comprehensive Plan, the Strategic Neighborhood Area Plan, or the Comprehensive Housing Strategy Plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-3)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a proposed disposition of real property will result in the development of multifamily residential property consisting of 10 or more units (“multifamily units”), the following affordable housing requirements shall apply:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the multifamily units are located in the following areas, at least 30% of the units shall be dedicated as affordable housing:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Within ½ mile of a Metrorail station that is in operation or for which a construction contract has been awarded on or before the date of the disposition;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Within ¼ mile of a streetcar line that is in operation or for which a construction contract has been awarded on or before the date of the disposition; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Within ¼ mile of a Priority Corridor Network Metrobus Route, as designated by the Washington Area Metropolitan Transit Authority, located entirely or partially within the District of Columbia;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If the multifamily units are located outside of the areas described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, at least 20% of the units shall be dedicated as affordable housing;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The units dedicated as affordable housing pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph shall remain affordable housing units for the life of the building; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The purchase price for the second and subsequent sales of the units dedicated as affordable housing described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph shall be determined by a formula established by the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The units dedicated as affordable housing pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph shall be made available according to the following affordability levels:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of rental units, 25% of the units shall be housing for which a very low-income household will pay no more than 30% of its income toward housing costs, and 75% of such units shall be housing for which a low-income household will pay no more than 30% of its income toward housing costs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of ownership units, 50% of the units shall be housing for which a low-income household will pay no more than 30% of its income toward housing costs, and 50% of the units shall be housing for which a moderate-income household will pay no more than 30% of its income toward housing costs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall take into account the affordable housing requirements of this subsection when establishing the terms and conditions under which real property is to be disposed. The Mayor may transfer real property at less than its appraised value or provide additional subsidies to a developer, as necessary, to ensure that the affordable housing requirements imposed by this subsection are met.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may waive the affordable housing requirements of this subsection; provided, that the Mayor certifies that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The appraised value of the property to be disposed is insufficient to support the affordable housing requirements, taking into account all other available sources of public funding for affordable housing, whether provided by the District of Columbia or the federal government;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The terms and conditions under which the real property is to be disposed satisfy the housing requirements to the maximum extent possible; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Chief Financial Officer has provided to the Mayor and the Council a financial analysis, which shall consist of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A review and analysis of the financial condition of disposed land; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>An advisory opinion stating whether or not it is likely that the developer could be reasonably expected to meet the affordable housing requirements outlined in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (4) of this subsection shall not apply to the disposition of the building and property owned by the District located at 425 2nd Street, N.W., unless the District commits to using all of the proceeds from the disposition of the property for the construction of a new homeless shelter and affordable housing to serve homeless populations.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may reduce the affordable housing requirements of this section if the proposed disposition of real property finances the development of a significant public facility. For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “public facility” means a building, structure, or system that is an asset of the District government eligible for capital spending and subject to depreciation. A public facility may include a fire station, public library, public school, stadium, or homeless shelter. Notwithstanding the priority to finance a significant public facility, the Mayor shall nevertheless endeavor to provide affordable housing, consistent with this section, to the extent economically feasible.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, shall transmit to the Council a proposed resolution that contains the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The name and business address of the developer, and, if the developer is a joint venture or partnership, the name and business address of each person that constitutes the partnership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A description of the real property to be disposed of;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A description of the intended use for the property (“Project”);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If applicable, a finding that the Developer will achieve the affordable housing requirements established by subsection (a-3) of this section or, if those requirements will not be achieved, a written certification by the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to subsection (a-3)(4) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A finding that the Developer will enter into an agreement that shall require the Developer to, at a minimum, contract with Certified Business Enterprises for at least 35% of the contract dollar volume of the project, and shall require at least 20% equity and 20% development participation of Certified Business Enterprises;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A finding that the Developer will enter into a First Source Agreement with the District that shall govern certain obligations of Developer pursuant to <cite path="§2-219.03">§ 2-219.03</cite> and Mayor’s Order 83-265 (November 9, 1983) regarding job creation and employment generated as a result of the construction on the Property;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The proposed method of disposition, which may be one of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A public or private sale to the highest bidder;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A negotiated sale to a for-profit or nonprofit entity for specifically designated purposes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A lease for a period of greater than 20 years;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A combination sale/leaseback for specifically designated purposes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>An exchange of interests in real property; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>A public or private sale to the bidder providing the most benefit to the District; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The following statement:</text>
      <text>“All documents that are submitted with this resolution pursuant to subsection (b-1) of this section shall be consistent with the executed Memorandum of Understanding or term sheet transmitted to the Council pursuant to subsection (b-1)(2) of this section.”.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>A proposed resolution to provide for the disposition of real property transmitted to the Council pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be accompanied by the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An analysis prepared by the Mayor of the economic factors that were considered in proposing the disposition of the real property, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The chosen method of disposition, and how competition was maximized;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The manner in which economic factors were weighted and evaluated, including estimates of the monetary benefits and costs to the District that will result from the disposition. The benefits shall include revenues, fees, and other payments to the District, as well as the creation of jobs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A description of all disposition methods considered and an accompanying narrative for the proposed disposition method that contains comparisons to the other methods and shows why the proposed method was more beneficial for the District than the others in the areas of return on investment, subsidies required, revenues paid to the District, and any other relevant category, or why it is being proposed despite it being less beneficial to the District in any of the measured categories.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An executed term sheet or Memorandum of Understanding between the District and the selected developer that shall include the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A description of the major business terms of the transaction;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A description of the method of disposition;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A description of the Certified Business Enterprise requirements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A description of the green building requirements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A description of the schedule of performance; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Any other terms that the Mayor finds to be in the best interest of the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A document reporting the value of the property prepared by an independent appraiser or assessor performed within 12 months of transmission of the proposed resolution.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For any development project where the total value of the government assistance is greater than $10 million, a description of the project funding and financing plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For all District land being disposed for purposes of development and requiring government assistance the following additional items shall be transmitted to the Council concurrent with the proposed resolution and analysis:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A Land Disposition Agreement between the District and the selected developer;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Any community benefits agreement between the developer and the relevant community, if any; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A Certified Business Enterprise (“CBE”) Agreement pursuant to subchapter IX-A of <cite path="2|2">Chapter 2 of Title 2</cite> [<cite path="§2-218.01">§ 2-218.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Documents in this paragraph shall be transmitted in the most current form available at the time the resolution is transmitted.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>All documents referenced in this paragraph shall be consistent with the proposed resolution for land disposition and language to that effect shall be included in those agreements prior to execution.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If a substantive change is made to the term sheet or Memorandum of Understanding referenced in subsection ((b-1)(2) of this section, after the resolution was transmitted to and approved by the Council pursuant to this subsection, a resolution describing the change accompanied by an amended term sheet or Memorandum of Understanding in redline format shall be transmitted to Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed amendments to the term sheet, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 30-day review period, the proposed amendments shall be deemed approved.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For the purpose of this paragraph, the term:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>“Redline format” means the changes that are deletions have a line through them and the changes that are additions are underlined.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>“Substantive change” means a change that makes the agreement inconsistent with the executed Memorandum of Understanding or term sheet transmitted with the proposed resolution.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The proposed resolution to provide for the disposition of real property pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be submitted to the Council for a 90-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove of the proposed disposition of the property, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 90-day period, the proposed resolution shall be deemed disapproved. Nothing in this section shall affect any requirements imposed upon the Mayor by <cite path="2|5|I">subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Approval of the disposition of the real property by the Council shall expire 2 years after the effective date of the resolution of approval. If the Mayor determines prior to the end of the 2-year period that the property cannot be disposed of within the 2-year period, the Mayor may submit to the Council, no later than 60 days prior to the end of the 2-year period, a resolution seeking additional time for the disposition of the property, and shall include with the resolution a detailed status report on efforts made toward disposition of the property as well as the reasons for the inability to dispose of the property within the 2-year period. If the Council does not take action to approve or disapprove the resolution within 30 days of receipt of the resolution, not including Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, or days of Council recess, the resolution shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of the property located at 2341 4th Street, N.E., pursuant to the Unsolicited Proposal Submitted by the H Street Community Development Corporation for the Acquisition and Development of 2341 4th Street, N.E., Resolution of 1999, deemed approved February 10, 2000 (PR13-436), is extended to February 10, 2004.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall apply as of February 10, 2000.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-2)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of Square 5912, Lot 804 in Ward 8 in accordance with the Request for Proposals for the Disposition of Camp Simms Approval Resolution of 2000, effective December 5, 2000 (Res. 13-715; 47 DCR 9984), is extended to March 2, 2006.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall apply as of December 5, 2002.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-3)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (d) and (e) of this section, the Mayor may dispose of the following properties:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Lots 106 and 803 in Square 442, in a manner not inconsistent with the Council’s approval of the dispositions of these parcels pursuant to the Development of Small Parcels Resolution of 2006, deemed approved October 27, 2006 (Res. 16-849; 53 DCR 9376); and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Lots 848 and 849 in Square 2906 in a manner not inconsistent with the Council’s approval of the dispositions of these parcels pursuant to the Disposition of Lots 848 and 849 in Square 2906 Approval Resolution of 2005, deemed approved July 2, 2005 (Res. 16-280; 52 DCR 7961).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor’s authority to dispose of the properties listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall expire on November 5, 2009.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-4)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (d) and subsection (e)of this section, the Mayor shall dispose of the property located at 35-41 K Street, N.E., designated for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 0838 in Square 0675 (“K Street property”), through a solicitation to be issued no later than October 1, 2013; provided, that if the contingency set forth in paragraph (2)(B) of this subsection is met, the Mayor may dispose of the K Street property through a solicitation to be issued no later than October 1, 2013.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Except as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection, the net proceeds from the disposition by sale, as authorized by subsection (b)(8) of this section, of the K Street property shall be deposited into the Housing Production Trust Fund, established by <cite path="§42-2802">§ 42-2802</cite> (“HPTF”), unless the HPTF has been fully funded pursuant to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph and paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If, before the K Street property disposition, the Chief Financial Officer certifies that there is revenue available to fund section 10002(a)(4) of the Revised Revenue Estimate Contingency Priority List Act of 2012, effective September 20, 2012 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>; 59 DCR 8025) (“priority number 4”), the certified available revenue shall be deposited into the HPTF.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If, after the K Street property disposition and the deposit of the net proceeds into the HPTF, the Chief Financial Officer certifies that there is revenue available to fund priority number 4, the certified available revenue, less any shortfall of the $18 million provided for in priority number 4 that was not deposited into the HPTF, which shall be deposited into the HPTF, shall be available to fund NoMa in accordance with priority number 4.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d-5)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of District-owned real property located at the northeast corner of Sixth and E Streets, S.W., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 0036 in Square 0494, for the construction of a mixed-use development, which was approved by the Council pursuant to the Fourth/Sixth and E Streets, S.W., Property Disposition Approval Resolution of 2009, effective November 3, 2009 (Res. 18-290; 56 DCR 8799), as extended by the Fourth/Sixth and E Streets, S.W., Property Disposition Extension Approval Resolution of 2011, effective July 12, 2011 (Res. 19-170; 58 DCR 6589), is extended to November 3, 2017.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall incorporate into the terms of the disposition of real property disposed of through a negotiated sale pursuant to this section, the right of the District to reacquire the property at the price originally conveyed plus any amounts secured by the property that have been approved by the Mayor, if the property is no longer used for the authorized purpose. For property located within the corporate boundaries of the District, if the District does not exercise its reacquisition option, the owner in fee simple shall be entitled to use the property or sell, convey, or otherwise dispose of the property for use in a manner that is consistent with the designation of the real property on:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Generalized Land Use Maps adopted pursuant to <cite path="§1-301.63">§ 1-301.63</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Official Zoning Map of the District of Columbia adopted pursuant to <cite path="§6-641.01">§ 6-641.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e-1)</num>
    <text>In the case of any real property to be disposed under this section through a request for proposals or competitive sealed proposals, the Mayor shall include economic factors, including revenues, fees, and other payments to the District, as one of the criteria to evaluate the request for proposals or competitive sealed proposals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall take any steps necessary to ensure continuous community input in the disposition of any real property to be disposed of in accordance with this section, which shall include, for property located within the corporate boundaries of the District, providing notice to any affected Advisory Neighborhood Commission of the final terms and conditions for the sale of the property, for review and comment in accordance with <cite path="§1-309.10">§ 1-309.10</cite>, prior to the disposition of the property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f-1)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to any real property which is acquired under <cite path="§42-3171.02">§ 42-3171.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>For real property that the Mayor has determined, after input from affected communities, to be no longer needed by the District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”), the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report on whether the Mayor intends to dispose of the real property to a public charter school under <cite path="§38-1802.09">§ 38-1802.09</cite> or for use by another agency of the District government. The report shall be submitted to the Council by the Mayor within 90 days of the determination that the real property is no longer needed by the DCPS. If the report is not submitted by the Mayor to the Council within the 90-day period, the Mayor shall dispose of the real property in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter and shall transmit to the Council the resolutions required by subsection (a)(2) of this section within 180 days of the Mayor’s determination.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, or any rule of law, the Board is authorized to sell and convey the property located at 13th and K Streets, N.W., Lot 808, Square 285, commonly referred to as the Franklin School (“Franklin”) to the H Street Community Development Corporation (“H Street”), and to enter into and execute all agreements necessary to consummate this sale, provided that the Board and H Street have entered into a contract specifying that H Street shall resell and reconvey Franklin to the District of Columbia, for the use of the Board, for an amount equal to the price for which H Street purchased Franklin, once renovations have been completed and all of the Board’s outstanding debts to H Street related to the renovation of Franklin have been discharged. The Board is further authorized and directed to enter into and execute all agreements necessary to consummate the repurchase of Franklin within 90 days of the completion of the renovations and the discharge of the Board’s debts for said renovation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Board is authorized to expend an amount not to exceed $4 million for the renovation of Rabaut and 2 other schools for District of Columbia Public Schools administrative offices, excluding Franklin; provided, however, that if these renovation costs are likely to exceed $4 million, the Board must come back to the Council for approval of additional expenditures of appropriated operating funds for these purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>All District fees and taxes associated with the Board’s sale and repurchase of Franklin, and H Street’s ownership and renovation of Franklin, shall be waived.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>The contractor hired by the Board shall provide an opportunity for students from the District of Columbia Public Schools to participate in vocational training programs with employment opportunities with this renovation project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>The Board shall not expend any appropriated funds to pay for restoration costs but shall use funds to renovate the building to meet minimum occupancy requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(m)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this subchapter shall not apply to real property acquired by the District or an instrumentality of the District (or a subsidiary thereof) under <cite path="§47-1353|(a)|(3)">§ 47-1353(a)(3)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(n)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Area median income” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>For a household of 4 persons, the area median income in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For a household of 3 persons, 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a household of 2 persons, 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>For a household of one person, 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>For a household of more than 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons, increased by 10% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons for each household member exceeding 4 persons.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Housing costs” means:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the case of rental units, rent and utilities.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of ownership units, mortgage payments, including principal, interest, and property insurance, taxes, homeowner association, condominium, or cooperative fees, and utilities.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Low-income household” means a household consisting of one or more persons with a total household income that is more than 30% and less than or equal to 50% of the area median income.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Moderate-income household” means a household consisting of one or more persons with total household income more than 50% and less than or equal to 80% of the area median income.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“Very low-income household” means a household consisting of one or more persons with total household income less than or equal to 30% of the area median income.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(o)</num>
    <text>The net proceeds from the disposition of the McMillan Sand Filtration Site approved by the McMillan Residential Townhomes Parcel Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-705; 62 DCR 1091), the McMillan Residential Multifamily Parcels Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-706; 62 DCR 1094), and the McMillan Commercial Parcel Disposition Approval Resolution of 2014, effective December 2, 2014 (Res. 20-707; 62 DCR 1097), shall not be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia but instead shall be deposited into the capital fund account associated with the McMillan Site Redevelopment, EB0-AMS11C.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-1-ch449" path="§1">Aug. 5, 1939, 53 Stat. 1211, ch. 449, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-96" type="History">Mar. 15, 1990, D.C. Law 8-96, § 3, 37 DCR 795</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-158" type="History">Sept. 11, 1990, D.C. Law 8-158, § 2(a), 37 DCR 4167</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-216" type="History">Mar. 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-216, § 2 41 DCR 8038</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-110" type="History">Apr. 18, 1996, D.C. Law 11-110, § 21, 43 DCR 530</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114" type="History">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 102, 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 15(a), 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 5, 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-127" type="History">Mar. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-127, § 2, 51 DCR 1549</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-285" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-285, § 2, 52 DCR 857</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 92, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-112" type="History">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-112, § 2, 53 DCR 2536</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-138" type="History">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 704, 55 DCR 1689</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-76" type="History">Oct. 22, 2009, D.C. Law 18-76, § 2, 56 DCR 6895</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-115" type="History">Mar. 11, 2010, D.C. Law 18-115, § 2(a), 57 DCR 886</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-201" type="History">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-201, § 2, 57 DCR 4742</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2132, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 67, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-193" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-193, § 2, 61 DCR 12407</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 8012, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-62" type="History">Feb. 2, 2016, D.C. Law 21-62, § 2, 62 DCR 15612</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-94">D.C. Law 7-94</cite> “Conveyance of Real Property Act of 1984”, see Mayor’s Order 88-123, May 16,</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">The functions, powers and duties of the National Capital Park and Planning Commission were transferred to the National Capital Planning Commission by the Act of June 6, 1924, ch. 270, § 9, as added by the Act of July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 790, ch. 949, § 1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">A description of the Generalized Land Use Maps adopted pursuant to <cite path="§1-306.02">§ 1-306.02</cite>, referred to in (e)(1), is located at  10 DCMR § 1135 (March 1989).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 2131 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle N of Title II of the act may be cited as the “African-American Civil War Memorial Freedom Foundation Inc., Museum Development Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Sixth and E Streets, S.W., Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-286, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1195).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-185, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14218).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Property Located at Sixth and E Streets, S.W., Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-181, Oct. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 14209).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8012 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-4, Feb. 19, 2015,  62 DCR 2470, 21 STAT 803).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary  (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension  of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Second Congressional Review  Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-478, Nov. 13, 2014, 61  DCR 12127, 20 STAT 4402).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) approval of Contract No. DCPL-2013-C-0004 with Martinez and Johnson Architecture to provide architectural and engineering design services for the Martin Luther King Jr. Memorial Library, see § 2 of the Proposed Multiyear Contract No. DCPL-2013-C-0004 Approval and Payment Authorization Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-394, July 29, 2014,  61 DCR 8076).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-270, January 16, 2014,  61 DCR 790).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-205, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15482).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) African-American Civil War Memorial Museum Development, see §§ 2132 and 2133 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) African-American Civil War Memorial Museum Development, see §§ 2132 — 2134 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Hine Junior High School Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-113, July 23, 2013,  60 DCR 11104, 20 DCSTAT 1814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Justice Park Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-66, May 15, 2013,  60 DCR 7230, 20 DCSTAT 1416).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) extension of time to dispose of Strand Theater property, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-11, February 20, 2013,  60 DCR 3958, 20 DCSTAT 464).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) extension of time to dispose of Eastern Avenue property, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Eastern Avenue Property Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-10, February 20, 2013,  60 DCR 3956, 20 DCSTAT 462).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (d-6), see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-11, February 20, 2013,  60 DCR 3958), applicable as of January 2, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (d-5), see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Eastern Avenue Property Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-10, February 20, 2013,  60 DCR 3956, applicable as of January 2, 2013).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (d-6), see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Eastern Avenue Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-457, October 4, 2012,  59 DCR 11748).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (d-5), see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Eastern Avenue Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-456, October 4, 2012,  59 DCR 11746).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2132 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2132 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Howard Theatre Easement Disposition Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-267, January 15, 2012,  59 DCR 209).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Review Period for the Proposed Disposition of the J.F. Cook School Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-576, October 19, 2010,  57 DCR 10105).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Review Period for the Proposed Disposition of the J.F. Cook School Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-509, July 30, 2010,  57 DCR 7588).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Old Naval Hospital Community Obligation Requirements Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-399, May 5, 2010,  57 DCR 4365).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 and 3 of Washington Center for Aging Services Disposition Approval Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-363, April 2, 2010,  57 DCR 3161).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of District Land Disposition Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-209, October 21, 2009,  56 DCR 8483).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of District Land Disposition Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-140, July 16, 2009,  56 DCR 5864).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 and 3 of Franklin Shelter Closing Requirements Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-518, September 30, 2008,  55 DCR 10898).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Time to Dispose of the Old Congress Heights School Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-303, February 22, 2008,  55 DCR 2512).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of School Without Walls Development Project Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-673, December 28, 2006,  54 DCR 1163).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) re-authorization of agreement provisions, see § 2 of Fringe Lot Real Property Exclusive Rights Agreement Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-412, July 12, 2006,  53 DCR 5774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of School Without Walls Development Project Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-373, May 19, 2006,  53 DCR 4386).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of School Without Walls Development Project Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-285, February 27, 2006,  53 DCR 1637).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-202, November 17, 2005,  52 DCR 10511).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Time to Dispose of Property for Golden Rule Development Project Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-37, February 17, 2005,  52 DCR 3028).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-33, February 17, 2005,  52 DCR 3018).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District-Owned Surplus Real Property in Ward 8 Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-7, January 19, 2005,  52 DCR 2686).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-627, November 30, 2004,  52 DCR 1137).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Time to Dispose of Property for Golden Rule Development Project Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-588, November 1, 2004,  51 DCR 10714).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District-owned Surplus Real Property in Ward 8 Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-449, June 23, 2004,  51 DCR 6568).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District-Owned Surplus Real Property in Ward 8 Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-406, March 18, 2004,  51 DCR 3657).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-339, January 29, 2004,  51 DCR 1818).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-77, April 16, 2003,  50 DCR 3640).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-534, December 2, 2002,  49 DCR 11643).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of provisions, see §§ 1 to 12 of Abandoned and Vacant Properties Community Development Disposition, and Disapproval of Disposition of Certain Scattered Vacant and Abandoned Properties Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-484, October 3, 2002,  49 DCR 9624).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of provisions, see §§ 2 to 12 of Abandoned and Vacant Properties Community Development Disposition, and Disapproval of Disposition of Certain Scattered Vacant and Abandoned Properties Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-396, June 25, 2002,  49 DCR 6502).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-159, November 2, 2001,  48 DCR 10393).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Master Facility Plan Requirement Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-50, April 19, 2001,  48 DCR 3351).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Master Facility Plan Requirement Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-34, April 2, 2001,  48 DCR 3351).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-10, March 2, 2001,  48 DCR 2494).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-476, December 8, 2000,  48 DCR 560).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-281, March 7, 2000,  47 DCR 2024).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-208, December 8, 1999,  46 DCR 10474).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see §§ 2(a) and 3 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of District Owned Surplus Real Property Revised Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-441, September 3, 1998,  45 DCR 6515).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the District of Columbia Board of Education Sale, Renovation, Lease-back, and Repurchase of Franklin School Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-321, August 4, 1994,  41 DCR 5371) and § 2 of the District of Columbia Board of Education Sale, Renovation, Lease-back, and Repurchase of Franklin School Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-362, December 15, 1994,  41 DCR 8057).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary designation of the building and all property in Square 255, located at 1350 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., popularly referred to as the District Building, under the exclusive authority of the Council of the District of Columbia to determine the use, management, maintenance, operation, repair, renovation, security, lease, sale, or other disposition of the building and property, see § 701 of the Omnibus Spending Reduction Emergency Act of 1993 (D.C. Act 10-102, August 9, 1993,  40 DCR 6144) and § 601 of the Omnibus Spending Reduction Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1993 (D.C. Act 10-145, November 4, 1993,  40 DCR 8081).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-53">D.C. Law 21-53</cite>, Jan. 30, 2016,  62 DCR 15593).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-65">D.C. Law 20-65</cite>, January 25, 2014,  60 DCR 16538).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Hine Junior High School Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-41">D.C. Law 20-41</cite>, December 5, 2013,  60 DCR 14714).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of Justice Park Property Temporary Approval Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-19">D.C. Law 20-19</cite>, October 3, 2013,  60 DCR 10874).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-216">D.C. Law 19-216</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-215">D.C. Law 19-215</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d-6) Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of the property located at 5131 Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E., known as the Strand Theater, for which disposition was approved by the Council pursuant to the Strand Theater Disposition Approval Resolution of 2009, effective October 6, 2009 (Res. 18-0263;  56 DCR 8410), and extended by the Strand Theater Disposition Extension Approval Resolution of 2011, effective September 20, 2011 (Res. 19- 246;  58 DCR 8477), is extended to October 6, 2013.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-216">D.C. Law 19-216</cite> added subsection (d-6) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d-5) Notwithstanding subsection (d) of this section, the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of the property located at 400-414 Eastern Avenue, N.E., and in the 6100 block of Dix Street, N.E., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lots 17, 18, 19, and 806 in Square 5260, for which disposition was approved by the Council pursuant to the Eastern Avenue Property Disposition Approval Resolution of 2009, effective October 6, 2009 (Res. 18-0264;  56 DCR 8412), and extended by the Eastern Avenue Property Disposition Extension Approval Resolution of 2011, effective September 20, 2011 (Res. 19- 245;  58 DCR 8475), is extended to October 6, 2013.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-215">D.C. Law 19-215</cite> added subsection (d-5) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-283">D.C. Law 17-283</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Except as provided for in subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall continue to operate the Franklin Shelter as a 300-person low barrier shelter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) A description of the ability to seasonally increase capacity to reduce incidences of hypothermia among the homeless population.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) Any expected increase or decrease in the need for low barrier shelter space generally and, specifically, during the winter months, when the temperature is at or below 32 degrees Fahrenheit; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Analysis of the impact, if any, that closing the Franklin Shelter may have on the homeless population, including any risk of increased cases of hypothermia during winter months resulting from any reduced capacity in the emergency shelter system;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The number of men using low barrier shelters each month during the current fiscal year and the prior fiscal year;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) A description of the current capacity, current availability, and location of replacement-shelter space;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) The percentage of a shelter’s clients that were placed in supportive-housing units;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iv) Supportive services being provided to complement housing;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iii) Name and address of the shelter from which the client relocated; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) Date the client was placed in the unit;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Client’s name and supportive-housing address;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) For each client who has been placed in a supportive-housing unit since August 1, 2008, the:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A description of the supportive-housing placements, including:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 3. (a) Prior to the closing of the Franklin Shelter, located at 925 13th Street, N.W., the Mayor shall certify to the Council that no fewer than 300 men have been placed in supportive-housing units and submit the certification to the Council along with a report on the proposed Franklin Shelter closing that includes:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Supportive-housing unit’ means housing provided in connection with voluntary services designed primarily to help tenants maintain housing, including coordination or case management, physical and mental health, substance use management and recovery support, job training, literacy and education, youth and children’s programs, and money management.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Low barrier shelter’ means an overnight housing accommodation for individuals who are homeless, provided directly by, or through contract with or grant from, the District, for the purpose of providing shelter to individuals without imposition of identification, time limits, or other program requirements.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 and 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-283">D.C. Law 17-283</cite> added provisions to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Fringe Lot Real Property Exclusive Rights Agreement Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-164">D.C. Law 16-164</cite>, September 29, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 8600).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Extension of Time to Dispose of the Strand Theater Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-162">D.C. Law 20-162</cite>, February 26, 2015, 60 DCR 10751).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-276">D.C. Law 18-276</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c-1) Notwithstanding subsection (c) of this section, the Council review period for the proposed disposition of the property located at 44 P Street, N.W., commonly known as J.F. Cook School, and designated for purposes of assessment and taxation as Square 0616, Lot 0866, or some portion thereof, is extended for an additional 90 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holiday, and days of Council recess.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-276">D.C. Law 18-276</cite> added subsec. (c-1) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-204">D.C. Law 18-204</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) The Mayor is deemed to have met the requirements of paragraph (2)(C) and paragraph (4) of this subsection with respect to the District-owned real property known as the Old Naval Hospital, located at 921 Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E., in Square 0948, for which the Mayor engaged in community outreach efforts regarding the property’s proposed redevelopment plan, and which followed notice to and consent from the applicable Advisory Neighborhood Commission.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-204">D.C. Law 18-204</cite> added subsec. (a-1)(6) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-77">D.C. Law 18-77</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) ‘Substantive change’ means a change that makes the agreement inconsistent with the executed Memorandum of Understanding or term sheet transmitted with the proposed resolution.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) ‘Redline format’ means the changes that are deletions have a line through them and the changes that are additions are underlined.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) For the purposes of this paragraph, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6)(A) If a substantive change is made to the term sheet or Memorandum of Understanding referenced in subsection ((b-1)(2) of this section, after the resolution was transmitted to and approved by the Council pursuant to this subsection, a resolution describing the change accompanied by an amended term sheet or Memorandum of Understanding in redline format shall be transmitted to Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed amendments to the term sheet, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 30-day review period, the proposed amendments shall be deemed approved.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) All documents referenced in this paragraph shall be consistent with the proposed resolution for land disposition and language to that effect shall be included in those agreements prior to execution.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Documents in this paragraph shall be transmitted in the most current form available at the time the resolution is transmitted.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iii) A Certified Business Enterprise (’CBE’) Agreement pursuant to the Small, Local and Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite>; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§2-218.01">§ 2-218.01</cite> et seq.).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) Any community benefits agreement between the developer and the relevant community, if any; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) A Land Disposition Agreement between the District and the selected developer;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5)(A) For all District land being disposed for purposes of development and requiring government assistance the following additional documents shall be transmitted to the Council concurrent with the proposed resolution and analysis:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) For any development project where the total value of the government assistance is greater than $10 million, a description of the project funding and financing plan.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A document reporting the value of the property prepared by an independent appraiser or assessor performed within 12 months of transmission of the proposed resolution.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) Any other terms that the Mayor finds to be in the best interest of the District.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) A description of the schedule of performance; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) A description of the green building requirements;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) A description of the Certified Business Enterprise requirements;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) A description of the method of disposition;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) A description of the major business terms of the transaction;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) An executed term sheet or Memorandum of Understanding between the District and the selected developer that shall include the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) A description of all disposition methods considered and an accompanying narrative for the proposed disposition method that contains comparisons to the other methods and shows why the proposed method was more beneficial for the District than the others in the areas of return on investment, subsidies required, revenues paid to the District, and any other relevant category, or why it is being proposed despite it being less beneficial to the District in any of the measured categories.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) The manner in which economic factors were weighted and evaluated, including estimates of the monetary benefits and costs to the District that will result from the disposition. The benefits shall include revenues, fees, and other payments to the District, as well as the creation of jobs; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The chosen method of disposition, and how competition was maximized;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) An analysis prepared by the Mayor of the economic factors that were considered in proposing the disposition of the real property, including:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b-1) A proposed resolution to provide for the disposition of real property transmitted to the Council pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall be accompanied by the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) The following statement: ”All documents that are submitted with this resolution pursuant to subsection (b-1) of this section shall be consistent with the executed Memorandum of Understanding or term sheet transmitted to the Council pursuant to subsection (b-1)(2) of this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) A public or private sale to the bidder providing the most benefit to the District; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) An exchange of interests in real property; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) A combination sale/leaseback for specifically designated purposes;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) A lease for a period of greater than 20 years;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) A negotiated sale to a for-profit or nonprofit entity for specifically designated purposes;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) A public or private sale to the highest bidder;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) The proposed method of disposition, which may be one of the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) A finding that the Developer will enter into a First Source Agreement with the District that shall govern certain obligations of Developer pursuant to section 4 of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 5-93">D.C. Law 5-93</cite>; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§2-219" proof="true">§ 2-219</cite>. 03), and Mayor’s Order 83-265 (November 9, 1983) regarding job creation and employment generated as a result of the construction on the Property;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) A finding that the Developer will enter into an agreement that shall require the Developer to, at a minimum, contract with Certified Business Enterprises for at least 35% of the contract dollar volume of the project, and shall require at least 20% equity and 20% development participation of Certified Business Enterprises;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) A description of any affordable housing to be provided as part of the Project;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) A description of the intended use for the property (‘Project’);</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A description of the real property to be disposed of;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The name and business address of the developer, and, if the developer is a joint venture or partnership, the name and business address of each person that constitutes the partnership;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Mayor, to carry out the provisions of this act, shall transmit to the Council a proposed resolution that contains the following:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-77">D.C. Law 18-77</cite> rewrote subsecs. (b) and (b-1) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Time to Dispose of the Old Congress Heights School Temporary Amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-160">D.C. Law 17-160</cite>, May 13, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 5894).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of School Without Walls Development Project Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-303">D.C. Law 16-303</cite>, March 27, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of School Without Walls Development Project Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-116">D.C. Law 16-116</cite>, June 8, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 5354).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Temporary Amendment Act of 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-61">D.C. Law 16-61</cite>, March 8, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 2332).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of Abatement of Nuisance Construction Projects Temporary Amendment Act of 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-4">D.C. Law 16-4</cite>, May 14, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 5427).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Second Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-313">D.C. Law 15-313</cite>, April 8, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 4702).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Extension of Time to Dispose of Property for Golden Rule Development Project Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-251">D.C. Law 15-251</cite>, March 17, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 4127).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District-Owned Surplus Real Property in Ward 8 Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-170">D.C. Law 15-170</cite>, June 19, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 7335).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Real Property Disposition Economic Analysis Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-137">D.C. Law 15-137</cite>, April 22, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 4921).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-24">D.C. Law 15-24</cite>, July 22, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 6094).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-294">D.C. Law 14-294</cite>, April 11, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 5852).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of the Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 5 of the Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, Oct. 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-71">D.C. Law 14-71</cite>, February 27, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 2281).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Temporary Amendment Act of 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-242">D.C. Law 13-242</cite>, April 3, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 3484).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Disposal of District Owned Surplus Real Property Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-223">D.C. Law 12-223</cite>, April 13, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 3845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Extension of Time to Dispose of District Owned Surplus Real Property Revised Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-198">D.C. Law 12-198</cite>, March 26, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 3424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of District of Columbia Board of Education Sale, Renovation, Lease-back, and Repurchase of Franklin School Temporary Amendment Act of 1994 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-196">D.C. Law 10-196</cite>, March 14, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1513).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-62">D.C. Law 21-62</cite> added the subsection designated herein as (d-5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> added the subsection designated herein as (o).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-193">D.C. Law 20-193</cite> added (a-3); rewrote (b)(5); and added (n).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in (b)(9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (d-4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-201">D.C. Law 18-201</cite> added subsec. (a-1)(5).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-115">D.C. Law 18-115</cite>, in subsec. (a), designated the existing text as par. (1) and added par. (2); added subsecs. (a-1) and (a-2); repealed subsec. (b)(1); in subsec. (d), substituted “disapproved” for “approved”; in subsec. (e), substituted “pursuant to this section” for “pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of this section”; and rewrote subsec. (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-76">D.C. Law 18-76</cite> rewrote subsecs. (b) and (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-138">D.C. Law 17-138</cite> added subsec. (d-3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-112">D.C. Law 16-112</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “that contains a finding that the real property is no longer required for public purposes and a description” for “that contains a description”; added subsec. (b-1); in subsec. (c), substituted “shall be deemed disapproved.” for “shall be deemed approved.”; and added subsec. (e-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite>, in subsec. (d-1), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-285">D.C. Law 15-285</cite> added subsec. (d-2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-127">D.C. Law 15-127</cite> added subsec. (d-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite> added subsec. (m).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-213">D.C. Law 14-213</cite>, in subsec. (f-1), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</cite> added subsec. (f-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 10-216">D.C. Law 10-216</cite> added subsecs. (h), (i), and (j).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 9-301.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 9-401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-351.05">§ 2-351.05</cite>, <cite path="§2-1217.151">§ 2-1217.151</cite>, <cite path="§6-1005">§ 6-1005</cite>, <cite path="§10-901">§ 10-901</cite>, <cite path="§10-1904">§ 10-1904</cite>, <cite path="§10-1905">§ 10-1905</cite>, <cite path="§16-1332">§ 16-1332</cite>, and <cite path="§24-261.05">§ 24-261.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Sale of lands not needed for public purposes, see <cite path="§16-1332">§ 16-1332</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Industrial Home School, disposal, see <cite path="§44-1303">§ 44-1303</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">District of Columbia Alley Dwelling Act, rent, sale, or exchange of lands acquired thereunder, see <cite path="§6-101.01">§ 6-101.01</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Correctional Treatment Facility, exemptions from leasing and property laws, see <cite path="§24-261.05">§ 24-261.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Authority of Council, exchange of district-owned land, see <cite path="§10-901">§ 10-901</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, duties and responsibilities, see <cite path="§1-309.10">§ 1-309.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    <text type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 402 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided that the Council approved the disposition of the Property to the Developer pursuant to the terms set forth in <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite>, § 401.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) Except as provided in paragraph (1) of this subsection, be consistent with the terms in the documents submitted by the Mayor to the Council in conjunction with the Skyland Town Center Omnibus Act of 2014. Any substantive change shall be submitted to the Council consistent with section 1(b-1)(6) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code  Section 10-801(b-1)(6)).”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) Incorporate the District's right to reacquire the Property at the price originally conveyed consistent with section 1(e) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code  Section 10-801(e)); and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(f) The Land Disposition Agreement to be executed between the District and the Developer shall:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(e) The Developer shall comply with the terms set forth in Zoning Commission Order No. 09-03, July 12, 2010, pertaining to the following properties: Square 5640, Lot 33; Square 5640, Lot 35; Square 5640, Lot 816; and Par 0213, Lot 64.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(d) The Developer shall enter into a First Source Agreement with the District that shall govern certain obligations of the Developer pursuant to section 4 of the First Source Employment Agreement Act of 1984, effective June 29, 1984 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 5-93">D.C. Law 5-93</cite>; D.C. Official Code  Section 2-219.03) and Mayor's Order 83-265, dated November 9, 1983, regarding job creation and employment as a result of the construction on the Property.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) The Developer shall enter into an agreement with the District requiring the Developer to, at a minimum, contract with Certified Business Enterprises for at least 35% of the contract dollar volume of the Project, and requiring at least 20% equity and 20% development participation of Certified Business Enterprises.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The Project shall include affordable housing, such that 20% of the residential units shall be reserved for households with incomes at or below 80% AMI. An additional 10% of the residential units shall be reserved for households with incomes at or below 120% of AMI.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) The Property is located at the intersection of Naylor Road, S.E., Good Hope Road, S.E., and Alabama Avenue, S.E., consists of approximately 18.7 acres of land, and is further defined in section 101(22).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided: “Findings.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 302 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided that the Council determined that the Property is no longer required for public purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) A public hearing was held on June 26, 2013, at the Francis A. Gregory Neighborhood Library located at 3660 Alabama Ave. S.E., regarding the finding that the Property is no longer required for public purposes.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The Property was acquired with the intention of eliminating blight by redeveloping the underused site into retail and residential space to benefit the surrounding community and the District. Therefore, the Property is not required for public purposes and the Property needs to be declared surplus in order to dispose of the Property for redevelopment purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) The Property is located at the intersection of Naylor Road, S.E., Good Hope Road, S.E., and Alabama Avenue, S.E., and consists of approximately 18.7 acres of land and is further defined in section 101(22).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 301 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite> provided: “Findings.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">African-American Civil War Memorial and Museum Development: Sections 2132 to 2134 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided for a protective covenant on, and restrictions on disposal of, 1925 Vermont Avenue, N.W., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 0827, Square 0361 (“the Grimke School”), for the establishment and operation of the African-American Civil War Memorial Museum and Visitor’s Center.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 6 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-368">D.C. Law 18-368</cite> provided: “Notwithstanding section 1(d) of An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§10-801|(d)">§ 10-801(d)</cite>), the time period within which the Mayor may dispose of the property located at 1101-1111 24th Street, N.W., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 836, Square 37, 2301 L Street, N.W., Lot 837, Square 37, and 2225 M Street, N.W., Lot 822, Square 50, pursuant to the West End Parcels Disposition Approval Resolution of 2010, effective July 13, 2010 (Res.18-553;  57 DCR 7623), is extended to July 13, 2013.” Establishment of the Saint Elizabeths Redevelopment Initiative, see Mayor’s Order 2011-109, June 15, 2011 ( 58 DCR 5348).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-165">D.C. Law 18-165</cite> provided: “Notwithstanding An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§10-801">§ 10-801</cite> et seq.), the Council approves the disposition of the real property formerly designated as federal reservations 129, 130, and 299 to CASCO Marina Development LLC, in accordance with the agreement between the District of Columbia and CASCO Marina Development, LLC.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-112">D.C. Law 16-112</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-112">D.C. Law 16-112</cite> provided: “This act shall apply to resolutions submitted to the Council after the effective date of this act [June 8, 2006].”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) shall deposit the net proceeds of each sale in the Treasury to the credit of the District of Columbia.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) may pay the reasonable and necessary expenses of the sale of each parcel of land sold; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) PAYING EXPENSES AND DEPOSITING PROCEEDS—The Mayor—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) AUTHORITY TO SELL—With the approval of the National Capital Planning Commission, the Mayor of the District of Columbia, for the best interests of the District of Columbia, may sell to the highest bidder at public or private sale real estate in the District of Columbia owned in fee simple by the District of Columbia for municipal use that the Council of the District of Columbia and the Commission find to be no longer required for public purposes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 8734. Sale of land by Mayor</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 8734 of Public Law 107-217 provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) Termination Of Provisions.—If the District of Columbia enacts legislation to reform the practices and procedures governing the entering into of leases for the use of real property by the District of Columbia government and the disposition of surplus real property of the District government, the provisions of subsection (a) shall cease to be effective upon the effective date of the legislation.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) The Mayor and Council within 60 days of the date of the enactment of this Act have filed with the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate, the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report which provides a comprehensive plan for the management of District of Columbia real property assets, and are proceeding with the implementation of the plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) The Mayor and Council implement a program for the periodic survey of all District property to determine if it is surplus to the needs of the District.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, there is made available for sale or lease all real property of the District of Columbia that the Mayor from time-to-time determines is surplus to the needs of the District of Columbia, unless a majority of the members of the Council override the Mayor’s determination during the 30-day period which begins on the date the determination is published.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) The Mayor and Council of the District of Columbia certify to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate that existing real property available to the District (whether leased or owned by the District government) is not suitable for the purposes intended.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Management Of Existing District Government Property.—upon the expiration of the 60-day period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act, none of the funds contained in this Act may be used to enter into a lease (or to make rental payments under such a lease) for the use of real property by the District of Columbia government (including any independent agency of the District) or to purchase real property for the use of the District of Columbia government (including any independent agency of the District) or to manage real property for the use of the District of Columbia (including any independent agency of the District) unless the following conditions are met:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Related federal enactments: Section 152 of Public Law 106-113 provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Request for Offers for the Disposition of the Roosevelt Apartment, 2101 — 16th Street, N.W., Lot 802 in Square 188, Approval Resolution of 1999 (PR12-1115): Pursuant to Resolution 13-32, effective February 2, 1999, the Council reviewed and approved the Request for Offers for disposition of the Roosevelt Apartment, located at 2101 16th Street, N.W., and legally described as Lot 802 in Square 188, in Ward One.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Public Offering Document to Receive Proposals to Develop the McMillan Sand Filter Plan Site Disapproval Resolution of 1998 (PR12-981): Pursuant to Resolution 13-31, effective February 2, 1999, the Council disapproved an offering document to receive proposals to develop the McMillan Sand Filter Plant Site, located in Ward 5.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disposition of Lot 0061 in Square 555 Emergency Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-800, effective December 1, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the disposition of Lot 0061 in Square 555, real property owned by the District government, as surplus property in accordance with District of Columbia law.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disposition of Lot 41 in Square 484 Emergency Conditional Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-677, effective August 24, 1998, the Council approved, on an emergency basis, the disposition of Lot 41 in Square 454, located at 614 H Street, N.W., as surplus property.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Authorization to Sell Lots 804, 805 and 806 in Square 3587 Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution PR 12-824. effective December 10, 1998, the Council authorized the sale of Lots 804, 805, and 806 in Square 3587 to existing tenants.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disposition of Lot 824 in Square 1189 to Millennium Georgetown Development L.L.C. Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-704, effective October 6, 1998, the Council approved the disposition of Lot 824 in Square 1189 to Millennium Georgetown Development L.L.C.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disposition of Lots 90, 91, 92, 105, 106 and 125 in Square 2560 to Adams Morgan Development Company Limited Partnership Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-703, effective October 6, 1998, the Council approved the disposition of Lots 90, 91, 92, 105, 106 and 125 in Square 2560 to Adams Morgan Development Company Limited Partnership.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Extension of Time To Dispose of Square 4107, Lots 227 and 900 and Square 4103, Lots 826 and 827 to Crane Rental Company Approval Resolution of 1998: Pursuant to Resolution 12-(PR12-721), effective May 29, 1998, the Council approved a request for additional time for the disposition of property on W Street, N.E., Square 4107, Lots 227 and 900 and Square 4103, Lots 826 and 827, to Crane Rental Company.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Unsolicited Proposal to Develop the Anacostia Northern Gateway Project Approval Resolution of 1997: Proposed Resolution 12-0111, the “Unsolicited Proposal to Develop the Anacostia Northern gateway project Approval Resolution of 1997” was deemed approved, effective Feb. 12, 1997.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Request for Offers for the Disposition for the Roosevelt Apartment for Senior Citizens, 2101 16th Street, N.W., Lot 802, in Square 188, Approval Resolution of 1996: Pursuant to Resolution 11-633, effective December 3, 1996, Council approved the Request for Offers for the disposition of the Roosevelt Apartment for Senior Citizens located at 2101 16th Street, N.W., and legally described as Lot 802, Square 188, in Ward 1.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Negotiated Disposition of Property   Upshur Street, N.W., to the National Baptist Convention USA Housing Inc., Twenty-Seven, Approval Resolution of 1996: Pursuant to Resolution 11-632, effective December 3, 1996, Council approved the negotiated disposition of property located in Square 2820, Lot  Upshur Street, N.W., to the National Baptist Convention USA Housing Inc., Twenty-Seven, for the development of the “Upshur House” in Ward Four.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of the Negotiated Disposition of the “Golden Rule Property” to Golden Rule Plaza, Inc., and Reorganization Plan No. 8 of 1996 for the Business of Public Management Disapproval Resolution of 1996: Pursuant to Resolution 11-569, effective November 7, 1996, Council approved a negotiated disposition and redevelopment of the “Golden Rule Property” to Golden Rule Plaza, Inc., and to disapprove Reorganization Plan No. 8 of 1996 for the business of public management.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Request for Proposals to Solicit Development of the Georgetown Incinerator Property, Lot 824 in Square 1189, Approval Emergency Resolution of 1996: Pursuant to Resolution 11-478, effective July 17, 1996, Council approved, on an emergency basis, the request for proposals soliciting proposals to develop the Georgetown Incinerator Property located in the Georgetown Waterfront area and legally described as Lot 824, Square 1189.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Transfer of Lot 40 in Square 454 Emergency Approval Resolution of 1995: Pursuant to Resolution 11-150, effective October 10, 1995, the Council approved the transfer of certain real property owned by the District of Columbia Government, further described as Lot 40 in Square 454, a portion of which to be transferred to the District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency and the remaining portion to be used or disposed of in accordance with District of Columbia law.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Glenn Dale Hospital Site Sale Approval Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Proposed Resolution 11-17, deemed approved January 7, 1995, Council approved the sale of the Glenn Dale Hospital Site.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Oyster Elementary School Construction and Revenue Bonds: <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-174">D.C. Law 12-174</cite>, the Oyster Elementary School Construction and Revenue Bond Act of 1998, effective October 21, 1998, pursuant to § 169 of Pub. Law. 105-277, authorized the demolition of the James F. Oyster Elementary School and the construction of a new school, the lease or conveyance of a portion of the Oyster School site to a private developer, and the funding for construction of the new Oyster School facility through the issuance of revenue bonds by the District for the benefit of the District of Columbia Public Schools, with the payments on such revenue bonds secured through payment by the developer of a payment in lieu of taxes.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Authority over the John A. Wilson Building: Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-65">D.C. Law 10-65</cite>, provided, inter alia, that notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, the John A. Wilson Building is designated under the exclusive authority of the Council of the District of Columbia to determine the use, management, maintenance, operation, repair, renovation, security, lease, sale, or other disposition of the property pursuant to <cite path="§10-1301">§ 10-1301</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disposal of surplus real property: Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-96">D.C. Law 8-96</cite> provided that for the purposes of this act, the term “real property” means land titled in the name of the District of Columbia (“District”) or in which the District has a controlling interest and includes all structures of a permanent character erected thereon or affixed thereto, any natural resources located thereon or thereunder, all riparian rights attached thereto, or any air space located above or below the property or any street or alley under the jurisdiction of the Mayor.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Conveyance of property: <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-96">D.C. Law 10-96</cite> authorized the Mayor to convey certain real property of the District of Columbia known as Engine Company No. 24, located on Lot 816, Square 2900, with a street address at 3702 Georgia Avenue N.W., to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority for the purpose of constructing the Georgia Avenue/Petworth Station facilities.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Unsolicited Proposal Submitted by Washington Properties, Inc./Square 673 Partners for the Negotiated Disposition of 59 M Street, N.E., Resolution of 1994: Pursuant to Resolution 10-475, effective December 6, 1994, amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, § 110, the Council reviewed and provided comments on an Unsolicited Proposal submitted by Washington Properties, Inc./Square 673 Partners for the negotiated disposition of 59 M Street, N.E.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Children’s Island Disposition Resolution of 1993: Pursuant to Resolution 10-92, effective July 30, 1993, the Council authorized conditionally the disposition of property in the Anacostia River known as Children’s Island, upon the approval by the Council of the District of Columbia of a transfer of jurisdiction over the property from the National Park Service to the District of Columbia, pursuant to a Lease and Restated Cooperative Agreement between the District of Columbia and National Children’s Island, Inc. and Island Development Corporation, and subject to compliance with the provisions of the Children’s Island Development Plan Emergency Act of 1993 and successor permanent legislation.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Lease of the Employment Services Building Site Disapproval Resolution of 1993: Pursuant to Resolution 10-62, effective June 11, 1993, the Council disapproved the lease of the Employment Services Building site for a period of up to 99 years.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Proposal to Develop 10 Lots Located at Benning Road, S.E., Lots 309 through 318, Square 5359 Resolution of 1992: Pursuant to Resolution 9-264, effective June 12, 1992, the Council reviewed and approved an unsolicited proposal to develop 10 lots located at Benning Road between Hanna Place and H Street, S.E., Lots 309 through 319, Square 5359.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Precinct Station Site Lease Approval Resolution of 1991: Pursuant to Resolution 9-146, effective December 13, 1991, the Council approved the request by the Mayor to lease the Old Number 8 Precinct Station (Lot 804; Square 1730) to Iona Senior Services for a period of greater than 20 years.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Disapproval of request to lease Employment Services Building: Pursuant to Resolution 8-292, the “Employment Services Building Lease Disapproval Resolution of 1990,” effective November 30, 1990, the Council disapproved the request by the Mayor to lease the Employment Services Building Site for a period not to exceed 99 years.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Approval of Prevocational School Site: Pursuant to Resolution 8-291, the “Prevocational School Site Lease Approval Resolution of 1990”, effective November 30, 1990, the Council approved the request by the Mayor to lease the Prevocational School Site for a period not to exceed 99 years.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 10-139">D.C. Law 10-139</cite>, effective July 23, 1994, authorized the Mayor to convey property located at 2025 2nd Street, N.W., commonly referred to as the Gage School.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 8-82">D.C. Law 8-82</cite>, effective March 15, 1990, authorized the Mayor to convey property located at Lot 13 in Square 4446.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 8-32">D.C. Law 8-32</cite>, effective September 22, 1989, as amended by D.C. Act 8-97, effective October 17, 1989, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 8-171">D.C. Law 8-171</cite>, effective September 26, 1990, authorized the Mayor to convey property located at 1529 16th Street, N.W., Lot 818 of Square 194, commonly referred to as the Jewish Community Center.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 7-94">D.C. Law 7-94</cite>, effective March 16, 1988, authorized the Mayor to convey property located at 525-9th Street, N.E., Lots 32, 33, and 34 of Square 936, commonly referred to as Old Police Precinct #9.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Conveyance of property: Pursuant to authority of this section, the Act of March 16, 1978, <cite doc="D.C. Law 2-63">D.C. Law 2-63</cite>, conveying square 491 to the Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation, was adopted.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Sale, lease or transfer of certain United States property in District to foreign governments and international organization: See Act of October 8, 1968, Pub. L. 90-553, as amended by Act of May 25, 1982, Pub. L. 97-186, as amended by § 124 of the Act of August 16, 1985, Pub. L. 99-93, as amended by § 120 of the Act of February 16, 1990, Pub. L. 101-246.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-649, the “Disposition of Nichols Avenue School Emergency Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective July</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-645, the “Disposition of Certain Vacant Land That Is a Portion of the Area Known as the Anacostia Northern Gateway Site Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective July 13, 2004.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-523, the “Disposition of the Armstrong Adult Education Center, Square 553, Lot 844, Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective May 4, 2004.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-522, the “Request for Proposals for the Disposition of 201 Florida Avenue, N.E., Square E-710, Lot 801, Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective May 4, 2004.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-142, the “Request for Proposals for the Disposition of the Georgia Avenue—Petworth Metro Station Parcel A Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective July 8, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-346, the “Declaration of Square E-710, Lot 801 as Surplus Property Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective December 2, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-218, the “Disposition of Square 5359, Lots 307 and 827, Also Known as the Hilltop Terrace Property Emergency Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective July 14, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-214, the “Unsolicited Proposal Submitted by Sang Oh &amp; Company for the Negotiated Purchase and Disposition of Surplus  Property at 375 Morse Street, N.E., Also Known as the Ironworks Parcel, Emergency Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective July 8, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-202, the “Revised Lease of a Parcel of District Property Held under a Letter Transfer at U.S. Reservation 13 to St. Coletta of Greater Washington, Inc. Emergency Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective July 8, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-142, the “Disposition by a Request for Proposals for the Disposition of the Georgia Avenue—Petworth Metro Station Parcel a Site Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective July 8, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-128, the “Transfer of Easement for Vehicular and Pedestrian Access to 115 New York Avenue, N.W., Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective July 8, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-64, the “Disposition of Square 1030, Lot 813, also known as the Kingsman Elementary School Approval Resolution of 2003”, was approved effective March 18, 2003.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-620, the “Disposition of Square 5155, Lot 802 Emergency Approval Resolution of 2002”, was approved effective November 22, 2002.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-539, the “Disposition of the Existing Convention Center Site Emergency Approval Resolution of 2002”, was approved effective July 26, 2002.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-440, the “Request for Proposals for the Disposition of the Washington Beef Properties, 1240 — 1248 4th St., N.E., Lots 5, 800, and 802 in Square 3587, Approval Resolution of 2002”, was approved effective May 24, 2002.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-429, the “Disposition of Square 5155, Lots 11-14, 150-152, 835, 838, 839, 849, 851 &amp; 853, Also Known as the George Carver Elementary School Emergency Approval Resolution of 2002”, was approved effective April 26, 2002.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-429, the “Disposition of Squares 5155, Lots 11-14, 150-152, 835, 838, 839, 849, 851 and 853, also known as the George Carver Elementary School, Emergency Approval Resolution of 2002”, was approved effective April 16, 2002.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-96, the “Negotiated Sale of District-Owned Property at First Street and New York Avenue, N.E., to the General Services Administration/Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms Approval Resolution of 2001, was approved effective May 1, 2001.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 14-71, the “Negotiated Sale of District-Owned Property at Brentwood Road, N.E. to Graimark/Walker Urban Land Development, LLC Approval Resolution of 2001”, was approved effective April 3, 2001.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
