<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1331</num>
  <heading>Findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council of the District of Columbia finds that:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to § <cite root="10-1301">10-1301</cite>, the Council has the exclusive authority to determine the use, management, maintenance, operation, repair, renovation, security, lease, and sale or other disposition of the building located at 1350 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., known as the John A. Wilson Building (“Wilson Building”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The Wilson Building is the traditional seat of local government located on Pennsylvania Avenue, the “Main Street” of the Nation’s Capital, and a source of pride and hope for our District residents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The Wilson Building is in need of renovation and restoration and contains environmental conditions which should be eliminated to provide a safe and healthy working environment and to ensure compliance with all federal and local building regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Because of the current fiscal state of the District government, funds are not available to make expenditures estimated at $47.1 million to $60 million to renovate and restore the Wilson Building.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-180">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-180, § 2, 43 DCR 4246</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 9-731.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of subchapter, see §§ 2 through 8 of the Establishment of the John A. Wilson Building Foundation Emergency Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-161, November 27, 1995,  42 DCR 6781), §§ 2 through 8 of the Establishment of the John A. Wilson Building Foundation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-209, February 14, 1996,  43 DCR 798), § 2 through 7 of the John A. Wilson Building Foundation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-406, October 24, 1996,  43 DCR 5814), and § 2 through 7 of the Establishment of the John A. Wilson Building Foundation Congressional Adjournment Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-8, March 3, 1997,  44 DCR 1625).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
