<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-1902</num>
  <heading>Findings and purpose.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Walter Reed Army Medical Center Site has been declared surplus and closed by the Department of Defense pursuant to the procedures and authorities of the Base Closure Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Mayor’s Order No. 2006-21 designated the District of Columbia government as the Walter Reed LRA that was recognized by the Office of Economic Adjustment on behalf of the Secretary of Defense for the purpose of developing a Walter Reed Reuse Plan and established the Walter Reed LRA Committee and charged the committee with developing final recommendations for the Mayor and the Council for a Walter Reed Reuse Plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor, in conjunction with the Walter Reed LRA Committee, developed the Walter Reed Reuse Plan during public meetings on January 28, 2010, March 10, 2010, April 21, 2010, May 26, 2010, August 5, 2010, September 1, 2010, October 6, 2010, October 13, 2011, December 1, 2011, and January 25, 2012, which were supplemented by community input received at community meetings held on June 9, 2010, July 10, 2010, August 19, 2010, October 5, 2011, November 15, 2011, December 8, 2011, and February 2, 2012.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Walter Reed LRA Committee made final recommendations to the Mayor and Council on the Homeless Submission by motion approved on January 25, 2012.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Walter Reed Reuse Plan envisions a vibrant campus integrated into the community through the provision of expanded retail opportunities, preservation of open space, creative reuse of historic assets into a range of cultural and educational uses, creation of a range of jobs for District residents, and development of a variety of housing options to support a range of incomes and needs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Walter Reed Reuse Plan recommends homeless-assistance provider uses providing affordable housing and support services, subject to the Legally Binding Agreements.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to the terms of the Legally Binding Agreements, the transfer of the portions of the Walter Reed Army Medical Center Site to homeless-assistance providers shall be conditioned on, among other things, final approval of the Homeless Submission by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development and the U.S. Department of the Army conveying the Walter Reed Army Medical Center Site to the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Walter Reed Reuse Plan also provides for the public benefit conveyance uses identified in the Memorandum of Agreement. Pursuant to the terms of the Memorandum of Agreement, the conveyance of the portions of the Walter Reed Army Medical Center Site to the public benefit conveyance users is conditioned on, among other things, final approval of the Homeless Submission by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development and the U.S. Department of the Army conveying the Walter Reed Army Medical Center Site to the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall seek to have the Office of Economic Adjustment on behalf of the Secretary of Defense recognize the District as an Implementation Local Reuse Authority, as defined in the Base Closure Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Upon approval of the Homeless Submission by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Department of Defense, the Mayor, on behalf of the Walter Reed LRA, will seek to acquire and submit an application for approximately 67.5 acres of real property from the Department of Defense for redevelopment pursuant to section 2905(b)(4) of the Base Closure Act.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-175">Oct. 16, 2012, D.C. Law 19-175, § 3, 59 DCR 9106</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of section, see § 3 of the Walter Reed Army Medical Center Base Realignment and Closure Homeless Assistance Submission Congressional Review Emergency Approval Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-528, November 2, 2012,  59 DCR 13325), applicable as of October 16, 2012.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
