<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>10-505.02</num>
  <heading>Transfer of member of Metropolitan Police to Capitol Police — Election.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any member of the Metropolitan Police force detailed to the Capitol Police (other than the Capitol Police Chief):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Who on August 31, 1980, has completed 20 years or more of police service shall be reassigned to the Metropolitan Police force effective October 1, 1980, unless during the 30-day period beginning on September 1, 1980, such member makes an election under subsection (b) of this section; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Who after August 31, 1980, completes 20 years of police service shall be reassigned to the Metropolitan Police force effective at the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date of such completion, unless, during such period, such member makes an election under subsection (b) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A member of the Metropolitan Police force described in subsection (a) of this section may elect to transfer to the Capitol Police with the rank, pay, and seniority that are most nearly equivalent to the rank, pay, and seniority of such member on the day before the date of such transfer, as determined by the Capitol Police Board.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A transfer to the Capitol Police under this subsection shall be effective on the date on which the electing member would have been reassigned to the Metropolitan Police force but for the election by such member under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An election under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be made in writing to the Chairman of the Capitol Police Board in such form and manner as may be prescribed by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In each case in which a member of the Metropolitan Police force transfers to the Capitol Police under subsection (b) of this section, the position occupied by such member immediately before the effective date of such transfer shall, beginning on such date, be a position on the rolls of the Capitol Police for the purpose of providing for the assimilation of such member.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Dec. 20, 1979, 93 Stat. 1099, Pub. L. 96-152, § 2</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="10-505.03">10-505.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 9-117.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
