<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1371.07</num>
  <heading>Subpoena power.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When necessary for the discharge of its duties, the Committee shall have the authority to issue subpoenas to compel witnesses to appear and testify and to produce books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, documents, or other relevant records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, subpoenas shall be served personally upon the witness or his or her designated agent, not less than 5 business days before the date the witness must appear or the documents must be produced, by one of the following methods, which may be attempted concurrently or successively:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By a special process server, at least 18 years of age, designated by the Committee from among the staff of the Committee or any of the offices or organizations represented on the Committee; provided, that the special process server is not directly involved in the investigation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By a special process server, at least 18 years of age, engaged by the Committee.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If, after a reasonable attempt, personal service on a witness or witness’ agent cannot be obtained, a special process server identified in subsection (b) of this section may serve a subpoena by registered or certified mail not less than 8 business days before the date the witness must appear or the documents must be produced.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a witness who has been personally summoned neglects or refuses to obey the subpoena issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Committee may report that fact to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and the court may compel obedience to the subpoena to the same extent as witnesses may be compelled to obey the subpoenas of the court.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History" path="§4607">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 4607, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Legislative Review Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-82, July 9, 2001,  48 DCR 6355).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 7 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-40, April 25, 2001,  48 DCR 5917).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Child Fatality Review Committee Establishment Temporary Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-20">D.C. Law 14-20</cite>, September 6, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 9090).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-1371.09">§ 4-1371.09</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
