<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-1451.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Authorized Receiving Facility” means a hospital, or other place authorized by the Mayor, by rule, to accept a newborn for surrender pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“CFSA” means the Child and Family Services Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Newborn” means an infant whose parent refuses or is unable to assume the responsibility for the infant’s care, control, and subsistence and who is surrendered by that parent and who a licensed physician or other person authorized to accept the surrender reasonably believes is 14 days old or less.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Surrender” means to bring a newborn to an Authorized Receiving Facility during its hours of operation and to leave the newborn with personnel of the Authorized Receiving Facility.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-158" type="History" path="§101">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-158, § 101, 57 DCR 3000</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101 of Newborn Safe Haven Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-321, March 1, 2010,  57 DCR 1842).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Newborn Safe Haven Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-49, April 27, 2009,  56 DCR 3581).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 10(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-29">D.C. Law 18-29</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) ‘Surrender’ means to bring a newborn to an Authorized Receiving Facility during its hours of operation, and to leave the newborn with personnel of the Authorized Receiving Facility.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) ‘Newborn’ means an infant that a licensed physician or other person authorized to accept the surrender reasonably believes is 7 days old or less.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘CFSA’ means the Child and Family Services Agency.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Authorized Receiving Facility’ means a hospital, or other place authorized by the Mayor, by rule, to accept a newborn for surrender pursuant to this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-29">D.C. Law 18-29</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
