<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-204.14</num>
  <heading>Purposes, powers, and duties of the Office.</heading>
  <text>The primary purpose of the Office is to redesign the District of Columbia’s Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance infrastructure to improve the operational management of Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance programs on an agency level. The Office shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Provide technical assistance and support to District of Columbia agencies for the purpose of documenting and processing Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance claims, and maximizing Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance reimbursements, where not duplicative of assistance already provided to District of Columbia agencies by the State Medicaid Office;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Manage Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance costs and project revenues in liaison with the State Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance Office and the Chief Financial Officer;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Review and support legislation ensuring service expansion for all entitled residents in collaboration with the Mayor and the State Medicaid Office;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Oversee the implementation of Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance reforms within District of Columbia agencies to fulfill statutory requirements;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Prepare an annual report for the Mayor and the Council on the Office’s activities and recommendations; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Engage in other activities as needed to carry out the purposes of this part.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-190" type="History" path="§1504">Oct. 1, 2002, D.C. Law 14-190, § 1504, 49 DCR 6968</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 1502(d), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 30(a), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1502(d) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1502(d) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in par. (6), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, in the introductory paragraph, substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance infrastructure” for “Medicaid infrastructure” and substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance Programs” for “Medicaid programs”; in par. (1), substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance claims, and maximizing Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance reimbursements,” for “Medicaid claims, and maximizing Medicaid reimbursements,”; and in pars. (2) and (4), substituted “Medicaid, Medicare, and Foster Care and Adoption Assistance” for Medicaid“.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
