<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-205.19g</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall promulgate rules describing those categories of TANF applicants who are exempt from the requirements of <cite path="§4-205.19b|(b)">§ 4-205.19b(b)</cite> [(b) repealed]. The rules promulgated by the Mayor shall require that notice be provided to TANF applicants of the exemptions from the requirements of <cite path="§4-205.19b">§ 4-205.19b</cite>. Exempt TANF applicants shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Minors who are not the head of an assistance unit, including minors in payee-only cases;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Individuals in a single-parent assistance unit who are already working in volunteer employment, work experience, or participating in another activity that has been approved by the Mayor as work participation, if, in the discretion of the Mayor, the participation in the activity is likely to lead to paid employment within the next 3 months, and the individual is participating in the activity for:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>20 hours or more per week, or an average of 80 hours or more per month, during the period of October 1, 1997, through September 30, 1998;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>25 hours or more per week, or an average of 100 hours or more per month, during the period of October 1, 1998, through September 30, 1999; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>30 hours or more per week, or an average of 120 hours or more per month, after September 30, 1999;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Individuals in a two-parent assistance unit who are already working in volunteer employment, work experience, or participating in another activity that has been approved by the Mayor as work participation, if, in the discretion of the Mayor, the participation in the activity is likely to lead to paid employment within the next 3 months, and the total number of hours in which the individual and the other parent in the assistance unit are participating is at least 35 hours per week (or 55 hours per week, if the family receives federally-funded child care and no adult in the family has a disability or is caring for a child with a disability).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Single custodial parents caring for a child less than 12 months old;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Applicants more than 60 years old;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>With respect to the District-funded portion of TANF, individuals who are enrolled in local, accredited post-secondary educational institutions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall promulgate rules describing those categories of TANF recipients who are exempt from the requirements of <cite path="§4-205.19d|(b)">§ 4-205.19d(b)</cite> [(b) repealed], (c), and (d). The rules promulgated by the Mayor shall require that notice be provided to TANF recipients of the exemptions from the requirements of <cite path="§4-205.19d|(b)">§ 4-205.19d(b)</cite> [(b) repealed], (c), and (d). Exempt TANF recipients shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Minor who are not the heads of assistance units, including minors in payee-only cases;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Single custodial parents caring for a child less than 12 months old; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recipients more than 60 years old.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any TANF applicant or recipient who is exempt from mandatory participation in job search, job readiness, or work activities shall be permitted to participate in those activities on a voluntary basis to the extent that participation opportunities are available and the District’s resources otherwise permit.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History" path="§519g">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 519g</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-241" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-241, § 2(w), 46 DCR 905</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 14(b), 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see note to <cite path="§4-205.19a">§ 4-205.19a</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(w) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(i) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-130">D.C. Law 12-130</cite>, July 24, 1998, law notification  45 DCR 6501).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition of section, see § 2(i) of Public Assistance Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-7">D.C. Law 12-7</cite>, August 1, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 4639).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in subsec. (a)(3), substituted “has a disability or is” for “is disabled or”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-205.19g.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§4-205.19a">§ 4-205.19a</cite>, <cite path="§4-205.19b">§ 4-205.19b</cite>, <cite path="§4-205.19c">§ 4-205.19c</cite>, <cite path="§4-205.19d">§ 4-205.19d</cite>, and <cite path="§4-754.13">§ 4-754.13</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
