<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>4-218.05</num>
  <heading>Penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who knowingly uses, transfers, acquires, alters, purchases, possesses, or transports one or more food stamp coupons or access devices in a manner not authorized by the Food Stamp Act of 1964, approved August 31, 1964 (78 Stat. 703; 7 U.S.C. § 2011 et seq.) (“Food Stamp Act”), or by regulations issued pursuant to that Act, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be fined no more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to the penalty in subsection (a) of this section, any person convicted of a misdemeanor under this section shall be subject to suspension by the Superior Court from participation in the District of Columbia food stamp program for a period of one year consecutive to that period of suspension mandated by section 6(b)(1) of the Food Stamp Act (7 U.S.C. § 2015(b)(1)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Prosecution under this section shall be conducted in the Superior Court by the Corporation Counsel.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Access device” means any card, plate, code, account number, or other means of access, which can be used, alone or in conjunction with another access device, to obtain payments, allotments, benefits, money, goods, or other things of value, or which can be used to initiate a transfer of funds under the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Food stamp coupon” means a coupon issued by the United States Department of Agriculture pursuant to the Food Stamp Act or regulations issued pursuant to the Food Stamp Act.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Person” means an individual, firm, partnership, group, corporation, institution, agency, or other entity, public or private.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-101" type="History" path="§1805">Apr. 6, 1982, D.C. Law 4-101, § 1805</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-254" type="History">as added Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-254,§ 2(c), 46 DCR 1276</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 3-218.5.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
