<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-16">
  <num type="bill">23-112</num>
  <num type="act">23-16</num>
  <heading type="short">Board of Elections Domicile Requirement Emergency Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to exempt the current Executive Director of the District of Columbia Board of Elections from the domicile requirement.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-02-04</introduced>
    <effective>2019-02-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41787/B23-0112-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-16</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 2688</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0112">
      <vote date="2019-02-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-02-28</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Board of Elections Domicile Requirement Emergency Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 5(e)(1) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 700; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-1001.05(e)(1)), is amended by adding a new subparagraph (B-i) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <para>
        <num>(B-i)</num>
        <text>The requirements of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall not apply to Executive Director Alice Miller, beginning on her hire date of July 6, 2016.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง1-1001.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of February 13, 2019.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
