<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-120">
  <num type="bill">23-97</num>
  <num type="act">23-120</num>
  <heading type="short">Access to Public Benefits Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to extend the opt out from denying Temporary Assistance for Needy Families to certain drug felons to Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program benefits and other locally funded non-TANF cash assistance benefits.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-01-24</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2019-11-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41740/B23-0097-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-120</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 13144</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0097">
      <vote date="2019-07-09" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2019-09-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-10-07</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced it extends the opt out from denying TANF benefits to certain drug felons to other locally-funded public benefit programs.</summary>
      <committee>Committee on Human Services</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Access to Public Benefits Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 571 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code ยง 4-205.71), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
    <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง4-205.71"/>
        <num codify:value="4-205.71">571</num>
        <heading>Granting cash and food assistance benefits to drug felons.</heading>
        <text>An adult who is a drug felon shall not be denied cash or food assistance benefits, including TANF, Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program<span codify:value=","> ,</span> POWER, GAC, or Interim Disability Assistant benefits, solely because he or she is a drug felon.</text>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
