<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-217">
  <num type="bill">23-1</num>
  <num type="act">23-217</num>
  <heading type="short">Comprehensive Plan Framework Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 to modify the Framework Element to reflect updated data and analysis of forces driving change and growth projections, and to clarify land use designations and how to use the Generalized Policy Map and Future Land Use Map to reflect longstanding policy.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-01-03</introduced>
    <effective>2020-02-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/41515/B23-0001-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-217</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0001">
      <vote date="2019-07-09" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2019-10-08" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2019-10-08" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2019-10-08" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-02-11</enacted>
      <summary>Chairman Mendelson as submitted by the Mayor.</summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Comprehensive Plan Framework Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Chapter 2 (10-A DCMR § 200.1 <em>et seq.</em>) (Framework Element) of section 3 of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984, effective April 10, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-76; D.C. Official Code § 1-306.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <text>[Text available only in pdf format.]</text>
    <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-306.01" type="Editor's Notes" history="false">
      For amendments to the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 to modify the Framework Element to reflect updated data and analysis of forces driving change and growth projections, and to clarify land use designations and how to use the Generalized Policy Map and Future Land Use Map to reflect longstanding policy, see the <cite doc="D.C. Act 23-217">Comprehensive Plan Framework Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-217)</cite>.
    </codify:annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Residential zoning guidance.</heading>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <text>Upon submission of amendments to the Land Use Element of the Comprehensive Plan, the Office of Planning shall provide to the Council additional guidance on the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Options for increasing the variety of housing types in areas zoned for single-family detached and semi-detached housing; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The implications on equity and affordability of allowing small multifamily buildings in all residential zones.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>No District element of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital shall apply until it has been reviewed by the National Capital Planning Commission as provided in Section 2(a) of the National Capital Planning Act of 1952, approved June 6, 1924 (43 Stat. 463; D.C. Official</text>
    <text>Code § 2-1002(a)), and Section 423 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 792; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.23).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973, (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
