<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-335">
  <num type="bill">23-816</num>
  <num type="act">23-335</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Health Emergency Authority Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2020 [Effective from July 12, 2020]</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980, on an emergency basis, to authorize the Mayor to extend the 15-day March 11, 2020 emergency orders issued in response to the coronavirus through October 9, 2020.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2020-07-06</introduced>
    <effective>2020-07-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/45294/Signed_Act/B23-0816-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 23-335</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 9146</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0816">
      <vote date="2020-07-07" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-07-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Health Emergency Authority Extension Emergency Amendment Act of 2020".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7 of the District of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980, effective March 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-149; D.C. Official Code ยง 7-2306), is amended by adding a new subsection (c-1) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง7-2306|(c-1)"/>
        <num>(c-1)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Council authorizes the Mayor to extend the 15-day March 11, 2020, emergency executive order and public health emergency executive order ("emergency orders") issued in response to the coronavirus (SARS CoV-2) through October 9, 2020.  After the extension authorized by this subsection, the Mayor may extend the emergency orders for additional 15-day period pursuant to subsection (b) or (c) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Repealers.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 507(d) of the Coronavirus Support Temporary Amendment Act of 2020, enacted on July 7, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-334; 67 DCR ____), is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 507(c) of the Coronavirus Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020, effective June 8, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-328; 67 DCR 7598), is repealed.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of July 12, 2020.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section</text>
    <text>412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
