<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-87">
  <num type="bill">23-354</num>
  <num type="act">23-87</num>
  <heading type="short">Florida Avenue Multimodal Project Completion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, section 47-362 of the District of Columbia Official Code to require Council approval of capital reprogrammings made by the District Department of Transportation if certain conditions are not met.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-06-25</introduced>
    <effective>2019-07-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/42875/B23-0354-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-87</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 8489</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0354">
      <vote date="2019-06-25" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-07-17</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Florida Avenue Multimodal Project Completion Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 47-362 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (h) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(h)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding § 47-363, after September 30, 2019, the District Department of Transportation ("DDOT") shall not, unless the Council has approved the action by resolution, make a capital reprogramming until the following conditions on Florida Avenue, N.E., between 2nd Street, N.E., and H Street, N.E., have been met:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The number of vehicle travel lanes are reduced from 6 to a maximum of 4 through lanes;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Design elements are installed to ensure that all right-of-way width affected by the reduction in travel lanes described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph are available for use exclusively by modes of transportation other than motor vehicles, as that term is defined in section 8 of An Act To provide for the annual inspection of all motor vehicles in the District of Columbia, effective March 15, 1985 (D.C. Law 5-176; D.C. Official Code § 50-1108); and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>High-visibility crosswalk markings are installed at all locations that meet the standards for high-visibility crosswalk markings in DDOT's 2019 Design and Engineering Manual.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>On June 4, 2019 and the first Tuesday of each month thereafter, DDOT shall submit to the Council committee with oversight over DDOT and the Councilmembers representing Wards 5 and 6, a letter that:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Describes the status of the procurements for design and for construction of the Florida Avenue Multimodal Transportation Project ("Project");</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Estimates the percent of final design the Project has reached and the projected date that the Project will reach 100% design;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Describes any outreach made during the previous month, or planned for the following month, to District residents about the design of the Project; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Includes the most current publicly available design of the Project.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>This subsection shall expire on the date that the Office of Contracting and Procurement publishes on its website a request for proposals for the construction phase of the Project.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-362"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
