<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1011.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of evening, weekend, and summer adult technical career training program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish an evening, weekend, and summer adult technical career training program (“Program”) for District residents in partnership with existing technical career training programs within 8 months of March 3, 2010. The Program shall provide technical career training opportunities for adults during evening hours, weekends, and summer months. The Program shall be conducted at the following locations:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Phelps Architecture, Construction and Engineering High School;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Academy for Construction and Design at Cardozo Senior High School; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Hospitality Public Charter High School at Roosevelt High School.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Part of the funding directed to support adult technical career training should be applied to cover the cost of operating these facilities beyond traditional school hours.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2171, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2171 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2171 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Short title: Section 2170 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle R of title II of the act may be cited as the “Get DC Residents Training for Jobs Now Act of 2009”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
