<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1802.01</num>
  <heading>Process for filing charter petitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Existing public school. —</heading>
    <text>An eligible applicant seeking to convert a District of Columbia public school into a public charter school:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shall prepare a petition to establish a public charter school that meets the requirements of § <cite root="38-1802.02">38-1802.02</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall provide a copy of the petition to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The parents of minor students attending the existing school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Adult students attending the existing school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Employees of the existing school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Parents of minor students who both attend:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The school grade immediately lower than the first school grade which is served by the public school which is the subject of the conversion petition; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A school that is located within the attendance zone of the public school which is the subject of the conversion petition.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Each Advisory Neighborhood Commission which represents an area within the attendance area of the public school which is the subject of the conversion petition; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Shall file the petition with an eligible chartering authority for approval after the petition:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is signed by two-thirds of the sum of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The total number of parents of minor students attending the school; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The total number of adult students attending the school; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is endorsed by at least two-thirds of full-time teachers employed in the school.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Private or independent school. —</heading>
    <text>An eligible applicant seeking to convert an existing private or independent school in the District of Columbia into a public charter school:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shall prepare a petition to establish a public charter school that is approved by the Board of Trustees or authority responsible for the school and that meets the requirements of § <cite root="38-1802.02">38-1802.02</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Shall provide a copy of the petition to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The parents of minor students attending the existing school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Adult students attending the existing school; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Employees of the existing school; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Shall file the petition with an eligible chartering authority for approval after the petition:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is signed by two-thirds of the sum of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The total number of parents of minor students attending the school; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The total number of adult students attending the school; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Is endorsed by at least two-thirds of full-time teachers employed in the school.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>New school. —</heading>
    <text>An eligible applicant seeking to establish in the District of Columbia a public charter school, but not seeking to convert a District of Columbia public school or a private or independent school into a public charter school, shall file with an eligible chartering authority for approval a petition to establish a public charter school that meets the requirements of § <cite root="38-1802.02">38-1802.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <heading>Jointly operated school. —</heading>
    <text>The Public Charter School Board shall have the authority to approve one joint program for applicants seeking to establish a jointly operated school where 2 or more public charter schools that have adopted, for the combined program, identical mission statements, goals, curricula and educational philosophy (“member schools”) may combine to create a jointly operated middle and high school. Notwithstanding any other law, the jointly operated school shall have the same duties, powers and responsibilities of a public charter school, shall be funded as if a public charter school, and shall be treated as a single local educational agency under federal and local law. Students matriculating directly from the highest grade of a member school into the entry grade of the jointly operated school shall be exempt from the requirements of § <cite root="38-1802.06">38-1802.06</cite>(c).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Limitations on filing. —</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <heading>Multiple chartering authorities. —</heading>
      <text>An eligible applicant may not file the same petition to establish a public charter school with more than one eligible chartering authority during a calendar year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <heading>Multiple petitions. —</heading>
      <text>An eligible applicant may not file more than one petition to establish a public charter school during a calendar year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <heading>Petition for public charter school is public. —</heading>
    <text>A petition to establish a public charter school in the District of Columbia, or to convert a District of Columbia public school or an existing private or independent school, is a public document.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <heading>Existing public charter schools. —</heading>
    <text>A public charter school that existed prior to June 12, 2007, and that was chartered by the District of Columbia Board of Education pursuant to Chapter 17 of this title [§ <cite root="38-1701.01">38-1701.01</cite> et seq.] [repealed], shall not be required to file a petition with the Public Charter School Board; it shall be considered approved and chartered for the purposes of this chapter and shall be subject to the powers and duties granted to the Public Charter School Board as an eligible chartering authority pursuant to §§ <cite root="38-1802.11">38-1802.11</cite>, <cite root="38-1802.12">38-1802.12</cite>, and <cite root="38-1802.13">38-1802.13</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321 234, Pub. L. 104-134, § 2201</annotation>
      <annotation>Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009 1461, Pub. L. 104-208, § 5205(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 2503(a), 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
      <annotation>Oct. 18, 2004, 118 Stat. 1348, Pub. L. 108-335, §§ 341, 342(a)</annotation>
      <annotation>Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 3342, Pub. L. 108-447, Div. J., title I, § 103(a)(3)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 802(a), 54 DCR 4102</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 4112, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="38-1802.02">38-1802.02</cite>, § <cite root="38-1802.06">38-1802.06</cite>, and § <cite root="38-1802.09">38-1802.09</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-2853.11.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> added subsec. (a)(2) (D) and (E).</annotation>
      <annotation>Pub. L. 108-335 added subsec. (e).</annotation>
      <annotation>Pub. L. 108-447 deleted amendments of subsecs. (a)(3)(B) and (b)(3)(B) by Pub. L. 108-335, § 342(a). See Editor’s Notes.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite> added subsec. (f).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (c-1).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 2503(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2503(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4032(b) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 804 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite>, see § 4043(b) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  4112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  4112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  4112 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <annotation>Section 103(b) of Div. J, title I, of Pub. L. 108-447, provided: “The amendments made by this section shall take effect as if included in the enactment of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2005 Pub. L. 108-335 ”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>The amendment of subsecs. (a)(3)(B) and (b)(3)(B) by Pub. L. 108-335, § 342(a), was deleted by Pub. L. 108-447, Div. J, title I, § 103(a)(3), and did not take effect. See Effective Dates note.</text>
      <text>Applicability: Section 804 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite> provided that section 802 shall apply upon enactment by Congress. Section 804 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite> was repealed by section 4043(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
