<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2432</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“American Sign Language” or “ASL” means a visual language that is separate and distinct from English and other languages, and uses the hands, arms, facial markers, and body movements to convey grammatical information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“ASLTA” means the American Sign Language Teachers Association.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Deaf” means the inability to hear or understand oral communication, with or without the assistance of amplification devices.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Deaf people” means persons who use ASL as their primary language to communicate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Hard of hearing” means permanent hearing loss which is severe enough to necessitate the use of amplification devices to hear oral communication.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Professional certification” means a teacher has met the ASLTA professional level certification requirements specified in the standards section of the ASLTA Certification Procedures and Standards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Provisional certification” means a teacher has met the minimum ASLTA provisional level certification requirements specified in the standards section of the ASLTA Certification Procedures and Standards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Qualified certification” means a teacher has met the ASLTA qualified level certification requirements specified in the standards section of the ASLTA Certification Procedures and Standards.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-50">Oct. 26, 2001, D.C. Law 14-50, § 3, 48 DCR 7952</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
