<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-273.01</num>
  <heading>Expansion to universal pre-k.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The OSSE shall conduct, by September 30th of each year, an evaluation of all pre-k programs to establish existing capacity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By September 2009, and every 5 years thereafter, the OSSE shall submit to the Mayor and the Council a 5-year strategic expansion plan, including an assessment of the number of children interested in attending pre-k and the District’s fiscal and physical capacity to accommodate them.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning in September 2009, and each year thereafter, OSSE shall submit to the Mayor and the Council an implementation plan for the following school year to expand pre-k to the maximum extent possible, but shall expand pre-k each year to accommodate a minimum of 15% of the unserved children, based on the strategic expansion plan, until pre-k programs are available to all children of pre-k age whose parents choose to send them to pre-k.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>During the expansion to universal pre-k, OSSE shall use its best efforts to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Ensure that over a 5-year period a minimum of 25% of all new pre-k programs are operated by CBOs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Maintain a balance of diversity among the children.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of this subsection, “diversity” means a mix of children:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>From families of different income levels;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>With, and without, disabilities or special needs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Whose first language is, and is not, English.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A pre-k program established following July 18, 2008, shall comply with the HQ standards, established pursuant to, respectively, §§ <cite root="38-271.02">38-271.02</cite>(b)(4) and <cite root="38-272.01">38-272.01</cite>(b), upon the effective date of the HQ standards.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-202">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-202, § 301, 55 DCR 6297</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
