<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-121.02</num>
  <heading>Agency performance measures.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By January 1, 2011, the District of Columbia Public Schools, shall submit, in accordance with § <cite path="§1-204.56a">1-204.56a</cite>, comprehensive, measurable, objective agency performance measures that are to be included in the next 4 budget submissions for the purposes of measuring the agency’s performance in certain areas, including student outcomes, recruitment and retention of teachers and principals, management and business operations, and parent and community involvement.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Beginning in 2012, this information shall be submitted by January 31 of each year in accordance with subsection (b) of this section to the Council for review and comment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A performance measure shall be included in the budget submission that includes at least one year of actual data. Once included in a budget submission, a performance measure shall be included in its original form for at least 4 successive years.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History" path="§4052">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 4052, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4052 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4051 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</law-cite> provided that subtitle F of title IV of the act may be cited as the “DCPS Performance Measures Standardization Act of 2010”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
