<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1412</num>
  <heading>Grants from Secretary of Education — Authorized.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Secretary of Education (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to make grants to the Mayor of the District of Columbia (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Mayor”) in amounts the Secretary determines to be the minimum amounts necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. The total amount of grants under this section for any fiscal year shall not exceed the sum of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The product of $5,000 times the number of full-time students enrolled in private nonprofit accredited medical schools in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The product of $3,000 times the number of full-time students enrolled in private nonprofit accredited dental schools in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section and § <cite root="38-1416">38-1416</cite>, in determining eligibility for, and the amount of, grants with respect to private nonprofit medical and dental schools, consideration shall be given to any grants made to such schools pursuant to the portion of the program under § 773 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. § 295f-3, repealed] relating to financial assistance to schools which are in serious financial straits to aid them in meeting their costs of operation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1977, to make grants under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1934, Pub. L. 91-650, title III, § 303</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 24, 1974, 88 Stat. 763, Pub. L. 93-389, § 3</annotation>
      <annotation>June 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 682, Pub. L. 94-308</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="38-1413">38-1413</cite>, § <cite root="38-1414">38-1414</cite>, § <cite root="38-1415">38-1415</cite>, and § <cite root="38-1416">38-1416</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-1712.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 31-922.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>“Secretary of Education” was substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare” in subsection (a) of this section pursuant to § 301 of the Act of October 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 677, Pub. L. 96-88.</text>
      <text>“Section 773 of the Public Health Service Act,” referred to in subsection (b) of this subsection, was codified as  42 U.S.C. § 295f-3, and was repealed by the Act of October 12, 1976, 90 Stat. 2293, Pub. L. 94-484.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
