<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1109</num>
  <heading>Federal City College and Washington Technical Institute administered as land-grant colleges; appropriations; allocations to Federal Extension Service of Department of Agriculture.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In the administration of the Act of May 8, 1914 (7 U.S.C. §§ 3<cite path="§41-346">41-346</cite>, 347a-349) (known as the Smith-Lever Act):</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Federal City College and the Washington Technical Institute shall each be considered to be a college established for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts in accordance with the provisions of the Act of July 2, 1862 (7 U.S.C. §§ 3<cite path="§01-305">01-305</cite>, 307, 308); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The term “state” as used in such Act of May 8, 1914, shall include the District of Columbia, except that the District of Columbia shall not be eligible to receive any sums appropriated under 7 U.S.C. § 343.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In lieu of an authorization of appropriations for the District of Columbia under 7 U.S.C. § 343, there is authorized to be appropriated to the District of Columbia such sums as may be necessary to provide cooperative agricultural extension work in the District of Columbia under such Act. For the fiscal years ending June 30, 1969, and June 30, 1970, sums appropriated under this subsection may be used to pay the total cost of providing such extension work; and for each fiscal year thereafter such sums may be used to pay no more than one half of such cost. Any reference in such Act (other than 7 U.S.C. § 343) to funds appropriated under such Act shall in the case of the District of Columbia be considered a reference to funds appropriated under this subsection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Four per centum of the sums appropriated under subsection (b) of this section for each fiscal year shall be allotted to the Federal Extension Service of the Department of Agriculture for administrative, technical, and other services provided by the Service in carrying out the purposes of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-791">Nov. 7, 1966, Pub. L. 89-791, title I, § 109</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-354">June 20, 1968, 82 Stat. 241, Pub. L. 90-354, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-650">Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1935, Pub. L. 91-650, title IV, § 401(b)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-1110">38-1110</cite>, § <cite path="§38-1111">38-1111</cite>, and § <cite path="§38-1112">38-1112</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-1409.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 31-1609.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>“Such Act” referred to throughout subsection (b), means the Act of May 8, 1914, codified in §§ 341 to 346 and 347a to 349 of Title 7, United States Code.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
