<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1003</num>
  <heading>Accountability for funds received.</heading>
  <text>The District of Columbia Board of Education shall account for all funds received pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-221" type="History">Mar. 16, 1995, D.C. Law 10-221, § 4, 41 DCR 8047</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-133.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Sections 2 and 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-199">D.C. Law 19-199</cite> established a task force to develop a city-wide strategic plan for career and technical education programs in the District, to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Section 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Career cluster’ means a non-duplicative, sequential CTE course of study recognized by the U.S. Department of Education and approved by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education and the respective industry council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Completion rate’ means the percentage of students who enroll and complete, within 4 years at the secondary level and 2 years at the post-secondary level, a non-duplicative, sequential CTE course sequence of 3 credits or more, which result in an industry-recognized credential, certificate, or degree, or relevant college credit, or both.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) ‘Concentration rate’ means the percentage of students enrolled in CTE courses who complete 3 credits in a non-duplicative, sequential CTE course sequence of 4 credits or more, or 2 credits in a non-duplicative, sequential CTE course sequence of 3 credits within 4 years.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) ‘CTE’ means career and technical education.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) ‘DCPS’ means the District of Columbia Public Schools.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) ‘Industry council’ means a group of representatives from the private sector, established or approved by OSSE or WIC, working in the same area as a particular career cluster.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) ‘OSSE’ means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education established by section 2 of the State Education Office Establishment Act of 2000, effective October 21, 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-176">D.C. Law 13-176</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§38-2601">38-2601</cite>).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) ‘PCSB’ means the Public Charter School Board established by section 2214 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§38-1802.14">38-1802.14</cite>).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) ‘UDCC’ means the University of the District of Columbia Community College.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) ‘WIC’ means the Workforce Investment Council established by section 4 of the Workforce Investment Implementation Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-150">D.C. Law 13-150</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§32-1603">32-1603</cite>).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Section 3. Establishment of CTE Task Force.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) By August 1, 2012, the Mayor shall establish the CTE Task Force to review best practices for CTE programs and develop a city-wide strategic plan for CTE programs administered by District of Columbia Public Schools, District of Columbia public charter schools, the University of the District of Columbia Community College, or any other secondary or post-secondary institution that receives federal or local funding for CTE programming.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The CTE Task Force shall consist of the following 8 members:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The Chairman of the Council’s Committee on Economic Development and Housing, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Chairman of the Council’s Committee on Jobs and Workforce Development, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Deputy Mayor for Education, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools, or her designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) The Executive Director of the Public Charter School Board, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) The State Superintendent of Education, or her designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) The Executive Director of the Workforce Investment Council, or her designee; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) The Interim Chief Executive Officer of the University of the District of Columbia Community College, or his or her designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Throughout the creation of the city-wide strategic plan, the CTE Task Force shall consult with additional stakeholder groups, including representatives of the District business community who represent industries involved with CTE, representatives from the Washington Teachers Union, representatives from the philanthropic community, and representatives from organizations focused on education or youth workforce development research or service provision.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Office of the State Superintendent shall be responsible for convening and facilitating the CTE Task Force as well as leading the effort to draft the city-wide strategic plan.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) By January 1, 2013, the CTE Task Force shall present to the Mayor and the Council the city-wide strategic plan for CTE. The plan shall align with all federal laws, regulations, funding guidance, and the national Common Career Technical Core and shall include:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A city-wide analysis of CTE programs currently offered at District of Columbia Public Schools, District of Columbia public charter schools, and the University of the District of Columbia Community College to determine their quality, popularity, concentration and completion rates, and whether the career cluster is focused on high-skill, high-wage, or high-demand occupations;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Specific requirements of all CTE programs, including:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The implementation of a CTE curriculum that consists of a non-duplicative, sequential course of study consisting of 3 credits or more that at a minimum:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Integrate academic, career, and technical education;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) Utilize work-based learning experiences, including industry-relevant internships or work-study placements;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iii) Provide technical preparation for high-skill, high-wage, or high-demand occupations, as determined by the relevant industry council and in accordance with standards set forth by federal and local law;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(iv) Result in an industry-recognized credential, certificate or degree, or relevant college credit;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(v) Are designed to lead to placement in high-skill, high-wage, or high-demand occupations or lead to further education in the relevant field; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(vi) Meet any other requirements and spending restrictions prescribed by federal or local law;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Where appropriate, the creation and implementation of dual-enrollment, articulation, or early-college programs with local colleges, universities, post-secondary institutions, or apprenticeship programs;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C)(i) Established partnerships with an industry council, facilitated by OSSE or WIC, which shall be tasked with informing and assisting with:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(I) The CTE curriculum for each career cluster;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(II) The criteria utilized for selecting, training, evaluating, compensating, and scheduling CTE staff and faculty;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(III) The development and monitoring of outcome measurements; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(IV) The identification of internship and job opportunities for students and graduates; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(ii) Alternatively, the Local Education Agency has the option to establish and facilitate its own industry council as long as the industry council is approved by OSSE or WIC;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) A strategy to significantly increase the District’s concentration and completion rates of the relevant CTE curriculum as outlined in paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection with annual benchmarks and a 5-year goal that every CTE program achieve a completion rate and a concentration rate that meet or exceed the national averages;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) An outreach and engagement strategy for students who may consider participating in CTE programs, including specific consideration as to how CTE programs can be used to re-engage youth, between the ages of 16 and 24 years, who are currently disconnected from school, do not have a high school diploma or equivalency, and who are not employed;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) An implementation plan for a pilot program that would accept students into CTE programs from other District of Columbia public or charter schools for the sole purpose of completing CTE-specific course work without requiring a change in full-time enrollment;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) A process for determining the eligibility of career clusters that includes consultation with the WIC and review of labor market data to ensure the field of study is focused on high-skill, high-wage, or high-demand occupations;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) An analysis of whether any new career clusters should be added to fill a gap in course offerings and a determination as to which institution would be best equipped to develop and offer that career cluster;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) A detailed delineation of responsibilities among the relevant agencies, including OSSE, DCPS, PCSB, UDCCC, and other post-secondary institutions, and the WIC;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) An analysis of whether CTE programs should receive additional flexibility in determining, in conjunction with their relevant industry councils, appropriate guidelines for hiring, scheduling, assessing, and compensating CTE faculty in accordance with federal and local law and collective bargaining agreements, and, if so, a process for granting and administering such flexibility;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) A strategy to support and incentivize CTE programs to provide night or weekend CTE course offerings to adult District residents; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(11) A policy allowing individual public charter schools to apply to the PCSB for a waiver from the CTE standards set forth in the plan as long as the PCSB has found that the particular charter school has a compelling justification for such a waiver and has established an alternative set of standards and outcome measures for the particular charter school that will be communicated to the OSSE and monitored by the PCSB.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f)(1) The city-wide strategic plan shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the plan, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the plan shall be deemed approved.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) If the plan is disapproved by the Council, the Council’s Committee of the Whole shall transmit a report to the CTE Task Force citing the Council’s concerns within 30 days of the disapproval and the CTE Task Force shall have 30 days from the date it received the report to review the report and re-submit a new plan to the Mayor and the Council for approval in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-199">D.C. Law 19-199</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 2 and 3 of the (D.C. Act 19-408, July 24, 2012,  59 DCR 9130).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
