<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1853.05</num>
  <heading>Applications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>In general. —</heading>
    <text>In order to receive a grant under § <cite path="§38-1853.04">38-1853.04</cite>(a), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Contents. —</heading>
    <text>The Secretary may not approve the request of an eligible entity for a grant under § <cite path="§38-1853.04">38-1853.04</cite>(a) unless the entity’s application includes—</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>a detailed description of—</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>how the entity will address the priorities described in § <cite path="§38-1853.06">38-1853.06</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>how the entity will ensure that if more eligible students seek admission in the program of the entity than the program can accommodate, eligible students are selected for admission through a random selection process which gives weight to the priorities described in § <cite path="§38-1853.06">38-1853.06</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>how the entity will ensure that if more participating eligible students seek admission to a participating school than the school can accommodate, participating eligible students are selected for admission through a random selection process;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>how the entity will notify parents of eligible students of the expanded choice opportunities in order to allow the parents to make informed decisions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>the activities that the entity will carry out to provide parents of eligible students with expanded choice opportunities through the awarding of scholarships under § <cite path="§38-1853.07">38-1853.07</cite>(a);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>how the entity will determine the amount that will be provided to parents under § <cite path="§38-1853.07">38-1853.07</cite>(a)(2) for the payment of tuition, fees, and transportation expenses, if any;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>how the entity will seek out private elementary schools and secondary schools in the District of Columbia to participate in the program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>how the entity will ensure that each participating school will meet the reporting and other program requirements under this chapter;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>how the entity will ensure that participating schools submit to site visits by the entity as determined to be necessary by the entity, except that a participating school may not be required to submit to more than 1 site visit per school year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>how the entity will ensure that participating schools are financially responsible and will use the funds received under § <cite path="§38-1853.07">38-1853.07</cite> effectively;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>how the entity will address the renewal of scholarships to participating eligible students, including continued eligibility; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>how the entity will ensure that a majority of its voting board members or governing organization are residents of the District of Columbia; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>an assurance that the entity will comply with all requests regarding any evaluation carried out under § <cite path="§38-1853.09">38-1853.09</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 112-10" type="History">Apr. 15, 2011, 125 Stat. 201, Pub. L. 112-10, Div. C, § 3005</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-1853.04">38-1853.04</cite> and § <cite path="§38-1853.07">38-1853.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
