<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-153</num>
  <heading>Coordination of municipal programs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Education and the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall jointly develop procedures to assure the maximum coordination of educational and other municipal programs and services in achieving the most effective educational system and utilization of educational facilities and services to serve broad community needs. Such procedures shall cover such matters as:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Design and construction of educational facilities to accommodate civic and community activities such as recreation, adult and vocational education and training, and other community purposes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Full utilization of educational facilities during nonschool hours for community purposes;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Utilization of municipal services, such as police, sanitation, recreational, and maintenance services to enhance the effectiveness and stature of the school in the community;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Arrangements for cost-sharing and reimbursements on school and community programs involving utilization of educational facilities and services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Other matters of mutual interest and concern.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Education may invite the Mayor of the District of Columbia or his designee to attend and participate in meetings of the Board on matters pertaining to coordination of educational and other municipal programs and services and on such other matters as may be of mutual interest.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-292" type="History">Apr. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 107, Pub. L. 90-292, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Use of school buildings, negotiation and approval, see § <cite path="§38-401">38-401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-401">38-401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-104b.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment—D.C. State Advisory Council on Adult Education participatory planning committee: See Mayor’s Order 90-179, November 29, 1990.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Establishment of District of Columbia Advisory Committee on Education: See Mayor’s Order 89-256, November 7, 1989.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
