<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1837.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Public Charter School Facilities Allotment Task Force (“Task Force”). The Task Force shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Consult with:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Public charter schools;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Council;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Relevant District government agencies; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Banking, or other financial, professionals to determine the financial implications of any changes to the current uniform per student formula for the public charter schools facilities allotment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Conduct a comprehensive analysis of facilities expenditures among public charter schools, including the allowable facilities expenditures recommended by the Mayor, and identify additional factors bearing on expenditures, if any, for consideration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Develop recommendations for a cost-based allocation formula for the public charter schools facilities allotment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Identify cost-saving strategies and measures to ensure that public charter schools facilities allotment funds are used exclusively on public charter school facilities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall submit to the Council its analysis and recommendations, including its recommendation for a cost-based allocation formula for the public charter schools facilities allotment, by November 30, 2009.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be disbanded by no later than December 31, 2009.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History" path="§4021">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4021, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4020 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle C of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Public Charter School Facilities Allotment Task Force Establishment Act of 2009”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4021 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4021 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4021 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
