<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-1404</num>
  <heading>Injunction against operation of college.</heading>
  <text>In any case when such action shall be necessary in the opinion of the said Mayor to give full effect to the intent of this subchapter he shall have power, and it shall be his duty, to file in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, in the name of the said District, a petition against the proper parties praying an injunction against the opening or continuance of any such college not registered and granted a permit as aforesaid; and jurisdiction is hereby conferred upon such court to hear and determine such causes.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>May 4, 1896, 29 Stat. 113, ch. 154, § 5</annotation>
      <annotation>June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
      <annotation>June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
      <annotation>May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 572, Pub. L. 91-358, title I,§ 155(c)(35)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-1704.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 31-904.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
