<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-156</num>
  <heading>Power to raze buildings; limitations.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor, with the consent of the Council by resolution, shall have the power to raze structures. The razing of any building, structure, or part of any building or structure that is on the National Register of Historic Places, the District of Columbia inventory of historic sites, or for which application for one of these listings is pending, shall not be approved.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 59-1-ch3446" path="§14">June 20, 1906, ch. 3446, § 14</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-158" type="History">as added Sept. 11, 1990, D.C. Law 8-158, § 3, 37 DCR 4167</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-259" type="History">Apr. 12, 1997, D.C. Law 11-259, § 311, 44 DCR 1423</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 703, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9" type="History">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 1003(e), 54 DCR 4102</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-120.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-172">D.C. Law 13-172</cite> deleted the concluding sentence providing: “Any contract services required to carry out this purpose shall be procured through the Office of Contracting and Procurement.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite> substituted “The Mayor, with the consent of the Council by resolution,” for “The Board of Education, upon the approval of the Mayor, and with the consent of the Council by resolution,”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) authorization to fix and regulate salaries of teachers and other employees, see § 703 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-376, July 24, 2000,  47 DCR 6574).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 703 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Authorization to charge fees for educational courses: For temporary authorization of the District of Columbia Board of Education to charge fees for select adult, community, and continuing education courses, see §§ 2-5 of the District of Columbia Board of Education Fees for Select Adult, Community, and Continuing Education Courses Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-299, July 25, 1994,  41 DCR 5186).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
