<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-131</num>
  <heading>Provisional duties of the Chancellor.</heading>
  <text>The Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools is authorized to accept the resignation or the application for retirement of any employee, to grant leave of absence to any employee, to extend or terminate any temporary appointment, and to make all changes in personnel and appointments growing out of such resignation, retirement, leave of absence, termination of temporary appointment, or caused by the decease or suspension of any employee.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Apr. 22, 1932, 47 Stat. 134, ch. 131, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 1004, 54 DCR 4102</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-132">38-132</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-108.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 31-106.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite>, in the section heading, substituted “Chancellor” for “Superintendent”; and rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The Superintendent of Schools of the District of Columbia is authorized to accept the resignation or the application for retirement of any employee, to grant leave of absence to any employee, to extend or terminate any temporary appointment, and to make all changes in personnel and appointments growing out of such resignation, retirement, leave of absence, termination of temporary appointment, or caused by the decease or suspension of any employee, or the organization of a new class or classes, and to perform such other duties necessary for the operation of the public school system as may be authorized by the Board of Education, provisionally and until the next regular meeting of the Board of Education.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
