<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1271.01</num>
  <heading>University of the District of Columbia Community College Transition to Independence Advisory Board.</heading>
  <text>There is established a 5-member University of the District of Columbia Community College Transition to Independence Advisory Board. Two of the advisory board members shall be nominated by the Chairman of the Council and 3 advisory board members shall be nominated by the Mayor. All advisory board members shall be subject to confirmation by the Council.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History" path="§4702">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 4702, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4071 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle H of title IV of the act may be cited as “Community College of the District of Columbia Plan for Independence Act of 2011”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 2151 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle P of Title II of the act may be cited as the “University of the District of Columbia Community College Workforce Development Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 4041 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title IV of the act may be cited as the “University of the District of Columbia Accreditation Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4042 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>, § 4042, provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) By November 1, 2012, the University of the District of Columbia shall transmit to the Middle States Commission on Higher Education a request for approval of a substantive change to reclassify the University of the District of Columbia Community College as a Branch Campus of the University of the District of Columbia. A copy of this request shall also be transmitted to the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) By October 1, 2012, the Chief Executive Officer of the University of the District of Columbia Community College shall be responsible for the day-to-day management of the Community College and shall have direct spending authority over the Community College budget, identified as Division (8000) in the University of the District of Columbia operating budget and shall regularly report directly to the Board of Trustees, or a subcommittee of the Board of Trustees, respecting the affairs of the Community College.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) By December 1, 2013, the University of the District of Columbia shall submit to the Council a timeline, using existing resources, for the separate accreditation of the University of the District of Columbia Community College. This timeline shall address the following areas:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) Transition of financial and administrative independence in the areas of student affairs and academic affairs of the University of the District of Columbia Community College from the University of the District of Columbia;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) Ability of the University of the District of Columbia Community College to obtain self-sufficiency in the areas of admissions and financial aid;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) A separate personnel classification of University of the District of Columbia Community College employees;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) Ability for the University of the District of Columbia Community College to initiate and sustain its own academic programs;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(5) A policy for the University of the District of Columbia Community College Chief Executive Officer to regularly report to the University of the District of Columbia’s Board of Trustees regarding the University of the District of Columbia Community College’s affairs;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(6) A fully operational University of the District of Columbia Community College foundation;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(7) A financial plan for the University of the District of Columbia Community College that addresses funding, resource planning, and allocation responsibilities;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(8) Approval of degree-granting authority from the Office of the State Superintendent for Education; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(9) Other evidence that the University of the District of Columbia Community College is effectively fulfilling its mission and serving students in a manner consistent with Middle States Commission on Higher Education’s 10 requirements of affiliations and 14 accreditation standards.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2152 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds not subject to federal requirements that are transferred from the Department of Employment Services (“Department”) to the Workforce Development Program at the University of the District of Columbia Community College (“Community College”) for workforce-development purposes shall be used by the Community College without regard to any reporting requirements or other oversight requirements by the Department. The Community College shall adopt or use policies and procedures currently in place to ensure appropriate reporting, tracking of funds, and controls.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4043 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided: “In fiscal year 2014, of the funds allocated to Non-Departmental, an amount up to $1 million shall be transferred to the University of the District of Columbia (‘UDC’) if, by January 1, 2014, UDC raises an amount of $1 million from private donations for the purpose of meeting accreditation standards. The amount transferred under this section shall be matched dollar-for-dollar from the amount raised.”</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) UDC accreditation, see § 4042 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) UDC Community College Workforce Development, see § 2152 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) UDC accreditation, see § 4042 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) UDC Community College Workforce Development, see § 2152 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of provisions relating to University of the District of Columbia College Autonomy, see § 4042 of the Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
