<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-174.01</num>
  <heading>Event sponsorships.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chancellor may contract for advertisements and sponsorships for athletics, community engagement events, educational programs, or facilities improvements designed to generate resources for the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a special fund the District of Columbia Public Schools Advertisements and Sponsorships Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Chancellor in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Fund shall consist of all revenue from contracts for advertisements and sponsorships for athletics, community engagement events, educational programs, or facilities improvements pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Fund shall be used for the support of the operations of the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and financial plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9" type="History">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 105a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">as added Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 4052, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 4052 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
