<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1312</num>
  <heading>Violations; penalties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person or persons who, directly or indirectly, participate in, aid, or assist in offering postsecondary education or the operation of a postsecondary educational institution by any unlicensed individual or individuals, association, or institution, or by any individual or individuals, association, or institution whose license has been revoked, who advertises or claims any authority to offer education, except pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, or who violates a provision of this chapter shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(a-1)</num>
    <text>The Commission may impose civil fines and penalties as alternative sanctions for violations of the provisions of this chapter or of rules promulgated under the authority of this chapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-1801.01">2-1801.01</cite> et seq.] (“Civil Infractions Act”). Enforcement and adjudication of a violation shall be pursuant to the Civil Infractions Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each day of noncompliance shall constitute a separate violation of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Violations of this chapter shall be prosecuted in the District of Columbia Superior Court by the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in this chapter shall preclude any person from being subject to a penalty under provisions of § <cite path="§28-3904">28-3904</cite>, if the person engages in an unlawful trade practice.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-104" type="History">Apr. 6, 1977, D.C. Law 1-104, § 12</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-217" type="History">as added Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-217, § 2(h), 36 DCR 523</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-74" type="History">Feb. 27, 2016, D.C. Law 21-74, § 2(h), 63 DCR 252</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1612.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-74">D.C. Law 21-74</law-cite> added (a-1); and substituted “Office of the Attorney General for” for “Corporation Counsel of” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(h) of the Higher Education Licensure Commission Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-51">D.C. Law 21-51</law-cite>, Jan. 9, 2016,  62 DCR 13983).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(h) of the Higher Education Licensure Commission Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-158, Oct. 16, 2015,  62 DCR 13715).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(h) of the Higher Education Licensure Commission Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2016 (D.C. Act 21-284, Jan. 27, 2016,  63 DCR 1188).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
