<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1121</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>As used in this subchapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “Washington Technical Institute” means the vocational and technical school established pursuant to this subchapter. Such institute shall provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Vocational and technical education designed to fit individuals for useful employment in recognized occupations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Vocational and technical courses on an individual, noncredit basis.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “Mayor” means the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “Vocational Board” means the Board of Vocational Education established by § <cite path="§38-1122">38-1122</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “Board of Education” means the Board of Education of the District of Columbia established by § <cite path="§1-204.95">1-204.95</cite> [repealed].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-791" type="History" path="§201">Nov. 7, 1966, 80 Stat. 1430, Pub. L. 89-791, title II, § 201</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-1621.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1421.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Provisions of subchapter I applicable to Washington Technical Institute, see §§ <cite path="§38-1107">38-1107</cite> to 38-1112.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Authorization of appropriations for carrying out purpose of this subchapter, see § <cite path="§38-1106">38-1106</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
