<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1202.11</num>
  <heading>Transfer of powers of Board of Governors.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All functions, powers, and duties of the Board of Governors of the District of Columbia School of Law established by <cite path="§38-1205.03">§ 38-1205.03</cite> [repealed] shall be vested in and exercised by the Trustees. The District of Columbia School of Law shall be merged with and become a component of the University of the District of Columbia, as a single independent agency of the District of Columbia under the authority and jurisdiction of the Trustees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All employees, property (real and personal), and unexpended balances (available or to be made available) of appropriations, allocations, and all other funds and assets and liabilities of the Board of Governors are transferred to the Trustees. All rules, orders, obligations, determinations, and any other understandings of the Board of Governors shall remain in effect until such time as they may be lawfully amended, modified, or repealed by the Trustees. Thereafter, any reference in any law, rule, regulation, or other document of the United States or the District of Columbia to the Board of Governors shall be deemed to be a reference to the Trustees, and any reference in any law, rule, regulation, or other document of the United States or the District of Columbia to the District of Columbia School of Law shall be deemed to be a reference to the University of the District of Columbia School of Law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Trustees shall be bound by the terms of the Merger Agreement between the University of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia School of Law, signed November 6, 1995.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-471" type="History" path="§211">Oct. 26, 1974, 88 Stat. 1429, Pub. L. 93-471, title II, § 211</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">as added Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 301(d), 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Law School buildings: For provisions directing the District of Columbia School of Law to submit any lease or building purchase agreement to the Council for review, see § 702 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-128">D.C. Law 10-128</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 38-1205.03, referred to in (a), was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-152">D.C. Law 11-152</cite>,  43 DCR 2978.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 501 of D.C. Act 11-335 provided for the application of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 301(d) of the Fiscal Year 1996 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-264, Apr. 26, 1996,  43 DCR 2412), and § 201(d) of the Fiscal Year 1996 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-335, August 1, 1996,  43 DCR 4256).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1520.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-2853.04">§ 47-2853.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Regulated non-health related occupations and professions, license taxes, see <cite path="§47-2853.04">§ 47-2853.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
