<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-172</num>
  <heading>Mayor’s authority; rulemaking.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall govern the public schools in the District of Columbia. The Mayor shall have authority over all curricula, operations, functions, budget, personnel, labor negotiations and collective bargaining agreements, facilities, and other education-related matters, but shall endeavor to keep teachers in place after the start of the school year and transfer teachers, if necessary, during summer break.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may delegate any of his authority to a designee as he or she determines is warranted for efficient and sound administration and to further the purpose of DCPS to educate all students enrolled within its schools or learning centers consistent with District-wide standards of academic achievement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In accordance with Chapter 5 of Title 2, the Mayor shall promulgate rules and regulations governing DCPS, including rules governing the process by which the Mayor and DCPS will seek and utilize public comment in the development of policy.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 103, 54 DCR 4102</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-174">38-174</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of the Mayor’s Authority under the Public Education Reform Amendment Act of 2007 to chair Special Community Meeting Relating to Reorganization and Rightsizing Plan for the District of Columbia Public Schools, see Mayor’s Order 2008-35, February 27, 2008 ( 55 DCR 5298).</annotation>
      <annotation>Delegation of Authority—Director of the Department of Employment Services, see Mayor’s Order 2009-115, June 19, 2009 ( 56 DCR 6864).</annotation>
      <annotation>Delegation of Official to Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools (DCPS) to execute a Ground Lease for the Scott Montgomery School, see Mayor’s Order 2011-130, August 8, 2011 ( 58 DCR 7325).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Mayor's Orders</heading>
      <text>Transfer of Property—District of Columbia Public Schools, see Mayor’s Order 2008-104, July 29, 2008 ( 55 DCR 9386).</text>
      <text>Transfer of the Hine Junior High School located at 302  8th Street, SE, Washington, D.C. from District of Columbia Public Schools to the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic, see Mayor’s Order 2010-62, April 23, 2010 ( 57 DCR 3510).</text>
      <text>Transfer of Webb Elementary School located at 1375 Mount Olivet Road, NE, Washington, D.C. from District of Columbia Public Schools to the Department of Real Estate Services, see Mayor’s Order 2010-182, December 31, 2010 ( 57 DCR 12643).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
