<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-1124</num>
  <heading>Board of Vocational Education — Facilities.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor and the Board of Education may furnish to the Vocational Board, upon request of such Board, such space and facilities in private buildings or in public buildings of the government of the District of Columbia, records, information, services, personnel, offices, and equipment as may be available and which are necessary to enable the Vocational Board properly to perform its functions under this subchapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-791" type="History" path="§204">Nov. 7, 1966, 80 Stat. 1433, Pub. L. 89-791, title II, § 204</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">The Board of Higher Education and the Vocational Board were abolished on the day the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia convened its first meeting. See § <cite path="§38-1202.08">38-1202.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-1624.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1424.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
