<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-274.02</num>
  <heading>HEI scholarship program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to awarding HEI grants, the University of the District of Columbia may establish and administer a scholarship-award program for qualified individuals who have an interest in the pre-k education field. In exchange for a commitment to teach in the pre-k-education system in the District for 3 years, the University of the District of Columbia may provide a scholarship to the HEI program, as well as a stipend, to a qualified applicant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A qualified applicant shall be an individual who has graduated from college within 3 years of submission of the application.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A preference shall be given to individuals who:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Are domiciled in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Graduated from a District college or university; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Commit to be domiciled in the District within 180 days of accepting a scholarship.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An individual who accepts the scholarship and fails to fulfill the 3-year commitment shall be required to repay the scholarship.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-202" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-202, § 402, 55 DCR 6297</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-285" type="History">Mar. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-285, § 2(h), 57 DCR 11005</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-271.01">38-271.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-285">D.C. Law 18-285</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “grants” for “grants to pre-k teachers and assistant teachers” and “the University of the District of Columbia” for “OSSE”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>Section 2(i) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-142">D.C. Law 18-142</cite> deleted “to pre-k teachers and assistant teachers”; and substituted “the University of the District of Columbia” for “OSSE” both times it appears.</text>
      <text>Section 5(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-142">D.C. Law 18-142</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Pre-K Acceleration and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-304, January 28, 2010,  57 DCR 1475).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Pre-k Acceleration and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-602, December 1, 2010,  57 DCR 11039).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(h) of Pre-k Acceleration and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 19-4, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1399).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
