<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-272.03</num>
  <heading>Pre-k programs assistance grants.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The OSSE shall establish and administer a grant program to assist existing and new pre-k programs in public schools, public charter schools, and CBOs in meeting the required HQ standards. Each grant shall be a 2-year grant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The OSSE shall establish the criteria for eligibility to receive a grant; provided, that, in evaluating grant applications, OSSE shall give priority to those applications that demonstrate need and a capacity to achieve and maintain the HQ standards.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], shall issue revised administrative and procedural rules for the grant program and HQ standards and submit the rules to the Council within 45 days of March 8, 2011. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-202" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-202, § 203, 55 DCR 6297</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-285" type="History">Mar. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-285, § 2(e), 57 DCR 11005</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-285">D.C. Law 18-285</cite> rewrote subsec. (a); and added subsec. (c). Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “(a) Beginning in September 2009, OSSE shall establish and administer a 5-year grant program to assist pre-k programs in meeting the required HQ standards. Each grant shall be a 2-year grant. The last grants to be awarded pursuant to this section shall be awarded in 2013.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">Section 2(e) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-142">D.C. Law 18-142</cite> rewrote subsec. (a) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">“(a) The OSSE shall establish and administer a grant program to assist existing and new pre-k programs in public schools, public charter schools, and CBOs in meeting the required HQ standards. Each grant shall be a 2-year grant.”.; and added subsec. (c) is added to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">“(c) The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), shall issue administrative and procedural rules for the grant program and HQ standards and submit the rules within 45 days of the effective date of the Pre-K Acceleration and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2010, passed on emergency basis on January 5, 2010 (Enrolled version of Bill 18-603). If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">Section 5(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-142">D.C. Law 18-142</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Pre-K Acceleration and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-304, January 28, 2010,  57 DCR 1475).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Pre-k Acceleration and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-602, December 1, 2010,  57 DCR 11039).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e) of Pre-k Acceleration and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 19-4, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1399).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
