<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2402.10</num>
  <heading>International students.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Enrollment. —</heading>
    <text>Effective with new admissions for academic year 1993-1994 and each succeeding academic year, the University (including preparatory, undergraduate, and graduate students) and NTID shall limit the enrollment of international students to approximately 10 percent of the total postsecondary student population enrolled respectively at the University or NTID.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Tuition surcharge. —</heading>
    <text>Effective with new admissions, the tuition for postsecondary international students enrolled in the University (including preparatory, undergraduate, and graduate students) or NTID shall include a surcharge of 75% for the academic year 1993-1994 and 90 percent beginning with the academic year 1994-1995.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Reduction of surcharge. —</heading>
    <text>Beginning with the academic year 1993-1994, the University or NTID may reduce the surcharge under subsection (b) of this section to 50% if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A student described under subsection (b) of this section is from a developing country;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Such student is unable to pay the tuition surcharge under subsection (b) of this section; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Such student has made a good faith effort to secure aid through such student’s government or other sources.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <heading>Definition. —</heading>
    <text>For purposes of subsection (c), the term “developing country” means a country that has a 1990 per capita income not in excess of $4,000 in 1990 United States dollars.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 99-371" type="History">Aug. 4, 1986, 100 Stat. 781, Pub. L. 99-371, § 410</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">renumbered as § 210, Oct. 1, 1992, 106 Stat. 2151, Pub. L. 102-421, § 139</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 103-73" type="History">Aug. 11, 1993, 107 Stat. 735, Pub. L. 103-73, § 204(h)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 36, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1842.10.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
