<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2554</num>
  <heading>Composition of the Task Force.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be comprised of the following 9 voting members, or designees thereof:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation for the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Chair of the Committee of Finance and Revenue for the Council of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The President of the Board of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Superintendent of the District of Columbia Public Schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The State Education Officer of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Deputy Mayor for Children, Youth, Families and Elders;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following shall serve as advisory, nonvoting members of the Task Force:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The members of the Council’s Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The department head or designee of the Office of Special Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The department head or designee of the Committee on Special Education and Student Services for the Board of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Corporation Counsel for the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The department head or designee of the Department of Mental Health;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The department head or designee of the Child and Family Service Agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The department head or designee of the Medical Assistance Administration;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The department head or designee of the Office of Medicaid Public Provider Operation Reform;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The representative of the State Advisory Panel on Special Education in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Two parents of District of Columbia Special Education students.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Task Force shall be co-chaired by the Mayor and the Chair of the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation for the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Director of the State Education Office shall provide staffing for the Task Force.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 375, 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 5 of Special Education Task Force Establishment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-232, November 25, 2003,  50 DCR 10729).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
