<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2981</num>
  <heading>Turkey Bowl Revenue Generation and Sponsorship.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Mayor may enter into one or more written agreements for advertisements and sponsorships to supplement local funding for the annual District of Columbia Interscholastic Athletic Association (“DCIAA”) Championship Turkey Bowl and other DCIAA athletic activities and programs.  The Mayor may delegate this authority to the Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Chancellor of DCPS may sub-delegate, by written order, the authority to contract for advertisements or sponsorships to another official within DCPS.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An agreement  pursuant to this chapter shall not require the District to expend  funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Only advertisements  shall be agreed to in exchange for corporate goods, services, or funds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>There shall be  no limit to the value of goods, services, or funds that may be received  from an organization, registered or not, or from an individual, regardless  of whether the organization is located, or the individual resides,  within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Any sponsorship  or advertisement pursuant to this chapter shall be memorialized by  written agreement of the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Chief Financial  Officer shall deposit all cash proceeds received from advertisements  and sponsorships pursuant to this chapter to the credit of the District  of Columbia Public Schools in the same manner as that used for donations  under § <cite path="§1-329.01">1-329.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Chancellor  of DCPS shall keep an accounting of all goods, services, and funds  received pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-232" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-232, § 2, 62 DCR 422</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
