<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2021.21</num>
  <heading>Adjustment of annuities on basis of price index; computation; definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Effective December 1, 1965, each annuity payable from the fund which has a commencing date not later than January 1, 1966, shall be increased by: (1) the per centum rise in the price index, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%, determined by the Mayor of the District of Columbia on the basis of the annual average price index for calendar year 1962 and the price index for the month of July 1965; plus (2) 6 1/2% if the commencing date (or in the case of a survivor of a deceased annuitant the commencing date of the annuity of the retired employee) occurred on or before October 1, 1956, or 1 1/2% if the commencing date (or in the case of the survivor of a deceased annuitant the commencing date of the annuity of the retired employee) occurred after October 1, 1956. The month used in determining the increase based on the per centum rise in the price index under this subsection shall be the base month for determining the per centum change in the price index until the next succeeding increase occurs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For the payments of benefits accrued by teachers after June 30, 1997, on January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If, in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor determines in a year (beginning with 1999) that the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year indicates a rise in the price index, each annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the year shall, effective March 1 of the year, be increased by an amount equal to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of such preceding year, the per centum change computed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date after March 1 of such preceding year, a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/12 of the per centum change computed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>On January 1, 1998, or within a reasonable time thereafter, the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index published for December 1997 over the price index published for June 1997. If such per centum change indicates a rise in the price index, effective March 1, 1998:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Each annuity having a commencing date on or before September 1, 1997, shall be increased by an amount equal to such per centum change, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Each annuity having a commencing date after September 1, 1997, and on or before March 1, 1998, shall be increased by a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/6 of such per centum change, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 6 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1 per centum.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>On January 1 of each year, or within a reasonable time thereafter, the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year and by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If, in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor determines in a year, beginning with 1997, that the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year indicates a rise in the price index, each annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the year shall, effective March 1 of the year, be increased by an amount equal to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the preceding year, the per centum change computed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In the case of an annuity having a commencing date after March 1 of the preceding year, a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/12 of the per centum change computed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>On January 1, 1996, or within a reasonable time thereafter, the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index published for December 1995 or the price index published for June 1995. If such per centum change indicates a rise in the index, effective March 1, 1996;</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Each annuity having a commencing date on or before September 1, 1995, shall be increased by an amount equal to the per centum change, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Each annuity having a commencing date after September 1, 1995, and on or before March 1, 1996, shall be increased by a pro rata increase equal to the product of 1/6 of the per centum change, multiplied by the number of months (not to exceed 6 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall apply only to public school teachers hired after December 31, 1979.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Eligibility for an annuity increase under this section shall be as provided in subsection (b)(2) of this section, except as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Effective from its commencing date, an annuity payable to an annuitant’s survivor (other than a child entitled under § <cite path="§38-2021.09">38-2021.09</cite>(b)(2)), which annuity commences the day after the annuitant’s death and after the effective date of the 1st increase under this section, shall be increased by the total per centum increase the annuitant was receiving under this section at death;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purpose of computing the annuity of a child under § <cite path="§38-2021.09">38-2021.09</cite>(b)(2) that commences after October 31, 1969, the items $900, $1,080, $2,700, and $3,240 appearing in § <cite path="§38-2021.09">38-2021.09</cite>(b)(2) shall be increased by the total per centum increases allowed and in force under this section on or after such day and, in case of a deceased annuitant, the items 60% and 75% appearing in § <cite path="§38-2021.09">38-2021.09</cite>(b)(2) shall be increased by the total per centum allowed and in force to the annuitant under this section on or after such day.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each annuity increase payable from the fund to an annuitant hired on or after the first day of the first pay period which begins after October 29, 1996, or to such annuitant’s beneficiary or survivor, shall in no event exceed 3% per annum.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No increase in annuity provided by this section shall be computed on any additional annuity purchased at retirement by voluntary contributions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The monthly installment of annuity after adjustment under this section shall be fixed at the nearest dollar, except that such installments shall after adjustment reflect an increase of at least $1.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, the term “price index” shall mean the Consumer Price Index (all items — United States city average) published monthly by the Bureau of Labor Statistics. The term “base month” shall mean the month for which the price index showed a per centum rise forming the basis for a cost-of-living annuity increase.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 7, 1946, ch. 779, § 21</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-881" type="History">as added Oct. 24, 1962, 76 Stat. 1236, Pub. L. 87-881, title II, § 202</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-494" type="History">July 5, 1966, 80 Stat. 266, Pub. L. 89-494, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-231" type="History">Dec. 29, 1967, 81 Stat. 751, Pub. L. 90-231, § 1(9)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-263" type="History">May 22, 1970, 84 Stat. 257, Pub. L. 91-263, § 1(c)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122" type="History">Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, § 251(a)(1), (b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 806b, 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-218" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-218, § 4(d), 43 DCR 6172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 33, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 719, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11013(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-152" type="History">Sept. 18, 1998, D.C. Law 12-152, § 207(b), 45 DCR 4045</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-2021.27">38-2021.27</cite> and § <cite path="§38-2023.13">38-2023.13</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1241.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-739a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 206(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-58">D.C. Law 12-58</cite> rewrote (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 209(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-58">D.C. Law 12-58</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(d) of the New Hires Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Pension Modification Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-428, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6147), and § 4(d) of the New Hires Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Pension Modification Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-10, March 3, 1997,  44 DCR 1633).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 206(b) of the Police Officer, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-155, October 1, 1997,  44 DCR 5896), and see § 206(b) of the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-240, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 531).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Full Funding of Pension Liability Reform Amendment Act of 1994: Section 312 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-135">D.C. Law 10-135</cite> amends (b)(1) and (2) to read as follows:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b)(1) On January 1 of each year (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year by determining the difference between the index published for December of the preceding year and the index published for December of the second preceding year.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2)(A) If (in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection) the Mayor determines in a year (beginning with 1997) that the per centum change in the price index for the preceding year indicates a rise in the price index, each annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of the year shall, effective March 1 of the year, be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(i) In the case of an annuity having a commencing date on or before March 1 of such preceding year, the per centum change computed under paragraph (1), adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%; or.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(ii) In the case of an annuity having a commencing date after March 1 of such preceding year, a pro rata increase equal to the product of:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(I) One-twelfth of the per centum change computed under paragraph (1), multiplied by.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(II) The number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(B) On January 1, 1996 (or within a reasonable time thereafter), the Mayor shall determine the per centum change in the price index published for December 1995 over the price index published for June 1995. If such per centum change indicates a rise in the price index, effective March 1, 1996—</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(i) Each annuity having a commencing date on before September 1, 1995, shall be increased by an amount equal to such per centum change, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%; and.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(ii) Each annuity having a commencing date after September 1, 1995, and on or before March 1, 1996, shall be increased by a pro rata increase equal to the product of.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(I) One-sixth of such per centum change, multiplied by.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(II) The number of months (not to exceed 6 months, counting any portion of a month as an entire month) for which the annuity was payable before the effective date of the increase, adjusted to the nearest 1/10 of 1%.”</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
