<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2001.14</num>
  <heading>Records to be kept by Mayor.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall prepare and keep all needful tables, records, and accounts required for carrying out the provisions of this subchapter. The records to be kept shall include data showing the mortality experience of the teachers in the service of the public schools of the District of Columbia and the rate of withdrawal from such service, and any other information pertaining to such service that may be of value and may serve as a guide for future valuations and adjustments of the plan for the retirement of teachers.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 15, 1920, 41 Stat. 389, ch. 39, § 14</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 11, 1926, 44 Stat. 730, ch. 556, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122" type="History">Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, § 146(c)(2)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-1215.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 31-715.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
