<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2571.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Child with a disability” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 602(3) of IDEA (20 U.S.C. § 1401(3)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“IDEA” means the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, approved April 13, 1970 (84 Stat. 175; 20 U.S.C. § 1400et seq.), and its implementing regulations.</text>
    <text>
      <em>et seq.</em>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Individualized education program” or “IEP” means a written plan that specifies the special education programs and services to be provided to meet the unique educational needs of a child with a disability, as required under section 614(d) of IDEA (20 U.S.C. § 1414(d)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Individualized family service plan” or “IFSP” means a written plan for providing early intervention services to an infant or toddler with a disability and the infant’s or toddler’s family that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is based on the evaluation and assessment of the child and family, consistent with the requirements of 34 C.F.R. § 303.321;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Consistent with the requirements of 34 C.F.R. § 303.344, includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Information about the child’s present levels of development;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Information about the family;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>The results or outcomes to be achieved;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iv)</num>
        <text>The early intervention services necessary to meet the needs of the child and family, and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(v)</num>
        <text>To the extent appropriate, the identification of other services that the child or family needs or is receiving through other sources;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is implemented as soon as possible once parental consent for the early intervention services in the IFSP is obtained, consistent with 34 C.F.R. § 303.420; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Is developed in accordance with the IFSP procedures in 34 C.F.R. §§ 303.342, 303.343, and 303.345.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Infant or toddler with a disability” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 632(5) of the IDEA (20 U.S.C. § 1432(5)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Local education agency” or “LEA” means the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“OSSE” means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, as established by Chapter 26 of this title [§ <cite path="§38-2601">38-2601</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Parent” means a natural or adoptive parent of a child, a legal guardian, a person acting in the place of a parent, such as a grandparent or stepparent with whom the child lives, or a person who is legally responsible for the child’s welfare, or a surrogate parent who has been appointed in accordance with 34 C.F.R. §300.519. The term “parent” may also include a foster parent when the natural parent’s authority to make educational decisions on the child’s behalf has been extinguished under applicable law and the foster parent has an ongoing, long-term parental relationship with the child, is willing to make educational decisions for the child as required under IDEA, and has no interest that conflicts with the interest of the child.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Public agency” means either OSSE or a local education agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Service location” means the physical address at which instruction occurs or at which a student with disabilities receives special education and related services. The term “service location” does not refer to a specific classroom within a building or a specific building on a campus.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-194" type="History" path="§102">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-194, §  102, 61 DCR 12411</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
