<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-271.03</num>
  <heading>Annual evaluation of the quality of current pre-k programs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 30 days of July 18, 2008, the Mayor shall submit to the Council for its approval, a plan, including the name of a proposed independent evaluator, to evaluate pre-k programs in accordance with this section. Within 60 days of Council approval, the Mayor shall execute a contract with the approved evaluator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The approved evaluator shall perform a baseline quality assessment for a sampling of pre-k classrooms in each of the following sectors:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>District of Columbia Public Schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Public charter schools; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>CBOs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The evaluator shall collect baseline quality data to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Describe the overall program structure;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Assess the language and literacy environment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assess the quality of instructional support, classroom climate, and classroom management.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The evaluator’s data and analysis shall be used to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide an assessment of the level of quality of all sectors; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Serve as baseline data from which to develop benchmarks for ongoing quality assessment of the pre-k-education system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council by September 15 of each year, beginning in 2009, projected benchmarks by which to measure annual achievements within the pre-k-education system.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-202" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-202, § 103, 55 DCR 6297</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-271.05">38-271.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
