<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2731</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Academic year” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 481 of the Higher Education Act [20 U.S.C. § 1088].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program” means the college financial assistance program administered by the State Education Office pursuant to Subpart 4 of Part A of Title IV of the Higher Education Act [20 U.S.C. § 1070c et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Eligible institution” means an institution that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is an institution of higher education, either public or private, with its principal campus in the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is eligible to receive Student Aid Program funds under Title IV of the Higher Education Act [20 U.S.C. § 1070 et seq.].</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Eligible student” means a District resident who meets the eligibility criteria for the DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program administered by the State Education Office.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Higher Education Act” means the Higher Education Act of 1965, approved November 8, 1965 [(79 Stat. 1219; 20 U.S.C. § 1001 et seq.)].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Institution of higher education” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 101 of the Higher Education Act [20 U.S.C. § 1001].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Qualified higher education expenses” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Tuition, fees, and the cost of books, supplies, and equipment required for the enrollment or attendance of a qualified beneficiary at an eligible institution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The costs of room and board of a qualified beneficiary incurred while attending an eligible institution; provided, that the amount of room and board shall not exceed the minimum room and board allowance determined in calculating costs of attendance for federal financial aid programs under section 472 of the Higher Education Act [20 U.S.C. § 1087ll], or any subsequent legislation and implementing regulations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Additional living expenses.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 4022, 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 137, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4022 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4022 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4022 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-192">D.C. Law 16-192</cite> provided that subtitle C of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Higher Education Financial Aid Assistance Act of 2006”.</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 481 of the Higher Education Act, referred to in par. (1), is codified at  20 U.S.C. § 1088.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Subpart 4 of part A of Title IV of the Higher Education Act, referred to in par. (2), is codified at  20 U.S.C. § 1070c et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Title IV of the Higher Education Act, referred to in par. (3)(B), is codified at  20 U.S.C. § 1070 et seq.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 101 of the Higher Education Act, referred to in par. (6), is codified at  20 U.S.C. § 1001.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">Section 472 of the Higher Education Act, referred to in par. (7)(B), is codified at  20 U.S.C. § 1088.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
