<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2831</num>
  <heading>Budget submission requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools (“Chancellor”) shall prepare and execute a performance-based budget on an annual basis. The budget prepared by the Chancellor shall have its operations organized by major programs, which in turn will be composed of activities and services. The budget submitted by the Chancellor shall allocate all monies by revenue source for programs, activity, and service levels, and by revenue source for comptroller source group by program and activity. The District of Columbia Public Schools (“DCPS”) submission shall include the number of full-time equivalents with job titles by program and revenue source.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The DCPS submission shall also include a delineation of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All funds budgeted for each school, by revenue source for activities and service levels, and by revenue source for comptroller source group by activities and service levels;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The programs and services, along with a narrative description of each program and service, to be supported by the allowable maximum 5% allocation for central administration functions as prescribed in § <cite path="§38-2907.01">38-2907.01</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All funds not allocated directly to a school or to central administration functions, by revenue source for activities and service levels, and by revenue source for comptroller source group by activities and service levels, including a presentation of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Any funds that will support costs associated with programs and services provided at the school level or directly to students; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Any funding associated with at-risk students, as defined in § <cite path="§38-2901">38-2901</cite>(2A), that has been retained by the Chancellor.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No later than 21 days before the Mayor’s submission of the District’s budget and financial plan to the Council, the Chancellor shall, annually, make available on the DCPS website and post at each school a detailed estimate, in accordance with this section, of the amount of money required to operate the public schools for the ensuing year, including preliminary school-by-school budgets.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor’s annual submission of the District’s budget and financial plan to the Council shall include as an attachment an accurate and verifiable report on the positions and employees of the District of Columbia Public Schools to include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A compilation of DCPS Schedule A positions for the ensuing fiscal year on a full-time equivalent basis, including a compilation of all positions by organization Level 4, job title, pay plan and grade, program and activity, revenue fund, and annual salary; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A compilation of all DCPS employees as of the preceding March 1, on a full-time equivalent basis, including a compilation of all positions by organization Level 4, job title, pay plan, grade, and step, program and activity, revenue fund, and annual salary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No later than October 30 of each year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a revised appropriated funds operating budget for DCPS for the fiscal year beginning on the preceding October 1 that sets forth the total amount of the approved appropriation and that realigns budgeted data with anticipated actual expenditures with the specification set forth in of subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2011, the Mayor shall submit to the Council quarterly financial reports for DCPS setting forth by organization Level 4 approved budget, revised budget, actual expenditures and funds obligated to date, and projected expenditures for the full fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-211" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-211, § 6, 51 DCR 8805</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-325" type="History">Mar. 21, 2009, D.C. Law 17-325, § 4, 56 DCR 499</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 4032, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-87" type="History">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-87, § 3, 61 DCR 309</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-325">D.C. Law 17-325</law-cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The Board of Education shall approve an annual budget for submission to the Council that is consistent with the goals and objectives established by the Board of Education for the operation of the public schools of the District of Columbia. The Board shall prepare and execute a performance-based budget on an annual basis. The budget prepared by the Board shall have its operations organized by major programs, which in turn will be composed of activities and services. The budget submitted by the board shall allocate all monies by activities and object class. The DCPS submission shall also include a presentation that specifies the monies budgeted for each school. This presentation shall specify the funds available to each school for which the decision to spend is made by the school’s local schools restructuring team, and shall specify other responsibility center funds the spending of which directly benefit local schools (e.g., for textbooks, substitute teachers, transportation, maintenance/engineers, nurses, teachers salaries, etc.), so that the Council and the public may know the totality of funds, goods and services that will be provided to the local schools directly.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</law-cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The Chancellor of the District of Columbia Public Schools (‘Chancellor’) shall prepare and execute a performance-based budget on an annual basis. The budget prepared by the Chancellor shall have its operations organized by major programs, which in turn will be composed of activities and services. The budget submitted by the Chancellor shall allocate all monies by revenue source for programs, activity, and service levels, and by revenue source for comptroller source group by program and activity. The District of Columbia Public Schools submission shall include the number of full-time equivalents with job titles by program and revenue source. The DCPS submission shall also include a presentation that specifies the monies budgeted for each school. This presentation shall specify the funds available to each school for which the decision to spend is made by the school’s local schools restructuring team, and shall specify other responsibility center funds the spending of which directly benefit local schools (e.g., for textbooks, substitute teachers, transportation, maintenance/engineers, nurses, teachers salaries, etc.), so that the Council and the public may know the totality of funds, goods and services that will be provided to the local schools directly.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-87">D.C. Law 20-87</law-cite> rewrote (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4 of Public Schools Hearing Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-11, February 25, 2009,  56 DCR 1915).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4032 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4031 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</law-cite> provided that subtitle D of title IV of the act may be cited as the “District of Columbia Public Schools Fiscal Transparency Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
