<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2571.04</num>
  <heading>Transfer of rights.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A child with a disability who has reached 18 years of age shall be presumed to be competent, and all rights under IDEA shall transfer to the student, unless:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The student has been adjudged incompetent under law;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Pursuant to a procedure established by OSSE pursuant to 20 U.S.C. § 1415(m)(2), the student has been determined to not have the ability to provide informed consent and another competent adult has been appointed to represent the educational interests of that student; provided, that the adult student shall have the opportunity to challenge any determination made under this paragraph; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The student has designated, in writing, by power of attorney or similar legal document, another competent adult to be the student’s agent to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Make educational decisions;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Receive notices; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Participate in meetings and all other procedures related to the student’s educational program on behalf of the student.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The student may terminate the power of attorney at any time and assume the right to make decisions regarding his or her education.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A student who has reached 18 years of age may receive support from another competent and willing adult to aid them in their decision-making.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The student’s decisional choice shall prevail any time that a disagreement exists between the student and the other adult providing support.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No less than one year before a child with a disability reaches 18 years of age, the LEA shall notify the parents, in writing, that adult students with disabilities are presumed competent, and that all rights under IDEA will transfer to the student when the student reaches 18 years of age, unless the student or the family exercises one of the options described in subsection (a) of this section. The notice shall also describe the necessary procedure to exercise any of the options provided for in subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-194">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-194, §  104, 61 DCR 12411</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
