<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-236</num>
  <heading>Annual reporting requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each local education agency and entity operating a publicly funded community-based organization shall maintain data for each student that includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Demographic data including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The campus attended by the student;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The student’s grade level;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The student’s gender identification;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The student’s race;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The student’s ethnicity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Whether the student receives special education services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Whether the student is classified as an English language learner; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Whether the student is considered at-risk as defined in § <cite root="38-2901">38-2901</cite>(2A); and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Discipline data including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Total number of out-of-school suspensions and in-school suspensions experienced by the student during each school year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Total number of days excluded from school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Whether the student was referred to an alternative education setting for the duration of a suspension;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Whether the student was expelled during the school year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Whether the student voluntarily or involuntarily transferred or withdrew from the school during the school year; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>For each suspension or expulsion, a description of the action that led to the suspension or expulsion.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By August 15 of each year, each local education agency or entity operating a publicly funded community-based organization shall submit a report to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education disaggregated by each of the demographic categories identified in subsection (a)(1) of this section. The report shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The students suspended for at least one and no more than 5 days;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The students suspended for at least 6 and no more than 10 days;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The students suspended for more than 10 days total;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The students who received more than one suspension in a school year;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The students who were referred to an alternative educational setting for the course of a suspension;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A description of the types of actions that led to the suspension or expulsion;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The students expelled; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The students who voluntarily or involuntarily transferred or withdrew from the school during the school year.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each local education agency or entity operating a publicly funded community-based organization shall provide the requested data in subsection (b) of this section in a form and manner prescribed by the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>By October 1 of each year, beginning in 2016, the Office of the State Superintendent of Education shall publicly report on the suspensions and expulsions that were imposed in local education agencies and publicly funded community-based organizations during the preceding school year, including a relevant trend analysis.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Community-based organization” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite root="38-271.01">38-271.01</cite>(1A).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Local education agency” means the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual public charter school or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-17">September 19, 2013, D.C. Law 20-17, § 202</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-12">as added June 23, 2015, D.C. Law 21-12, § 3, 62 DCR 5942</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
