<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2601.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Child with a disability” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 602(3) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, approved April 13, 1970, (84 Stat. 175; 20 U.S.C. § 1401(3)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>“CTE grant program” is the supplemental career and technical education grant program established by § <cite root="38-2611">38-2611</cite> that provides grants to DCPS and public charter schools to support and enhance their career and technical education programs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <text>“DCPS” means the District of Columbia Public Schools established by § <cite root="38-171">38-171</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1C)</num>
    <text>“Districtwide assessments” has the same meaning as provided in § <cite root="38-1800.02">38-1800.02</cite>(13).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Field test” means a test used during the test-development process to assess the quality and appropriateness of test items, administration procedures, scoring, and reporting.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>“Formula” shall have the meaning as provided in § <cite root="38-2901">38-2901</cite>(8).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2B)</num>
    <text>“Fund” means the CTE Grant Program Fund established by § <cite root="38-2612">38-2612</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2C)</num>
    <text>“IDEA “ means the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, approved April 13, 1970 (84 Stat. 175; 20 U.S.C. § 1400 et seq. ), and its implementing regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2D)</num>
    <text>Individualized education program” or “IEP” means a written plan that specifies the special education programs and services to be provided to meet the unique educational needs of a child with a disability, as required under section 614(d) of IDEA (20 U.S.C. § 1414(d)).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Local education agency” or “LEA” means an educational institution at the local level that exists primarily to operate a publicly funded school or schools in the District of Columbia, including the District of Columbia Public Schools and a District of Columbia public charter school.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“OSSE” means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education established by § <cite root="38-2601">38-2601</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Practice test” means any test or other evaluation that has as its primary purpose the simulation of a Districtwide assessment or other test or evaluation as administered by an LEA rather than for assessing student proficiency levels or informing instruction and remediation needs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“State Superintendent” means the head of OSSE appointed by the Mayor pursuant to § <cite root="38-2601">38-2601</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-176">Oct. 21, 2000, D.C. Law 13-176, § 2b</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-84">as added Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-84, § 102(b), 61 DCR 178</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-87">Feb. 22, 2014, D.C. Law 20-87, § 2(a), 61 DCR 309</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-195">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-195, § 102(a), 61 DCR 12419</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-84">D.C. Law 20-84</cite> added this section.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-87">D.C. Law 20-87</cite> redesignated (1) as (1B); and added (1), (1A), (2A) and (2B).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-195">D.C. Law 20-195</cite> redesignated (1) through (1B) as (1A) through (1C); added (1); and added (2C) and (2D).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
