<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-271.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Child-occupied facility” means a building, or portion of a building, which, as part of its function, receives children under 6 years of age on a regular basis and is required to obtain a certificate of occupancy as a precondition to performing that function. The term “child- occupied facility” includes a daycare center, nursery, preschool center, kindergarten classroom, child development center, child development home, child development facility, child-placing agency, infant care center, or similar entity. The location of a child-occupied facility as part of a larger structure does not make the entire structure a child-occupied facility. Only the portion of the facility occupied or regularly visited by children under 6 years of age shall be considered the child-occupied facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>“Community-based organization” or “CBO” means a Head Start or early childhood education program operated by a nonprofit entity, faith-based organization, or other entity that participates in federally funded early childhood programs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <text>“Coordinating Council” means the State Early Childhood Development Coordinating Council establish pursuant to § <cite root="38-271.07">38-271.07</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1C)</num>
    <text>“DC Collaborative” means the collaborative of District of Columbia colleges and universities established pursuant to § <cite root="38-274.01">38-274.01</cite>(a)(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1D)</num>
    <text>“Elementary and secondary education” means education from and including pre-k through the end of high school or their equivalent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>“HEIG fund” means the Higher Education Incentive Grant Fund established by § <cite root="38-274.03">38-274.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“HEI program” means the Higher Education Incentive grant program established pursuant to § <cite root="38-274.01">38-274.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3A)</num>
    <text>“HEI scholarship program” means the scholarship program established pursuant to §§ <cite root="38-274.01">38-274.01</cite> and <cite root="38-274.02">38-274.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“HQ standards” means high-quality content standards and program requirements for pre-k programs established by the OSSE pursuant to § <cite root="38-272.01">38-272.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“OSSE” means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, established by Chapter 26 of this title [§ <cite root="38-2601">38-2601</cite> et seq.].</text>
    <text>
      <em>et seq.</em>
    </text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5A)</num>
    <text>“Out-of-school suspension” means the removal of a student from school attendance for an entire school day or longer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Pre-k” means the educational gradation available to children of pre-kindergarten age for the 2 years prior to their eligibility for enrollment in kindergarten.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Pre-k age” means children 3 or 4 years of age, and children who become 5 years of age after September 30th of the upcoming school year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Pre-k-education services” means the District-wide educational services provided to the publicly funded CBOs, District of Columbia Public Schools, and Public Charter Schools who provide pre-k care and education services to pre-k age children.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Pre-k program” means a classroom or a group of classrooms serving pre-k children. A single organization or entity may operate multiple pre-k programs in different locations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Professional development” means a data-driven, continuous improvement process that provides a range of formal and informal experiences designed for teaching and administrative staff to increase their knowledge and understanding of research-based, developmentally appropriate content and teaching strategies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“School readiness” means a child’s mastery of approved early-learning standards in the domains of language and literacy, mathematical thinking, social and emotional development, scientific inquiry, social studies, approaches to learning, and health.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11A)</num>
    <text>“Serious bodily injury” means bodily injury that involves a substantial risk of death, unconsciousness, extreme physical pain, protracted and obvious disfigurement, or protracted loss or impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Technical assistance” means the human and technological resources that support the establishment of age-appropriate classroom environments, provide strategies that develop children’s early language and literacy development and mathematical thinking, aid in the mastery of early-learning standards, and develop appropriate instructional strategies for children with disabilities and for children whose first language is not English.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Workforce development” means a range of educational and training experiences that support and increase the capacity of individuals to enter and remain a part of the early-care and education-labor market.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-202">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-202, § 101, 55 DCR 6297</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-285">Mar. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-285, § 2(a), 57 DCR 11005</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9061(a), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-262">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 303(a), 60 DCR 1300</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-12">June 23, 2015, D.C. Law 21-12, § 2(a), 62 DCR 5942</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="2-1595">2-1595</cite>, § <cite root="7-2031">7-2031</cite>, § <cite root="38-1802.14">38-1802.14</cite>, and § <cite root="38-2602">38-2602</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-285">D.C. Law 18-285</cite> rewrote pars. (1) and (3); and added pars. (1A), (1B), (1C), (2A), and (3A).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> repealed par. (2), which formerly read:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2) ‘Fund’ means the Pre-k Program Assistance Grant Fund established by § <cite root="38-272.04">38-272.04</cite>.”</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-262">D.C. Law 19-262</cite> added (1); and redesignated former (1), (1A), (1B), and (1C) as present (1A), (1B), (1C), and (1D), respectively.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-12">D.C. Law 21-12</cite> added (5A) and (11A).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-142">D.C. Law 18-142</cite> rewrote par. (1) to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(1) ‘Community-based organization’ or ‘CBO’ means a Head Start or early childhood education program operated by a nonprofit entity, faith-based organization, or organization that participates in federally funded or District-funded early childhood programs, including the child care subsidy program funded by the federal Child Care and Development Fund.”; in par. (3), substituted “pursuant to” for “by”; and added pars. (2A) and (3A) to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2A) ‘HEIG fund’ means the Higher Education Incentive Grant Fund established by section 403.”.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(3A) ‘HEI scholarship program’ means the scholarship program established pursuant to sections 401 and 402.”.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 5(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-142">D.C. Law 18-142</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Pre-K Acceleration and Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-304, January 28, 2010,  57 DCR 1475).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Pre-k Acceleration and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-602, December 1, 2010,  57 DCR 11039).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Pre-k Acceleration and Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 19-4, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1399).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 7101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> repealed section 701 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-202">D.C. Law 17-202</cite>.</text>
      <text>Establishment—District of Columbia Early Childhood Advisory Council, see Mayor’s Order 2010-68, May 21, 2010 ( 57 DCR 4460).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
