<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-2803</num>
  <heading>Multiyear Facilities Master Plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning on December 15, 2012 and every 5 years thereafter, the Mayor shall prepare and submit to the Council for its review and approval a comprehensive 5-year Master Facilities Plan for public education facilities, along with a proposed resolution, in accordance with this section. The Council shall vote on the 5-year Master Facilities Plan concurrently with its vote on the Mayor’s capital budget proposal. If approved by the Council, the 5-year Master Facilities Plan shall take effect on the first day of the succeeding fiscal year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Council shall conduct at least one public hearing on the proposed 5-year Master Facilities Plan before approval.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If, subsequent to Council approval of the 5-year Master Facilities Plan, material changes to the plan become necessary, the Mayor may modify the plan; provided, that any modification shall be submitted to the Council for review and approval along with the Mayor’s annual submission of a capital budget recommendation for public schools.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall establish an Office of Public Education Facilities Planning (“OPEFP”) within the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Education responsible for the development of the Master Facilities Plan, which shall function as a citywide public education facilities plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(1A)</num>
      <text>Repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The OPEFP shall include in the Master Facilities Plan detailed, current analyses and data on:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The facilities condition assessment for each school building and facility under the control and jurisdiction of the District of Columbia Public Schools;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The capacity of existing schools, current level of utilization, projected 5-year facility needs for each local education agency, and recommendations for the utilization or reduction of excess space, including, as appropriate, specific recommendations on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Consolidation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Closure; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Co-location;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Historical and projected enrollment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Current and projected demographic information for the surrounding neighborhood;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Other neighborhood issues, in coordination with the Office of Planning;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>A school-by-school description relating facility needs and requirements to:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The facility’s programmatic usage with specific linkages and relationships to adopted education plans of a local education agency, school district, or institution, including specific plans for special education, early childhood education, and career and technical education programs; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The statewide education and youth development plan described in § <cite path="§38-191">38-191</cite>, and how it enables schools to be centers of the community;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>A detailed facility portfolio analysis that will inform any decisions related to alternative financing options, including public/private development partnerships and co-location opportunities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>A communications and community involvement plan for each school that includes engagement of key stakeholders throughout the community, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Local school restructuring teams;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>School improvement teams; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Advisory Neighborhood Commissions;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>The coordination of the District’s education sector with housing, health, and welfare sectors, and with economic development policies and plans;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>The location, planning, use, and design of the District’s educational facilities and campuses;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Any school disposition, including a plan delineating the process through which citizen involvement shall be facilitated, and establishing the criteria that will be utilized in disposition decisions, one of which shall be consideration of the impact of any proposed new use of a school building on the neighborhood in which the school building is located; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>A safety and security assessment of educational facilities based upon a comprehensive examination of the facility's physical environment for crime vulnerabilities, including an analysis of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Surveillance capabilities, both active and passive;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Access control, including the ability to securely manage who enters and exits the facility; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Facility maintenance.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2A)</num>
      <text>Beginning on December 15, 2014, and every year thereafter, the OPEFP shall prepare and make publicly available an annual supplement to the Master Facilities Plan that includes:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Results of the Department of General Services annual survey as set forth in paragraph (3)(E) of this subsection;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Updated information on:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Enrollment projections at the local education agency level and the individual school level for both DCPS and public charter schools; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Facility needs for each local education agency;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A plan, including co-location options, to increase utilization at any school facility in use by DCPS with a utilization rate of less than 50%;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A plan to ensure that each school facility in use by DCPS that is at 95% utilization or above does not suffer from overcrowding but can sufficiently meet the facility and academic needs of it students; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Each school facility's designation as one or more of the following:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>In use primarily for classroom instruction;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>In use primarily for swing space;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>In use primarily for DCPS administrative purposes, including storage;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>In use by an entity other than DCPS;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Vacant; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>Significantly underused.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The following agencies shall work with the OPEFP in the development of the Master Facilities Plan and the annual supplement:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The District of Columbia Public Schools, which shall transmit to the OPEFP:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Educational plans and policies it considers relevant to the facilities planning process;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Educational specifications for each facility subject to modernization;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Its 5-year enrollment projections; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Its 5-year projections of facility needs;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Public Charter School Board, which shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Collect and transmit to the OPEFP educational plans and policies of individual public charter schools, 5-year enrollment growth plans, data on existing public charter school facilities and facilities-related needs, and other information considered relevant to the planning process; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Establish a Public Charter School facilities registry in which individual public charter schools will have the opportunity to register to receive facilities planning and technical support from the OPEFP, including the analyses and data compiled pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The Office of Planning, which shall provide demographic and neighborhood data support;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization, which shall implement the Master Facilities Plan consistent with the policy priorities set forth in this chapter; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The Department of General Services, which shall conduct an annual survey to update information on the enrollment, utilization, and condition of each DCPS and charter school facility, including a review of whether or not the facility has a working carbon monoxide detector, and transmit the results to OPEFP.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Of the fiscal year 2011 capital funds appropriated to the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization, it shall transfer:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Up to $500,000 to the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Education to support capital planning pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of this section; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An amount of $100,000 to the District of Columbia Public Schools and $100,000 to the Public Charter School Board to support capital planning activities as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In developing the Facilities Master Plan, the Mayor shall consider the facilities needs of all public school students and shall consult with:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Public Charter School Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Representatives of public charter schools; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Key stakeholders throughout the community.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning in fiscal year 2010, a Public School Facility capital improvement plan (“School Facility CIP”) shall be updated each fiscal year as part of the Mayor’s capital improvement plan for all public facilities, as required by § <cite path="§1-204.44">1-204.44</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The School Facility CIP shall include for each school and other education facilities of DCPS and public charter schools, the following information:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A description of the scope of work to be done and schedule of major milestones;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Justification for the work pursuant to the Master Facilities Plan;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A full-funded cost estimate of improvements planned for the next fiscal year and the succeeding 5 fiscal years;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>The estimated cost of operating the improved facility, whether the new cost is more or less than the previous School Facility CIP estimate;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>The amount of capital funds expended in the prior fiscal year; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(vi)</num>
          <text>The name, address, and ward of each project.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Each School facility CIP shall:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Meet the requirements listed in subsection (b) of this section;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Give due consideration to the record established by the testimony, and any exhibits, during the hearing required by paragraph (3) of this subsection; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Be consistent with the policy of broad public participation, as stated in this section.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>No more than 60 days or less than 30 days prior to the Mayor’s submission of a School Facility CIP to the Council, and upon 15 days public notice, the Mayor shall conduct a public hearing to solicit the views of the public. In no event shall the hearing be prior to the annual submission by the Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization of its proposed budget to the Mayor.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor shall transmit the record of the hearing to the Council at or before the public hearing on the annually submitted proposed budget for Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Within 30 days of the release of the annual supplement to the Master Facilities Plan as required by subsection (b)(2A) of this section, the District shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Determine which school facilities will be designated as excess; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Make a list of these properties, and those deemed excess pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, publicly available on its website.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Unless written justification is made publicly available at the time of the publication of the list as required in paragraph (1) of this subsection based on projected operational needs of DCPS or another District agency, a school facility shall be automatically deemed excess if it has been designated in the annual supplement to the Master Facilities Plan as:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Vacant; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Significantly underused for 2 consecutive years.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175" type="History" path="§1104">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1104, 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 4047, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-123" type="History">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-123, § 221, 53 DCR 2843</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-9" type="History">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-9, § 1009, 54 DCR 4102</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 4071, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 4122, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4012, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-114" type="History">June 21, 2014, D.C. Law 20-114, § 3(b), 61 DCR 4669</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-271" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-271, § 316, 62 DCR 1884</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-325.44">1-325.44</cite> and § <cite path="§38-1805.52">38-1805.52</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-153.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> substituted “June 30, 2006” for “December 31, 1998”; and deleted “There shall be a moratorium on disposition decisions until the facilities plan has been approved by the Council.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-123">D.C. Law 16-123</cite>, designated the existing text as subsec. (a); in subsec. (a), substituted “multiyear Facilities Master Plan, which shall include” for “Long Range Master Facilities Plan which shall include annual updates to the facilities plan, as well as”; and added subsecs. (b), (c), and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-9">D.C. Law 17-9</cite> rewrote subsecs. (a), (b)(1), (c), and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> rewrote subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> rewrote (a); added (b)(1A) and (b)(2)(K); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-114">D.C. Law 20-114</cite> repealed (b)(1)(A); added “projected 5-year facility needs for each local education agency” in (b)(2)(B); made minor stylistic changes in (b)(2)(J) and (b)(2)(K); and added (b)(2)(L) and (b)(2A); added “and the annual supplement” in the introductory language of (b)(3); rewrote (b)(3)(A); in (b)(3)(B)(i), substituted “Collect and transmit” for “Transmit” and added “5-year enrollment growth plans”; made minor stylistic changes in (b)(3)(C) and (b)(3)(D); and added (b)(3)(E) and (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-271">D.C. Law 20-271</cite> repealed (c)(5) and made a related change.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of subchapter see notes to § <cite path="§38-2801">38-2801</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of Chapter 1B 1981 Ed., see notes following § 38-2801.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4047 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4011 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4071 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4071 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4112 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4122 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) approval of the 2013 Master Facilities Plan for public education facilities, see § 4082 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) approval of the 2013 Master Facilities Plan for public education facilities, see § 4082 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  316 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-481, November 18, 2014, 61 DCR 12133, 20 STAT 4405).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 316 of the New Columbia Statehood Initiative, Omnibus Boards and Commissions, and Election Transition Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-7, Feb. 26, 2015,  62 DCR 2646, 21 STAT 807).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4070 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle H of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Master Facilities Plan and School Facility Capital Improvement Plan Reconciliation Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle L of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Master Facilities Plan Approval Act of 2010”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4121 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle M of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Office of Public Education Facilities Planning Establishment Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 4081 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle H of Title IV of the act may be cited as the “Public Education Master Facilities Plan Approval Act of 2013”.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4112 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“Sec. 4112. (a) Pursuant to section 1104 of the School Based Budgeting and Accountability Act of 1998, approved March 26, 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-175">D.C. Law 12-175</cite>; D. C. Official Code § <cite path="§38-2803">38-2803</cite>), the following components of the Master Facilities Plan for the District of Columbia Public Schools for 2010, as submitted by the Mayor to the Council, on April 1, 2010 (‘2010 MFP’) are approved:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(1) All priorities, objectives, and methods of defining modernization, including the phased approach to elementary and middle schools;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(2) Demographics and Data;</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(3) Plan Detail Narrative, including school-by-school detail, known as Mini-Master Plans; and</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(4) The glossary of terms.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The Schedule of modernization, including sequencing and project implementation timelines and the budget, including the 8-Year Master Facilities Plan Financial Projection and Scope of Work and Estimated Methodology in the 2010 MFP shall be adjusted pursuant to the Capital Improvement Plan Amendments for Public Education Facilities Act of 2010, passed on 2nd reading on June 15, 2010 (Enrolled version of Bill 18-731), and resubmitted by October 15, 2010, to the Council for review and approval.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4082 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that the Council approves the 2013 Master Facilities Plan for public education facilities submitted by the Mayor on March 28, 2013.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
