<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2021.17</num>
  <heading>Funds not assignable or subject to execution.</heading>
  <text>Except as provided in subchapter VI of Chapter 5 of Title 1 (§ <cite path="§1-529.01">1-529.01</cite> et seq.), none of the money mentioned in this part, including any assets of the District of Columbia Teachers’ Retirement Fund established by § <cite path="§1-713">1-713</cite>(a), shall be assignable, either in law or equity, or be subject to execution or levy by attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, except with respect to a domestic relations order that substantially meets all of the requirements of section 414(p) of the Internal Revenue Code  , as determined solely by the District of Columbia Retirement Board.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 7, 1946, 60 Stat. 882, ch. 779, § 17</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 96-122">Nov. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 866, Pub. L. 96-122, § 123(b)(1)(F)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-214">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-214, § 5, 36 DCR 513</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-312">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-312, § 2(k), 60 DCR 3434</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-1238.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 31-737.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-312">D.C. Law 19-312</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2(k) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-313">D.C. Law 19-313</cite> amended this section to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Except as provided in the District of Columbia Spouse Equity Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 7-214">D.C. Law 7-214</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§1-529.01">1-529.01</cite> et seq.), none of the money mentioned in this act, including any assets of the District of Columbia Teachers’ Retirement Fund established by section 123(a) of the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C Official Code § <cite path="§1-713">1-713</cite>(a)), shall be assignable, either in law or equity, or be subject to execution or levy by attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, except with respect to a domestic relations order that substantially meets all of the requirements of  section 414(p) of the Internal Revenue Code, as determined solely by the District of Columbia Retirement Board.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-313">D.C. Law 19-313</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(j) of the Retirement of Public-School Teachers Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-584, January 1, 2013,  60 DCR 134).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(k) of the Retirement of Public-School Teachers Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-41, March 25, 2013,  60 DCR 5361, 20 DCSTAT 527).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>The “District of Columbia Spouse Equity Act of 1988” is <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-214">D.C. Law 7-214</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
