<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2021.18</num>
  <heading>Applicability.</heading>
  <text>The provisions of this part shall constitute a defined benefit plan and a governmental plan, as described in section 414(d) of the Internal Revenue Code  , which is intended to qualify under section 401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code  . Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in this part, Chapter 7 of Title 1 (§ <cite root="1-701">1-701</cite> et seq.), or Chapter 9 of Title 1 (§ <cite root="1-901.01">1-901.01</cite> et seq.), the provisions of this part shall apply to and control the provision of any annuity payable. The provisions of this part shall apply to all teachers on the rolls of the public schools of the District who accrue service after June 30, 1997, under the Teachers’ Retirement Program established pursuant to Chapter 9 of Title 1 (§ <cite root="1-901.01">1-901.01</cite> et seq.), if otherwise eligible.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Aug. 7, 1946, 60 Stat. 882, ch. 779, § 18</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-312">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-312, § 2(l), 60 DCR 3434</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 31-1239.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 31-738.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-312">D.C. Law 19-312</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2(l) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-313">D.C. Law 19-313</cite> amended this section to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Applicability.</annotation>
      <annotation>“The provisions of this act and the associated acts shall constitute a defined benefit plan and a governmental plan, as described in  section 414(d) of the Internal Revenue Code, which is intended to qualify under  section 401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained in this act, the District of Columbia Retirement Reform Act, approved November 17, 1979 (93 Stat. 866; D.C. Official Code § <cite root="1-701">1-701</cite> et seq.), or the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Act of 1998, effective September 18, 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-152">D.C. Law 12-152</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite root="1-901.01">1-901.01</cite> et seq.), the provisions of this act shall apply to and control the provision of any annuity payable. The provisions of this act shall apply to all teachers on the rolls of the public schools of the District who accrue service after June 30, 1997, under the Teachers’ Retirement Program established pursuant to the Police Officers, Fire Fighters, and Teachers Retirement Benefit Replacement Plan Act of 1998, effective September 18, 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-152">D.C. Law 12-152</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite root="1-901.01">1-901.01</cite> et seq.), if otherwise eligible.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-313">D.C. Law 19-313</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(k) of the Retirement of Public-School Teachers Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-584, January 1, 2013,  60 DCR 134).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(l) of the Retirement of Public-School Teachers Omnibus Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-41, March 25, 2013,  60 DCR 5361, 20 DCSTAT 527).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
