<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-2609</num>
  <heading>Development of the educational data warehouse system.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The OSSE, in coordination with the Office of the Chief Technology Officer, shall develop and implement a longitudinal educational data warehouse system (“EDW system”) to be used by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The OSSE;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The University of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Public schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Public charter schools;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Publicly funded educational programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Policymakers;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Institutions of higher education; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Researchers.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The EDW system shall be used to compile, analyze, research, and organize student, teacher, and school-level data to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Facilitate compliance with District of Columbia and federal reporting requirements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Aid in local and state-level policymaking and programming; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Improve information exchanges, while maintaining the confidentiality of individual student and staff data, in accordance with District of Columbia and federal confidentiality laws, rules, and regulations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The EDW system shall be designed to allow for compatibility with other data systems that currently exist or that are in development in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Upon the request of the State Superintendent, necessary data pertaining to students, teachers, and school levels shall be submitted to the OSSE for the purpose of constructing, updating, or maintaining the EDW system by:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The University of the District of Columbia;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A public school;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A public charter school; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>An entity administering a publicly funded educational program.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The requested data shall be submitted within a reasonable time, as determined by the OSSE, following a request, and in a standardized format to be established by the OSSE.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All providers of public education in the District of Columbia shall participate in the EDW system, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The University of the District of Columbia;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Public schools;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Public charter schools; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Entities operating publicly funded educational programs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The OSSE shall ensure that technical assistance and training is provided to the staff participating in the EDW system.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The OSSE shall ensure that a unique identifier is assigned to every student and teacher in a:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Public school;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Public charter school; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A publicly funded educational program.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The OSSE shall ensure that a unique identifier is assigned to every student of the University of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A unique identifier shall be assigned to a student the first time that the student receives educational services from a provider of public education in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-176" type="History">Oct. 21, 2000, D.C. Law 13-176, § 7c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20" type="History">as added Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 4012(b), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4012(b) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
