<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-306</num>
  <heading>Proof of residency.</heading>
  <text>All students enrolled in District of Columbia public schools and public charter schools funded by the District of Columbia or a student for whom educational services are paid by the District of Columbia shall provide proof of residency in the District or pay tuition pursuant to § <cite path="§38-302">38-302</cite>. A determination of residency status shall be made annually for each such student. The methods used to determine residency status shall be consistent across District of Columbia public schools and public charter schools and shall be crafted to facilitate rather than hinder school enrollment of eligible students.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-725" type="History">Sept. 8, 1960, 74 Stat. 854, Pub. L. 86-725, § 9</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">as added Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 4012(c), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219" type="History">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 4012(a), 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</law-cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “All students enrolled in District of Columbia public schools and public charter schools must provide proof of residency in the District or pay tuition pursuant to § <cite path="§38-302">38-302</cite>. A determination of residency status shall be made annually for each student. The methods used to determine residency status shall be consistent across District of Columbia public schools and public charter schools and shall be crafted to facilitate rather than hinder school enrollment of eligible students.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4012(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4012(c) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 4011 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</law-cite> provided that subtitle F of title IV of the act may be cited as the “Residency Verification Amendment Act of 2008”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Former § <cite path="§38-306">38-306</cite> has been recodified as § <cite path="§38-305">38-305</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
