<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-401.01</num>
  <heading>Annual report.</heading>
  <text>The Board of Education shall submit to the Mayor of the District of Columbia and the Council of the District of Columbia, not later than January 15th of each year, a report covering all activities with respect to public school buildings and grounds that were undertaken during the preceding fiscal year pursuant to the authority granted by this section and §§ <cite path="§38-401">38-401</cite> and <cite path="§38-401.02">38-401.02</cite>.  Such report shall include, but shall not be limited to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>All lease, use, or other agreements exceeding a period of 30 days, indicating the name of the tenant and the terms and conditions of the agreement;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>An itemization of all collections and expenditures associated with each agreement;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>A statement of the actual amount of funds transferred by the Board of Education towards the repayment of capital outlay loans and interest outstanding;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>A statement of the actual condition of major structural components of each property under an agreement, and any repairs or improvements made thereto;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>A list, including each parcel, of real property transferred by the Board of Education to the Department of General Services and the date of each transfer; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>A statement by the Board of Education of benefits and enhancements to the  educational environment and the community resulting from the authority granted  by this section and §§ <cite path="§38-401">38-401</cite> and <cite path="§38-401.02">38-401.02</cite>, and recommendations, if any, for  the improvement thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-158" type="History">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-158, § 3, 29 DCR 3632</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-401">38-401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 31-201.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Department of General Services were transferred, in part, to the Department of Public Works by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984, and transferred, in part, to the Department of Administrative Services by Reorganization Plan No. 5 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
