<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-651.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Emergency circumstances” means reasonably apparent circumstances that indicate that any delay in treatment would endanger the health or life of the student.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Medication” means any prescription or non-prescription drug used to treat conditions and illnesses covered by this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Medication action plan” means a written medical treatment plan for an individual student that is developed and submitted to a school in accordance with § <cite path="§38-651.03">38-651.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3A)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3B)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Responsible person” means, in the case of a student under 18 years of age, a parent, legal guardian, legal custodian, foster parent, or other adult charged with the ongoing care and supervision of the student, and, in the case of a student 18 years of age or older, the student himself or herself.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“School” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any public school operated under the authority of the Mayor of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any charter school, parochial school, or private school in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-107" type="History">Feb. 2, 2008, D.C. Law 17-107, § 2, 54 DCR 12230</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-77" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-77, § 2(a), 63 DCR 756</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</law-cite> would have added (3A), (3B), (6), and (7).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of Law 17-52 added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Medication action plan’ means a written medical treatment plan for an individual student with prescription medication that is developed and submitted to a school in accordance with section 4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Responsible person’ means, in the case of a student under 18 years of age, a parent, legal guardian, legal custodian, foster parent, or other adult charged with the ongoing care and supervision of the student, and in the case of a student 18 years of age or older, the student himself or herself.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) ‘School’ means:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) Any public school operated under the authority of the Mayor of the District of Columbia; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Any charter school, parochial school, or private school in the District.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-52">D.C. Law 17-52</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Student Access to Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-82, July 26,</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</law-cite>: Section 4 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</law-cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusions of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
