<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-651.09</num>
  <heading>Storage of medication.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A school may procure medication for the treatment of asthma, anaphylaxis, or other illness for use in emergency circumstances. The medication shall be properly stored and maintained in an easily accessible location.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A school may receive medication to store for the treatment of asthma, anaphylaxis, or other illness from the responsible person for a student with a valid medication action plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The medication shall be:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Properly stored at the school in a location to which the student has immediate access in case of an emergency; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Labeled with the:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Name of the student;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Name of the medication;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Dosage;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Time of administration; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(v)</num>
          <text>Duration of medication.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>No school shall be required to store more than a 3-school-day supply of medication for any one student.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-107" type="History" path="§10">Feb. 2, 2008, D.C. Law 17-107, § 10, 54 DCR 12230</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-77" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-77, § 2(e), 63 DCR 756</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite>, in (a), would have added "Except as provided in § <cite path="§38-0651.04a">38-0651.04a</cite>” and would have deleted “anaphylaxis” following “asthma.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 6 of Law 17-52 added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 6. Storage of medication.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) A school may receive additional medication from the responsible person for a student with a valid medication action plan; provided, that no school shall be required to store more than a 30-school-day supply of medication for any one student.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Additional medication shall be:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Properly stored at the school in a location to which the student has immediate access in case of an emergency; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Labeled with the name of the student and the name of the medication, including the dosage, the frequency of administration, and the duration of the medication.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-52">D.C. Law 17-52</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6 of Student Access to Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-82, July 26, 2007,  54 DCR 7999).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6 of Student Access to Treatment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-140, October 17, 2007,  54 DCR 10736).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusions of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
