<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-651.03</num>
  <heading>Medication action plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A valid medication action plan shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Written medical authorization, signed by a licensed health practitioner, that states:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name of the student;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Emergency contact information for the responsible person;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Contact information for the licensed health practitioner;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>The name, purpose, and prescribed dosage of the medication;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The frequency that the medication is to be administered;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The possible side effects of the medication as listed on the label;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Special instructions or emergency procedures; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>In the case of self-administered medication, confirmation that the student has been instructed in the proper technique for self-administration of the medication and has demonstrated the ability to self-administer the medication effectively.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Written authorization, signed by the responsible person, that states:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A trained employee or agent of the school may administer medication to the student in accordance with rules established by the Mayor; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In the case of self-administration, the student may possess and self-administer the medication at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, and while on school-sponsored transportation; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The name of the student may be distributed to appropriate school staff, as determined by the principal; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Written acknowledgment that the District, a school, or an employee or agent of a school shall be immune from civil liability for the good-faith performance of responsibilities under this subchapter; except, that no immunity shall extend to criminal acts, intentional wrongdoing, gross negligence, or wanton or willful misconduct.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Immediately following any changes regarding the health or treatment of the student, the responsible person shall submit to the school an amended medication action plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The medication action plan shall be updated at least annually, in accordance with a schedule determined by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-107" type="History" path="§4">Feb. 2, 2008, D.C. Law 17-107, § 4, 54 DCR 12230</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-77" type="History">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-77, § 2(b), 63 DCR 756</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-651.01">38-651.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite> would have added “or, if the student is 18 years of age or older, another adult suitable to serve as an emergency contact” in (a)(1)(B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4 of Law 17-52 added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 4. Medication action plan.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) No student shall possess or self-administer medication at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, or while on school-sponsored transportation, unless the school has a valid medication action plan for that student.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) A valid medication action plan shall include:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Written medical authorization, signed by the student’s health practitioner, that states:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The name of the student;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) Emergency contact information for the responsible person;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) Contact information for the health practitioner;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) The name, purpose, and prescribed dosage of the medication;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) The frequency that the medication is to be administered;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) The possible side effects of the medication;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(G) Special instructions or emergency procedures; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(H) In the case of self-administered medication, confirmation that the student has been instructed in the proper technique for self-administration of the medication and has demonstrated the ability to self-administer the medication effectively;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Written authorization, signed by the responsible person, that states:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) A trained school employee may administer medication to the student in accordance with rules established by the Mayor; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) In the case of self-administration, the student may possess and self-administer the medication at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, and while on school-sponsored transportation; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Written acknowledgment that the school and its employees shall incur no liability and that the responsible person shall indemnify and hold harmless the school and its employees against any claims that may arise relating to the administration, general supervision, training, administration, or self-administration of the authorized medication.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Within 30 days of any changes in the student’s health that affect the medication action plan, the responsible person shall revise the medication action plan and submit the amended plan to the school.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The medication action plan shall be updated at least annually, in accordance with a schedule determined by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) A school may deny a medication action plan, pursuant to terms established by the Mayor.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-52">D.C. Law 17-52</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Student Access to Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-82, July 26,</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusions of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
