<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-651.10</num>
  <heading>Misuse.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A school may deny a medication action plan pursuant to terms established by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A student who self-administers medication while at school, at a school-sponsored activity, or while on school-sponsored transportation for a purpose other than his or her own treatment may be subject to disciplinary action by the school; provided, that disciplinary action shall not limit or restrict the access of a student to his or her prescribed medication. The school shall promptly notify the responsible person of any disciplinary action imposed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-107" type="History">Feb. 2, 2008, D.C. Law 17-107, § 11, 54 DCR 12230</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 7 of Law 17-52 added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 7. Misuse.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“A student who self-administers medication while at school, at a school-sponsored activity, or while on school-sponsored transportation for a purpose other than his or her own authorized treatment may be subject to disciplinary action by the school; provided, that disciplinary action shall not limit or restrict the access of a student to his or her prescribed medication. The school shall promptly notify the responsible person of any disciplinary action imposed.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 11(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-52">D.C. Law 17-52</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7 of Student Access to Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-82, July 26, 2007,  54 DCR 7999).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 7 of Student Access to Treatment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-140, October 17, 2007,  54 DCR 10736).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
