<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-752.03</num>
  <heading>Post-secondary preparation plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Beginning with the graduating class of 2014, the Mayor shall ensure that each public high school student applies to at least one post-secondary institution before graduation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall ensure that each public high school student participates in a program designed to provide students with information on applying to an appropriate post-secondary institution, including information on financial aid and other resources necessary to streamline a transition to a post-secondary institution. The program may include school-based and non-school-based resources.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue a report that details the number of students that attend a post-secondary institution, including the number of students who attend each type, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Universities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Colleges;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Vocational schools; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Other post-secondary institutions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning with the graduating class of 2014, the Mayor shall require that each student attending public high school takes the SAT or the American College Testing program before graduation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may exempt a student from the requirements of subsections (a)(1) and (c) of this section, if the Mayor determines that it would constitute an undue hardship on the student.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-142" type="History">June 19, 2012, D.C. Law 19-142, ยง 203, 59 DCR 3642</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
