<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-771.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Authorized personnel” means an individual who has access to Districtwide assessment materials or is directly involved in the administration of a Districtwide assessment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Districtwide assessments” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§38-1800.02">38-1800.02</cite>(13); provided, that for the purposes of this chapter, the term “Districtwide assessment” means assessments used only for accountability purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“IEP” means a student’s individualized education program.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“ELL” means English language learner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Local education agency” or “LEA” means the District of Columbia Public Schools system or any individual or group of public charter schools operating under a single charter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Test monitor” means an individual designated by a local education agency to be responsible for testing integrity and security at each individual school subject to the LEA’s control during the administration of a Districtwide assessment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“OSSE” means the Office of the State Superintendent of Education.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Test integrity coordinator” means an individual designated by a LEA to be responsible for testing integrity and security for the LEA in its entirety during the administration of a Districtwide assessment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Testing integrity and security notification statement” means a statement developed by OSSE that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Sets forth requirements for ensuring integrity of Districtwide assessments pursuant to District law and regulation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Notifies the recipient that knowingly and willingly violating a District law, regulation, or test security plan could result in civil liability, including the loss of an OSSE-granted certification or license.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-27">Oct. 17, 2013, D.C. Law 20-27, § 101, 60 DCR 11120</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-44">Jan. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-44, § 2(a), 62 DCR 14236</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-2602">38-2602</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-44">D.C. Law 21-44</cite> added “provided, that for the purposes of this act, the term ‘Districtwide assessment’ means assessments used only for accountability purposes” in (2); and rewrote (9).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
