<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-731.04</num>
  <heading>Members of the Financial Literacy Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Financial Literacy Council shall consist of 9 members, as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>One member shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Council.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>One member shall be appointed by the chairperson of the Council committee with oversight of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>One member shall be appointed by the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Six members shall be appointed by the Mayor and shall be comprised of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>One member who shall represent the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>One member who shall represent the District of Columbia Public Schools; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Four members who shall be District residents with extensive knowledge of financial institutions, personal finance, and financial literacy programs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Members shall not be compensated for their service on the Financial Literacy Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Members shall serve for terms of 4 years; provided, that of the initial members appointed:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Members appointed under subsection (a)(4)(C) of this section shall serve initial terms of 2 years; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Members appointed under subsections (a)(1), (a)(2), (a)(3), (a)(4)(A), and (a)(4)(B) of this section shall serve initial terms of 4 years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate one member as the chairperson. The designated member shall serve as chairperson until the conclusion of his or her current term of membership.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-209" type="History" path="ยง5">Aug. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-209, ยง 5, 55 DCR 6979</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
