<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-827.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Healthy Youth and Schools Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Healthy Youth and Schools Commission with the purpose of advising the Mayor and the Council on health, wellness, and nutritional issues concerning youth and schools in the District, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>School meals;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Farm-to-school programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Physical activity and physical education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Health education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Environmental programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>School gardens;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Sexual health programming;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Chronic disease prevention;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Emotional, social, and mental health services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Substance abuse; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Violence prevention.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Specific functions of the Commission shall include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advising on the operations of all District health, wellness, and nutrition programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Reviewing and advising on the best practices in health, wellness, and nutrition programs across the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recommending standards, or revisions to existing standards, concerning the health, wellness, and nutrition of youth and schools in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Advising on the development of an ongoing program of public information and outreach programs on health, wellness, and nutrition;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Making recommendations on enhancing the collaborative relationship between the District government, the federal government, the University of the District of Columbia, local nonprofit organizations, colleges and universities, and the private sector in connection with health, wellness, and nutrition;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Identifying gaps in funding and services, or methods of expanding services to District residents; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Engaging students in improving health, wellness, and nutrition in schools.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>On or before November 30 of each year, the Commission shall submit to the Mayor and the Council a comprehensive report on the health, wellness, and nutrition of youth and schools in the District. The report shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Explain the efforts made within the preceding year to improve the health, wellness, and nutrition of youth and schools in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Discuss the steps that other states have taken to address the health, wellness, and nutrition of youth and schools; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Make recommendations about how to further improve the health, wellness, and nutrition of youth and schools in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§701">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 701, 57 DCR 4779</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4062(n), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-821.01">38-821.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> substituted “November 30” for “September 30” in the first sentence of the introductory language of (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(n) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(n) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4063 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> provided that § 4062 of the act shall apply as of June 20, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
