<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-824.02</num>
  <heading>Physical and health education requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Public schools and public charter schools shall provide physical education as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For students in Kindergarten through Grade 5:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>School years 2010-2011 to 2013-2014: an average of at least 30 minutes per week or the same level of physical education as provided in school year 2009-2010, whichever is greater; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>School year 2014-2015 and after: an average of at least 150 minutes per week;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For students in Grades 6 through 8:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>School years 2010-2011 to 2013-2014: an average of at least 45 minutes per week or the same level of physical education as provided in school year 2009-2010, whichever is greater; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>School year 2014-2015 and after: an average of at least 225 minutes per week.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At least 50% of physical education class time shall be devoted to actual physical activity, with as much class time as possible spent in moderate-to-vigorous physical activity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Public schools and public charter schools shall provide health education to students in Grades Kindergarten through 8 as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>School years 2010-2011 to 2013-2014: an average of at least 15 minutes per week or the same level of health education as provided in school year 2009-2010, whichever is greater; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>School year 2014-2015 and after: an average of at least 75 minutes per week;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The State Board of Education, with assistance from the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, shall consider ways to expand physical education in high schools.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The physical education and health education required by this section shall meet the curricular standards adopted by the State Board of Education.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§402">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 402, 57 DCR 4779</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4062(i) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 4062(i) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-821.02">38-821.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
