<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-825.01</num>
  <heading>Environmental programs office.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An environmental programs office is established in the Department of General Services and shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Contract with vendors to recycle all materials required by District law at all public schools, including food services, by December 31, 2010, and provide technical assistance to public charter schools about recycling.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Develop a master recycling plan for public schools on or before December 31, 2011 to reach a system-wide diversion rate of 45% by August 1, 2015;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Analyze utility usage at each public school and develop a plan to reduce that amount by 20% on or before August 1, 2015;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Establish an integrated pest management program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Test drinking water in public schools for lead and promptly take any remedial action required;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Comply with the Environmental Protection Agency’s Lead; Renovation, Repair, and Painting Program, established by 40 C.F.R. Part 745;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Post the results of its environmental testing online;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Promote the Environmental Protection Agency’s Indoor Air Quality Tools for Schools Program to reduce exposure to environmental factors that impact asthma among children and adults in public schools;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Develop an electronic recycling policy for public schools on or before December 31, 2011; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Establish a composting program in the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The contracts under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection shall be negotiated to provide a financial incentive to reduce the amount of waste created in public schools and, when possible, to increase diversion rates in public schools;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Schools shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Use environmentally friendly cleaning supplies in public schools; provided, that the agency may exhaust its current supply of conventional cleaners; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Prepare and transmit to the Mayor, the Council, and the Healthy Schools and Youth Commission, on or before December 31, 2012, a plan to use sustainable products in serving meals to students.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>On or before December 31, 2012, the Mayor shall prepare and transmit to the Council a comprehensive report describing the implementation of recycling, composting, energy-reduction, pest management, air quality, and environmentally friendly cleaning supplies programs in public schools. The report shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A thorough, school-by-school breakdown of the waste stream in public schools, including tonnages, components, and diversion rates;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Baseline energy usage, an analysis of usage patterns, and savings achieved;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Recommendations and a timeline for further implementing these programs; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A proposal for recognizing and rewarding schools that significantly improve their environmental portfolio.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§501">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 501, 57 DCR 4779</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-37" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-37, § 2(i), 58 DCR 6841</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4062(j), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-37">D.C. Law 19-37</law-cite>, in subsec. (a)(1), substituted “December 31, 2011” for “December 31, 2010” in subpar. (B), deleted “and” from the end of subpar. (G ), substituted “; and” for a period the end of subpar. (H), and added subpar. (I); and, in subsec. (c), substituted “December 31, 2011” for “December 31, 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> substituted “Department of General Services” for “Office of Public Education Facilities Modernization” in the introductory language of (a)(1); added (a)(1)(J); substituted “December 31, 2012” for “December 31, 2010” in (b)(2); substituted “December 31, 2012” for “December 31, 2011” in the first sentence of the introductory language of (c); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Healthy Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-143, August 9, 2011,  58 DCR 6814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(j) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(j) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4063 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> provided that § 4062 of the act shall apply as of June 20, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
