<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>38-822.05</num>
  <heading>Public disclosure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Food service providers shall provide the following information to public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The menu for each breakfast and lunch meal served;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The nutritional content of each menu item;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The ingredients for each menu item if requested by parents and legal guardians; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The location where fruits and vegetables served in schools are grown and processed and whether growers are engaged in sustainable agriculture practices.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools shall provide the information provided to them under subsection (a) of this section:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In the school’s office;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Online, if the school has a website; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>To parents and legal guardians upon request</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools shall inform families that vegetarian food options and milk alternatives are available upon request.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-209" type="History" path="§205">July 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-209, § 205, 57 DCR 4779</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-37" type="History">Oct. 20, 2011, D.C. Law 19-37, § 2(g), 58 DCR 6841</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 4062(e), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§38-821.02">38-821.02</cite> and § <cite path="§38-826.02">38-826.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-37">D.C. Law 19-37</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools” for “public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools”; in subsecs. (b)(1) and (2), substituted “Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools” for “Public schools, public charter schools, and participating private schools”; and added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added “if requested by parents and legal guardians” in (a)(3); substituted “shall provide” for “shall post” in the introductory language of (b)(1); added the comma following “Online” in (b)(1)(B); added (b)(1)(C); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Healthy Schools Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-143, August 9, 2011,  58 DCR 6814).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(e) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 4062(e) of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 4063 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that § 4062 of the act shall apply as of June 20, 2012.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
