<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>38-651.12</num>
  <heading>Rules.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite root="2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may establish, by regulation, additional types of medication that a student may self-administer and other illnesses for which a student may self-administer medication other than those provided in this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All existing rules and regulations promulgated pursuant to subchapter III of this chapter [§ <cite root="38-631">38-631</cite> et seq.] [repealed], shall remain in effect until rules promulgated pursuant to this subchapter become effective.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>[Not funded].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-107">Feb. 2, 2008, D.C. Law 17-107, § 13, 54 DCR 12230</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-77">Mar. 9, 2016, D.C. Law 21-77, § 2(g), 63 DCR 756</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2016 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite> would have added (d).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>Section 9 of Law 17-52 added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Sec. 9. Rules.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(a) The Mayor, pursuant to Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite root="2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.), shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this act.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(b) The Mayor may establish, by regulation, additional types of medication a student may self-administer and potentially life-threatening illnesses for which a student may self-administer medication other than those provided in this act.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 11(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-52">D.C. Law 17-52</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 9 of Student Access to Treatment Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-82, July 26, 2007,  54 DCR 7999).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 9 of Student Access to Treatment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-140, October 17, 2007,  54 DCR 10736).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of Authority to the Student Access to Treatment Act of 2007, see Mayor’s Order 2008-85, June 11, 2008 ( 55 DCR 9362).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite>: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-77">D.C. Law 21-77</cite> provided (a) that the act shall apply upon the date of inclusions of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan; (b) that the Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification; and (c) that the Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register and that the date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the act.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
