<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>22-3306</num>
  <heading>Defacing books, manuscripts, publications, or works of art.</heading>
  <text>Any person who shall wrongfully deface, injure, or mutilate, tear, or destroy any book, pamphlet, or manuscript, or any portion thereof belonging to the Library of Congress, or to any public library in the District of Columbia, whether the property of the United States or of the District of Columbia or of any individual or corporation in said District, or who shall wrongfully deface, injure, mutilate, tear, or destroy any book, pamphlet, document, manuscript, public record, print, engraving, medal, newspaper, or work of art, the property of the United States or of the District of Columbia, shall be held guilty of a misdemeanor, and, on conviction thereof, shall, when the offense is not otherwise punishable by some statute of the United States, be punished by a fine of not less than $10 and not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, and by imprisonment for not less than 1 month nor more than 180 days, or both, for every such offense.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§849">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1327, ch. 854, § 849</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 30, 1902, 32 Stat. 535, ch. 1329</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-164" type="History">Dec. 1, 1982, D.C. Law 4-164, § 601(d), 29 DCR 3976</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-19" type="History">Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-19, § 14(b), 32 DCR 3590</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-151" type="History">Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151,§ 105(n), 41 DCR 2608</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 201(l), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 201(l) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 105(n) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994,  41 DCR 4286).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “and not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>” for “nor more than $1,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 22-3106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 22-3106.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
