<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1108</num>
  <heading>Notice of Commission and Committee meetings; minutes.</heading>
  <text>At least 15 days notice to the public of meetings of the Commission and the Committee shall be provided by advertising in at least 3 local newspapers, through public service announcements, and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Copies of the minutes of meetings of the Commission and the Committee shall be provided on a quarterly basis to each member of the Council and the Mayor.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-183" type="History" path="§9">Mar. 16, 1985, D.C. Law 5-183, § 9, 32 DCR 841</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Health maintenance organizations, “provider” defined, see § <cite path="§31-3401">31-3401</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Health-care and community residence facilities, personnel criminal background checks, see § <cite path="§44-552">44-552</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Human tissue banks, transfer of blood components within District, authority of licensed blood banks, see § <cite path="§7-1541.08">7-1541.08</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Injuries caused by firearms or other dangerous weapons, reports by physicians and institutions, requirements, see § <cite path="§7-2601">7-2601</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Medical records, “health professional” defined, see § <cite path="§44-801">44-801</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Neglected children, persons required to make reports, procedure, see § <cite path="§4-1321.02">4-1321.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Non-health related occupations, licensure, certification, and registration criteria, see § <cite path="§47-2853.02">47-2853.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Presidential inaugural ceremonies, authorization of appropriations, see § <cite path="§2-810">2-810</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Substance abuse, prevention program, financial assistance, see § <cite path="§44-1205">44-1205</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Substance abuse, treatment and prevention, “qualified health professional” defined, see § <cite path="§44-1201">44-1201</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Workers’ compensation, “physician” defined, see § <cite path="§32-1501">32-1501</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3108.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
