<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1205.17</num>
  <heading>Voluntary surrender of license, registration, or certification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any health professional who is the subject of an investigation into, or a pending proceeding involving, allegations involving misconduct may voluntarily surrender his or her license, registration, certification, or privilege to practice in the District, but only by delivering to the board regulating the health occupation an affidavit stating that the health professional desires to surrender the license, registration, certification, or privilege and that the action is freely and voluntarily taken, and not the result of duress or coercion.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of the required affidavit, the board shall enter an order revoking or suspending the license, registration, or certification of the health professional or the privilege to practice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The voluntary surrender of a license, registration, or certification shall not preclude the imposition of civil or criminal penalties against the licensee, registrant, or person certified.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§517">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 517, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26" type="History">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(e)(17), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3305.17.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-26">D.C. Law 18-26</law-cite>, in the section heading, inserted “, registration, or certification”; in subsec. (a), inserted “, registration, or certification,” twice; in subsec. (b), inserted “, registration, or certification”; and rewrote subsec. (c), which had read as follows: “(c) The voluntary surrender of a license shall not preclude the imposition of civil or criminal penalties against the licensee.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e)(17) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
