<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1210.10</num>
  <heading>Injunctions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia may bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia to enjoin the unlawful practice of any health occupation or any other action which is grounds for the imposition of a criminal penalty or disciplinary action under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Corporation Counsel may bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia to enjoin the unlawful sale of drugs or the unlawful trade practice or unlawful operation of a pharmacy, nursing home, community residential facility, or any other establishment purporting to provide health services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Remedies under this section are in addition to criminal prosecution or any disciplinary action by a board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In any proceeding under this section, it shall not be necessary to prove that any person is individually injured by the action or actions alleged.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 1010, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26" type="History">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(j), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3310.10.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-26">D.C. Law 18-26</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “The Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia may bring an action” for “The Corporation Counsel may bring an action”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
