<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1251.05</num>
  <heading>Committee powers and duties.</heading>
  <text>In addition to the powers and duties set forth elsewhere in this chapter, the Committee shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Evaluate a nurse who requests participation in the Program according to the guidelines prescribed by the Committee and consider recommendations for a nurse’s admission into the Program;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Designate and review facilities and providers to which nurses in the Program may be referred for treatment and services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Receive and review information concerning a nurse participating in the Program;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Consider whether a nurse participating in the Program may safely continue or resume the practice of nursing;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Hold meetings, as necessary, to consider the requests of nurses to participate in the Program and the reports regarding nurses participating in the Program;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Establish rules and guidelines for the operation of the Program, including the evaluation of facilities and providers that provide treatment and services to nurses eligible to participate in the program;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Prepare reports to be submitted to the Board; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Set forth in writing a rehabilitation program established for each nurse participating in the Program, including the requirements for supervision and surveillance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-297" type="History" path="§6">May 1, 2001, D.C. Law 13-297, § 6, 48 DCR 2036</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
