<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1207.10</num>
  <heading>Qualifications for licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Professional Counseling shall license as a professional counselor a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter, has satisfactorily completed the examination process, has completed 60 hours of postgraduate education in counseling or a related subject from an accredited college or university, and has completed 2 years of supervised counseling experience.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Professional Counseling shall license as a graduate professional counselor a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter [§3-1205.01 et seq.], has satisfactorily completed the examination process and has completed 48 hours of graduate education leading to a Master’s degree in counseling or a related subject from an accredited college or university.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board of Professional Counseling shall license, by endorsement, a professional counselor who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter [§3-1205.01 et seq.],, is currently licensed in another state and meets the American Association of State Counseling Boards Tier II requirements, which consist of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Completion of at least 60 hours of postgraduate education leading to a Master’s degree in counseling or a related field obtained from an institution of higher education that is regionally accredited by an accrediting body recognized by the U.S. Department of Education;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Supervision by another person, which shall consist of at least 2 years of post-Master’s counseling experience with a minimum of 4,000 hours;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Having 2,500 hours of direct client contact within the 4,000 hours;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A minimum of 100 hours of clinical supervision, post-Master’s, of which 50 hours may be in group supervision; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Five years of post-licensure experience in clinical counseling at the independent level.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 710</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-126">as added July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-126, § 2(g), 39 DCR 3824</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-13">July 7, 2009, D.C. Law 18-13, § 2(d), 56 DCR 3608</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 2-3307.10.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-13">D.C. Law 18-13</cite> designated subsec. (a); and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
