<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1208.41</num>
  <heading>Qualifications for licensure.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology shall license as an audiologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter, has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Graduated with a Master’s degree or a Doctoral degree in audiology from a recognized educational institution that incorporates the academic course work and minimum hours of supervised training required by the regulations adopted by the Board and whose audiology program is regionally accredited by the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association or an equivalent accrediting body;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Passed a qualifying examination given by the Board or from an accrediting body recognized by the Board; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Completed a period of supervised postgraduate professional practice in audiology as specified by rulemaking issued by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology shall license as a speech-language pathologist a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter, has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Graduated with a Master’s degree or Doctoral degree in speech-language pathology from a recognized educational institution that incorporates the academic course work and minimum hours of supervised training required by the regulations adopted by the Board and whose speech-language pathology program is regionally accredited by the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association or an equivalent accrediting body;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Passed a qualifying examination given by the Board or from an accrediting body recognized by the Board; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Completed a period of supervised postgraduate professional practice in speech-language pathology as specified by rulemaking issued by the Board.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An audiology or speech-language pathology license shall be renewable every 2 years by the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 841</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-219" type="History">as added Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-219, § 2(g), 53 DCR 10211</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</law-cite> validated a previously made technical correction in the heading of this subchapter.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
