<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1205.07</num>
  <heading>Reciprocity and endorsement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Endorsement” means the process of issuing a license, registration, or certification to an applicant who is licensed, registered, certified, or accredited by an accrediting association or a state board and recognized by the Board as a qualified professional according to standards that were the substantial equivalent at the time of the licensing, registration, certification, or accreditation to the standards for that profession set forth in this chapter and who has continually remained in good standing with the licensing, registering, certifying, or accrediting association or state board from the date of licensure, registration, certification, or accreditation until the date of licensure, registration, or certification in the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Reciprocity” means the process of issuing a license, registration, or certification to an applicant who is licensed, registered, or certified and in good standing under the laws of another state with requirements that, in the opinion of the Board, were substantially equivalent at the time of licensure, registration, or certification to the requirements of this chapter, and that state admits health professionals licensed, registered, or certified in the District of Columbia in a like manner.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each board shall issue a license, registration, or certification to an applicant who qualifies by reciprocity or endorsement and who pays the applicable fees established by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§507">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 507, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-247" type="History">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-247, § 2(m), 42 DCR 457</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-86" type="History">Apr. 29, 1998, D.C. Law 12-86, § 403, 45 DCR 1172</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26" type="History">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(e)(7), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 30(b)(1), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e)(7) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-26">D.C. Law 18-26</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3305.7.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§3-1205.06">3-1205.06</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
