<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1210.11</num>
  <heading>Patient or client records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon written request from a patient or client, or person authorized to have access to the patient’s record under a health care power of attorney for the patient or client, the health care provider having custody and control of the patient’s or client’s record shall furnish, within a reasonable period of time, a complete and current copy of that record. If the patient or client is deceased, the request may be made by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person authorized immediately prior to the decedent’s death to have access to the patient’s or client’s record under a health care power of attorney for the patient;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The executor for the decedent’s estate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The temporary executor for the decedent’s estate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The administrator for the decedent’s estate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The temporary administrator for the decedent’s estate; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any survivor of the decedent.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A health care provider may require the patient or client, or person authorized to have access to the patient’s or client’s record, to pay a reasonable fee for copying, as determined by the board through rulemaking.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term “record” includes a copy of a bill that has been requested by an individual but excludes x-rays.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Medical or client records shall be maintained for a minimum period of 3 years from the date of last contact for an adult and a minimum period of 3 years after a minor reaches the age of majority.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 1011</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26" type="History">as added July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(k), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Durable power of attorney for health care, see § <cite path="§21-2205">21-2205</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(k) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
