<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1205.16</num>
  <heading>Cease and desist orders.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When a board or the Mayor, after investigation but prior to a hearing, has cause to believe that any person is violating any provision of this chapter and the violation has caused or may cause immediate and irreparable harm to the public, the board or the Mayor may issue an order requiring the alleged violator to cease and desist immediately from the violation. The order shall be served by certified mail or delivery in person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The alleged violator may, within 15 days of the service of the order, submit a written request to the board or the Mayor to hold a hearing on the alleged violation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a timely request, the board or the Mayor shall conduct a hearing and render a decision pursuant to § <cite path="§3-1205.19">3-1205.19</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The alleged violator may, within 10 days of the service of an order, submit a written request to the board or the Mayor for an expedited hearing on the alleged violation, in which case he or she shall waive his or her right to the 15-day notice required by § <cite path="§3-1205.19">3-1205.19</cite>(d).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Upon receipt of a timely request for an expedited hearing, the board or the Mayor shall conduct a hearing within 10 days of the date of receiving the request and shall deliver to the alleged violator at his or her last known address a written notice of the hearing by any means guaranteed to be received at least 5 days before the hearing date.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The board or the Mayor shall issue a decision within 30 days after an expedited hearing.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a request for a hearing is not made, the order of the board or the Mayor to cease and desist is final.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If, after a hearing, the board determines that the alleged violator is not in violation of this chapter, the board or the Mayor shall revoke the order to cease and desist.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>If any person fails to comply with a lawful order of a board or the Mayor issued pursuant to this section, the board or the Mayor may petition the court to issue an order compelling compliance or take any other action authorized by this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History" path="§516">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 516, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3305.16.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§3-1205.14">3-1205.14</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
