<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1205.21</num>
  <heading>Reinstatement of suspended or revoked license, registration, or certification.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a board may reinstate the license, registration, or certification or privilege of an individual whose license, registration, or certification or privilege has been suspended or revoked by the board only in accordance with:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The terms and conditions of the order of suspension or revocation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A final judgment or order in any proceeding for review.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If an order of suspension or revocation was based on the conviction of a crime which bears directly on the fitness of the individual to be licensed, registered, or certified, and the conviction subsequently is overturned at any stage of an appeal or other postconviction proceeding, the suspension or revocation shall end when the conviction is overturned.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>After the process of review is completed, the clerk of the court issuing the final disposition of the case shall notify the board or the Mayor of that disposition.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 521, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(e)(20), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 2-3305.21.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-26">D.C. Law 18-26</cite>, in the section heading, inserted “registration, or certification”; in subsec. (a), substituted “license, registration, or certification” for “license”; and, in subsec. (b), substituted “licensed, registered, or certified” for “licensed”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e)(20) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
