<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1205.01</num>
  <heading>License, registration, or certification required.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A license issued pursuant to this chapter is required to practice acupuncture, advanced practice addiction counseling, assisted living administration, audiology, chiropractic, cytotechnology, dental hygiene, dentistry, dietetics, histotechnology, home health care administration, marriage and family therapy, massage therapy, medical laboratory technology, medicine, naturopathic medicine, nutrition, nursing home administration, occupational therapy, optometry, pharmaceutical detailing, pharmacy, physical therapy, podiatry, practical nursing, professional counseling, psychology, registered nursing, respiratory care, social work, speech-language pathology, veterinary medicine, or to practice as an anesthesiologist assistant, athletic trainer, personal fitness trainer, physician assistant, physical therapy assistant, polysomnographic technologist, occupational therapy assistant, surgical assistant, or trauma technologist in the District, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Registration is required to practice as an audiology assistant, dental assistant, nursing assistive personnel, phlebotomist, psychology associate, polysomnographic technician or trainee, speech-language pathology assistant, or speech-language pathology clinical fellow.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Certification is required to practice as an addiction counselor I, addiction counselor II, advanced practice registered nursing, veterinary technician, or a veterinary euthanasia technician.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Except for administering general or sedation anesthesia in a hospital as defined in § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(1), a federal agency or facility, or a dental school, certification is required for a dentist, or for a facility where dentistry is practiced, to administer general or sedation anesthesia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A license, registration, or certification is the property of the District of Columbia and shall be surrendered on demand of the licensor.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 501, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-126">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-126, § 2(f), 39 DCR 3824</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-203">Mar. 14, 1995, D.C. Law 10-203, § 2(e), 41 DCR 7707</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-205">Mar. 14, 1995, D.C. Law 10-205, § 2(d), 41 DCR 7712</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-247">Mar. 23, 1995, D.C. Law 10-247, § 2(h), 42 DCR 457</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-88">Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-88, § 2(g), 50 DCR 10999</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-172">July 8, 2004, D.C. Law 15-172, § 2(e), 51 DCR 4938</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-237">Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-237, § 2(f), 51 DCR 10593</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-219">Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-219, § 2(f), 53 DCR 10211</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-220">Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-220, § 2(c), 53 DCR 10216</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-228">Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-228, § 2(f), 53 DCR 10244</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-131">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-131, § 102(e), 55 DCR 1659</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26,§ 2(e)(2), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-303">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-303, § 2(c), 60 DCR 2711</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-64">Jan. 25, 2014, D.C. Law 20-64, § 2(e), 60 DCR 16533</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-96">Mar. 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-96, § 102(k), 61 DCR 1184</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-272">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-272, § 2(e), 62 DCR 1911</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§3-1208.62">3-1208.62</cite>, § <cite path="§16-2301">16-2301</cite>, § <cite path="§21-501">21-501</cite>, and § <cite path="§21-2202">21-2202</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 2-3305.1.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-88">D.C. Law 15-88</cite> inserted “marriage and family therapy,” after “dietetics,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-172">D.C. Law 15-172</cite> substituted “massage therapy, naturopathic medicine,” for “massage therapy,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-237">D.C. Law 15-237</cite> substituted “an anesthesiologist assistant, physician assistant, or occupational therapy assistant” for “a physician assistant or occupational therapy assistant”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-219">D.C. Law 16-219</cite> inserted “audiology, speech-language pathology,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-220">D.C. Law 16-220</cite>, inserted “physical therapy assistant,” following “physician assistant,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-228">D.C. Law 16-228</cite>, inserted “or surgical assistant” following “occupational therapy assistant,”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-131">D.C. Law 17-131</cite> substituted “pharmaceutical detailing, pharmacy” for “pharmacy”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-26">D.C. Law 18-26</cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “A license issued pursuant to this chapter is required to practice medicine, acupuncture, chiropractic, registered nursing, practical nursing, dentistry, dental hygiene, dietetics, marriage and family therapy, massage therapy, naturopathic medicine, nutrition, nursing home administration, occupational therapy, optometry, pharmaceutical detailing, pharmacy, physical therapy, podiatry, psychology, social work, professional counseling, audiology, speech-language pathology, and respiratory care or to practice as an anesthesiologist assistant, physician assistant, physical therapy assistant, occupational therapy assistant, or surgical assistant in the District, except as provided in this chapter. A certification issued pursuant to this chapter is required to practice advanced practice registered nursing.”</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-303">D.C. Law 19-303</cite> substituted “dental assistant, or pharmacy technician or trainee” for “or dental assistant” in (a).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-64">D.C. Law 20-64</cite> added “trauma technologist” in (a); and made a related change.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-96">D.C. Law 20-96</cite> rewrote (a).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-272">D.C. Law 20-272</cite>, in (a)(1), added “cytotechnology,” “histotechnology,” and “medical laboratory technology“; and added “phlebotomist” in (a)(2).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e)(2) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
