<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1208.62</num>
  <heading>Qualifications for license to practice veterinary medicine.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Veterinary Medicine shall issue a license to practice veterinary medicine to a person who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter [§ <cite path="§3-1205.01">3-1205.01</cite> et seq.]:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Is a graduate of a school of veterinary medicine approved by the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has passed an examination as prescribed by the Board to determine the person’s competence to engage in the practice of veterinary medicine; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has not been convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude or animal cruelty.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board may waive the examination requirements of this section upon the request of any applicant for licensure, when that applicant has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Submitted a properly completed application and paid the requisite application fees; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated that he or she has passed an examination in a state or territory of the United States where the requirements for licensure are deemed by the Board to be substantially equivalent to those in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated that he or she has maintained a license in good standing and has practiced continuously in the jurisdiction for the 12 months preceding the date of application.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Board shall, upon receipt of a properly completed application, issue a license to engage in the practice of veterinary medicine in the District to a graduate of a foreign school of veterinary medicine who, in addition to meeting the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter [§ <cite path="§3-1205.01">3-1205.01</cite> et seq.], has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Graduated from a school of veterinary medicine that is accredited by the jurisdiction in which it is located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submitted proper credentials to the Board as may be determined in rules issued by the Mayor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Passed a written examination as required by the Board to determine the person’s competency to engage in the practice of veterinary medicine.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any person licensed to practice veterinary medicine pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of this title [§ <cite path="§3-501">3-501</cite> et seq.] shall be considered to be licensed under this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 862</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-96" type="History">as added Mar. 26, 2014, D.C. Law 20-96, § 102(q), 61 DCR 1184</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-96">D.C. Law 20-96</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
