<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1205.18</num>
  <heading>Voluntary limitation or surrender of a license, registration, or certification by impaired health professional.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any license, registration, or certification issued under this chapter may be voluntarily limited by the licensee, registrant, or person certified either:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Permanently;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For an indefinite period of time to be restored at the discretion of the board regulating the health occupation; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a definite period of time under an agreement between the licensee, registrant, or person certified and the board.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>During the period of time that the license, registration, or certification has been limited, the licensee, registrant, or person certified shall not engage in the practices or activities to which the voluntary limitation of practice relates.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As a condition for accepting the voluntary limitation of practice, the board may require the licensee, registrant, or person certified to do 1 or more of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Accept care, counseling, or treatment by physicians or other health professionals acceptable to the board;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Participate in a program of education prescribed by the board; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Practice under the direction of a health professional acceptable to the board for a specified period of time.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any license, registration, or certification issued under this chapter may be voluntarily surrendered to the board by the licensee, registrant, or person certified either:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Permanently;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>For an indefinite period of time to be restored at the discretion of the board regulating the health occupation; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For a definite period of time under an agreement between the licensee, registrant, or person certified and the board.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>During the period of time that the license, registration, or certification has been surrendered, the individual surrendering the license, registration, or certification shall not practice, attempt to practice, or offer to practice the health occupation for which the license, registration, or certification is required, shall be considered as unlicensed, unregistered, or uncertified, and shall not be required to pay the fees for the license, registration, or certification.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All records, communications, and proceedings of the board related to the voluntary limitation or surrender of a license, registration, or certification under this section shall be confidential.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 518, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-26" type="History">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-26, § 2(e)(18), 56 DCR 4043</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 30(b)(2), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§3-1205.14">3-1205.14</cite> and § <cite path="§3-1251.09">3-1251.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3305.18.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-26">D.C. Law 18-26</law-cite>, in the section heading, substituted “a license, registration, or certification” for “license”; substituted “license, registration, or certification” for “license”; and substituted “licensee, registrant, or person certified” for “licensee”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</law-cite> substituted “unlicensed, unregistered, or uncertified” for “unlicensed” in (b)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(e)(18) of Health Occupations Revision General Amendment Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-146, July 28, 2009,  56 DCR 6308).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
