<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1203.02</num>
  <heading>Responsibilities of Mayor.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor shall be responsible for:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Planning, developing, and maintaining procedures to ensure that the boards receive administrative support, including staff and facilities, sufficient to enable them to perform their responsibilities;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Processing and providing licenses as required and approved by the boards;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Providing investigative and inspection services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Holding hearings on cases pursuant to guidelines established in § <cite path="§3-1205.19">3-1205.19</cite> when requested to do so by the board, and appointing hearing officers to enable the boards to hold hearings;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Furnishing expert services in noncompliance cases brought in an administrative or court proceeding;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Providing budgetary and personnel services;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Maintaining central files of records pertaining to licensure, inspections, investigations, and other matters requested by the boards;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Furnishing facilities and staff for hearings and other proceedings;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Providing information to the public concerning licensing requirements and procedures;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Publishing and distributing procedural manuals concerning licensing and inspections and other materials prepared by the boards;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>Assisting, supplying, furnishing, and performing other administrative, clerical, and technical support the Mayor determines is necessary or appropriate;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>Issuing rules, as the Mayor may periodically determine to be necessary to protect the health and welfare of the citizens of the District, for the temporary licensure for a fixed period of time not to exceed 90 days and under conditions to be prescribed by the Mayor by rule, of applicants for licensure to practice a health occupation in the District, except the Mayor may provide for the issuance of temporary licenses to applicants for licensure to practice social work and marriage and family therapy for a period not to exceed 1 year, and to applicants for licensure to practice as anesthesiologist assistants for a period not to exceed 2 years;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>Making necessary rules relating to the administrative procedures of the boards; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>Issuing all rules necessary to implement the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 302, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-165" type="History">Oct. 1, 1992, D.C. Law 9-165, § 2, 39 DCR 5817</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-88" type="History">Mar. 10, 2004, D.C. Law 15-88, § 2(e), 50 DCR 10999</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-237" type="History">Mar. 16, 2005, D.C. Law 15-237, § 2(d), 51 DCR 10593</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 17(b), 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§3-1205.04">3-1205.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3303.2.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-88">D.C. Law 15-88</cite>, in par. (12), substituted “social work and marriage and family therapy” for “social work”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-237">D.C. Law 15-237</cite>, in par. (12), substituted “to exceed 1 year, and to applicants for licensure to practice as anesthesiologist assistants for a period not to exceed 2 years;” for “exceeding 1 year;”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in par. (12), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Temporary Licensure of Social Workers Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 9-92">D.C. Law 9-92</cite>, April 8, 1992, law notification  39 DCR 2858).</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Temporary Licensure of Social Workers Emergency Amendment Act of 1992 (D.C. Act 9-148, January 28, 1992,  39 DCR 714). Section 3 of D.C. Act 9-148 provided that any 90-day temporary licenses to practice social work issued prior to January 28, 1992, shall be extended automatically for a period of 1 year from the date the license was issued, subject to any conditions prescribed by the mayor pursuant to § 302(12) of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to the “District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985”, see Mayor’s Order 98-140, August 20, 1998 ( 45 DCR 6593).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">District of Columbia Nursing Home Advisory Commission established: See Mayor’s Order 88-60, March 15, 1988.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
