<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1208.06</num>
  <heading>Waiver of requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Social Work shall waive the educational and examination requirements for any applicant for licensure as a social worker who can demonstrate, to the satisfaction of the Board, that he or she has been performing the functions of a social worker, as defined in this chapter, on a full-time or substantially full-time basis continually at least 12 months immediately preceding March 25, 1986, and is qualified to do so on the basis of pertinent education, training, experience, and demonstrated current competence, provided that application for the license is made within 24 months of March 25, 1986.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Social Work shall waive the examination requirement for any applicant who meets the educational requirements for licensure as a social worker, has practiced as a social worker or as a social work administrator, whether full time or not, within a 3-year period immediately preceding March 25, 1986, and is qualified to do so on the basis of pertinent experience, and demonstrated current competence, provided that application for the license is made within 24 months of March 25, 1986.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Applicants licensed under the waiver provisions of this section shall be eligible for license renewal on the same terms as all other licensed social workers.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-99" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-99, § 806, 33 DCR 729</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-20" type="History">July 25, 1987, D.C. Law 7-20, § 2(b), 34 DCR 3814</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-87" type="History">Mar. 11, 1988, D.C. Law 7-87, § 2(b), 35 DCR 162</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-3308.6.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Temporary Amendment Act of 1987 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 7-20">D.C. Law 7-20</cite>, July 25, 1987, law notification  34 DCR 5251).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">In subsection (c), “section” was substituted for “subsection,” to correct an error in <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-99">D.C. Law 6-99</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
