<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-1336</num>
  <heading>Competitive bid contracts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No Board member, officer, or employee of the Board designated to enter into contracts for the operation of any of the forms of gambling authorized by this chapter shall have any material interest, either directly or indirectly, in any contract with a vendor for the purchase of supplies, materials, equipment, machinery, work, or other items relating to or necessary for the operation of such gambling form.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Office of Contracting and Procurement shall procure supplies, materials, equipment, machinery, work, or other items relating to or necessary for the operation of any gambling form on behalf of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No contract awarded or entered into by the Board may be assigned by the holder thereof except by specific approval of the Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Contracts awarded by the Board for more than 1 year shall not be governed by the provisions of the Antideficiency Act (31 U.S.C. §§ 1341, 1342, and 1349 to 1351, and 1511 through 1519).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-172" type="History">Mar. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 3-172, § 4, 27 DCR 4736</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-259" type="History">Apr. 12, 1997, D.C. Law 11-259, § 310, 44 DCR 1423</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2536.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The Antideficiency Act ( 31 U.S.C. § 1341,  1342, and  1349 to  1351, and  1511 through  1519, referred to in subsection (g) of this section, was originally codified as  31 U.S.C. § 665 and was recodified by the Act of September 13, 1982, Pub. L. 97-258.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
