<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-1313</num>
  <heading>Operation of lottery.</heading>
  <text>The Board shall operate and conduct a lottery and shall determine the number of times a lottery shall be held each year, the form and price of tickets, and the number and value of prizes to winning participants, determined in a manner and on a basis designated by the Board. The proceeds of the sale of tickets shall be deposited in the Fund from which prizes shall be paid according to regulations established by the Board under § <cite path="§3-1312">3-1312</cite>. The Board may provide by regulation for the payment of prizes to winners directly by licensed agents.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-172" type="History">Mar. 10, 1981, D.C. Law 3-172, § 4, 27 DCR 4736</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 762, 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-128" type="History">May 31, 2012, D.C. Law 19-128, § 2, 59 DCR 2254</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-2513.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (b); and added subsecs. (a) and (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-128">D.C. Law 19-128</law-cite> rewrote the section, which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) A lottery or lottery game means both games of skill and games of chance that are operated by and for the benefit of the District of Columbia by the Board; provided, that:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(1) If the games of skill and games of chance are offered via the Internet, any technology employed for the play shall confirm the play to be at all times within the District; provided further, that the restriction shall not apply to the conduct of fantasy sports and sweepstakes-style games if such games are lawful; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) No method, media, or device for play of the games of skill and games of chance shall violate An Act To prohibit transportation of gambling devices in interstate and foreign commerce, approved January 2, 1951 ( 15 U.S. C. § 1171 et seq.), or any other federal law.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) The Board shall operate and conduct a lottery and shall determine the number of times a lottery shall be held each year, the form and price of tickets therefor, the number and value of prizes to winning participants, determined in a manner and on a basis designated by the Board. The proceeds of the sale of tickets shall be deposited in the Fund from which prizes shall be paid according to regulations established by the Board under § <cite path="§3-1312">3-1312</cite>. The Board may provide by regulation for the payment of prizes to winners directly by licensed agents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) The Board, through the Chief Financial Officer, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2, may issue rules to implement the provisions of this section, and may establish which games may be offered and additional terms and conditions for the conduct of the games not inconsistent with subsection (a) of this section, including the percentage of wagered amounts to be retained by the Board, minimum and maximum wagers, and time limitations for the games.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 762 of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Lottery Amendment Repeal Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-312, February 22, 2012,  59 DCR 1701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-332">D.C. Law 19-332</law-cite>, see § 7007 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) repeal of section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-128">D.C. Law 19-128</law-cite>, see § 7007 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 761 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</law-cite> provided that subtitle G of title VII of the act may be cited as “Lottery Modernization Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-128">D.C. Law 19-128</law-cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-128">D.C. Law 19-128</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-128">D.C. Law 19-128</law-cite>, § 3, was repealed by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite>, § 7007.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7016 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> provided that Sections 7001, 7004, 7007, 7009, 7011, and 7015 of the act shall apply as of June 19, 2012.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
