<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-302</num>
  <heading>Establishment; composition; term of office; alternates; compensation; election of Chairman.</heading>
  <text>There is established an Armory Board, to be composed of the Commanding General of the District of Columbia National Guard, and 2 other members appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia by and with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia. The members appointed by the Mayor shall each serve for a term of 4 years beginning on the date such member qualifies. Each member of the Armory Board is authorized to appoint, and in his discretion to withdraw the appointment of, an alternate and to delegate to such alternate authority to act in his place and stead in respect of the powers granted by this subchapter. The members of said Board and the alternates shall serve without additional compensation. Said Armory Board shall elect a Chairman from among its members.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 4, 1948, 62 Stat. 339, ch. 418, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-198" type="History">Dec. 24, 1973, 87 Stat. 811, Pub. L. 93-198, title IV, § 494</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">“Agency” defined, see 1-315.02.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Disclosure of financial interests, requirements, see 1-1106.02.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Nomination and approval of agency heads, see 1-523.01.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Personnel authority, rules and regulations, implementation, see 1-604.06.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-315.02">1-315.02</cite>, § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>, and § <cite path="§1-604.06">1-604.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-302.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-1702.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The National Guard, referred to in the first sentence of this section, was substituted for the Militia pursuant to the Act of February 18, 1909, 35 Stat. 636.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">Transfer of nonmilitary functions to Sports Commission: Section 19 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-152">D.C. Law 10-152</law-cite>, provided, in part, that the Sports Commission shall assume all nonmilitary functions of the Armory Board as are set forth in § <cite path="§2-306">2-306</cite> repealed and that all references to the Armory Board in Subchapter II of Chapter 3 of Title 2 are intended to be references to the Sports Commission unless the clear meaning requires otherwise.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 2 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-206">D.C. Law 10-206</law-cite> amended § 19 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 10-152">D.C. Law 10-152</law-cite> by adding (e) and (f) which contain provisions authorizing the Armory Board to exercise its nonmilitary functions and authority on an interim basis and ratifying actions taken by the Board during the interim period.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-211">1-211</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-213">1-213</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
