<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-607</num>
  <heading>Administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All receipts of the Commission shall be deposited to the General Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Every person holding or conducting an event within the jurisdiction of the Commission shall file with the Commission, within 24 hours after the event is over, a report concerning fees, prices, revenues, and gross receipts from the event at the time and in the form prescribed by the Commission; however, this shall not preclude the Commission from demanding manifests or reports at an earlier time. Such person shall pay to the Commission, at the time of the filing of the report, a fee of 5 per centum of the gross receipts realized by such person as a result of holding or conducting the event except that the Commission may require the amount so collected be not less than that necessary for the payment of compensation to the personnel necessary to conduct such contest, match or exhibition. Each ticket of admission to any covered event shall bear clearly upon its face its price.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Every person presenting or showing any boxing or wrestling match, contest, or exhibition on closed circuit telecast or subscription television viewed within the District, whether or not originating within the District, shall, within 72 hours excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays after the presentation or showing is over:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>File with the Commission a report stating the exact number of tickets sold for the presentation or showing and the gross receipts from the presentation or showing or, if no tickets are sold, the price in money or value paid or owed for the presentation or showing, and any other information the Commission may require; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Pay to the Commission a fee of 5% of the first $100,000 of the gross receipts from, or price paid or owed for, the presentation or showing and 2% of any gross receipts or price paid or owed in excess of $100,000.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Commission may seek an advance payment for a presentation or showing when it deems an advance payment to be appropriate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission may also charge such other nonlicense fees as are reasonable in amount for services it renders in carrying out its lawful functions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall report quarterly to the Mayor and to the Council on its official acts and its efforts to promote the District of Columbia as a location for boxing, wrestling, and martial arts events. The Commission shall make recommendations, as it deems appropriate, to further the promotion of the District of Columbia as a location for boxing, wrestling, and martial arts events and to promote the effective regulation of professional and amateur boxing, wrestling, and martial arts events that are conducted or shown within the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Auditor shall conduct at least every 3 fiscal years an audit of the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall conduct quarterly audits of the Commission and furnish the Commission with such office space as it needs and with administrative aid as the Commission may request.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-20" type="History" path="§8">Oct. 8, 1975, D.C. Law 1-20, § 8, 23 DCR 1815</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-50" type="History">Feb. 26, 1976, D.C. Law 1-50, § 3, 22 DCR 5127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-70" type="History">June 14, 1980, D.C. Law 3-70, § 7(e), 27 DCR 1776</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-137" type="History">Aug. 13, 1986, D.C. Law 6-137, § 2(b), 33 DCR 3798</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-169" type="History">Sept. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-169, § 2(d), 35 DCR 5749</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-152" type="History">Aug. 1, 1996, D.C. Law 11-152, § 402, 43 DCR 2978</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-205" type="History">Dec. 7, 2004, D.C. Law 15-205, § 1192(b), 51 DCR 8441</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-594, October 26, 2004,  51 DCR 11725).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1192(b) of Fiscal Year 2005 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-486, August 2, 2004,  51 DCR 8236).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 402 of the Fiscal Year 1996 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-264, April 26, 1996,  43 DCR 2412), and § 302 of the Fiscal Year 1996 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-335, August 1, 1996,  43 DCR 4256).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-205">D.C. Law 15-205</cite>, in subsec. (f), substituted “at least every 3 fiscal years an” for “a biennial”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-1237.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-607.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§3-608">§ 3-608</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
