<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>3-653</num>
  <heading>Powers of the Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Serve as an advocate for fashion retailers, designers, and beauty businesses in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Advise and make recommendations to the Mayor and the Council concerning needs of the people of the District for fashion-design activities and concerning the development and improvement of fashion and cultural affairs programs in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Stimulate and encourage study and review of the status of fashion arts projects and serve as the clearinghouse for activities aimed at realizing a fashion retail corridor that will serve as a centralized shopping destination featuring local, national, and international fashion designers and boutiques in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Prepare and recommend to the Mayor and the Council an annual plan for fashion arts projects and events in the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Work with District departments and agencies, private organizations, and the fashion-design community to develop and undertake programs which will encourage maximum participation in fashion art and cultural affairs activities and which will promote greater appreciation and enjoyment of the trade.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Nominate special advisors to serve and provide technical and expert advice on matters relevant to the functions of the Commission; provided, that decision-making shall reside with the Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Form task forces, as required, composed of Commission members, special advisors, and others interested in serving;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Apply for and receive grants to fund its program activities in accordance with procedures relating to grants management and recommend to the Mayor and the Council applications for federal grants-in-aid to projects or productions in fashion design; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Accept private gifts and donations to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-148" type="History">Apr. 15, 2008, D.C. Law 17-148, ยง 4, 55 DCR 2219</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
