<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>3-702</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is hereby established in the District of Columbia a Commission for Women (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”). The Commission shall be composed of 21 members appointed by the Mayor, from among the residents of the District of Columbia with experience in the areas of public affairs and issues of particular interest and concern to women, representative by geographic area and reflective by race and age of the population of the District of Columbia. The Commission shall be the successor to the Commission on the Status of Women established by Organization Order No. 38, Commissioner’s Order No. 73-94a, effective April 24, 1973 (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission on the Status of Women”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Members of the Commission shall be appointed to serve terms of 3 years and shall serve until their successors are appointed. The present members of the Commission on the Status of Women shall be members of the Commission established by this chapter for the remainder of their current terms. A member of the Commission may be reappointed but may serve no more than 2 consecutive full terms. Tenure on the Commission on the Status of Women shall count toward the consecutive 2 full term limit on the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Whenever a vacancy occurs on the Commission, the Mayor shall, within 90 working days of such vacancy, appoint a successor to fill the unexpired portion of the term.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall designate, from among the members appointed to the Commission, the Chairperson, who shall serve in that capacity at the pleasure of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>All members of the Commission shall serve without compensation; except, that expenses incurred by the Commission as a whole or by its individual members, when duly authorized, shall become an obligation against appropriated District of Columbia funds designated for that purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may remove, after notice and hearing, any member of the Commission for neglect of duty, incompetence, misconduct or malfeasance in office.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-109" type="History">Sept. 22, 1978, D.C. Law 2-109, § 3, 25 DCR 1456</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-285" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-285, § 4(k), 46 DCR 1355</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 313, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 29, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-802.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-2602.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite>, in subsec. (c), deleted “, with the advice and consent of the Council,” following “the Mayor”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made punctuation correction in (c).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(k) of the Confirmation Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-25, March 15, 1999,  46 DCR 2971).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(k) of the Confirmation Act Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-92, June 4, 1999,  46 DCR 5330).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 4(k) of the Confirmation Act Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-92, June 4, 1999,  46 DCR 5330).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
