<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-198">
  <num type="act">24-198</num>
  <num type="bill">24-296</num>
  <heading type="short">Wilkinson School Disposition Authorization Temporary Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To authorize, on a temporary basis, the disposition of District-owned real property located at 2330 Pomeroy Road, S.E., Washington, D.C., commonly known as the Wilkinson School, and known for real property taxation and assessment purposes as Square 5828, Lot 0806.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-06-07</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2022-02-15</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47369/Signed_Act/B24-0296-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-198</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 011634</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0296">
      <vote date="2021-08-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2021-10-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2021-11-01</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Wilkinson School Disposition Authorization Temporary Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including An Act Authorizing the sale of certain real estate in the District of Columbia no longer required for public purposes, approved August 5, 1939 (53 Stat. 1211; D.C. Official Code ยง 10-801), and section 2209 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code ยง 38-1802.09), the Council authorizes the Mayor to dispose of the real property located at 2330 Pomeroy Road, S.E., commonly known as the Wilkinson School, and known for real property taxation and assessment purposes as Square 5828, Lot 0806  to D.C. Preparatory Academy, a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation, pursuant to a 25-year lease with a 25-year extension option, and to execute any documents related to the disposition.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)) and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
