<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 24-131">
  <num type="law">24-131</num>
  <num type="act">24-401</num>
  <num type="bill">24-652</num>
  <heading type="short">Law Enforcement Career Opportunities for District Residents Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">Officer and Firefighter Cadet Programs Funding Authorization and Human Rights Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1982 to remove the requirement that applicants shall graduate from District high schools in order to qualify for the Metropolitan Police Department's cadet program.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-01-31</introduced>
    <effective>2022-06-30</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48739/Signed_Act/B24-0652-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-131</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 005038</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0652">
      <vote date="2022-04-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-04-05" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-04-19" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-05-09</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Law Enforcement Career Opportunities for District Residents Expansion Temporary Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§5-109.01">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2 of the Police Officer and Firefighter Cadet Programs Funding Authorization and Human Rights Act of 1977 Amendment Act of 1982, effective March 9, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-172; D.C. Official Code § 5-109.01), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(a)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:replace/>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department ("MPD") shall establish a police officer cadet program for the purpose of instructing, training, and exposing cadets to:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>MPD's operations; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>The duties and responsibilities of serving as an MPD police officer.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The police officer cadet program established in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be composed of the following persons residing in the District, who shall have substantial ties to the District, such as currently or formerly residing, attending school, or working in the District for a significant period of time:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Senior-year high school students; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>High school graduates under 25 years of age.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(b)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "the Metropolitan Police Department" and inserting the acronym "MPD" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>the Metropolitan Police Department</find>
        <replace>MPD</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
     <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-109.01"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-109.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
              *NOTE: This section includes amendments by temporary legislation that will expire on February 10, 2023. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-109.01(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
            </text>
      </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
