<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 24-145">
  <num type="law">24-145</num>
  <num type="act">24-436</num>
  <num type="bill">24-511</num>
  <heading type="short">Department of Motor Vehicles Extension of Deadlines Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Department of Motor Vehicles Establishment Act of 1998 to authorize the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles to extend certain deadlines when there is a closure of the District government or the Department of Motor Vehicles due to an emergency, an administrative closure of the District government or the Department of Motor vehicles, or a major disruption of Department of Motor Vehicles operations.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-11-16</introduced>
    <effective>2022-07-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48294/Signed_Act/B24-0511-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-145</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 006264</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0511">
      <vote date="2022-04-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-05-23</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 24-511 would allow the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles to extend due dates for matters under the jurisdiction of the Department as a result of a major disruption in the Department’s operations. </summary>
      <committee>Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Motor Vehicles Extension of Deadlines Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1822(c) of the Department of Motor Vehicles Establishment Act of 1998, effective March 26, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-175; D.C. Official Code § 50-901(c)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-901|(c)"/>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>Notwithstanding any other law, the Director of the DMV may:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>For any of the reasons described in paragraph (2) of this subsection extend the time period for a person, without penalty, to:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Adjudicate or pay a notice of infraction;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Obtain a new vehicle registration;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>Renew the registration of a vehicle;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Pass a vehicle inspection; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(E)</num>
            <text>Obtain or renew a noncommercial or commercial driver license, learner permit, or provisional permit; and</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Extend any of the time periods for the actions listed in paragraph (1) of this subsection for any of the following reasons:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>A closure of the District government or the DMV due to an emergency;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>An administrative closure of the District government or the DMV; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>A major disruption of DMV operations.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
