<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 24-193">
  <num type="law">24-193</num>
  <num type="act">24-579</num>
  <num type="bill">24-135</num>
  <heading type="short">Non-Public Student Educational Continuity Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Nonresident Tuition Act to allow District of Columbia students enrolled at District of Columbia Public Schools or public charter schools who attend non-public schools or programs to continue their education for the remainder of the school year in which legal permanency is achieved and through the end of the following school year, without payment of nonresident tuition, if the child ceases to be in the care and custody of the District as a result of being placed in the permanent care and custody of a parent, guardian, or custodian who resides outside the District of Columbia.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-03-01</introduced>
    <effective>2022-12-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/46657/Signed_Act/B24-0135-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-193</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 012701</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0135">
      <vote date="2022-07-12" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-10-17</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 24-135 would allow a child who was previously under the custody and care of the District, that is placed in permanent care and custody of a parent, guardian or custodian who resides outside of the District of Columbia to continue their education for the remainder of the school year and through the end of the following school year, without being required to pay nonresident tuition. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Non-Public Student Educational Continuity Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§38-302|(e)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 2(e) of the District of Columbia Nonresident Tuition Act, approved September 8, 1960 (74 Stat. 853; D.C. Official Code § 38-302(e)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "school, ceases" and insert the phrase "school, or while enrolled in a DCPS or public charter school and attending a non-public school or program pursuant to section 103 of the Placement of Students with Disabilities in Nonpublic Schools Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-269; D.C. Official Code § 38-2561.03) ("Placement Act"), ceases" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace>
        <find>school, ceases</find>
        <replace>school, or while enrolled in a DCPS or public charter school and attending a non-public school or program pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2561.03">§ 38-2561.03</cite>, ceases</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "currently attends." and insert the phrase "currently attends, if the child attends a DCPS or public charter school, or the remainder of the school year in which the change in care and custody occurs and through the end of the following school year, if the child is currently enrolled in a DCPS or public charter school and attending a non-public school or program pursuant to section 103 of the Placement Act." in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace>
        <find>currently attends.</find>
        <replace>currently attends, if the child attends a DCPS or public charter school, or the remainder of the school year in which the change in care and custody occurs and through the end of the following school year, if the child is currently enrolled in a DCPS or public charter school and attending a non-public school or program pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2561.03">§ 38-2561.03</cite>.</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval of the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C Official Code § 1-206.22(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
