<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 24-174">
  <num type="law">24-174</num>
  <num type="act">24-524</num>
  <num type="bill">24-237</num>
  <heading type="short">Clean Hands Certification Equity Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to exempt the issuance and renewal of driver's licenses from the Clean Hands Certification requirement.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-05-03</introduced>
    <effective>2022-09-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/47106/Signed_Act/B24-0237-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-174</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 009906</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0237">
      <vote date="2022-06-28" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-07-12" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2022-07-12" reading="Amendment"/>
      <enacted>2022-07-27</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 24-237 would simplify the District’s Clean Hands certification requirements. It amends the definition for the type of licenses and permits that require Clean Hands, so that individuals can obtain a drivers’ license or permit without Clean Hands. The bill will also increase the minimum threshold for allowable debt, so that applicants owing $5,000 or less in certain debts will still be able to obtain Clean Hands certification. It will also limit the type of debt that will prevent an applicant from certifying Clean Hands among other things. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Clean Hands Certification Equity Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§47-2861|(2)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 47-2861(2) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(A)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the word "or" at the end.</text>
      <codify:find-replace position="last">
        <find> or</find>
        <replace/>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(B)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; or" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace position="last">
        <find>.</find>
        <replace>; or</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new subparagraph (C) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
          <codify:insert/>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Beginning on October 1, 2023, any operator's permit or identification card issued pursuant to §§ <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1401.01">50-1401.01</cite> through <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1405.01">50-1405.01</cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2861" type="Applicability" history="false">
        Applicability of D.C. Law 24-174: § 3 of D.C. Law 24-174 provided that the change made to this section by § 2(c) of D.C. Law 24-174 is subject to the inclusion of the law’s fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Therefore that amendment has not been implemented.
      </codify:annotation>
      <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-2861" type="Applicability" history="false">
       According to the Office of the Budget Director, D.C. Law 24-174 is currently funded. Therefore, the amendment to this section made by D.C. Law 24-174 has been implemented. 
     </codify:annotation>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <!-- <codify:applicability doc="D.C. Law 24-174" date="notfunded" history="false" display-template=""/> -->
      <!-- Funded per Budget Office 6/15/23 -->
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(C)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(C)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
