<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Law 24-166">
  <num type="law">24-166</num>
  <num type="act">24-486</num>
  <num type="bill">24-716</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year 2023 Local Budget Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To adopt the local portion of the budget of the District of Columbia government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-03-16</introduced>
    <effective>2022-09-09</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/49081/Signed_Act/B24-0716-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-166</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 008870</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0716">
      <vote date="2022-05-10" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-10" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2022-05-24" reading="Amendment"/>
      <enacted>2022-07-13</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiscal Year 2023 Local Budget Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading>Adoption of the local portion of the Fiscal Year 2023 budget.</heading>
    <text>The following expenditure levels are approved and adopted as the local portion of the budget for the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023.</text>
    <container name="district-of-columbia-budget-for-the-fiscal-year-ending-september-30-2023">
      <heading>DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA BUDGET FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING SEPTEMBER 30, 2023</heading>
      <text>The following amounts are appropriated for the District of Columbia government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023 ("Fiscal Year 2023"), out of the General Fund of the District of Columbia ("General Fund"), except as otherwise specifically provided; provided, that notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in section 450A of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved November 22, 2000 (114 Stat. 2440; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.50a), and provisions of this act, the total amount appropriated in this act for operating expenses for the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2023 shall not exceed the lesser of the sum of the total revenues of the District of Columbia for such fiscal year or $20,018,896,595 (of which $10,853,426,907 shall be from local funds, $554,595,383 shall be from dedicated taxes, $1,708,026,208 shall be from federal grant funds, $2,700,216,789 shall be from Medicaid payments, $770,858,155 shall be from other funds, $12,463,835 shall be from private grant funds, $854,320 shall be from private donations; $357,960,302 shall be from funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress as federal payments pursuant to the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2023, passed on May 24, 2022 (Enrolled version of Bill 24-715) ("the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022") and federal payment funds for COVID relief, $163,789,508 shall be from enterprise and other funds – dedicated taxes, and $2,896,705,186 shall be from enterprise and other funds); provided further, that of the local funds, such amounts as may be necessary may be derived from the General Fund balance; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this act may be increased by proceeds of one-time transactions, which are expended for emergency or unanticipated operating or capital needs; provided further, that such increases shall be approved by enactment of local District law and shall comply with all reserve requirements contained in the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 774; D.C. Official Code § 1-201.01 <em>et seq.</em>); provided further, that local funds are appropriated, without regard to fiscal year, in such amounts as may be necessary to pay vendor fees, including legal fees, that are obligated in this fiscal year, to be paid as a fixed percentage of District revenue recovered from third parties on behalf of the District under contracts that provide for payment of fees based upon and from such District revenue as may be recovered by the vendor; provided further, that amounts appropriated pursuant to this act as operating funds may be transferred to enterprise and capital funds and such amounts, once transferred, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this act; provided further, that there may be reprogrammed or transferred for operating expenses any local funds transferred or reprogrammed in this or the 4 prior fiscal years from operating funds to capital funds, and such amounts, once transferred or reprogrammed, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this act; except, that there may not be reprogrammed for operating expenses any funds derived from bonds, notes, or other obligations issued for capital projects; provided further, that the local funds (including dedicated taxes) and other funds appropriated by this act may be reprogrammed and transferred as provided in subchapter IV of Chapter 3 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, or as otherwise provided by law, through November 15, 2023; provided further, that local funds and other funds appropriated under this act may be expended by the Mayor for the purpose of providing food and beverages, not to exceed $30 per employee per day, to employees of the District of Columbia government while such employees are deployed in response to or during a declared snow or other emergency; provided further, that local funds and other funds appropriated under this act may be expended by the Mayor to provide food and lodging, in amounts not to exceed the General Services Administration per diem rates, for youth, young adults, and their parents or guardians who participate in a program of the District of Columbia government that involves overnight travel outside the District of Columbia; provided further, that notwithstanding any other provision of law, local funds are appropriated, without regard to fiscal year, to the extent such funds are certified as available by the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, to pay termination costs of multiyear contracts entered into by the District of Columbia during this fiscal year, to design, construct, improve, maintain, operate, manage, or finance infrastructure projects procured pursuant to the Public-Private Partnership Act of 2014, effective March 11, 2015 (D.C. Law 20-228; D.C. Official Code § 2-271.01 <em>et seq</em>.), including, by way of example and not limitation, a project for the replacement and modernization of the District of Columbia's streetlight system and a project for the rehabilitation and modernization of the Henry J. Daly Building, and such termination costs may be paid from appropriations available for the performance of such contracts or the payment of termination costs or from other appropriations then available for any other purpose, not including the emergency cash reserve fund (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.50a(a)) or the contingency cash reserve fund (D.C. Official Code § 1-204.50a(b)), which, once allocated to these costs, shall be deemed appropriated for the purposes of paying termination costs of such contracts and shall retain appropriations authority and remain available until expended; provided further, that during Fiscal Year 2023 and any subsequent fiscal year, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the District of Columbia may enter into annual and multiyear agreements with the National Park Service for the purposes of planning, designing, constructing, maintaining, improving, and operating District of Columbia transportation infrastructure and related appurtenances on National Park Service land in the District of Columbia, and may in each fiscal year of such agreement expend such funds to implement the agreement as may be appropriated and available in that fiscal year for such purposes; provided further, that notwithstanding subchapter IV of Chapter 3 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, in Fiscal Year 2023, amounts appropriated from funds received from the federal government under the American Rescue Plan Act, approved March 11, 2021 (Pub. L. No. 117-2; 135 Stat. 4) ("ARPA") or the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act, approved March 27, 2020 (Pub. L. No. 116-136; 134 Stat. 281) ("CARES Act") may be transferred or reprogrammed between appropriated funds, consistent with the requirements of the ARPA and the CARES Act and consistent with the purpose for which the funds are appropriated under this act, upon the request of the Mayor to the Chief Financial Officer and certification of the availability of the funds by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, and such amounts, once transferred, shall retain appropriation authority consistent with the provisions of this act; provided further, that amounts appropriated from funds received from the federal government under the ARPA and the CARES Act shall be available until expended, provided that such funds are expended for the same purpose for which the funds are appropriated under this act; provided further, that any unspent amount remaining in a non-lapsing fund described below at the end of Fiscal Year 2022 is to be continually available, allocated, appropriated, and expended for the purposes of such fund in Fiscal Year 2023 in addition to any amounts deposited in and appropriated to such fund in Fiscal Year 2023; provided further, that the Chief Financial Officer shall take such steps as are necessary to assure that the foregoing requirements are met, including the apportioning by the Chief Financial Officer of the appropriations and funds made available during Fiscal Year 2023.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="governmental-direction-and-support">
      <heading>Governmental Direction and Support</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Governmental direction and support, $1,139,847,571 (including $995,276,311 from local funds, $703,347 from dedicated taxes, $37,012,921 from federal grant funds, $288,317 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, $105,089,449 from other funds, $809,466 from private grant funds, and $667,760 from private donations funds), to be allocated as follows; provided, that any program fees collected from the issuance of debt shall be available for the payment of expenses of the debt management program of the District:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Board of Elections. $11,869,576 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Board of Ethics and Government Accountability. $3,977,407 (including $3,779,946 from local funds and $197,461 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Ethics Fund, the Lobbyist Administration and Enforcement Fund, and the Open Government Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Captive Insurance Agency. $10,479,928 (including $9,793,411 from local funds and $686,517 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Captive Trust Fund, the Medical Captive Insurance Claims Reserve Fund, and the Subrogation Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Contract Appeals Board. $1,984,453 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Council of the District of Columbia. $32,879,230 from local funds; provided, that not to exceed $25,000 of this amount shall be available for the Chairman for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that funds appropriated under this act may be used to pay expenses for employees of the Council of the District of Columbia to obtain or maintain professional credentials in the District that are related to their employment at the Council, including bar admission fees, bar dues and fees, court admission fees, and examinations to obtain such credentials; provided further, that funds appropriated under this act may be used for uniform shirts for employees of the Council of the District of Columbia; provided further, that amounts provided under this heading shall be available for the making of payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the Council; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Council Technology Projects Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Department of General Services. $385,456,306 (including $380,069,744 from local funds, $703,347 from dedicated taxes, and $4,683,214 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Eastern Market Enterprise Fund and the West End Library and Fire Station Maintenance Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Department of Human Resources. $22,149,562 (including $13,495,765 from local funds and $8,653,797 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Employees' Compensation Fund. $22,219,334 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Executive Office of the Mayor. $21,299,089 (including $15,793,112 from local funds, $4,696,511 from federal grant funds, and $809,466 from private funds); provided, that not to exceed $25,000 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Mayor for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Emancipation Day Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Mayor's Office of Legal Counsel. $1,754,855 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments. $1,205,533 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commissions. $2,575,153 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Technical Support and Assistance Fund and the Office of Advisory Neighborhood Commission Security Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Office of Campaign Finance. $7,473,090 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Fair Elections Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Office of Contracting and Procurement. $31,432,381 (including $29,821,868 from local funds and $1,610,514 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Office of Disability Rights. $2,079,929 (including $1,452,359 from local funds and $627,570 from federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Office of Employee Appeals. $2,310,711 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>Office of Finance and Resource Management. $32,542,783 (including $32,297,527 from local funds and $245,256 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>Office of Labor Relations and Collective Bargaining. $3,163,254 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(19)</num>
          <text>Office of Risk Management. $4,092,910 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Subrogation Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(20)</num>
          <text>Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. $147,830,658 (including $95,349,588 from local funds, $27,896,281 from federal grant funds, $288,317 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, $23,628,712  from other funds, and $667,760 from private funds); provided, that not to exceed $25,000 of this amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that local and other funds appropriated under this act may be used to pay expenses for District government attorneys at the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia to obtain professional credentials, including bar dues and court admission fees, that enable these attorneys to practice law in other state and federal jurisdictions and appear outside the District in state and federal courts; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Child Support-Reimbursements and Fees Fund, the Child Support-Interest Income Fund, the Child Support-Temporary Assistance for Needy Families Fund, the Drug-, Firearm-, or Prostitution-Related Nuisance Abatement Fund, and the Litigation Support Fund; provided further, that this amount may be further increased by amounts deposited into the Attorney General Restitution Fund, the Vulnerable and Elderly Person Exploitation Restitution Fund, and the Tenant Receivership Abatement Fund, which shall be continually available, without regard to fiscal year, until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(21)</num>
          <text>Office of the Chief Financial Officer. $230,714,129 (including $178,922,417  from local funds, $675,000 from federal grant funds, and $51,116,712 from other funds); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Chief Financial Officer for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that amounts appropriated by this act may be increased by the amount required to pay banking fees for maintaining the funds of the District of Columbia; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Other Post-Employment Benefits Fund, the Recorder of Deeds Automation Fund, and the Child Trust Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(22)</num>
          <text>Office of the Chief Technology Officer. $93,323,910 (including $81,061,643 from local funds and $12,262,266 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the DC-NET Services and Innovation Fund and the Technology Infrastructure Services Support Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(23)</num>
          <text>Office of the City Administrator. $12,221,190 from local funds; provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the City Administrator for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(24)</num>
          <text>Office of the District of Columbia Auditor. $7,676,064 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Audit Engagement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(25)</num>
          <text>Office of the Inspector General. $25,584,465 (including $21,466,906 from local funds, $1,000,000 from other funds and $3,117,559 from federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Inspector General Support Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(26)</num>
          <text>Office of the Secretary. $5,243,080 (including $4,243,080 from local funds and $1,000,000 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(27)</num>
          <text>Office of the Senior Advisor. $4,546,309 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(28)</num>
          <text>Office of Veterans Affairs. $1,160,798 (including $1,155,798 from local funds and $5,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(29)</num>
          <text>Office on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs. $1,502,328 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(30)</num>
          <text>Office on Latino Affairs. $6,433,626 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(31)</num>
          <text>Public Employee Relations Board. $1,362,828 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(32)</num>
          <text>Statehood Initiatives. $247,763 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the New Columbia Statehood Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(33)</num>
          <text>Tax Revision Commission. $994,688 from local funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(34)</num>
          <text>Uniform Law Commission. $60,250 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="economic-development-and-regulation">
      <heading>Economic Development and Regulation</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Economic development and regulation, $901,602,438 (including $673,909,366 from local funds, $45,299,000 from dedicated taxes, $59,322,910 from federal grant funds, $79,724,795 from other funds, and $43,346,367 from federal payment funds for COVID relief), to be allocated as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Business Improvement Districts Transfer. $56,850,000 (including $1,850,000 from local funds and $55,000,000 from other funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Commission on the Arts and Humanities. $45,202,000 (including $44,399,000  from dedicated taxes and $803,000 from federal grant funds); provided, that all dedicated taxes shall be deposited into the Arts and Humanities Fund; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Arts and Humanities Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023; provided further, that funds in the available fund balance of the Arts and Humanities Fund may be obligated in Fiscal Year 2023 pursuant to grant awards, through September 30, 2026, and that such funds so obligated are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2026;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Department of Housing and Community Development. $99,811,720  (including $35,467,870 from local funds, $57,431,850 from federal grant funds, and $6,912,000  from other funds); provided, that of such funds, the funds allocated to the District from the Homeowner Assistance Fund established under section 3206 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021, approved March 11, 2021 (135 Stat. 63;  15 U.S.C. § 9058d), shall remain available until expended; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Department of Housing and Community Development Unified Fund, the Home Again Revolving Fund, the Home Purchase Assistance Program-Repayment Fund, the Housing Preservation Fund, the Negotiated Employee Affordable Housing Fund, the Rent Supplement Program Project-Based Allocation Fund, and the Section 108 Debt Reserve Account; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Rental Housing Registration Fund are authorized for expenditure starting at the beginning of the applicable time period set forth section in 203e(d) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective October 30, 2018 (D.C. Law 22-168; D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.03e(d)), and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Department of Small and Local Business Development. $23,083,613 (including $22,530,553 from local funds and $553,060 from federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Medical Cannabis Social Equity Fund, the Small Business Capital Access Fund, the Small Business Licensing Fee Reimbursement Relief Fund, the Streetscape Business Development Relief Fund, and the Ward 7 and Ward 8 Entrepreneur Grant Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Housing Authority Subsidy. $185,662,686 from local funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the DCHA Rehabilitation and Maintenance Fund, the Housing Authority Rent Supplement Program Fund, and the Tenant-Based Rental Assistance Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Housing Production Trust Fund Subsidy. $354,197,301 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Office of Cable Television, Film, Music, and Entertainment. $15,697,188 (including $3,215,535 from local funds, $11,731,653 from other funds, and $750,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Film, Television, and Entertainment Rebate Fund and the OCTFME Special Account;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Office of Planning. $17,335,454 (including $16,700,454 from local funds, $535,000 from federal grant funds, and $100,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Historic Landmark-District Protection (Local) Fund and the Historical Landmark-District Protection (O-Type) Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development. $91,544,020 (including $43,221,926 from local funds, $900,000 from dedicated taxes, $5,337,407 from other funds, and $42,084,687 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Economic Development Special Account, the H Street Retail Priority Area Grant Fund, the Industrial Revenue Bond Account, the Soccer Stadium Financing Fund, the St. Elizabeths East Campus Redevelopment Fund, the Walter Reed Redevelopment Fund, and the Walter Reed Reinvestment Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Office of the Tenant Advocate. $4,685,256 (including $3,529,841 from local funds, $643,736 from other funds, and $511,680 from federal payment funds for COVID relief);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Office of Zoning. $4,142,436 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Real Property Tax Appeals Commission. $2,033,852 from local funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Rental Housing Commission. $1,356,912 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="public-safety-and-justice">
      <heading>Public Safety and Justice</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Public safety and justice, $1,711,976,627 (including $1,378,272,838 from local funds, $255,608,070 from federal grant funds, $300,000 from Medicaid payments, $37,856,185 from other funds, $630,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, $600,000 requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, $2,450,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, $35,394,351 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, and $865,184 from private grant funds), to be allocated as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure. $979,329 (including $649,329 from local funds and $330,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Corrections Information Council. $1,158,047 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Criminal Code Reform Commission. $960,224 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Criminal Justice Coordinating Council. $4,779,656 (including $2,179,656 from local funds, $150,000 from federal grant funds, and $2,450,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment to the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Department of Corrections. $200,116,628 (including $185,525,725 from local funds and $14,590,903 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Correction Reimbursement-Juveniles Fund, the Department of Corrections Reimbursement Fund, and the Inmate Welfare Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Department of Forensic Sciences. $32,819,004 (including $30,944,840 from local funds, $1,008,981 from federal grant funds, and $865,184 from private grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Department of Forensic Sciences Laboratory Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services. $89,580,423 (including $89,190,423 from local funds and $390,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia National Guard. $16,827,820 (including $5,830,260  from local funds, $10,250,047 from federal grant funds, $147,514 from other funds, and $600,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for the District of Columbia National Guard" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022); provided, that the Mayor shall reimburse the District of Columbia National Guard for expenses incurred in connection with services that are performed in emergencies by the National Guard in a militia status and are requested by the Mayor, in amounts that shall be jointly determined and certified as due and payable for these services by the Mayor and the Commanding General of the District of Columbia National Guard; provided further, that such sums as may be necessary for reimbursement to the District of Columbia National Guard under the preceding proviso shall be available pursuant to this act, and the availability of the sums shall be deemed as constituting payment in advance for emergency services involved;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Sentencing Commission. $1,618,202 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department. $316,396,944 (including $268,597,955 from local funds, $1,006,372 from other funds, and $46,792,617 from federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department EMS Reform Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency. $190,048,784 (including $6,018,527 from local funds and $184,030,257 from federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Judicial Nomination Commission. $307,569 (including $7,569 from local funds and $300,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Judicial Commissions" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Metropolitan Police Department. $526,084,233 (including $515,695,924 from local funds, $4,007,432 from federal grant funds, $6,021,877 from other funds; and $359,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Asset Forfeiture Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Office of Administrative Hearings. $11,991,337 (including $11,691,337 from local funds and $300,000 from Medicaid payments);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>Office of Human Rights. $9,670,558 (including $9,262,777 from local funds and $407,781 from federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement. $35,232,928 (including $20,209,658 from local funds and $15,023,270 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that the Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement is authorized to spend appropriated funds for the purposes set forth in section 101 of the Neighborhood Engagement Achieves Results Amendment Act of 2016, effective June 30, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-125; D.C. Official Code § 7-2411); provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Neighborhood Safety and Engagement Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>Office of Police Complaints. $2,964,584 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(18)</num>
          <text>Office on Returning Citizen Affairs. $2,751,097 (including $2,134,297 from local funds and $616,800 from federal payment funds for COVID relief);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(19)</num>
          <text>Office of the Chief Medical Examiner. $15,412,039 (including $14,792,723 from local funds and $619,316 from federal grants); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(20)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice. $2,989,539 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(21)</num>
          <text>Office of Unified Communications. $61,125,072 (including $46,144,985 from local funds, and $14,980,087 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Emergency and Non-Emergency Number Telephone Calling Systems Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(22)</num>
          <text>Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants. $110,654,612 (including $82,198,259 from local funds, $8,341,640 from federal grant funds, $1,109,432 from other funds, and $19,005,281 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that $31,689,347 shall be made available to award a grant to the District of Columbia Bar Foundation for the purpose of administering the Access to Justice Initiative and the Civil Legal Counsel Projects Program, of which not less than $950,000 shall be available to fund the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Repayment Assistance Program, and of which not less than $11,000,000 shall be available to fund the Civil Legal Counsel Projects Program; provided further, that the funds authorized for expenditure for the Access to Justice Initiative, the District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Repayment Assistance Program, and the Civil Legal Counsel Projects Program shall remain available for expenditure, without regard to fiscal year, until September 30, 2023; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Community-Based Violence Reduction Fund, the Crime Victims Assistance Fund, the Private Security Camera Incentive Fund, and the Shelter and Transitional Housing for Victims of Domestic Violence Fund; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(23)</num>
          <text>Police Officers' and Firefighters' Retirement System. $77,508,000 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="public-education-system">
      <heading>Public Education System</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Public education system, $4,116,548,286 (including $3,056,760,934 from local funds, $7,214,990 from dedicated taxes, $792,788,972 from federal grant funds, $86,045,086 from other funds, $20,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, $35,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022 for the purposes specified in section 3004(b) of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act, approved April 15, 2011 (125 Stat 200; D.C. Official Code § 38-1853.04(b)), $111,126,790 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, and $7,611,515 from private funds), to be allocated as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Department of Employment Services. $220,724,748 (including $71,458,267 from local funds, $46,771,843 from federal grant funds, $57,126,630 from other funds, $928,008 from private funds, and $44,440,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Reed Act Fund, the Unemployment Insurance Administrative Assessment Tax Fund, the Unemployment Insurance Interest/Penalties Fund, the Universal Paid Leave Fund, the Workers' Compensation Administration Fund, and the Workers' Compensation Special Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Department of Parks and Recreation. $85,184,972 (including $82,459,051 from local funds, $2,058,598 from other funds, and $667,323 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Recreation Enterprise Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023; provided further, that the Department of Parks and Recreation is authorized to spend appropriated funds from the Recreation Enterprise Fund for the purposes set forth in section 4 of the Recreation Act of 1994, effective March 23, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-246; D.C. Official Code § 10-303);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Charter School Board. $13,100,480 from other funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Charter Schools. $1,108,273,946 from local funds; provided, that there shall be quarterly disbursement of funds to the District of Columbia public charter schools, with the first payment to occur within 15 days of the beginning of the fiscal year; provided further, that if the entirety of this allocation has not been provided as payments to any public charter schools currently in operation through the per pupil funding formula, the funds shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023 for public education in accordance with section 2403(b)(2) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.03(b)(2)); provided further, that of the amounts made available to District of Columbia public charter schools, $230,000 shall be made available to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer as authorized by section 2403(b)(6) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.03(b)(6)); provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the District of Columbia public charter schools on July 1, 2023, an amount equal to 35 percent, or for new charter school local education agencies that opened for the first time after December 31, 2022, an amount equal to 45 percent, of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for payments to public charter schools in the budget of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2024 (as adopted by the District), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for such payments for Fiscal Year 2024; provided further, that the annual financial audit for the performance of an individual District of Columbia public charter school shall be funded by the charter school;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Library. $77,025,162 (including $74,504,712 from local funds, $1,103,450 from federal grant funds, $1,400,000 from other funds, and $17,000 from private funds); provided, that not to exceed $8,500 of such amount, from local funds, shall be available for the Chief Librarian of the District of Columbia Public Library for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Copies and Printing Fund, the E-Rate Reimbursement Fund, the Library Collections Account, the Books From Birth Fund, and the DCPL Revenue-Generating Activities Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Public Schools. $1,167,504,286 (including $1,103,393,324 from local funds, $29,631,009 from federal grant funds, $10,649,378 from other funds, $6,330,575 from private funds, and $17,500,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022); provided, that not to exceed $10,600 of such local funds shall be available for the Chancellor for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10); provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the District of Columbia Public Schools on July 1, 2023, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for the District of Columbia Public Schools in the budget of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2024 (as adopted by the District), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the District of Columbia Public Schools for Fiscal Year 2024; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the At-Risk Supplemental Allocation Preservation Fund, the Afterschool Program-Copayment Fund, the DCPS School Facility Colocation Fund, the District of Columbia Public Schools' Nonprofit School Food Service Fund, the District of Columbia Public Schools Sales and Sponsorship Fund, the E-Rate Education Fund, and the Reserve Officer Training Corps Fund; provided further, that the District of Columbia Public Schools is authorized to spend appropriated funds consistent with section 105(c)(5) of the Public Education Reform Amendment Act of 2007, effective June 12, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-9; D.C. Official Code § 38-174(c)(5));</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia State Athletics Commission. $1,342,282 (including $1,242,282 from local funds and $100,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the State Athletic Activities, Programs, and Office Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Non-Public Tuition. $59,069,776 (including $58,469,776 from local funds and $600,000 from federal grant funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Education. $51,469,557 (including $28,812,307 from local funds, $115,000 from private funds, and $22,542,250 from federal payment funds for COVID relief);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Office of the State Superintendent of Education. $1,058,269,637 (including $262,980,830 from local funds, $7,214,990 from dedicated taxes, $705,682,669 from federal grant funds, $1,610,000 from other funds, $220,932 from private funds, $17,500,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for School Improvement" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022 for the purposes specified in section 3004(b) of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act, approved April 15, 2011 (125 Stat 200; D.C. Official Code § 38-1853.04(b)), $20,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Resident Tuition Support" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, and $43,060,217 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Access to Quality Child Care Fund, the Charter School Credit Enhancement Fund, the Child Development Facilities Fund, the Common Lottery Board Fund, the Community Schools Fund, the Early Childhood Development Fund, the Healthy Schools Fund, the Healthy Tots Fund, the School Safety and Positive Climate Fund, the Special Education Enhancement Fund, the Statewide Special Education Compliance Fund, the Student Enrollment Fund, the Student Residency Verification Fund, and the Early Childhood Educator Pay Equity Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Special Education Transportation. $122,102,334 (including $113,102,334 from local funds and $9,000,000 in federal grant funds); provided, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the Special Education Transportation agency under the direction of the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, on July 1, 2023, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for the Special Education Transportation agency in the budget for the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2024 (as adopted by the District), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the Special Education Transportation agency for Fiscal Year 2024; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this paragraph may be used to offer financial incentives as necessary to reduce the number of routes serving 2 or fewer students;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>State Board of Education. $2,717,332 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Teachers' Retirement System. $47,835,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Unemployment Compensation Fund. $5,480,390 from local funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>University of the District of Columbia Subsidy Account. $96,448,383 (including $96,031,383 from local funds and $417,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that this appropriation shall not be available to subsidize the education of nonresidents of the District at the University of the District of Columbia, unless the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia adopts, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, a tuition-rate schedule that establishes the tuition rate for nonresident students at a level no lower than the nonresident tuition rate charged at comparable public institutions of higher education in the metropolitan area; provided further, that, notwithstanding the amounts otherwise provided under this heading or any other provision of law, there shall be appropriated to the University of the District of Columbia on July 1, 2023, an amount equal to 10 percent of the total amount of the local funds appropriations provided for the University of the District of Columbia in the budget of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2024 (as adopted by the District), and the amount of such payment shall be chargeable against the final amount provided for the University of the District of Columbia for Fiscal Year 2024; provided further, that not to exceed $10,600 of such local funds shall be available for the President of the University of the District of Columbia for official reception and representation expenses and for purposes consistent with the Discretionary Funds Act of 1973, approved October 26, 1973 (87 Stat. 509; D.C. Official Code § 1-333.10).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="human-support-services">
      <heading>Human Support Services</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Human support services, $5,769,153,656 (including $2,381,579,467 from local funds, $105,305,077 from dedicated taxes, $485,209,038 from federal grant funds, $44,719,697 from other funds, $2,699,916,789 from Medicaid payments, $892,552 from private funds, $5,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, and $46,531,036 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); to be allocated as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Child and Family Services Agency. $222,532,204 (including $161,065,175 from local funds, $60,462,469 from federal grant funds, $1,000,000 from other funds, and $4,560 from private funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Department of Aging and Community Living. $66,419,910 (including $52,185,960 from local funds, $10,966,715 from federal grant funds, and $3,267,235 from Medicaid payments);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Department of Behavioral Health. $377,018,932 (including $305,681,032 from local funds, $200,000 from dedicated taxes, $55,041,715 from federal grant funds, $2,742,751 from Medicaid payments, $2,673,080 from other funds, $522,290 private funds, and $10,158,064 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration-Choice in Drug Treatment (HCSN) Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Department of Health. $283,955,264 (including $98,469,027 from local funds, $158,594,599 from federal grant funds, $21,891,637 from other funds, and $5,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Testing and Treatment of HIV/AIDS" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Animal Education and Outreach Fund, the Board of Medicine Fund, the Civil Monetary Penalties Fund, the Communicable and Chronic Disease Prevention and Treatment Fund, the Health Professional Recruitment Fund (Medical Loan Repayment), the Howard University Hospital Centers of Excellence Fund, the Human Services Facility Fee Fund, the ICF/MR Fees and Fines Fund, the Opioid Abatement Fund; the Pharmacy Protection Fund, the State Health Planning and Development Agency Admission Fee Fund, and the State Health Planning and Development Agency Fees Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Department of Health Care Finance. $3,736,526,743 (including $954,955,220 from local funds, $105,105,077 from dedicated taxes, $5,174,115 from federal grant funds, $2,663,283,088 from Medicaid payments, $5,643,542 from other funds, $2,000,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, and $365,701 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Bill of Rights (Grievance and Appeals) Fund, the DC HealthCare Alliance Reform Fund, the Healthy DC and Health Care Expansion Fund, the Home and Community-Based Services Enhancement Fund, the Hospital Provider Fee Fund, the Hospital Fund, the Individual Insurance Market Affordability and Stability Fund, the Medicaid Collections-3rd Party Liability Fund, the Nursing Facility Quality of Care Fund, and the Stevie Sellow's Quality Improvement Fund,;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Department of Human Services. $865,110,007 (including $653,200,916 from local funds, $160,643,157 from federal grant funds, $796,427 from other funds, $16,195,054 from federal Medicaid payments, and $34,274,452 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Rent Supplement Program Tenant-Based Allocation Fund, the SNAP Reinvestment Fund, and the SSI Payback Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Department on Disability Services. $197,975,632 (including $136,407,171 from local funds, $34,326,268 from federal grant funds, $14,428,661 from Medicaid payments, $12,715,012 from other funds, and $98,520 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Contribution to Costs of Supports Fund, the Cost of Care for Non-Medicaid Clients Fund, and the Randolph Shepherd Unassigned Facilities Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation Subsidy. $15,000,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Office for the Deaf, Deafblind, and Hard of Hearing. $818,747 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Health and Human Services. $2,861,218 from local funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Office of the Ombudsperson for Children. $935,000 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="operations-and-infrastructure">
      <heading>Operations and Infrastructure</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Public works, $1,349,899,990 (including $898,586,868 from local funds, $73,183,388 from dedicated taxes, $59,619,309 from federal grant funds, $287,819,746 from other funds, $2,457,679 from private grant funds, $14,000 from private donations, and $28,219,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief), to be allocated as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration. $10,879,724 (including $385,192 from local funds, $1,379,388 from dedicated taxes, and $9,115,144 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Administration Fund, the Dedicated Taxes Fund, and the Medical Cannabis Administration Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Department of Buildings. $65,754,333 (including $45,633,476 from local funds, $4,328,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, and $15,792,857 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Green Building Fund, the Nuisance Abatement Fund, and the Expedited Building Permit Review Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Department of Licensing and Community Protection. $37,662,662 (including $7,998,793 from local funds, $28,772,869 from other funds, and $891,000 from federal payments for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Appraisal Fee Fund, the Basic Business License Fund, the Corporate Recordation Fund, the DC Combat Sports Commission Fund, the Occupational and Professional Licensing Administration Special Account, the Real Estate Guaranty and Education Fund, and the Vending Regulation Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Department of Energy and Environment. $225,490,440 (including $66,594,419 from local funds, $36,954,341 from federal grant funds, $96,484,002 from other funds, $2,457,679 from private funds, and $23,000,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Air Quality Construction Permits Fund, the Anacostia River Clean Up and Protection Fund, the Benchmarking Enforcement Fund, the Clean Land Fund/Brownfield Revitalization Fund, the Clean Rivers Impervious Area Charge Assistance Fund the District of Columbia Wetland Stream and Mitigation Trust Fund, the Economy II Fund, the Energy Assistance Trust Fund, the Fishing License Fund, the Hazardous Waste and Toxic Chemical Source Reduction Fund, the Indoor Mold Assessment and Remediation Fund, the Lead Service Line Replacement Fund the Lead Poisoning Prevention Fund, the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund, the Municipal Aggregation Fund, the Pesticide Product Registration Fund, the Product Stewardship Fund, the Rail Safety and Security Fund, the Renewable Energy Development Fund, the Residential Aid Discount Fund, the Residential Essential Services Fund, the Soil Erosion and Sediment Control Fund, the Special Energy Assessment Fund, the Stormwater Fees Fund, the Stormwater In-Lieu Fee Payment Fund, the Storm Water Permit Review Fund, the Sustainable Energy Trust Fund, the Underground Storage Tank Regulation Fund, and the WASA Utility Discount Program Fund; provided further, that funds in the available fund balance of the Renewable Energy Development Fund may be obligated in Fiscal Year 2023, pursuant to grant awards, through September 30, 2026, and that such funds so obligated are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2026;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Department of For-Hire Vehicles. $22,683,450 (including $12,040,674 from local funds and $10,642,777 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund and the Taxicab Assessment Act Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking. $37,397,902 (including $2,004,931 from local funds, $35,225,107 from other funds, and $167,864 from federal grant funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Capital Access Fund, the Foreclosure Mediation Fund, the Insurance Assessment Fund, the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund, and the Securities and Banking Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Department of Motor Vehicles. $55,318,875 (including $45,859,425 from local funds, $129,500 from federal grant funds, and $9,329,950 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Department of Motor Vehicles Kiosk Fund and the Motor Vehicle Inspection Station Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Department of Public Works. $188,618,856 (including $176,905,719 from local funds and $11,713,137 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Solid Waste Disposal Cost Recovery Special Account and the Super Can Program Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>District Department of Transportation. $192,355,336 (including $149,839,732 from local funds, $21,786,604 from federal grant funds, and $20,729,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Bicycle Sharing Fund, the DC Circulator Fund, the DDOT Enterprise Fund-Non Tax Revenues Fund, the Parking Meter and Transit Services Pay-by-Phone Transaction Fee Fund, the Performance Parking Program Fund, the Sustainable Transportation Fund, the Transportation Infrastructure Project Review Fund, the Tree Fund, the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund, and the Vision Zero Enhancement Omnibus Amendment Act Implementation Fund; provided further, that there are appropriated any amounts received, or to be received, without regard to fiscal year, from the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors, or assigns, for the purpose of paying or reimbursing the District Department of Transportation for the costs of designing, constructing, acquiring, and installing facilities, infrastructure, and equipment for use and ownership by the Potomac Electric Power Company, or any of its related companies, successors, or assigns, related to or associated with the undergrounding of electric distribution lines in the District of Columbia, and any interest earned on those funds, which amounts and interest shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund at the end of a fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation until expended for the designated purposes;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Office of the Deputy Mayor for Operations and Infrastructure. $1,282,808 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Office of the People's Counsel. $12,280,003 (including $1,012,875 from local funds and $11,267,128 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Office of People's Counsel Agency Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Public Service Commission. $18,842,775 (including $581,000 from federal grant funds, $18,247,775 from other funds, and $14,000 from private funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the PJM Settlement Fund and the Public Service Commission Agency Fund;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. $481,168,847 (including $388,864,847 from local funds, $71,804,000 from dedicated taxes, and $20,500,000 from other funds); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the following funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023: the Dedicated Taxes Fund and the Parking Meter WMATA Fund; provided further, that all funds budgeted without regard to fiscal year for the adult learner transit subsidy program established by section 6047 of the Student, Foster Youth, Summer Youth Employee, and Adult Learner Transit Subsidies Act of 2019, effective September 11, 2019 (D.C. Law 23-16; D.C. Official Code § 35-246), are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023; provided further, that there are appropriated any amounts deposited, or to be deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Dedicated Financing Fund for the purpose of funding WMATA capital improvements, which amounts shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund at the end of a fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available until expended for the designated purposes; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Commission. $163,978 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="financing-and-other">
      <heading>Financing and Other</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>Financing and Other, $1,885,152,347 (including $1,374,042,636 from local funds, $321,289,582 from dedicated taxes, $18,464,988 from federal grant funds, $140,105,141 from other funds, $30,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022, and $1,250,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief), to be allocated as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Commercial Paper Program. $3,750,000 from local funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Convention Center Transfer. $121,912,602 (including $3,210,000 from local funds, $114,302,333 from dedicated taxes, and $4,400,269 from other funds); provided, that the amount of local funds appropriated for the Convention Center Transfer shall be increased by up to $20,000,000 pursuant to this act under the heading "Appropriation of Additional Resources";</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Debt Service - Issuance Costs. $11,000,000 from local funds for the payment of debt service issuance costs;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>District Retiree Health Contribution. $41,500,000 from local funds for a District Retiree Health Contribution;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Emergency Planning and Security Fund. $30,000,000 from federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022; provided, that, notwithstanding any other law, obligations and expenditures that are pending reimbursement under the heading "Federal Payment for Emergency Planning and Security Costs in the District of Columbia" may be charged to this appropriations heading;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Highway Transportation Fund. $27,537,019 (including $24,712,022 from dedicated taxes and $2,824,997 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>John A. Wilson Building Fund. $5,233,315 from local funds for expenses associated with the John A. Wilson building;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Non-Departmental Account. $16,124,962 (including $11,804,000 from local funds, $1,250,000 from federal payment funds for COVID relief, and $3,070,962 from other funds);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Pay-As-You-Go Capital Fund. $502,925,589 (including $203,028,676 from local funds, $178,500,000 from dedicated taxes, and $121,396,913 from other funds) to be transferred to the Capital Fund, in lieu of capital financing;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Repayment of Loans and Interest. $1,029,192,970 (including $1,002,315,982 from local funds, $18,464,988 from federal grant funds, and $8,412,000 from other funds), for payment of principal, interest, and certain fees directly resulting from borrowing by the District of Columbia to fund District of Columbia capital projects as authorized by sections 462, 475, and 490 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 774; D.C. Official Code §§ 1-204.62, 1-204.75, and 1-204.90);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Repayment of Revenue Bonds. $3,775,227 from dedicated taxes for the repayment of revenue bonds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Settlements and Judgments. $28,024,759 from local funds for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government; provided, that this amount may be increased by such sums as may be necessary for making refunds and for the payment of legal settlements or judgments that have been entered against the District of Columbia government and such sums may be paid from the applicable or available funds of the District of Columbia; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Workforce Investments Account. $64,175,904 from local funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="enterprise-and-other">
      <heading>Enterprise and Other</heading>
      <para>
        <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
        <text>The amount of $3,115,297,393 (including $2,951,507,885 from enterprise and other funds and $163,789,508 from enterprise and other funds - dedicated taxes), shall be provided to enterprise funds as follows; provided, that, in the event that revenue dedicated by local law to an enterprise fund exceeds the amount set forth as follows, the General Fund budget authority may be increased as needed to transfer all such revenue, pursuant to local law, to the enterprise fund:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Ballpark Revenue Fund. $31,506,744 (including $12,486,856 from enterprise and other funds and $19,019,888 from enterprise and other funds - dedicated taxes);</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Retirement Board. $42,778,952 from the earnings of the applicable retirement funds to pay legal, management, investment, and other fees and administrative expenses of the District of Columbia Retirement Board;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority. $686,403,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that not to exceed $25,000 of this amount shall be available for reception and representation expenses; provided further, that not to exceed $15,000 of this amount shall be available for official meetings. For construction projects, $5,852,392,000, to be distributed as follows: $1,128,686,000 for Wastewater Treatment; $1,294,041,000 for the Sanitary Sewer System; $1,664,117,000 for the Water System; $70,769,000 for Non Process Facilities; $1,064,899,000 for the Combined Sewer Overflow Program; $236,893,000 for the Washington Aqueduct; $58,205,000 for the Stormwater Program; and $334,783,000 for the capital equipment program; in addition, $8,000,000 for Federal payment funds requested to be appropriated by the Congress under the heading "Federal Payment to the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority" in the Fiscal Year 2023 Federal Portion Budget Request Act of 2022;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>Green Finance Authority. $44,794,000 from enterprise and other funds, to be available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Health Benefit Exchange Authority. $35,684,055 from enterprise and other funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Housing Finance Agency. $15,891,252 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that all funds budgeted without regard to fiscal year for the Reverse Mortgage Foreclosure Prevention Program are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023; provided further, that all funds budgeted without regard to fiscal year for the Public Housing Credit-Building Pilot Program are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2024;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>Housing Production Trust Fund. $444,008,253 (including $364,197,301 from enterprise and other funds and $79,810,952 from enterprise and other funds - dedicated taxes); provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Housing Production Trust Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023; provided further, that funds directed to the Housing Production Trust Fund at the close of a fiscal year pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02(j-5) shall be deposited into the Housing Production Trust Fund, and that such funds are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available until expended;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Not-For-Profit Hospital Corporation. $155,000,000 from enterprise and other funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(9)</num>
          <text>Office of Lottery and Gaming. $360,000,000 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that, after notification to the Mayor, amounts appropriated herein may be increased by an amount necessary for the Lottery, Gambling, and Gaming Fund to make transfers to the General Fund and to cover prizes, agent commissions, and gaming-related fees directly associated with unanticipated excess lottery revenues not included in this appropriation;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(10)</num>
          <text>Other Post-Employment Benefits Trust Administration. $11,605,000 from enterprise and other funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(11)</num>
          <text>Repayment of PILOT Financing. $32,683,349 from enterprise and other funds - dedicated taxes;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(12)</num>
          <text>Tax Increment Financing Program. $32,275,319 from enterprise and other funds - dedicated taxes;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(13)</num>
          <text>Unemployment Insurance Trust Fund. $176,682,095 from enterprise and other funds;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <text>Universal Paid Leave Fund. $539,053,417 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(15)</num>
          <text>University of the District of Columbia. $196,434,105 from enterprise and other funds; provided, that these funds shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of a fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for expenditure until September 30, 2023, without regard to fiscal year limitation; provided further, that all funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Higher Education Incentive Program Fund are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(16)</num>
          <text>Washington Aqueduct. $138,227,183 from enterprise and other funds; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(17)</num>
          <text>Washington Convention and Sports Authority. $172,270,670 from enterprise and other funds.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="reserve-accounts">
      <heading>Reserve Accounts</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Cash Flow Reserve Account. All funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Cash Flow Reserve Account, established pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02(j-2), are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account. All funds deposited, without regard to fiscal year, into the Fiscal Stabilization Reserve Account, established pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-392.02(j-1), are authorized for expenditure and shall remain available for expenditure until September 30, 2023.</text>
      </para>
    </container>
    <container name="capital-outlay">
      <heading>Capital Outlay</heading>
      <text>For capital construction projects, an increase of $4,340,615,000 of which $3,699,512,000 shall be from local funds, $64,268,000 shall be from local transportation funds, $57,405,000 shall be from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $519,430,000 shall be from federal grant funds, and a rescission of $268,723,000 of which $211,669,000 shall be from local funds, $55,295,000 shall be from local transportation funds $410,000 shall be from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, and $1,349,000 shall be from federal grant funds appropriated under this heading in prior fiscal years, for a net amount of $4,071,892,000, to remain available until expended; provided, that all funds provided by this act shall be available only for the specific projects and purposes intended; provided further, that amounts appropriated under this act may be increased by the amount transferred from funds appropriated in this act as Pay-AsYou-Go Capital funds.</text>
    </container>
    <container name="appropriation-of-additional-resources">
      <heading>Appropriation of Additional Resources</heading>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>The amount appropriated as local funds shall be increased by up to $20,000,000, which amount shall be authorized for obligation and expenditure pursuant to subsection (b) of this section if the September 2022 or December 2022 quarterly revenue estimates for local funds in Fiscal Year 2022 exceed the revenue estimate of the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia dated February 28, 2022.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(b)</num>
        <text>The funds authorized to be obligated and expended pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be allocated to the Convention Center Transfer to provide cash assistance to District residents who are excluded workers pursuant to section 203a(a) of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective December 3, 2020 (D.C. Law 23-149; D.C. Official Code § 10-1202.03a(a)).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(c)</num>
        <text>The District of Columbia may obligate and expend the increase in the amount of funds authorized by this section only if the Chief Financial Officer certifies the increase in revenue and certifies that the use of the amounts is not anticipated to have a negative impact on the long-term financial plan of the District.</text>
      </para>
    </container>
    <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.46" type="Budget Legislation" history="false">
    For the adoption of the local portion of the budget of the District of Columbia government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, see <cite doc="D.C. Law 24-166">the Fiscal Year 2023 Local Budget Act of 2022, effective September 9, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-166; 69 DCR 8870)</cite>.
  </codify:annotation>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Local portion of the budget.</heading>
    <text>The budget adopted pursuant to this act constitutes the local portion of the annual budget for the District of Columbia government under section 446(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46(a)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of September 30, 2022.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975. approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § l-30l.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>As provided in section 446(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.46(a)), this act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>