<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 24-208">
  <num type="law">24-208</num>
  <num type="act">24-604</num>
  <num type="bill">24-352</num>
  <heading type="short">Players Lounge Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide a real property tax exemption for property located at 2737 Martin Luther King Jr., Ave., S.E., in Lot 46, Square 5982, owned by the GST LLC.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-07-12</introduced>
    <effective>2022-12-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/47650/Signed_Act/B24-0352-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-208</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 13944</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0352">
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-10-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-10-31</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 24-352 would provide for  a real property tax exemption for Georgena’s Restaurant also known as the Players Lounge located at 2737 Martin Luther King Jr., Ave., S.E.. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Players Lounge Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <prefix>§</prefix>
          <num>47-1099.12</num>
          <heading>Players Lounge; Lot 46, Square 5982.</heading>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new section 47-1099.12 is added to read as follows:</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="47|10"/>
    <prefix>§</prefix>
    <num>47-1099.12</num>
    <heading>Players Lounge; Lot 46, Square 5982.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The real property, and any improvements on the property, located at 2737 Martin Luther King Jr., Ave., S.E., known for tax and assessment purposes as Lot 46, Square 5982, ("Property") shall be exempt from the tax imposed by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="47|8">Chapter 8 of this title</cite> for the period beginning October 1, 2019, and ending September 30, 2026, so long as the Property is owned by GST LLC and operated as Georgena's restaurant (also known as Players Lounge) ("Players Lounge").</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The tax exemption provided pursuant to this subsection shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to Players Lounge.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>The Council of the District of Columbia orders that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against Lot 46, Square 5982 for the period beginning on October 1, 2019, through the end of the month following the effective date of this act be forgiven and any payments made for this period be refunded to the person who made the payments.</heading>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
