<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-243">
  <num type="act">24-243</num>
  <num type="bill">24-425</num>
  <heading type="short">Council Vaccination Policy Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to allow the Chairman of the Council to take disciplinary action against Council employees for failure to comply with the Council COVID-19 Vaccination Policy.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-10-04</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2022-02-18</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47965/Signed_Act/B24-0425-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-243</citation>
      <citation type="register">68 DCR 013509</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0425">
      <vote date="2021-10-05" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2021-11-02" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2021-11-02" reading="Amendment"/>
      <enacted>2021-12-14</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Council Vaccination Policy Enforcement Temporary Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-601.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 406 (D.C. Official Code § 1-604.06) is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of enforcing the Council's COVID-19 Vaccination Policy ("policy"), the Chairman of the Council may, consistent with the policy, take disciplinary action against Council employees for failing to comply with the policy, up to and including termination. The Chairman's authority under this subsection, when exercised, shall supersede the authority granted to another councilmember pursuant to subsection (b)(3)(B) of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 905 (D.C. Official Code § 1-609.05) is amended by striking the phrase "employing them without" and inserting the phrase "employing them, or the Chairman of the Council pursuant to section 406(c), without" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
