<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-286">
  <num type="act">24-286</num>
  <num type="bill">24-432</num>
  <heading type="short">School Financial Transparency Amendment Act of 2021</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Board of Education Continuity and Transition Amendment Act of 2004 to extend the due date for the Mayor to submit a report to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education of the previous school year's actual expenditures for each school; to amend the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools Amendment Act of 1998 to extend the due date for every local education agency to provide the Office of the State Superintendent of Education with data related to the expenditures of at-risk student funding; and to amend the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995 to extend the due date for the Board of Trustees for each public charter school to submit actual expenditure data for the prior year to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education, and to clarify that the Board of Trustees for each public charter school need only submit the current school year's budget and the draft budget for the following school year  to the Public Charter School Board.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-10-07</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2022-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/47988/Signed_Act/B24-0432-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-286</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 000444</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0432">
      <vote date="2021-12-07" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2021-12-21" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-01-12</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 24-432 would align the local education agency (LEA) timelines of audited expenditure data, for the Common Financial Reporting Standards, with existing LEA auditing processes and timelines.  It would also streamline LEAs’ submission of audited expenditure data to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education with the existing process in place to collect financial data. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "School Financial Transparency Amendment Act of 2021".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 6(g) of the Board of Education Continuity and Transition Amendment Act of 2004, effective December 7, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-211; D.C. Official Code § 38-2831(g)), is amended by striking the phrase "By December 1, 2023" and inserting the phrase "By March 31, 2024" in its place.</text>
    <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2831|(g)" count="1">
      <find>By December 1, 2023</find>
      <replace>By March 31, 2024</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
  </section>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code" codify:path="§38-2905.01|(d)">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 106a(d) of the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools  Act of 1998, effective February 22, 2014 (D.C. Law 20-87; D.C. Official Code § 38-2905.01(d)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "Beginning December 31, 2023" and insert the phrase "By March 31, 2024" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>Beginning December 31, 2023</find>
        <replace>By March 31, 2024</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "such funds consistent" and insert the phrase "such funds for the previous school year consistent" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>such funds consistent</find>
        <replace>such funds for the previous school year consistent</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>Section 2204(c)(23) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 38-1802.04(c)(23)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <codify:replace doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-1802.04|(c)|(23)"/>
        <num>(23)</num>
        <heading>School expenditures and budgets. —</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>By March 31, 2024, and annually thereafter, the Board of Trustees of each public charter school shall prepare and submit to OSSE, for each campus under its control, actual expenditure data for the prior school year.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Beginning July 29, 2022, and annually thereafter, the Board of Trustees of each public charter school shall prepare and submit to the Public Charter School Board, for each campus under its control, the current school year's budget and a draft budget for the following school year.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>The data submitted pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph shall conform to the common financial reporting standards established by the Department of Education pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-191|(b)|(1)">section 202(b)(10) of the Department of Education Establishment Act of 2007, effective June 12, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-9; D.C. Official Code § 38-191(b)(10))</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>The Public Charter School Board shall electronically publish the data it receives pursuant to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph in a uniform manner for each school by November 1 of each year.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December</text>
    <text>24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
