<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 24-205">
  <num type="law">24-205</num>
  <num type="act">24-601</num>
  <num type="bill">24-145</num>
  <heading type="short">Navy Place Redesignation Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To redesignate Ellen Wilson Place, S.E., within Square 878, bounded by 6th Street, S.E., G Street, S.E., 7th Street, S.E., and I Street, S.E., as Navy Place, S.E.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-03-04</introduced>
    <effective>2022-12-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/46680/Signed_Act/B24-0145-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-205</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 13938</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0145">
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-10-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-10-31</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 24-145 re-designates the street known as Ellen Wilson Place, S.E., in Ward 6 as Navy Place S.E. </summary>
      <committee>Committee of the Whole</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Navy Place Redesignation Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Pursuant to sections 401 and 402(4), and notwithstanding section 421, of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code §§ 9-204.01, 9-204.02(4), and 9-204.21), the Council redesignates Ellen Wilson Place, S.E., within Square 878, bounded by 6th Street, S.E., G Street, S.E., 7th Street, S.E., and I Street, S.E., as depicted on the plat in the committee report, as "Navy Place, S.E.".</text>
    <codify:street-designation-anno action="the Council redesignates Ellen Wilson Place, S.E., within Square 878, bounded by 6th Street, S.E., G Street, S.E., 7th Street, S.E., and I Street, S.E., as depicted on the plat in the committee report, as &quot;Navy Place, S.E."/>
  </section>
  <section codify:doc="D.C. Code">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Title IV of the Street and Alley Closing and Acquisition Procedures Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-201; D.C. Official Code § 9-204.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§9-204.21">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 421 (D.C. Official Code § 9-204.21) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(b)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "At least 15 days, but not more than 60 days," and inserting the phrase "At least 15 days," in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>At least 15 days, but no more than 60 days,</find>
          <replace>At least 15 days,</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(f)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (f) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>At least 5 days before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate an official name for an alley or street, or portion thereof, the initiator of the proposal to designate the official name of an alley or street, or portion thereof, shall submit to the Council letters or a petition in support of the proposal that have been signed by a majority of the households occupying property that abuts the portion of the alley or street proposed to be designated with an official name.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Such petition shall include a list of each postal address on the alley or street, or portion thereof, to be designated with an official name, and the postal address of each household in support of the proposal (signed by a representative of the household).</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new subsection (j) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <codify:insert/>
            <num>(j)</num>
            <text>The requirements of subsections (b) through (e) of this section shall be waived if a resolution in support of the proposed designation is adopted by each Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the street, alley, or portion thereof, is located.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="§9-204.23|(b)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 423(b) (D.C. Official Code § 9-204.23(b)) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:replace/>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Before the date of a Council hearing to consider legislation to designate a symbolic name for an alley or street, or portion thereof, or other public space, the Council shall provide notice of the hearing to each Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which the portion of the alley or street or other public space to be designated is located.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
