<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Law 24-203">
  <num type="law">24-203</num>
  <num type="act">24-575</num>
  <num type="bill">24-919</num>
  <heading type="short">Notice Requirements for Evictions for Nonpayment of Rent Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to clarify notice requirements for evictions in non-payment of rent cases established by the Eviction Record Sealing and Fairness in Renting Amendment Act of 2022.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-07-11</introduced>
    <effective>2022-12-13</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/49987/Signed_Act/B24-0919-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Law 24-203</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 12687</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0919">
      <vote date="2022-07-12" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2022-09-20" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-10-17</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Notice Requirements for Evictions for Nonpayment of Rent Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 501(a-1) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code ยง 42-3505.01(a-1)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(a-1)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>A housing provider may recover possession of a rental unit for nonpayment of rent when the tenant fails to pay rent in an amount equal to at least $600.  The housing provider shall serve on the tenant a notice of past due rent at least 30 days in advance of action to recover possession of the rental unit."</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A notice of past due rent shall contain the following or substantively similar language:</text>
          <text>The total amount of rent owed is [list specific amount due]. A ledger showing the dates of rent charges and payments for the period of delinquency is attached. You have the right to remain in the rental unit if the total balance of unpaid rent is paid in full.</text>
          <text>[Name of housing provider] has the right to file a case in court seeking your eviction if you do not pay the balance of unpaid rent in full within 30 days of this notice.</text>
          <text>You have the right to defend yourself in court. Only a court can order your eviction. For further help or to seek free legal services, contact the Office of the Tenant Advocate at 202-719-6560 or the Landlord Tenant Legal Assistance Network at 202-780-2575.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December</text>
      <text>24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
