<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 24-314">
  <num type="act">24-314</num>
  <num type="bill">24-568</num>
  <heading type="short">DSLBD Noncompetitive Grant Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Department of Small and Local Business Development Grant Act of 2021 to clarify that the Friendship Heights Alliance is the intended recipient of a budgeted grant.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-12-20</introduced>
    <effective>2022-01-31</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/48454/Signed_Act/B24-0568-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-314</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 000852</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0568">
      <vote date="2021-12-21" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-01-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-01-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "DSLBD Noncompetitive Grant Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding Rule 730 of the Rules of Organization and Procedure for the Council of the District of Columbia, Council Period 24, Resolution of 2021, effective January 4, 2021 (Res. 24-1; 68 DCR 228), section 2112(c) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Grant Act of 2021, effective November 13, 2021 (D.C. Law 24-45; 68 DCR 10163), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as paragraph (1).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The newly designated paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "an organization partnering with property owners in the Friendship Heights neighborhood" and inserting the phrase "the Friendship Heights Alliance, to be awarded no later than January 31, 2022," in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (2) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Friendship Heights Alliance shall not be required to have or provide a receipt of a tax exempt status determination letter from the Internal Revenue Service or a charitable solicitation license in order to receive the grant required by this subsection.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813, D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
