<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-637">
  <num type="act">24-637</num>
  <num type="bill">24-61</num>
  <heading type="short">Stormiyah Denson-Jackson Economic Damages Equity Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide that in a civil action for personal injury or wrongful death, any estimations, measures, or calculations of past, present, or future damages for lost earnings or impaired earning capacity shall not be reduced based on actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, or gender identity or expression.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2021-01-29</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2023-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/46433/Signed_Act/B24-0061-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-637</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 14588</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0061">
      <vote date="2022-10-04" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-10-18" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-11-21</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Judiciary and Public Safety</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Stormiyah Denson-Jackson Economic Damages Equity Act of 2022".</text>
  <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="16" after="28" history="false">
    <container>
      <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
      <num>28A</num>
      <heading>Calculating Economic Damages.</heading>
    </container>
  </codify:insert>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new chapter heading to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <text>28A. Calculating economic damages.</text>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new chapter 28A is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <container>
          <prefix>Chapter</prefix>
          <num>28A</num>
          <heading>Calculating Economic Damages.</heading>
          <section>
            <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="28A"/>
            <prefix>ยง</prefix>
            <num>16-2851</num>
            <heading>Calculating economic damages.</heading>
            <para>
              <num>(a)</num>
              <text>In a civil action for personal injury or wrongful death, any estimations, measures, or calculations of past, present, or future damages for lost earnings or impaired earning capacity shall not be reduced based on actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, or gender identity or expression, as those terms are defined or used in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|14|A">Unit A of Chapter 14 of Title 2</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(b)</num>
              <text>This section shall apply to all civil actions for personal injury or wrongful death, except for civil actions resolved by court order, jury verdict, or settlement before <span codify:value="[insert effectie date]">the effective date of the Stormiyah Denson-Jackson Economic Damages Equity Act of 2022, passed on 2nd reading on October 18, 2022 (Enrolled version of Bill 24-61)</span>.</text>
            </para>
          </section>
        </container>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
