<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-663">
  <num type="act">24-663</num>
  <num type="bill">24-1040</num>
  <heading type="short">Protecting Security-Sensitive Dashboard Data Temporary Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Department of General Services Establishment Act of 2011 to exempt data that is security sensitive from public dashboard disclosure requirements.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-10-13</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2023-03-08</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/51421/Signed_Act/B24-1040-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-663</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 14756</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-1040">
      <vote date="2022-10-18" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-11-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-11-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Protecting Security-Sensitive Dashboard Data Temporary Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1028e of the Department of General Services Establishment Act of 2011, effective September 21, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-167; D.C. Official Code ยง 10-551.07e), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "campus facility maintenance work orders," and inserting the phrase "campus facility maintenance work orders not exempted by subsection (e) of this section," in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "facility maintenance work orders," and inserting the phrase "facility maintenance work orders not exempted by subsection (e) of this section" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (e) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The following types of work order data of the following types shall be exempt from the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) of this section:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Any work order data regarding a door or lock issue that impairs ordinary operation or has the potential to impair lockdown of a campus space;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Any work order data regarding a window issue that impairs ordinary operation or has the potential to impair lockdown of a campus space; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Any work order data regarding a security camera or security alarm system if that data could be used to access a facility unlawfully.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The Department of General Services ("Department") shall provide prompt written notice to the chairs of the Council committees with jurisdiction over the Department, the District of Columbia Public Schools, and the Department of Parks and Recreation regarding any work order omitted from a dashboard pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection that remains open for 45 days or more.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The Department may delay its publication pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section of any work order data related to door, window, and security system issues for up to 10 business days for purposes of determining whether such data are exempt from disclosure pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
