<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-687">
  <num type="act">24-687</num>
  <num type="bill">24-653</num>
  <heading type="short">Period Equity Righting an Injustice of District Residents (PERIOD) Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To require the entity responsible for managing or maintaining a public bathroom to install and maintain dispensers or similar receptacles of free-for-use period products in women's and gender-neutral bathrooms.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-02-02</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2023-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/48744/Signed_Act/B24-0653-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-687</citation>
      <citation type="register">69 DCR 15101</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0653">
      <vote date="2022-11-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-11-15" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2022-12-08</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 24-653 would require the provision of free period products in District buildings and government operated spaces.</summary>
      <committee>Housing and Executive Administration</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Period Equity Righting an Injustice of District Residents (PERIOD) Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Definitions.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>"Public bathroom" means a toilet facility on property owned or operated by the District, including a District-owned property leased by a private entity, and on property owned or operated by entities that have been awarded human care agreements with the District.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>"Period product" means a tampon or a sanitary pad made from certified organic cotton and which do not contain the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Synthetic fibers;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Plastics, including a plastic applicator;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Chlorine;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Fragrances; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Other substances hazardous to user health.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Provision of period products.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Entities responsible for managing or maintaining a public bathroom shall install at least one dispenser or similar container for period products in all women's and gender-neutral bathrooms.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>If a public property does not have a gender-neutral bathroom, then the period products shall also be available in at least one men's bathroom and a sign must be placed in all other men's bathrooms indicating where period products are available in the building.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Entities shall stock every dispenser or similar container with sufficient period products to serve the needs of all building visitors.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Period products required to be made available pursuant to this act shall be free of charge.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>Applicability</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of this act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text proof="needed">The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (12 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <text>Effective date</text>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
