<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-736">
  <num type="act">24-736</num>
  <num type="bill">24-666</num>
  <heading type="short">Soil Disclosure Repeal Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to repeal a provision requiring disclosure of the characteristics of soil in all contracts drawn for the purpose of conveying real property in the District.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-02-16</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2023-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/48825/Signed_Act/B24-0666-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-736</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 589</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0666">
      <vote date="2022-11-15" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-12-06" reading="Mendelson"/>
      <vote date="2022-12-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-01-10</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 24-666 would require realtors to use up-to-date soil surveys from the Natural Resources Conservation Service. District law requires that all real estate contracts contain information regarding the characteristic of the soil on the property. </summary>
      <committee>Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Soil Disclosure Repeal Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 510(b)(1) of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1269; D.C. Official Code ยง 42-608(b)(1)), is repealed.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">O Street Wall.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Findings.</text>
      <text>The Council of the District of Columbia finds that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The District has expended several million dollars replacing the O Street retaining wall that was constructed to control soil erosion between the 3200-3300 blocks of Highwood Drive, S.E., and the 3200 block of O Street, S.E., in Square S-5542.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Construction on privately owned lots at the base of the O Street Wall may threaten the integrity of the Wall, which would not only be financially expensive to the District, but may once again threaten the residential structures on the south side of Highwood Drive, S.E.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Exercise of eminent domain.</text>
      <text>The Mayor may exercise eminent domain in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter II of Chapter 13 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to acquire the unimproved lots along O Street, S.E., in Square S-5542 for the purpose of protecting the structural integrity of the O Street Wall.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
