<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 24-737">
  <num type="act">24-737</num>
  <num type="bill">24-932</num>
  <heading type="short">Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 2022</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 1985 to authorize the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority to, via regulation, limit the linear dimension size of solid substances discharged into the District's wastewater system to less than one inch, and to permit cooling waters to be discharged into the District's wastewater system.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2022-07-08</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2023-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/50013/Signed_Act/B24-0932-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 24-737</citation>
      <citation type="register">70 DCR 591</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B24-0932">
      <vote date="2022-12-06" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2022-12-20" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2023-01-10</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 2022".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7 of the Wastewater System Regulation Amendment Act of 1985, effective March 12, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-95; D.C. Official Code ยง 8-105.06), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b)(2)(C) is amended to read as follow:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Solid or viscous substances in amounts which may cause, or contribute to obstruction of the flow in a sewer or otherwise interfere with the operation of the District's wastewater system, including:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Substances which may solidify or become viscous at temperatures above 32 degrees Fahrenheit or 0 degrees Centigrade;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Solids having a linear dimension established by the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority by rule, which shall not be greater than 1 inch;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Fats, oils, and grease; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Incompletely shredded garbage, animal remains, blood, feathers, ashes, cinders, sand, spent lime, stone or marble dust, metal, glass, straw, shavings, grass clippings, rags, spent grains, spent hops, waste paper, wood, plastic, gas, tar, asphalt residues, residues from refining or processing of fuel or lubricating oil, mud, glass grinding, or polishing wastes.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase "drainage, cooling waters" and inserting the word "drainage" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
