<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1555.07(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Commission on Out of School Time Grants and Youth Outcomes; duties and authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The duties of the Commission shall be as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Set the goals and scope of an annual, community-wide needs assessment, which the Office shall conduct, to identify and prioritize needs for out-of-school-time programs and establish targets for out-of-school-time funding.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Within 12 months of April 7, 2017, and at least every 3 years thereafter, draft and approve a strategic plan for out-of-school-time programs and funding ("strategic plan") in the District that encourages interagency and community coordination and promotes equitable access for youth and families to high-quality youth development programs.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The strategic plan shall draw on the data gathered and analyzed by the Office, including the annual community-wide needs assessment, to identify and resolve gaps in the distribution of out-of-school-time programs and funding, with a particular emphasis on at-risk students, geographic distribution of out-of-school-time programs and funding, and program quality.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Review, on a regular basis, the efforts of the Office to fulfill the goals and priorities of the strategic plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Review, on a regular basis, the efforts of other relevant District agencies to cooperate in achieving the strategic plan, including review of the allocation of out-of-school-time funding in school budgets, to the extent such data is available, and how such allocation aligns with the need.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Identify areas for improved collaboration, problem-solving, and cooperation among District agencies regarding out-of-school-time programs and funding.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Inform and approve plans for assessing the quality of out-of-school-time programs developed by the Office.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commission may use the personnel and resources of the Office, as needed, to accomplish its duties.</text>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-261" type="History" path="ยง8">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 21-261, ยง 8</annotation>
</section>
