<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-281.01(Perm)</num>
        <heading>Definitions.</heading>
        <para>
          <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2B">this subtitle</code-cite>, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Economically disadvantaged individual" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.02|(7)">section 2302(7) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.02(7))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>"Eligible business" means an equity impact enterprise that has $2 million or less in annual revenue and certifies in writing that the business is unable to obtain conventional financing or is a business enterprise that cannot reasonably be expected to qualify for financing under the standards of commercial lending.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the phrase "unable to obtain conventional financing" means that the business has attempted but failed in the attempt to obtain financing from conventional sources.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>"Equity impact enterprise" shall have the same meaning as set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-218.02|(8A)">section 2303(8A) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.02(8A))</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>"Fund" means the Equity Impact Fund established in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-281.02">section 2163</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>"Fund Manager" means a private financial organization selected by the Mayor pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-281.03">section 2164</code-cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(6)</num>
            <text>"Private financial organization" means a partnership, corporation, trust, limited liability company, Community Development Financial Institution, or a consortium of partnerships, corporations, trusts, limited liability companies, or Community Development Financial Institutions, whether organized on a profit or not-for-profit basis, that has as its primary activity the investment of capital into businesses.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="§2162">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, § 2162, 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
      </section>
