<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
 <num>2-281.04(Perm)</num>
        <heading>Minimum requirements for investment.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>The Fund Manager shall source, underwrite, and monitor all investments placed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2B">this subtitle</code-cite>. Except as otherwise provided by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2B">this subtitle</code-cite>, the Mayor shall not determine the recipient, amount, interest rate, or any other requirement related to an investment made pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="2|2B">this subtitle</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The following requirements shall apply to any investment in an eligible business made from the Fund using the District's initial investment or interest earned on the initial investment:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Fund Manager shall begin accepting applications from eligible businesses seeking investment, on a rolling basis, within 30 days of being selected for the position by the Mayor.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>For the Fund Manager to provide an investment from the Fund, the eligible business must agree, in writing, to participate in technical assistance training.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>The Fund Manager shall establish, for each selected eligible business, a 12-month individualized business plan. Investments shall be distributed to the eligible business in installments based upon completion of specific milestones clearly described in the business's individualized business plan. The individualized business plan shall include technical assistance, provided at no cost to the business, which shall include education on the management and scale of a business through live training or guided recorded sessions. All eligible businesses that receive an investment from the Fund shall be required to participate in at least 3 months of technical assistance training.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-149" type="History" path="ยง2165">Dec. 3, 2020, D.C. Law 23-149, ยง 2165, 67 DCR 10493</annotation>
      </section>
