<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-211.08(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Voting assistance and notifications to inmates in Department of Corrections custody.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>In addition to any obligations imposed upon the Department of Corrections ("Department") due to its designation as a voter registration agency by <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1001.07|(d)|(1)|(B)">section 7(d)(1)(B) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 700; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.07(d)(1)(B))</code-cite>, the Department shall, during the inmate intake process and again when an inmate exits the Department's custody:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Determine whether an inmate is a qualified elector, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1001.02|(2)">section 2(2) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.02(2))</code-cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Department determines that an inmate is a qualified elector, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-1001.02|(2)">section 2(2) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 699; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.02(2))</code-cite>, but is not registered to vote, provide that inmate with a voter registration application; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide an oral and written notification to each inmate of the right of an individual currently incarcerated or with a criminal record to vote in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Not Funded.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall include information about the District voting rights of individuals currently incarcerated or with a criminal record in its Inmate Handbook or other similar resource provided to inmates.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning on <span codify:value="April 26, 2019">the effective date of the Voting Rights Notification Amendment Act of 2018, passed on 2nd reading on December 18, 2018 (Enrolled version of Bill 22-312)</span>, and every 6 months thereafter, the Department shall provide to the Office on Returning Citizen Affairs the names and contact information of inmates released from its custody in the prior 6 months.</text>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-309" type="History" path="§3">June 27, 1946, ch. 507, §8; as added Apr. 26,2019, D.C. Law 22-309, § 3, 66 DCR 909</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 23-277" path="§4|(b)" type="History">Apr. 7, 2021, D.C. Law 23-277, § 4(b), 67 DCR 13867</annotation>
</section>
