<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>25-403(Perm)</num>
  <heading>License renewal application for manufacturer, wholesaler, or retailer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An applicant for license renewal shall verify, by affidavit, the accuracy of its application, including all documents and submissions constituting a part of the application for its initial license or, if appropriate, at the time of a Board-approved substantial change in operation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In the case of an application for renewal of a restaurant or hotel license, the applicant shall present evidence establishing that the sale of food accounted for at least 45% of gross annual receipts from the operation of the restaurant or of the dining room of the hotel during the current license period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The applicant shall submit documents or other written evidence establishing to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant has complied with the requirements of <cite path="§25-423">§ 25-423</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Board shall establish application procedures for the renewal of a caterer’s license under <cite path="§25-211|(b)">§ 25-211(b)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In the case of an application for renewal of a nightclub license, the applicant shall submit a written security plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the case of an application for renewal for a restaurant, tavern, or multipurpose facility license, the Board may, in its sound discretion, require that the applicant submit a written security plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A written security plan filed pursuant to this subsection shall include at least the following elements:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A statement on the type of security training provided for, and completed by, establishment personnel, including:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Conflict resolution training;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Procedures for handling violent incidents, other emergencies, and calling the Metropolitan Police Department; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Procedures for crowd control and preventing overcrowding;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The establishment’s procedures for permitting patrons to enter;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A description of how security personnel are stationed inside and in front of the establishment and the number and location of cameras used by the establishment;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Procedures in place to prevent patrons from becoming intoxicated and ensuring that only persons 21 years or older are served alcohol;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>A description of how the establishment maintains an incident log;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>The establishment’s procedures for preserving a crime scene; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>In the event that cameras are required to be installed by the Board or in accordance with the establishment’s security plan, the establishment shall ensure the following:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The cameras utilized by the establishment are operational;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Any footage of a crime of violence or a crime involving a gun is maintained for a minimum of 30 days; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The security footage is made available within 48 hours upon the request of ABRA or the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Jan. 24, 1934, 48 Stat. 327, ch. 4, § 14</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 25, 1937, 50 Stat. 802, 803, ch. 766, §§ 1, 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 15, 1938, 52 Stat. 691, ch. 396, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 103, ch. 159, § 404(e), (f)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-450" type="History">Aug. 2, 1968, 82 Stat. 616, Pub. L. 90-450, title IV, § 404</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-146" type="History">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-146, § 4, 27 DCR 4753</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-157" type="History">Sept. 29, 1982, D.C. Law 4-157, §§ 8, 15, 29 DCR 3617</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-51" type="History">Mar. 8, 1984, D.C. Law 5-51, § 2(b)(4), (c), 30 DCR 5927</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-97" type="History">June 29, 1984, D.C. Law 5-97, § 2, 31 DCR 2556</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-217" type="History">Mar. 7, 1987, D.C. Law 6-217, § 9, 34 DCR 907</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-7" type="History">June 5, 1987, D.C. Law 7-7, § 2, 34 DCR 2640</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-174" type="History">Oct. 3, 1992, D.C. Law 9-174, § 2(b), (c), 39 DCR 5859</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122" type="History">May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 2(f), 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(q)(2), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-39" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-39, § 2, 46 DCR 6548</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-298" type="History">May 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-298, § 101, 48 DCR 2959</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-201" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-201, § 4(c), 55 DCR 6289</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-310" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-310, § 2(n), 60 DCR 3410</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(n) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-52, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6372, 20 DCSTAT 1388).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (e), (f) and (g), see § 2(n) of the Omnibus Alcoholic Beverage Regulation Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-597, January 14, 2013,  60 DCR 1001).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-310">D.C. Law 19-310</cite> redesignated (e), (f), and (g) as (e)(1), (e)(2), and (e)(3), respectively; and rewrote (e)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-201">D.C. Law 17-201</cite> added subsecs. (e), (f), and (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 25-115.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 25-403.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
