<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
    <prefix>§</prefix>
    <num>7-2507.05(Perm)</num>
    <heading>Voluntary surrender of firearms, destructive devices, or ammunition; immunity from prosecution; determination of evidentiary value of firearm.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>If a person or organization within the District voluntarily and peaceably delivers and abandons to the Chief any firearm, destructive device, or ammunition at any time, such delivery shall preclude the arrest and prosecution of such person on a charge of violating any provision of this unit, with respect to the firearm, destructive device, or ammunition delivered and abandoned.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Delivery and abandonment under this section may be made at any police district, station, or central headquarters, or by summoning a police officer to the person's residence or place of business.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Every firearm to be delivered and abandoned to the Chief under this section shall be transported in accordance with <u>§ 22-4504.02</u>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>No person who delivers and abandons a firearm, destructive device, or ammunition under this section shall be required to furnish identification, photographs, or fingerprints.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>No amount of money shall be paid for any firearm, destructive device, or ammunition delivered and abandoned under this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Whenever any firearm, destructive device, or any ammunition is surrendered under this section, <u>§ 7-2502.10(c)(1)</u>, or <u>§ 7-2510.09(c)</u>, the Chief shall inquire of the United States Attorney and the Corporation Counsel for the District whether such firearm is needed as evidence; provided, that if the same is not needed as evidence, it shall be destroyed.</text>
    </para>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§705">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title VII, § 705, 23 DCR 2464</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-372" type="History">Mar. 31, 2009, D.C. Law 17-372, § 3(p), 56 DCR 1365</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-314" type="History">May 10, 2019 D.C. Law 23-314, § 2(c), 66 DCR 1672</annotation>
  </section>

