<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>7-2510.05(Perm)</num>
  <heading>Service of extreme risk protection orders.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an extreme risk protection order issued pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.03">section 1003</code-cite> or <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.04">section 1004</code-cite>, or renewed pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.06">section 1006</code-cite>, shall be personally served upon the respondent by a sworn member of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The court shall submit a copy of extreme risk protection order to the Metropolitan Police Department on or before the next business day after the issuance of the order for service upon the respondent. Service of an extreme risk protection order shall take precedence over the service of other documents, unless the other documents are of a similar emergency nature.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the Metropolitan Police Department cannot complete personal service upon the respondent within 5 business days after receiving an order from the court under paragraph (2) of this subsection, the Metropolitan Police Department shall notify the petitioner.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Within one business day after service, the Metropolitan Police Department shall submit proof of service to the court.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the respondent was personally served in court when the extreme risk protection order was addedsued, the requirements of subsection (a) of this section shall be waived.</text>
  </para>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-85" type="History" path="§1005">Sept. 24, 1976, D.C. Law 1-85, title X, § 1005</annotation>
  <annotation doc="D.C. Law 22-314" type="History" path="§2|(e)">as added May 10, 2019, D.C. Law 22-314, § 2(e), 66 DCR 1672</annotation>
</section>
