<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 22-334">
  <num type="bill">22-773</num>
  <num type="act">22-334</num>
  <heading type="short">Medical Marijuana Certified Business Enterprise Preference Emergency Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999 to establish a preference for certified business enterprises that apply for the registration of a dispensary, cultivation center, or testing laboratory.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2018-05-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/40022/B22-0773-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-334</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 5058</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0773">
      <vote date="2018-04-10" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-05-03</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medical Marijuana Certified Business Enterprise Preference Emergency Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7(d) of the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999, effective July 27, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-210; D.C. Official Code § 7-1671.06(d)), is amended by adding a new paragraph (5) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Any application for registration of a dispensary, cultivation center, or testing laboratory submitted by a certified business enterprise pursuant to this subsection after the effective date of the Medical Marijuana Certified Business Enterprise Preference Emergency Amendment Act of 2017, effective June 28, 2017 (D.C. Act 22-83; 64 DCR 6229), shall be awarded a preference equal to 20 points or 7.5% of the available points, whichever is more.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "certified business enterprise" shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2302(1D) of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.02(1D)).</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of April 19, 2018.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
