<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 22-301">
  <num type="bill">22-694</num>
  <num type="act">22-301</num>
  <heading type="short">Child Neglect and Sex Trafficking Temporary Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 to broaden the definitions of neglected child and abused to include a victim of sex trafficking or severe forms of sex trafficking; and to amend An Act To provide for the mandatory reporting by physicians and institutions in the District of Columbia of certain physical abuse of children to make a conforming amendment.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective projected="true">2018-06-09</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39690/B22-0694-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-301</citation>
      <citation type="register">65 DCR 3769</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0694">
      <vote date="2018-02-06" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-03-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2018-04-02</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Child Neglect and Sex Trafficking Temporary Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 102 of the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977, effective September 23, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-22; D.C. Official Code § 4-1301.02), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>"Abused", when used in reference to a child, means:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>Abused as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 16-2301(23); or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>Sexual abuse, which shall include sex trafficking or severe forms of trafficking in persons as those terms are defined in section 103(10) and (9)(A) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, approved October 28, 2000 (114 Stat. 1469; 22 U.S.C. § 7102(10) and (9)(A)).</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as preventing or intending to prevent sex trafficking or severe forms of trafficking in persons from being considered a form of sexual abuse for purposes of D.C. Official Code § 16-2301(32).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (15A) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(15A)</num>
          <text>"Neglected child" means a child who is a:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Neglected child as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 16-2301(9); or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Victim of sex trafficking or severe forms of trafficking in persons as those terms are defined in section 103(10) and (9)(A) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, approved October 28, 2000 (114 Stat. 1469; 22 U.S.C. § 7102(10) and (9)(A)).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 2(a) of An Act To provide for the mandatory reporting by physicians and institutions in the District of Columbia of certain physical abuse of children, approved November 6, 1966 (80 Stat. 1354; D.C. Official Code § 4-1321.02(a)), is amended by striking the phrase "neglected child, as defined in D.C. Code, sec. 16-2301(9), shall" and inserting the phrase "neglected child, as defined in section 102(15A) of the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977, effective September 23, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-22; D.C. Official Code § 4-1301.02(15A)), shall" in its place.</text>
    <codify:temporary doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1321.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
