<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Act 22-4">
  <num type="bill">22-17</num>
  <num type="act">22-4</num>
  <heading type="short">Elderly Tenant and Tenant with a Disability Protection Emergency Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to authorize the Rental Housing Commission to certify and publish before March 1 of each year, the most recent annual cost-of-living adjustment of benefits for social security recipients and the maximum annual rent adjustment that may be imposed on a unit occupied by an elderly tenant or a tenant with a disability, and to add the Social Security cost-of-living adjustment as a third-lowest option of the cap on the annual standard rent increase for a unit occupied by an elderly tenant or a tenant with a disability, in addition to the Consumer Price Index and 5 % of the current rent charged.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2017-01-10</introduced>
    <effective>2017-02-09</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/37173/Signed_Act/B22-0017-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-4</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 1680</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0017">
      <vote date="2017-01-10" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-02-09</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Elderly Tenant and Tenant with a Disability Protection Emergency Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3500 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 202(a)(3) (D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.02(a)(3)) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>Certify and publish before March 1 of each year:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The annual adjustment of general applicability of the rent charged of a rental unit under section 206;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The most recent annual cost-of-living adjustment of benefits for social security recipients established pursuant to section 415(i) of the Social Security Act, approved August 28, 1950 (64 Stat. 506; 42 U.S.C. § 415(i)); and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>The maximum annual rent adjustment that may be imposed on a unit occupied by an elderly tenant or a tenant with a disability pursuant to section 208(h)(2).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3502.02"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 208(h)(2) (D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.08(h)(2)) is amended by striking the phrase "shall not exceed the lesser of 5% or the adjustment of general applicability" and inserting the phrase "shall not exceed the least of 5%, the adjustment of general applicability, or effective May 1, 2017, the most recent annual cost-of-living adjustment of benefits for social security recipients established pursuant to section 415(i) of the Social Security Act, approved August 28, 1950 (64 Stat. 506; 42 U.S.C. § 415(i))" in its place.</text>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-3502.08"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
