<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 22-560">
  <num type="bill">22-661</num>
  <num type="act">22-560</num>
  <heading type="short">Rear-Facing Car Seat Safety Amendment Act of 2018</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Child Restraint Act of 1982 to provide that the operator of a motor vehicle may not transport a child under 2 years of age, who weighs less than 40 pounds or who measures less than 40 inches in length, unless the child is properly restrained in a rear-facing child restraint seat.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2018-01-09</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2019-03-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/39557/B22-0661-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-560</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 592</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B22-0661">
      <vote date="2018-11-13" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2018-12-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-01-15</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, this bill requires that children under 2 years of age are restrained in a rear-facing car seat when in a vehicle.. </summary>
      <committee>Committee on Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Rear-Facing Car Seat Safety Amendment Act of 2018".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 4(a) of the Child Restraint Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-194; D.C. Official Code ยง 50-1703(a)), is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; provided, that, if the child weighs less than 40 pounds or measures less than 40 inches in length, and is under 2 years of age, the child shall be properly restrained in a rear-facing child restraint seat." in its place.</text>
    <codify:find-replace doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง50-1703|(a)" position="last">
      <find>.</find>
      <replace>; provided, that, if the child weighs less than 40 pounds or measures less than 40 inches in length, and is under 2 years of age, the child shall be properly restrained in a rear-facing child restraint seat.</replace>
    </codify:find-replace>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)), and publication in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </section>
</document>
