<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Act 22-74">
  <num type="bill">22-282</num>
  <num type="act">22-74</num>
  <heading type="short">Medical Marijuana Cultivation Center Relocation Emergency Amendment Act of 2017</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999 to provide certain medical marijuana cultivation center applicants with the ability to relocate to another election ward.</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2017-06-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/38093/B22-0282-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 22-74</citation>
      <citation type="register">64 DCR 6078</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <vote date="2017-05-16" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2017-06-05</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medical Marijuana Cultivation Center Relocation Emergency Amendment Act of 2017".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 7(d)(3) of the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999, effective July 27, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-210; D.C. Official Code ยง 7-1671.06(d)(3)), is amended by adding a new subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any applicant that submitted an application on July 19, 2015, for a registration to operate a cultivation center shall be allowed to modify the location of the cultivation center on its application without negatively affecting the current status of the application.</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="ยง7-1671.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
