<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-120">
  <num type="law">9-120</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-06-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-120.pdf">D.C. Law 9-120</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 3195</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0356">
      <narrative>Law 9-120, the “Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-356, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 3, 1992, and April 7, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 24, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-194 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-120 became effective on June 11, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 247 280 0 ~0 -oi O 0 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-194 Enrolled Original District ¢,olumbia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTI~ICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 24, 1992 To amend the Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, and the Nonprofit Housing Developments’ Water and Sanitary Sewer Service 1~ate Charges l~eduction and the Consumer Credit Interest l~ate Amendments Clarification Act of 1982, to provide real property and water and sewer tax abatement relief to former public housing projects purchased by resident management corporations formed in accordance with the United States Housing Act of 1937, and to make conforming amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. The Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; D.C. Code §47-3501 et seq is amended by adding a new section 7a to read as follows See. 7a. Resident Management Corporations Qualifications; exemptions a) In order to qualify for an exemption under this section, a resident management corporation shall meet the requirements of section 20 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (103. Star. 1839; 42 U.S.C. 1437r b) l~eal property transferred to a qualifying resident management co}’.’poration pursuant to section 21 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Star. 1842; 42 U.S.C. 1437s shall be exempt from 1) The deed recordation tax pursuant to section 302 of the District of Columbia l~eal Estate Deed l~ecordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Star. 11; D.C. Code §45-922 2) The transfer tax pursuant to section 402 of the District of Columbia l~evenue Act of 1980, effective September 13, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-92; D.C. Code §47-902 and 3) The real property tax pursuant to section 1 of An Act To define real property exempt from taxation in the District of Columbia, approved December 24, 1942 (56 Star. 1089; D.C. Code §47-1002 th]’.’ough the end of the lOth tax year following the year in which the property is transferred to the resident management corporation. New Section 47-3506.1 Enrolled Original c) This section shall apply to real property transferred to all qualifying resident management corporations on, before, or after the effective date of the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992. Any taxes owed by a qualifying resident management corporation prior to the enactment of the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, which are exempted by the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, shall be forgiven. Any taxes paid by a qualifying resident management corporation prior to the enactment of the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, which are exempted by the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, shall be refunded See. 3. Section 2(1) of the Nonprofit Housing Developments’ Water and Sanitary Sewer Service Rate Charges Reduction and the Consumer Credit Interest l~ate Amendments Clarification Act of 1982, effective June 4, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-112; D.C. Code §§43-1522.5(1) and 43-1605.5(1 is amended as follows a) By striking the word "and" before the phrase "nonprofit cooperative housing developments b) By striking the semi-colon after the phrase "above the cost of the project" and inserting a comma in its place; and (c) By striking the period after the phrase "for the benefit of the project" and inserting the language and a resident management corporation that purchases real property or an entity to which a resident management corporation resells the real property pursuant to section 21 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Stat. 1842; 42 U.S.C. 1437s For the purposes of this paragraph the term "resident management corporation" means an entity which meets the requirements for a resident management corporation pursuant to section 20 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Star. 1839; 42 U.S.C. 1437r in its place. See. 4. Conforming amendments a) Section 302 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 11; D.C. Code §45-922 is amended by adding a new paragraph (20) to read as follows 20) A deed to property transferred to a resident management corporation in accordance with section 7a of the Lower Income ttomeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; to be codified at D.C. Code §4’7-3506.1 b) The District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1980, effective September 13, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-92; D.C. Code §47-902 is amended by adding a new paragraph (15) to read as follows 15) The transfer of property to a resident management corporation in accordance with section 7a of the Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; to be codified at D.C. Code §47-3506.1 c) Section 1 of An Act To define real property exempt from ta×ation in the District of Columbia, approved December 24, 1942 (56 Section 43-1522.5 and 43-1605.5 Section 45-922 Section 47-902 Section 47-1002 2 Enrolled Original Stat. 1089; D.C. Code §47-1002 is amended by adding a new subsection (x) to read as follows ×) Property transferred to a resident management corporation in accordance with section 7a of the Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; to be codified at D.C. Code §47-3506.1 Sec. 5. Rules. The Mayor may, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code §1-1506 issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. See. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal lZegulations. Chat Co~?l of ~tm.~Distl~ct of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: April 24, 1992 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: 9-356 Adopted First Reading, 3-3-92 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT coUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V I A.B. I CO_UNCIL MEMBER JARVISCHMN. WILSON I BRAZIL I LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROP P I NATHAN S ON ~v i 1 RAY X indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER NV Present, not votin SMITH h JR HOY’~S, SR ’ dDERTIFICATION RECORD £Secretary tathe Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading voice VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent: Date 4-7"92 AYE NAY N.V ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER 1AYE NAY N V. lAB. JARVISC £I WILSONI I LIGHTFOOTBRAZIL CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS 1 RAY X Indicates Vpte A,B Absent ’CERTIFICATION Secretary tb~e Council Item on Consent Calendar AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYECOUNCIL MEMBER NV Presen not voting RECORD OLARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS SR. Date NAY t N.V. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER "CiI~ o WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD OPP RVAN.q ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY NV. AB. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.B. NV Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMA SR. AYE NAY CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date AN ACT Enrolled Original Di=l C l bia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTt~ICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, and the Nonprofit Housing Developments’ Water and Sanitary Sewer Service Rate Charges Reduction and the Consumer Credit Interest Rate Amendments Clarification Act of 1982, to provide real property and water and sewer tax abatement relief to former public housing projects purchased by resident management corporations formed in accordance with the United States Housing Act of 1937, and to make conforming amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992" See. 2. The Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; D.C Code §47-3501 et seq is amended by adding a new section 7a to read as follows See. 7a. Resident Management Corporations Qualifications; exemptions a) In order to qualify for an exemption under this section, a resident management corporation shall meet the requirements of section 20 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Star. 1839; 42 U.S.C. 1437r b) Real property transferred to a qualifying resident management corporation pursuant to section 21 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Star. 1842; 42 U.S.C. 1437s shall be exempt from 1) The deed reeordation tax pursuant to section 302 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Deed l~ecordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Star. 11; D.C. Code §45-922 2) The transfer tax pursuant to section 402 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1980, effective September 13, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-92; D.C. Code §47-902 and 3} The real property tax pursuant to section 1 of An Act To define real property exempt from taxation in the District of Columbia, approved December 24, 1942 (56 Stat. 1089; D.C. Code §47-1002 through the end of the 10th tax year following the year in which the property is transferred to the resident management corporation. New Section 47-3506. i Enrolled Original c) This section shall apply to real property transferred to all qualifying resident management corporations on, before, or after the effective date of the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992. Any taxes owed by a qualifying resident management corporation prior to the enactment of the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, which are exempted by the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, shall be forgiven. Any taxes paid by a qualifying resident management corporation prior to the enactment of the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, which are exempted by the Public Housing Homeownership Tax Abatement Amendment Act of 1992, shall be refunded Sec. 3. Section 2(1) of the Nonprofit Housing Developments’ Water and Sanitary Sewer Service Rate Charges Reduction and-the Consumer Credit Interest Rate Amendments Clarification Act of 1982, effective June 4, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-112; D.C. Code §§43-1522.5(1) and 43-1605.5(1 is amended as follows a) By striking the word "and" before the phrase "nonprofit cooperative housing developments b) By striking the semi-colon after the phrase "above the cost of the project" and inserting a comma in its place; and (c By striking the period after the phrase "for the benefit of the project" and inserting the language and a resident management corporation that purchases real property or an entity to which a resident management corporation resells the real property pursuant to section 21 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Star. 1842; 42 U.S.C. 1437s For the purposes of this paragraph the term "resident management corporation" means an entity which meets the requirements for a resident management corporation pursuant to section 20 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved February 5, 1988 (101 Stat. 1839; 42 U.S.C. 1437r in its place. See. 4. Conforming amendments a) Section 302 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Star. 11; D.C. Code §45-922 is amended by adding a new paragraph (20) to read as follows 20) A deed to property transferred to a resident management corporation in accordance with section 7a of the Lower Income ttomeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; to be codified at D.C. Code §47-3506.1 b) The District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1980, effective September 13, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-92; D.C. Code §47-902 is amended by adding a new paragraph (15) to read as follows 15) The transfer of property to a resident management corporation in accordance with section 7a of the Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; to be codified at D.C. Code §47-3506.1 c) Section 1 of An Act To define real property exempt from taxation in the District of Columbia, approved December 24, 1942 (56 Section 43-1522.5 and 43-1605.5 Section 45-922 Section 47-902 Section 47-1002 2 Enrolled Original Star. 1089; D.C. Code §47-1002 is amended by adding a new subsection (×) to read as follows x) Property transferred to a resident management corporation in accordance with section 7a of the Lower Income Homeownership Tax Abatement and Incentives Act of 1983, effective October 8, 1983 (D.C. Law 5-31; to be codified at D.C. Code §47-3506.1).T Sec. 5. Rules. The Mayor may, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code §1-1506 issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Mayor District of Columbia X Item on Consent Calendar X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COL~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 3-3-92 Bill 9-356 X VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorde0 vote on request Absent: all present C ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CMMN. WILSON JARVIS CROPP NAT~SON EVANS x d~cates VGe AB Absem X It2/On Consen, Calendar X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final X voice VOTE Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent IAYE NA~’ NIV, NIV Present. not voting RECORD Date COUNCIL MEMBER !AYE [NAY I NV ROLA}LK L Reading, 4-7-92 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V AIB. COUNCIL MEMBER ’AYE NAY BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFQRD MASON CROPP NATIIANISoN N.V.A.B. X Ind,cates Vote AS Absent NV Present, not vot, ng I 3CERTIF CAT ON RECORD I Date Item on Consen~ CaJendar COUNCI~L MEMBER AYE I NAY :iN J A.BI OLARK f ’ i SMITH. JR.| i I.THOMAS, SR, t i ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N,V, A.B. COUNCIL IMEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. C.MN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CR.AWF 0 RD MRS ON gRoPe EVANS I RAY X Indtcates Vote A.B Absent N V Present. not votin~ CERTIFICATION RECORD ROLARK SMI.TH JR0 I ] NAY i N VCOUNCIL MEMBER AYE THOMAS, SR. tl Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
