<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-155" flag="true">
  <num type="law">9-155</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA UNIFORMED CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-148</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-09-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-155.pdf">D.C. Law 9-155</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 5679</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0148"/>
    <search-text>EN ROLLIVl ENT(S) kwiktag 103 246 832 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-155 "Uniform Controlled Substances Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-148 on first and second readings, June 2, 1992, and July 7, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 21, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-248, published in the July 31, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 5679) and transmitted to Congress on July 22, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-155, effective September 26, 1992 Dates Counted Durin9 the 30~ay~ongressional August 3,4,5,6,7 I0,II 1 Review Period: September 8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,25 AN ACT D.C. ACT 9-248 Enrolled Original District of Odumbla Code },99,3 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 21, 1992 To amend the District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981 to allow proceeds from the Drug Interdiction and Demand Reduction Fund to be distributed to provide grants to fund community-based drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs; to create a Grant Award Committee; and to make technical amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Controlled Substances Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. The District of Columbia Uniform Controlled Substances Act of 1981, effective August 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-29; D.C. Code §33-552(d)(3)(B is amended as follows a) Section 502(d)(3)(B D.C. Code §33-552(d)(3)(B is amended as follows 1) Sub-subparagraph (1) is amended by striking the sub-paragraph designation 1 and inserting sub- subparagraph designation i in its place 2) Sub-subparagraph (2) is amended to read as follows ii) To provide grants to fund community-based drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs b) Section 702(2 D.C. Code §33-572(2 is amended to read as follows 2) To provide grants to fund community-based drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs c) A new section 703 is added to read as follows Sec. 703. Grant Award Committee a) There is established a Grant Award Committee Committee which shall award grants from the Drug Interdiction and Demand Fund Fund for community-based drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs b) The Committee shall consist of 5 members appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council. The nomination of a Committee member shall be submitted to the Council for a 60-day period of review excluding days of Council recess. The Council may approve or disapprove the nomination by resolution within 60 days of the date the nomination is transmitted to the Council. If the Council does not act within the 60-day period, the nomination shall be deemed disapproved. Section 33-552 Section 33-572 New Section 33-573 Enrolled Original vT(c)(1) One member of the Committee shall be designated as chairperson by the Mayor. Members of the Committee shall be residents of the District and selected on the basis of their broad experience in responsible positions with community-based drug education, prevention, or demand reduction programs 2) Each member shall be appointed for a 2-year term. A vacancy shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment 3) A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. A quorum shall be necessary for the Committee to conduct business 4) Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for any reasonable expense associated with service on the Committee d) The duties of the Committee shall include 1) Determining criteria to be included in any request for proposals to be prepared by the Office of Criminal Justice Plans and Analysis (w~Office’) and funded through the Fund 2) Determining criteria for consideration of unsolicited drug education, prevention, and demand reduction proposals; provided that, no unsolicited proposal or program shall be funded for more than 2 years 3) Awarding grants based on Committee criteria; provided that, a member shall be recused from consideration or vote on any grant for a community-based drug education, prevention, or demand reduction program with which the member has been affiliated within the last 2 years; and 4) Submitting an annual report to the Mayor and the Council which shall, at a minimum, indicate funds received for grant dispersal and list each grantee and the amount granted 1(e) All meetings of the Committee shall be open to the public. ’(f) The Office shall provide staff, space, and support to assist the Committee in performing its duties. The Office may use up to 10~o of the grant funds to provide additional staff and office materials, if necessary. The duties of the office shall include, but not be limited to: ’(1) Preparation of requests for proposals (l~Fl~s) for drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs as directed by the Committee 2) Collection of all unsolicited drug education, prevention, and demand reduction programs; and 3) Disbursal of funds as directed by the Committee See. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in. section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Gove]nment and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Enrolled Original Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations I/ District of Columbia APPI~OVED: July 21, 1992 COL~NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted First Reading, 6-2-92 Bill 9-148 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all ,present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT CH~.COUNCILwILsoNMEMSER AYE NAY N.V J A.8. COUNCILjARvIsMEMBER BRAZIL LZGHTFOOT _CRAWFQRD LASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote ’ A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B NV Presen not volin~jCERTIFICATION RECORD ~ACTION&amp;amp;DATE Adopted Final COUNCIL MEMBER ROLAP~ SMITH JR. THOMAS SR. tAYE Reading, 7-7-92 NAY VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present A.S r- ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. C} WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFO i CROPF EVANS COUNCIL MEMBEf~ JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N,V, A.B, N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER %OLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY A,B. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: C VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on re~luest Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT C.OUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B oUNCILMEMBE I AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CH WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON ¯ NA~u^MS~N9~oeP ~ANS ~Y X n~c~tes Vo~e A.B Absem N V Present no; vo~n~ CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER .ROLARK SMITH~ JR, THOMAS. SR. AYE NAY N V A.B Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
