<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-173" flag="true">
  <num type="law">9-173</num>
  <heading type="short">Traffic Adjudication and Motor Carrier Safety Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-173.pdf">D.C. Law 9-173</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 5834</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0501">
      <narrative>Law 9-173, the “Traffic Adjudication and Motor Carrier Safety Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-501, which was referred to the Committee on Public Works. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 23, 1992, and July 7, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-271 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-173 became effective on October 1, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 248 681 ~x~Jtem on Consent CaJendar ~x~ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [~q{VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL~4B[A Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Adopted First Reading, 6-23-92 9-501 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY I N.V.A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD LAS ON CROPP I NATItANSON EVANS RAY X ndicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N,V A.B. N.V Present, not votin~j COUNCIL MEMBER SMIT.H, JR. THOMAS SR. Secr ’y to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Reading, 7-7-92 VOICE VOTE: Approved AYE NAY NV. Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N,V. A.B. C}~{N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS COUNCIL MEMBER JARVI$ LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY AYE NAY N.V, A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER B.OLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR AYE NAY NV. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ire n ;onS:ec rrlteCa~t~ t tah;e cO’nC‘l Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: ’ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. AB. CL,MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD fRoPp EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. JARVIS ILIGHTFooT MASON NATHAN$ON ~AY A.B Absent NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCILMEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR AYE NAY N.V, Secretary to the Councd Date Enrolled Original Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations. District of Columbia of Columbia APPROVED: July 23, 1992 Enrolled Original 4) All cargo and cargo areas, including the removal of cargo seals when necessary to conduct a safety inspection Sec. 4b. Consent to inspection a) The operation of a vehicle subject to this act and its implementing regulations on any highway or roadway in the District shall constitute the consent of the driver and the owner of the vehicle to the inspection pursuant to section 4a b) The driver of a vehicle shall obey every sign and every direction of a police officer to stop the vehicle and submit to an inspection c) Section 5 (D.C. Code §6-3304) is amended to read as follows Sec. 5. Penalties a) Violations of this act or any rule promulgated pursuant to section 6 shall be adjudicated as provided by the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Code §40-601 et seq b) The Mayor, by rule, may establish civil fines and penalties for violations of this act or any rule promulgated pursuant to section 6 c)(1) As an alternative sanction, any person who knowingly or willfully violates this act, or any rule promulgated pursuant to section 6 shall be subject to a fine of not less than $100 and not more than $10,000, imprisonment not to exceed 1 year for each violation, or both. Each day shall constitute a separate violation and the penalties prescribed shall be applicable to each violation 2) Prosecution for violations of this subsection shall be brought by the Corporation Counsel d) A new section 5a is added to read as follows Sec. 5a. P~eimbursements a) The owner of any hazardous material motor carrier that releases a hazardous material shall reimburse the District for all expenditures made by the District to contain, remove, or respond to such a release b) The Mayor shall notify by certified mail the owner of any hazardous material motor carrier that releases a hazardous material of the costs incurred by the District to contain, remove, or respond to the release c) If the owner of the hazardous material motor carrier does not reimburse the District for all expenditures made to contain, remove, or respond to the release, within 10 days of the posting of notice by the Mayor, the Corporation Counsel may bring a civil action to seek reimbursement from the owner of the motor carrier See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental P~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of New Section 6-3303.2 Section 6-3304 New Section 6-3304.1 Enrolled Original AN ACT Codification D,C, ACT 9-271 District of Columbia Code 1,9,93 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTt~ICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 23, 1992 To amend the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978 to provide for administrative adjudication of violations of rules and to amend the District of Columbia Hazardous Materials Transportation and Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1988 to provide civil penalties for violation of the act, to authorize members of the Metropolitan Police Department to conduct inspections of motor carriers, to require reimbursement to the District of Columbia for costs relating to the containment and removal of a hazardous materials release, and to rescind the requirement that hazardous materials transporters obtain District of Columbia permits. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Traffic Adjudication and Motor Carrier Safety Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. Section 201 of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Code §40-611 is amended by adding the phrase "including rules issued pursuant to the District of Columbia Hazardous Materials Transportation and Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-190; D.C. Code §6-3301 et seq after the word "District See. 3. The District of Columbia Hazardous Materials Transportation and Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-190; D.C. Code §6-3301 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4(7 D.C. Code §6-3303(8 is repealed b) New sections 4a and 4b are added to read as follows Sec. 4a. Stops and inspection To determine compliance with this act and its implementing regulations, a police officer may stop the driver of a motor vehicle and enter upon the premises of a motor carrier that is regulated pursuant to this act and inspect any of the following 1) All equipment, parts, and accessories, including carrier maintenance, certification, and safety records 2) All driver records, including driver’s license, permits, hours of service records, certificate of physical examination, and training records 3) All manifests, including bills of lading or other shipping documents and Section 40-611 Section 6-3303 New Section 6-3303.1 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-173 "Traffic Adjudication and Motor Carrier Safety Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-501 on first and second readings, June 23, 1992, and July 7, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 23, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-271, published in the August 7, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 5834) and transmitted to Congress on July 27, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this October 1, 1992. ctm veena ent as D.C Law 9-173,~ffecti jCh man of the_C~Y’uncil Dates Counted During the 3{ d~a~&amp;gt Congressional Review Period: duly 27,28,29,30,31 August 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12 September 8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
