<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-181">
  <num type="law">9-181</num>
  <heading type="short">Fraternal Benefit Association Beneficiaries Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-03-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-181.pdf">D.C. Law 9-181</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 8081</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0581">
      <narrative>Law 9-181, the “Fraternal Benefit Association Beneficiaries Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-581, which was retained by CounciL. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 7, 1992, and October 6, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-300 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-181 became effective on March 13, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® ’103 249 "195 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-181 "Fraternal Benefit Association Beneficiaries Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bil~ No. 9-581 on f~rs~ and second read~ngs, July 7, 1992, and October 6, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 23, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-300, published in the November 6, 1992, edition of the D.C. R ister Vol. 39 Da~e 8081) and transmitted to Congress on January 5, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-181, effective March 13, 1993 a~es. Counted During the 30-~ayz/Cong[es_sional Review Period: Januar~v 5,6,20,21,22,25,26,27 February 2,3,4,16,17,1.8,19,22,23,24,25,26 March 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-3OO Enrolled Original Coditiostion IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCT. 23, 1992 To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to allow members of fraternal benefit associations to freely designate beneficiaries. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fraternal Benefit Association Beneficiaries Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. Section 749 of An Act To establish a code of law for the Section District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Star. 1310; D.C. Code 35-1201 § 35-1201 is amended by adding the phrase "any person, organization, or institution designated by the member, including, but not limited to after the phrase "The payment of death benefits shall be to’. Sec. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Enrolled Original (b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upon the effective date of the Fraternal Benefit Association Designation Act of 1992, whichever occurs first Co/ncil Columbia ayor ’ District of Columbia APPROVED: October 23, 1992 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: 9-581 Adopted First Reading, 7-7-92 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER C~HMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS ~AYE NAY N,V. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTF00T MASON NATNAN S ON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting ’CLi~ S O the CounciI Item on Consent Calendar CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLAFJ&amp;lt; SMITH, JR. THOMAS, SR Date Adopted Final Reading, 10-6-92 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N,V. A.B H~IN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS RAY AYE NAY N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I ROLARK_ LIGHTFOOT SMITH. JR. MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSON X Indicates Vote [.~ecretary to the Council [] Item on Consent Calendar A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~MN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTF00T ’ CRAWFORD I MAS ON ~ROPP NATHANS6N EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROLARK SMITH JR, THOMAS, SR. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
