<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-184" flag="true">
  <num type="law">9-184</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA ARCHITECT LICENSURE ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-189</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-03-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-184.pdf">D.C. Law 9-184</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 8208</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0189"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 246 477 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-184 "Architect Licensure and Regulation Act of 1992" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-189 on first and second readings, July 7, 1992, and October 6, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 2, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-304, published in the November 13, 1992, edition of the D.C c eg..ist.e.r Vol. 39 page 8208) and transmitted to Congress on January 5, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-184, effective March 13, 1993 jj~ i r man of t h e Council Dates Counted During the 30-da~ Co.n~ressional Review Period January 5,6,20,21,22 25,26,2 February 2,3,4,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26 March 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12 Enrolled Original AN ACT District of Columbia, Code D,C, ACT 9-304 1,99} lpl~lim~nt) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER;2, 1992 New Subchapter II, Chapter 2, Title 2 Architect Licensure and Regulation Designate §$ 2-201 through 231 as Subchapter I Architects’ Registratior To revise the laws of the District of Columbia relating to the lioensure of architects and the regulation of the practice of architecture. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Architect Licensure and Regulation Act of 1992 TITLE I GENERAL PROVISIONS See. 101. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Architect" means an individual who is engaged in the practice of architecture as defined by this act 2 Board" means the Board of Architecture established by section 201 3 Day" means a calendar day 4 Direct supervision" means personal oversight by an individual whohas control over and detailed professional knowledge of the work prepared 5 Practice of architecture" means rendering or offering to render services in connection with the design and construction, enlargement, or alteration of a structure or group of structures that have as their principal purpose human occupancy or habitation, as well as the space within and surrounding these structures. These services include planning and providing studies, designs, drawings, specifications, and other technical submissions, and the administration of construction contracts. The practice of architecture does not include the practice of engineering, as defined in the Professional Engineers’ Registration Act, approved September 19, 1950 (64 Star. 854; D.C. Code § 2-2301 et seq although an architect may perform engineering work that is incidental to the practice of architecture 6 State" means any state, commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States 7 Technical submissions" means studies, designs, drawings, specifications, and any other technical documentation prepared in the course of the practice of architecture. New, Section 2-241 Enrolled Original Sec. 102. Architects registered or licensed under prior law a) Except as otherwise provided in this act, an architect who holds a current registration issued pursuant to An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 et seq shall be considered for all purposes to be licensed under this act for the duration of the term for which the registration or license was issued and may renew that license in accordance with the renewal provisions of this act b) For the purpose of this section, an architect who holds a current registration issued pursuant to An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 et seq shall be deemed to meet the training and experience requirements of this act. New, Section 2-242 Sec. 103. Responsibilities of the Mayor a) The Board of Architecture established by this act shall be under the administrative control of the Mayor b) The Mayor shall be responsible for 1) l~roviding the Board with administrative support, including staff and facilities, sufficient to enable it to perform its responsibilities; and (2) Promulgating all rules necessary to implement the provisions of this act, including rules establishing administrative procedures for the Board, rules establishing fees for all services related to the licensure of architects and the regulation of architecture under this act, and, upon the recommendation of the Board, rules establishing requirements for licensure and minimum standards for the practice of architecture. New, Section 2-243 TITLE II BOARD OF AI~CtIITECTUt~E Sec. 201. Establishment; appointment a) There is established a Board of Architecture to consist of 5 members appointed by the Mayor b) Of the members of the Board, 4 shall be architects and 1 shall be a consumer member who is not an architect and who shall represent the public interest c) Of the members initially appointed, 2 shall be appointed to a term of 3 years, 2 shall be appointed, to a term of 2 years, and 1 shall be appointed to a term of 1 year d) The terms of the members 1st appointed shall begin on the date that a majority of the 1st members are sworn in, which shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments e) The Mayor shall designate a chairperson from among the members of the Board. New, Section 2-251 See. 202. Qualifications of members a) The architect members of the Board, at the time of their appointments and while they are members of the Board, shall: New, Section 2-252 Enrolled Original (1) Be licensed and in good standing as architects in the District 2) Have had at least 5 years of experience in the practice of architecture in the District immediately preceding their appointments; and (3) Be residents of the District b) Of the architect members of the Board, at least 3 shall be graduates of a degree program accredited by an accrediting institution, as prescribed by rule c) The consumer member of the Board, at the time of appointment and while a member of the Board, shall 1) Be a resident of the District 2) Be at least 18 years of age 3) Not be an architect 4) Not be associated with or have any interest in any person providing architectural services, education, or training; and (5) Not have a household member who is an architect or who is associated with or has any interest in any person providing architectural services, education, or training d) For purposes of subsection (c)(5) of this section, the term "household member" means a relative by blood or marriage, a ward, or any individual who shares the residence of a consumer member. See. 203. Terms of members; filling of vacancies a) Except as provided in section 201(c the members of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 3 years b) At the end of a term, a member shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed and sworn into office c) A successor appointed to fill the unexpired term of a former member shall serve until the expiration of the former memberVs full term d) No member of the Board shall be appointed to more than 2 consecutive full terms. New, Section 2-253 See. 204. Removal a) The mayor may remove a member of the Board for incompetence, misconduct, or neglect of duty after due notice and an opportunity for a hearing b) The Mayor shall remove a member of the Board for failure to maintain the qualifications required by this act c) The failure of a member of the Board to attend at least 1/2 of the regular, scheduled meetings of the Board within a 12-month period shall constitute neglect of duty within the meaning of subsection (a) of this section. New, Section 2-254 Sec. 205. Meetings; officers; quor~lm a) The Board shall hold at least 1 regular meeting every 3 months and may hold special meetings as deemed necessary by the Board b) The Board shall determine the time of its meetings at a place to be determined by the Mayor and shall publish notice in the District of Columbia Register of regular meetings at least 1 week in advance c) A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum. New, Section 2-255 Enrolled Original Sec. 206. Compensation. Members of the Board shall be entitled to receive compensation in accordance with section 1108 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-612.8 and shall be reimbursed for reasonable travel and other expenses incurred in the performance of their duties from funds designated for that purpose. New, Section 2-256 See. 207. General powers and duties a) The Board shall 1) Administer and enforce the provisions of this act and rules promulgated pursuant to this act 2) l~ecommend programs, policies, standards, and rules necessary to carry out the purposes of this act 3) l~ecommend minimum standards for the practice of architecture 4) Receive applications, evaluate qualifications, and determine eligibility of applicants for licensure 5) Issue licenses to qualified applicants 6) l~eceive and review complaints of violations of this act or rules promulgated pursuant to this act 7) Request the Mayor, on the Board’s own initiative or on the basis of a complaint, to conduct investigations of allegations of violations of this act 8) Issue subpoenas, conduct hearings, administer oaths, examine witnesses, and render decisions relating to the denial, suspension, or revocation of licensure, or any disciplinary action; and (9) Maintain records of its proceedings b) The consumer member of the Board may exercise a vote in all matters before the Board except those relating to examination content c) A member of the Board shall not take part in an action on the member’s own application for licensure, license renewal, or on any other matter related to that member’s practice of architecture. New, Section 2-257 See. 208. Annual report. The Board shall, before January 1 of each year, submit a report to the Mayor and the Council of the District of Columbia of its official acts during the preceding fiscal year. New, Section 2-258 TITLE III LICENSING OF AI~CHITECTS Sec. 301. License required a) Only an individual shall be eligible to be licensed as an architect b) Except as provided in section 302, no unlicensed person shall engage, directly or indirectly, in the practice of architecture in the District or use the title "architect registered architect licensed architect architectural designer or display or use any words, letters, figures, titles, signs, cards, advertisements, or any other symbols or devices indicating, or tending to indicate, that the person is an architect or is practicing architecture. New, Section 2-261 Enrolled Original (c) No person shall aid or abet any person who is not licensed pursuant to this act, or who is not engaged in an activity excepted by section 302, in the practice of architecture. Sec. 302. Exceptions. Nothing in this act shall be construed to prohibit 1) Any activity that would constitute the practice of architecture when performed in connection with any alteration, renovation, or remodeling of an existing structure, if the alteration, renovation, or remodeling does not affect the structural or other safety features of the structure and if the work contemplated by the design does not require the issuance of a building permit under the Building Code (Title 12 DCM] 2) The preparation of any detailed or shop drawings required to be furnished by a contractor, or the administration of construction contracts by persons customarily engaged in contracting work 3) The preparation of technical submissions or the administration of construction contracts under the direct supervision of an architect licensed in the District by employees of a person lawfully engaged in the practice of architecture 4) The practice of architecture by officers and employees of the federal government while acting in the scope of employment 5) A partnership or corporation that is in compliance with Title IV of this act from performing or holding itself out as able to perform any of the services involved in the practice of architecture; or (6) An architect who holds a license or certificate of registration in good standing to practice architecture in a state from agreeing to perform or representing that he or she is able to perform any of the services involved in the practice of architecture, provided that the architect shall not perform any of the services involved in the practice of architecture until licensed under this act. New, Section 2-262 Sec. 303. General qualifications of applicants a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, an applicant for a license shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board that the applicant 1) Is of good moral character 2) Is a graduate of a degree program in architecture accredited by an accrediting institution prescribed by rule, or has completed an education program in architecture prescribed by rule as the equivalent of an accredited professional architectural degree program 3) Has passed an examination on the practice of architecture prescribed by rule; and (4) Meets any other requirements established by rule to ensure that the applicant has had the proper training, experience, and qualifications to practice architecture b) The Board shall waive the education requirement of subsection (a)(2) of this section for an applicant who 1) Demonstrates that the applicant has 3 years of practical experience as an architect that A) Meets the requirements of An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice New, Section 2-263 Enrolled Original of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 et seq B) Is completed within 2 years of the effective date of this act; and (C) Took place in a jurisdiction that, at the time the practical experience was completed, did not require applicants for a license to practice architecture to have completed an education program in architecture; and (2) Applies for licensure within 3 years of the effective date of this act. See. 304. Application for license. An applicant for a license shall submit an application to the Board on Board-approved forms and pay the applicable fees prescribed by rule. New, Section 2-264 Sec. 305. Examination requirements. New, Section (a) An applicant who otherwise qualifies for licensure is entitled 2-265 to be examined as provided by this act b) The Board shall notify each qualified applicant of the time and place of examination. Sec. 306. License by reciprocity. New, Section The Board may issue a license by reciprocity to an applicant who 2-266 is licensed, registered, or certified and in good standing under the laws of a state with standards that, in the opinion of the Board, are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this act, and which state admits architects licensed by the District in like manner. Sec. 3071 Issuance of license a) The Board shall issue a license to an applicant who meets the requirements of this act and rules issued pursuant to this act b) A license shall be effective upon issuance. New, Section 2-267 Sec. 308. Scope of license a) A person licensed under this act is authorized to practice architecture in the District only while the license is effective b) A person who fails to renew a license shall be considered to be unlicensed and subject to the penalties set forth in this act and other applicable laws of the District if the person continues the practice of architecture. New, Section 2-268 See. 309. Term and renewal of license a) A license issued or renewed under this act shall expire on the date prescribed by rule b) The Mayor may establish by rule continuing education requirements as a condition for renewal of a license c) At least 30 days before a license expires, the Board shall send to the licensee, by first class mail to the last known address of the licensee, a renewal notice that states 1) The date on which the license expires 2) The date by which the renewal application must be received by the Board; and (3) The amount of the renewal fee. New, Section 2-269 6 Enrolled Original (d) Before a license expires, the licensee may renew the license if the licensee 1) Submits a timely application to the Board 2) Is otherwise entitled to be licensed 3) Pays the renewal fee prescribed by rule; and (4) Submits to the Board satisfactory evidence of compliance with any continuing education requirements that may be established for license renewal e) The Board shall renew the license of each licensee who meets the requirements of this act. See. 310. l~einstatement of expired license a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Board shall reinstate the license of an architect who 1) Complies with current requirements for license renewal, including any continuing education requirements 2) Is otherwise qualified for licensure; and (3) Pays a reinstatement fee prescribed by rule b) The Board shall not reinstate the license of an architect who fails to apply for reinstatement of a license within 5 years after the license expires. An architect who fails to submit a timely application for reinstatement may become licensed only by meeting the requirements for obtaining an initial license c) For individuals holding certificates of registration to practice architecture issued pursuant to An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 et seq which certificates expired prior to the effective date of this act, the 5-year period set forth in this section shall commence on the effective date of this act. New, Section 2-270 Sec. 311. Display of license; change of address a) A licensee shall display his or her license conspicuously in the principal place of business or employment of the licensee b) A licensee shall notify the Board of any change of address of the licensee’s place of residence or place of business or employment within 30 days after the change of address. New, Section 2-271 Sec. 312. ArchitectVs seal required a) A licensee shall have a seal of a design prescribed by rule b) All technical submissions prepared by a licensee or under the direct supervision of a licensee shall be signed by the licensee and stamped with the impression of the licenseeVs seal c) No licensee shall sign or seal a technical submission or portion thereof unless it was prepared by the licensee or under the direct supervision of the licensee. New, Section 2-272 See. 313. Denials. New, Section The Board, subject to an opportunity for a hearing under section 2-273 315, may deny the application of any person who has failed to submit satisfactory evidence to the Board that the person meets the qualifications for licensure under this act and rules promulgated pursuant to this act, or who has committed any of the acts listed in section 314(a 7 Enrolled Original Sec. 314. Disciplinary actions a) The Board, subject to an opportunity for a hearing under section 315, may take 1 or more of the disciplinary actions provided for in subsection (b) of this section against any applicant or licensee who 1) Fraudulently or deceptively obtains or attempts to obtain a license 2) Traudulently or deceptively uses a license 3) Traudulently or deceptively engages in the practice of architecture 4) Incompetently or negligently engages in the practice of architecture 5) Is disciplined by any licensing or disciplinary authority or convicted or disciplined by any court for conduct that would be grounds for disciplinary action under this act 6) Has been convicted by any court of law of, or pleaded guilty or nolo contendere to, a crime that bears directly on the fitness of the person to practice architecture 7) Tails to pay a civil fine imposed by the Board, the Mayor, or any court 8) Violates an order of the Board or the Mayor; or (9) Violates any provision of this act or rules issued pursuant to this act b) Upon a finding by a preponderance of the evidence that a person committed an act set forth in subsection (a) of this section, the Board may take 1 or more of the following disciplinary actions 1) Deny, suspend, or revoke a license 2 Censure or reprimand an applicant or licensee 3) Limit a license 4) Impose a civil fine not to exceed $5,000 for each violation by an applicant or licensee 5) Require a course of reined;at;on that may include retraining and reexamination 6) Require a period of probation; or (7) Issue a cease and desist order pursuant to section 317 c) Nothing in this act shall preclude prosecution for a criminal violation of this act notwithstanding that the same violation has been or is the subject of i or more of the administrative or civil actions provided by this act. Criminal prosecution may proceed simultaneously with, or subsequent to, an administrative or civil action. New, Section 2-274 See. 315. Hearings a) Before the Board takes adverse action against a person, it shall give the person an opportunity for a hearing, except in the case of a denial of a license based solely on a personTs failure to pass a required examination b) The Board may request a person to attend a settlement conference prior to holding a hearing under this section, and may enter into negotiated settlement agreements and consent decrees to carry out its functions c) A notice of intended action or hearing shall be sent by certified mail to the last known address of the person who requested the hearing at least 20 days before the hearing. New, Section 2-275 8 Enrolled Original (d) A person who has requested a hearing may be represented at the hearing by counsel e 1) The Board may administer oaths and require, by subpoena, the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and other evidence in connection with any proceeding under this section 2) The Board shall require the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and other evidence reasonably requested by a person who has requested a hearing 3) In case of contumacy by or refusal to obey a subpoena issued by the Board, the Board may petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order compelling compliance. Kefusal to obey such an order shall constitute contempt of court f) If a person fails to request or appear at a hearing, the Board may issue an order without conducting a hearing g) The Board shall issue a final order in writing within 90 days after conducting a hearing h) The Board may delegate its authority to conduct hearings under this act to a panel of 2 Board members. Sec. 316. Summary action. New, Section (a) If the Mayor determines that the conduct of a licensee presents 2-276 an imminent danger to the health and safety of the residents of the District, the Mayor may summarily suspend or restrict the license without a hearing b) The Mayor, at the time of a summary suspension or restriction of a license, shall provide the licensee with written notice stating the action that is being taken, the basis for the summary action, and the right of the licensee to request a hearing c) A licensee shall have the right to request a hearing within 15 days after service of notice of a summary suspension or restriction of the license. The Mayor shall hold a hearing within 72 hours of receipt of a timely request, and shall issue a decision within 72 hours after the hearing d) Every order adverse to a licensee shall be in writing and shall be accompanied by findings of fact and conclusions of law. l~indings of fact shall be supported by substantial evidence. The Mayor shall provide a copy of the order and accompanying findings of fact and conclusions of law to the licensee or the licensee’s attorney of record. See. 317. Cease and desist orders a) When the Board or the Mayor, after investigation but prior to a hearing, has cause to believe that any person is violating any provision of this act and the violation has caused or may cause immediate and irreparable harm to the public, the Board or the Mayor may issue an order requiring the person to cease and desist immediately from the violation. The order shall be served by certified mail or delivered in person b 1) A person may, within 20 days of the service of such an order, submit a written request to the Board or the Mayor to hold a hearing on the alleged violation 2) Upon receipt of a timely request, the Board or the Mayor shall conduct a hearing and issue a final order pursuant to section 315. New, Section 2-277 Enrolled Original (c 1) A person may, within 15 days of the service of an order, submit a written request to the Board or the Mayor for an expedited hearing on an alleged violation, in which case the person shall waive the right to the 20-day notice required by section 315 2) Upon receipt of a timely request for an expedited hearing, the Board or the Mayor shall conduct a hearing within 10 days of the date of receiving the request and shall deliver to the person, at the personVs last known address, a written notice of hearing at least 5 days before the hearing date 3) The Board or the Mayor shall issue a final order within 30 days after an expedited hearing d) If a person fails to request or appear for a hearing, the cease and desist order of the Board or the Mayor shall become final e) If the Board or the Mayor determines that a person is not in violation of this act, the Board or the Mayor shall rescind the cease and desist order f) If a person fails to comply with a cease and desist order, the Board or the Mayor may petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia to issue an order compelling compliance, or may take any other action authorized by this act. See. 318. Voluntary surrender of license. New, Section (a) A licensee who is the subject of an investigation or a 2-278disciplinary action may voluntarily surrender his or her license by delivering to the Board an affidavit stating that the licensee desires to surrender the license, and that the action is freely and voluntarily taken and not the result of duress or coercion b) Upon receipt of a required affidavit, the Board shall enter an order revoking or suspending the license c) The voluntary surrender of a license shall not preclude the imposition of civil or criminal penalties against the licensee. Sec. 319. Judicial and administrative review. New, Section Any person aggrieved by a final decision of the Board or the Mayor~&amp;lt;_2~279 may appeal the decision pursuant to section 11 of the District of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1209; D.C. Code § 1-1510 See. 320. Reinstatement of a suspended or revoked license. New~ Section (a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Board 2-280 shall reinstate a license that has been suspended or revoked if the person applying for reinstatement 1) Has complied with the terms and conditions of the order of suspension or revocation 2) Complies with current requirements for license reinstatement, including any continuing education requirements 3) Is otherwise qualified for licensure; and (4) Pays a reinstatement fee prescribed by rule b) If an order of suspension or revocation was based on the conviction of a crime that bears directly on the fitness of a licensee to practice and the conviction subsequently is overturned at any stage of an appeal or other post conviction proceeding, the Board shall reinstate the license when the conviction is overturned and the person has 10 Enrolled Original provided the Board with a certified copy of the court order overturning the conviction. TITLE IV PARTNERSHIPS AND CORPORATIONS Sec. 401. Partnerships and corporations established for the practice of architecture a) Only an individual shall be eligible to be licensed as an architect under this act. A partnership, corporation, or other entity is not eligible to be licensed as an architect b) A partnership or corporation may perform and hold itself out as able to perform any of the services involved in the practice of architecture provided that 1) Direct supervision of the work prepared on behalf of the partnership or corporation shall be provided by an architect who is licensed to practice architecture under this act 2) In the case of a partnership, at least 2/3rds of the general partners are licensed, registered, or certified as architects in the United States; and (3) In the case of a corporation, the corporation complies with the District of Columbia Professional Corporation Act, approved December 10, 1971 (85 Star. 576; D.C. Code § 29-601 e~ seq c) A partnership or corporation subject to this section shall furnish the Board with information as is prescribed by rule. TITLE V PENALTIES ENFORCEMENT See. 501. Penalties; alternative sanctions a) Any person who violates any provision of this act, or rules issued pursuant to this act, shall, upon conviction, be guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be subject to imprisonment for not more than 1 year or a fine not to exceed $5,000, or both. Each act of unlawful practice shall constitute a separate violation b) Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this act, pursuant to titles I through III of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Code § 6-2701 e~ seq Sec. 502. Prosecution. Criminal prosecutions for violations of this act or rules issued pursuant to this act shall be conducted in the name of the District of Columbia in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel. Sec. 503. Injunctions a) The Corporation Counsel may bring an action in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia to enjoin the unlawful practice of architecture or other action that is grounds for the imposition of civil or criminal penalties or disciplinary action under this act. New, Section 2-281 New, Section 2-291 New, Section 2-292 New, Section 2-293 11 Enrolled Original (b) In a proceeding under this section, it shall not be necessary to prove that any person is injured by the action alleged c) Remedies under this section are in addition to criminal prosecution or disciplinary action of the Board. Sec. 504. Civil actions a) An applicant or licensee shall obtain and file with the Board a copy of any documents filed or orders entered in any civil or criminal action relating to the applicantVs or licenseeTs practice of architecture b) In any civil or criminal action relating to the practice of architecture by a partnership or corporation, a licensed architect who is a partner of the partnership or an officer or director of the corporation shall file with the Board a copy of any documents filed or orders entered in the action. TITLE VI TRANSITIONAL PROVISIONS; REPEALER; EI~FECTIVE DATE See. 601. Transfer of personnel, records, property, and funds, The personnel, records, property, and unexpended balances of appropriations and other funds that relate primarily to the functions of the Board of Examiners and Registrars of Architects are transferred to the Board of Architecture established by this act. Sec. 602. Board of Examiners and Kegistrars of Architects abolished. Members .of the Board of Examiners and Registrars of Architects abolished by this act shall serve as members of the Board of Architecture established by this act until their successors are appointed. Sec. 603. Pending actions and proceedings; existing orders a) No suit, action, or other judicial proceeding lawfully commenced by or against any member, officer, or employee of the Board of Examiners and Registrar of Architects in the official capacity of the officer or empIoyee shall abate by reason of the taking effect of this act, but the court or agency, unless it determines that survival of the suit, action, or other proceeding is not necessary for purposes of settlement of the question involved, shall allow the suit, action, or other proceeding to be maintained, with substitutions as to parties as are appropriate b) No disciplinary action against a person or other administrative action or proceeding lawfully commenced shall abate solely by reason of the taking effect of any provision of this act, but the action or proceeding shall be continued with substitutions as to parties and officers or agencies as are appropriate c) Except as otherwise provided in this act, all orders issued by the Board of Examiners and Registrars of Architects abolished by this act, or rules issued pursuant to An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 ef seq shall continue in effect and shall apply to the successor Board of Architecture until the orders or rules are repealed or superseded. New, Section 2-294 New, Section 2-296 New, Section 2-297 New, Section 2-298 12 Enrolled Original (d) Any individual who, on the effective date of this act, has an application for registration pending pursuant to, and qualifies under, An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 et seq shall be granted a license. Thereafter, any individual seeking licensure shall meet the qualifications required by this act. See. 604. Repealer. An Act To provide for the examination and registration of architects and to regulate the practice of architecture in the District of Columbia, approved December 13, 1924 (43 Star. 714; D.C. Code § 2-201 et seq is repealed. Sec. 605. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Ch~m ~duncil ]of ~t of Columbia /District of Columbia APPROVED November 2, 1992 Section 2-201 through 2-231 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Adopted First VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent’. all present 9-189 Readinq, 7-7-92 [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER C.HHN WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCILMEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY X Indicates Vote A.B.’~ Abseni AYE NAY N,V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLAP~&amp;lt; SMITH JR. THOMAS, SR. N.V Present, not voting i v I,/I CERTIFICATION RECORD ’ ~r’etar~ to the Council Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: A~op Fi.nal VOICE VOTE: ApprOv~ Recorded vote on request Absent: all present Reading: 10-6-92 [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. C~} WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote -[] It~/m on conSs~r~ttetca~etrC~tahre Council AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAYCOUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY AB Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ROSARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS SR. Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B CIIMN. WILSON I BRAZIL CRAWFORD _CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCILMEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.B. N,V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>101</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1641"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>102</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1642"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>103</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1643"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>201</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1651"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>202</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1652"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>203</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1653"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>204</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1654"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>205</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1655"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>206</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1656"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>207</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1657"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>208</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1658"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>301</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1661"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>302</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1662"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>303</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1663"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>304</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1664"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>305</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1665"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>306</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1666"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>307</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1667"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>308</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1668"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>309</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1669"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>310</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1670"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>311</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1671"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>312</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1672"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>313</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1673"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>314</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1674"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>315</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1675"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>316</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1676"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>317</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1677"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>318</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1678"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>319</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1679"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>320</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1680"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>401</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1681"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>501</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1691"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>502</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1692"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>503</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1693"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>504</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1694"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>601</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1696"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>602</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1697"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>603</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-1698"/>
  </section>
</document>
