<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-196">
  <num type="law">9-196</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1993-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-196.pdf">D.C. Law 9-196</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 9165</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0020">
      <narrative>Law 9-196, the “Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-20, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 6, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-321 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-196 became effective on March 16, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 249 005 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-196 "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-20 on first and second readings, October 6, 1992, and November 4 992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 25, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-321, published in the December 11, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 9165) and transmitted to Congress on January 6, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-196, effective Dates Counted During the 30 January February March March 16, 1993 0 WILSON /i alrman of the Council ongressional Review Period: 6,20,21,22,25,26,27 2,3 16,17,18,19,22,23,2~,25,26 ] ,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,ii,12,15 AN ACT D.C, ACT 9-321 Enrolled Original Cod;f ’ tion of ¢,olumbi Code IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 25, 1992 To amend Article 8 of the Uniform Commercial Code and to make conforming amendments to Articles 1, 5, and 9. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code Investment Securities Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. Section 28:1-201 o£ fhe District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the word "security" and inserting the phrase "certificated security" in its place b) Paragraph (14) is amended by striking the phrase "or securities" and inserting the phrase or certificated securities" in its place c) Paragraph (20) is amended by striking the phrase "an investment security drawn, issued or indorsed" and inserting the phrase "a certificated investment security drawn, issued, or indorsed" in its place. See. 3. Section 28:5-114(2) of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) By striking the word "security" and inserting in its place the phrase "certificated security" wherever it appears; and (b) By inserting a colon after the word "transaction See. 4. Article 8 of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended to read as follows ARTICLE 8. INVESTMENT SECURITIES Sec 28:8-101 28 8-102 28 8-103 28 8-104 28 8- i05 Part 1. Short Title and General Matters. Short title. Definitions and index of definitions. Issuer’s lien. Effect of overissue overissue Certificated securities negotiable; statements and instructions not negotiable; presumptions 28:8-106. Applicability. Section 28:1-201 Section 28:5-114 Enrolled Original "28 8-107 28 8-108. securities 28:8-201 28:8-202. or defense 28:8-203 28:8-204. Securities transferable; action for price. Registration of pledge and release of uncertificated "Part 2. Issue-Issuer Issuer Issuer’s responsibility and defenses; notice of defect Staleness as notice of defects or defenses. Effect of issuer’s restrictions on transfer 28:8-205. Effect of unauthorized signature on certificated security or initial transaction statement 28:8-206. Completion or alteration of certificated security or initial transaction statement 28:8-207. Rights and duties of issuer with respect to registered owners and registered pledgees 28:8-208. Effect of signature of authenticating trustee, registrar, or transfer agent Part 3. Transfer 28:8-301. Rights acquired by purchaser 28:8-302 Bona fide purchaser adverse claim title acquired by bona fide purchaser 28:8-303 Broker 28:8-304. Notice to purchaser of adverse claims 28:8-305. Staleness as notice of adverse claims 28:8-306. Warranties on presentment and transfer of certificated securities; warranties of originators of instructions. Effect of delivery without indorsement; right to compel"28 8- 307. indorsement 28 8- 308 28 8- 309 28 8- 310 28:8-311 28:8-312. instruction 28:8-313. Indorsements instructions. Effect of indorsement without delivery. Indorsement of certificated security in bearer form. Effect of unauthorized indorsement or instruction. Effect of guaranteeing signature, indorsement, or When transfer to purchaser occurs; financial intermediary as bona fide purchaser financial intermediary 28:8-314. Duty to transfer, when completed 28:8-315. Action against transferee based upon wrongful transfer 28:8-316. Purchaser’s right to requisites for registration of transfer, pledge, or release on books 28:8-317. Creditors; rights 28:8-318. No conversion by good faith conduct 28:8-319. Statute of frauds 28:8-320. Transfer or pledge within central depository system 28:8-321. Enforceability; attachment; perfection; and termination of security interests 28:8-401 28:8-402. effective 28:8-403 28:8-404 28:8-405 Part 4. Registration. Duty of issuer to register transfer, pledge, or release. Assurance that indorsements and instructions are Issuer’s duty as to adverse claims. Liability and non-liability for registration. Lost, destroyed, and stolen certificated securities. Enrolled Original "28:8-406. Duty of authenticating trustee, transfer agent, or registrar 28:8-407. Exchangeability of securities 28:8-408. Statements of uncertificated securities Part 1. Short Title and General Matters §28:8-101. Short title This article may be cited as "Uniform Commercial Code-Investment Securities §28:8-102. Definitions and index of definitions a) In this article, unless the context otherwise requires 1) A "certificated security" is a share, participation, or other interest in property or an enterprise of the issuer or an obligation of the issuer that is A) Kepresented by an instrument issued in bearer or registered form B) Of a type commonly dealt in on securities exchanges or markets, or commonly recognized in any area in which it is issued or dealt in as a medium for investment; and C) Either 1 of a class or series or by its terms divisible into a class or series of shares, participations, interests, or obligations 2) An "uncertificated security" is a share, participation, or other interest in property or an enterprise of the issuer or an obligation of the issuer that is A) Not represented by an instrument and the transfer of which is registered upon books maintained for that purpose by or on behalf of the issuer B) Of a type commonly dealt in on securities exchanges or markets; and C) Either 1 of a class or series or by its terms divisible into a class or series of shares, participations, interests, or obligations 3) A "security" is either a certificated or an uncertificated security. If a security is certificated the terms "security" and "certificated security" may mean either the intangible interest, the instrument representing that interest, or both, as the context requires. A writing that is a certificated security is governed by this article and not by Article 3, even though it also meets the requirements of that article. This article does not apply to money. If a certificated security has been retained by or surrendered to the issuer or its transfer agent for reasons other than registration of transfer, other temporary purpose, payment, exchange, or acquisition by the issuer, that security shall be treated as an uncertificated security for purposes of this article 4) A certificated security is in "registered form" if A) It specifies a person entitled to the security or the rights it represents; and B) Its transfer may be registered upon books maintained for that purpose by or on behalf of the issuer, or the security so states 5) A certificated security is in "bearer form" if it runs to bearer according to its terms and not by reason of any indorsement 6) A "subsequent purchaser" is a person who takes other than by original issue 7) A "clearing corporation" is a corporation registered as a "clearing agency" under the federal securities laws or a corporation: § 28:8-I0] § 28:8-I0~ Enrolled Original A) At least 90% of whose capital stock is held by or for 1 or more organizations, none of which, other than a national securities exchange or association, holds in excess of 20% of the capital stock of the corporation, and each of which is i) Subject to the supervision or regulation pursuant to the provisions of federal or state banking laws or state insurance laws ii) A broker, dealer, or investment company registered under the federal securities laws; or iii) A national securities exchange or association registered under the federal securities laws; and B) Any remaining capital stock of which is held by individuals who have purchased it at or prior to the time of their taking office as directors of the corporation and who have purchased only so much of the capital stock as is necessary to permit them to qualify as directors 8) A "custodian bank" is a bank or trust company that is supervised and examined by state or federal authority having supervision over banks and is acting as custodian for a clearing corporation b) Other definitions applying to this article or to specified parts thereof and the sections in which they appear are 1 Adverse claim §28:8-302 2 Bona fide purchaser §28:8-302 3 Broker §28:8-303 4 Debtor §28:9-105 5 Financial intermediary §28:8-313 6 Guarantee of the signature §28:8-402 7 Initial transaction statement §28:8-408 8 Instruction §28:8-308 9 Intermediary bank §28:4-105 10 Issuer §28:8-201 11 Overissue §28:9-105 12 Secured Party §28:8-105 13 Security Agreement §28:9-105 c) In addition, Article 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article §28:8-103. Issuer’s lien A lien upon a security in favor of an issuer thereof is valid against a purchaser only if 1) The security is certificated and the right of the issuer to the lien is noted conspicuously thereon; or 2) The security is uncertificated and a notation of the right of the issuer to the lien is contained in the initial transaction statement sent to the purchaser or, if the purchaser’s interest is transferred to the purchaser other than by registration of transfer, pledge, or release, the initial transaction statement to the registered owner or the registered pledgee §28:8-104. Effect of overissue overissue a) The provisions of this article that validate a security or compel its issue or reissue do not apply to the extent that validation, issue, or reissue would result in overissue; but: § 28:8-103 § 28:8-104 Enrolled Original 1) If an identical security that does not constitute an overissue is reasonably available for purchase, the person entitled to issue or validation may compel the issuer to purchase the security and either to deliver a certificated security or to register the transfer of an uncertificated security to the person against surrender of any certificated security the person holds; or 2) If a security is not so available for purchase, the person entitled to issue or validation may recover from the issuer the price the person or the last purchaser for value paid for it with interest from the date of the person’s demand b Overissue" means the issue of securities in excess of the amount the issuer has corporate power to issue §28:8-105. Certificated securities negotiable; statements and instructions not negotiable; presumptions a) Certificated securities governed by this article are negotiable instruments b) Statements (§28:8-408 notices, or the like, sent by the issuer of uncertificated securities and instructions (§28:8-308) are neither negotiable instruments nor certificated securities c) In any action on a security 1) Unless specifically denied in the pleadings, each signature on a certificated security, in a necessary indorsement, on an initial transaction statement, or on an instruction, is admitted 2) If the effectiveness of a signature is put in issue, the burden of establishing it is on the party claiming under the signature, but the signature is presumed to be genuine or authorized 3) If signatures on a certificated security are admitted or established, production of the security entitles a holder to recover on it unless the defendant establishes a defense or a defect going to the validity of the security 4) If signatures on an initial transaction statement are admitted or established, the facts stated in the statement are presumed to be true as of the time of its issuance; and 5) After it is shown that a defense or defect exists, the plaintiff has the burden of establishing that the plaintiff or some person under whom the plaintiff claims is a person against whom the defense or defect is ineffective (§28:8-202 §28:8-106. Applicability The law (including the conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction of organization of the issuer governs the validity of a security, the effectiveness of registration by the issuer, and the rights and duties of the issuer with respect to 1) Registration of transfer of a certificated security 2) Registration of transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security; and 3) Sending of statements of uncertificated securities §28:8-107. Securities transferable; action for price a) Unless otherwise agreed and subject to any applicable law or regulation respecting short sales, a person obligated to transfer securities may transfer any certificated security of the specified issue in bearer form or registered in the name of the transferee, or indorsed to the person or in blank, or the person may transfer an equivalent § 28:8-105 § 28:8-106 § 28:8-107 Enrolled Original uncertificated security to the transferee or a person designated by the transferee b) If the buyer fails to pay the price as it comes due under a contract of sale, the seller may recover the price of 1) Certificated securities accepted by the buyer 2) Uncertificated securities that have been transferred to the buyer or a person designated by the buyer; and 3) Other securities if efforts at their resale would be unduly burdensome or if there is no readily available market for their resale §28:8-108. Registration of pledge and release of uncertificated securities A security interest in an uncertificated security may be evidenced by the registration of a pledge to the secured party or a person designated by the secured party. There can be no more than 1 registered pledge of an uncertificated security at any time. The registered owner of an uncertificated security is the person in whose name the security is registered, even if the security is subject to a registered pledge. The rights of a registered pledgee of an uncertificated security under this article are terminated by the registration of release Part 2 Issue-Issuer "§28:8-201 Issuer a) With respect to obligations on or defenses to a security issuer" includes a person who 1) Places or authorizes the placing of the person’s name on a certificated security (other than as authenticating trustee, registrar, transfer agent, or the like) to evidence that it represents a share, participation, or other interest in the person’s property or in an enterprise, or to evidence the person’s duty to perform an obligation represented by the certificated security 2) Creates shares, participations, or other interests in the person’s property or in an enterprise or undertakes obligations, which shares, participations, interests, or obligations are uncertificated securities 3) Directly or indirectly creates fractional interests in the person’s rights or property, which fractional interests are represented by certificated securities; or 4) Becomes responsible for or in place of any other person described as an issuer in this section b) With respect to obligations on or defenses to a security, a guarantor is an issuer to the extent of the guarantor’s guaranty, whether or not the guarantor’s obligation is noted on a certificated security or on statements of uncertificated securities sent pursuant to §28:8-408 c) With respect to registration of transfer, pledge, or release (Part 4 of this article issuer" means a person on whose behalf transfer books are maintained §28:8-202. Issuer’s responsibility and defenses; notice of defect or defense a) Even against a purchaser for value and without notice, the terms of a security include 1) If the security is certificated, those stated on the security; § 28:8-108 § 28:8-201 § 28:8-202 6 Enrolled Original 2) If the security is uncertificated, those contained in the initial transaction statement sent to such purchaser or, if the interest is transferred to the purchaser other than by registration of transfer, pledge, or release, the initial transaction statement sent to the registered owner or registered pledgee; and 3) Those made part of the security by reference, on the certificated security or in the initial transaction statement, to another instrument, indenture, or document or to a constitution, statute, ordinance, rule, regulation, order or the like, to the extent that the terms referred to do not conflict with the terms stated on the certificated security or contained in the statement. A reference under this paragraph does not of itself charge a purchaser for value with notice of a defect going to the validity of the security, even though the certificated security or statement expressly states that a person accepting it admits notice b) A certificated security in the hands of a purchaser for value or an uncertificated security as to which an initial transaction statement has been sent to a purchaser for value, other than a security issued by a government or governmental agency or unit, even though issued with a defect going to its validity, is valid with respect to the purchaser if the purchaser is without notice of the particular defect unless the defect involves a violation of constitutional provisions, in which case the security is valid with respect to a subsequent purchaser for value and without notice of the defect. This subsection applies to an issuer that is a government or governmental agency or unit only if there has been either substantial compliance with the legal requirements governing the issue or the issuer has received a substantial consideration for the issue as a whole or for the particular security and a stated purpose of the issue is one for which the issuer has power to borrow money or issue the security c) Except as provided in the case of certain unauthorized signatures (§28:8-205 lack of genuineness of a certificated security or an initial transaction statement is a complete defense, even against a purchaser for value and without notice d) All other defenses of the issuer of a certificated or uncertificated security, including nondelivery and conditional delivery of a certificated security, are ineffective against a purchaser for value who has taken without notice of the particular defense e) Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the right of a party to a "when, as and if issued" or a "when distributed" contract to cancel the contract in the event of a material change in the character of the security that is the subject of the contract or in the plan or arrangement pursuant to which the security is to be issued or distributed §28:8-203. Staleness as notice of defects or defenses a) After an act or event creating a right to immediate performance of the principal obligation represented by a certificated security or that sets a date on or after which the security is to be presented or surrendered for redemption or exchange, a purchaser is charged with notice of any defect in its issue or defense of the issuer if 1) The act or event is one requiring the payment of money, the delivery of certificated securities, the registration of transfer of uncertificated securities, or any of these on presentation or surrender § 28:8-203 Enrolled Original of the certificated security, the funds or securities are available on the date set for payment or exchange, and the purchaser takes the security more than 1 year after the date; and 2) The act or event is not covered by paragraph (1) of this subsection and the purchaser takes the security more than 2 years after the date set for surrender or presentation or the date on which performance became due b) A call that has been revoked is not within subsection (a) of this section §28:8-204. Effect of issuer’s restrictions on transfer A restriction on transfer of a security imposed by the issuer, even if otherwise lawful, is ineffective against any person without actual knowledge of it unless 1) The security is certificated, and the restriction is noted conspicuously thereon; or 2) The security is uncertificated, and a notation of the restriction is contained in the initial transaction statement sent to the person, or, if the person~s interest is transferred to the person other than by registration of transfer, pledge, or release, the initial transaction statement sent to the registered owner or the registered pledgee §28:8-205. Effect of unauthorized signature on certificated security or initial transaction statement An unauthorized signature placed on a certificated security prior to or in the course of issue or placed on an initial transaction statement is ineffective, but the signature is effective in favor of a purchaser for value of the certificated security or a purchaser for value of an uncertificatedsecurity to whom the initial transaction statement has been sent, if the purchaser is without notice of the lack of authority and the signing has been done by 1) An authenticating trustee, registrar, transfer agent, or other person entrusted by the issuer with the signing of the security, of similar securities, or of initial transaction statements or the immediate preparation for signing of any of them; or 2) An employee of the issuer, or of any of the foregoing, entrusted with responsible handling of the security or initial transaction statement §28:8-206. Completion or alteration of certificated security or initial transaction statement a) If a certificated security contains the signatures necessary to its issue or transfer but is incomplete in any other respect 1) Any person may compIete it by filling in the blanks as authorized; and 2) Even though the blanks are incorrectly filled in, the security as completed is enforceable by a purchaser who took it for value and without notice of the incorrectness b) A complete certificated security that has been improperly altered, even though fraudulently, remains enforceable, but only according to its original terms c) If an initial transaction statement contains the signatures necessary to its validity, but is incomplete in any other respect 1) Any person may complete it by filling in the blanks as authorized; and § 28:8-204 § 28:8-205 § 28:8-206 Enrolled Original 2) Even though the blanks are incorrectly filled in, the statement as completed is effective in favor of the person to whom it is sent if the person purchased the security referred to therein for value and without notice of the incorrectness d) A complete initial transaction statement that has been improperly altered, even though fraudulently, is effective in favor of a purchaser to whom it has been sent, but only according to its original terms §28:8-207. ]~ights and duties of issuer with respect to registered owners and registered pledgees a) l~rior to due presentment for registration of transfer of a certificated security in registered form, the issuer or indenture trustee may treat the registered owner as the person exclusively entitled to vote, to receive notifications, and otherwise to excise all rights and powers of an owner b) l~ursuant to the provisions of subsections (c d and (f) of this section, the issuer or indenture trustee may treat the registered owner of an uncertificated security as the person exclusively entitled to vote, to receive notifications, and otherwise to exercise all the rights and powers of an owner c) The registered owner of an uncertificated security that is subject to a registered pledge is not entitled to registration of transfer prior to the due presentment to the issuer of a release instruction. The exercise of conversion rights with respect to a convertible uncertificated security is a transfer within the meaning of this section d) Upon due presentment of a transfer instruction from the registered pledgee of an uneertificated security, the issuer shall 1) Register the transfer of the security to the new owner free of pledge, if the instruction specifies a new owner (who may be the registered pledgee) and does not specify a pledgee 2) Register the transfer of the security to the new owner subject to the interest of the existing pledgee, if the instruction specifies a new owner and the existing pledgee; or 3) Register the release of the security from the existing pledge and register the pledge of the security to the other pledgee, if the instruction specifies the existing owner and another pledgee e) Continuity of perfection of a security interest is not broken by registration of transfer under subsection (d)(2) of this section or by registration of release and pledge under subsection (d)(3) of this section if the security interest is assigned f) If an uncertificated security is subject to a registered pledge 1) Any uncertificated securities issued in exchange for or distributed with respect to the pledged security shall be registered subject to the pledge 2) Any certificated securities issued in exchange for or distributed with respect to the pledged security shall be delivered to the registered pledgee; and 3) Any money paid in exchange for or in redemption of part or all of the security shall be paid to the registered pledgee g) Nothing in this article shall be construed to affect the liability of the registered owner of a security for calls, assessments, or the like §28:8-208. Effect of signature of authenticating trustee, registrar, or transfer agent. § 28:8-207 § 28:8-208 Enrolled Original a) A person placing his or her signature upon a certificated security or an initial transaction statement as authenticating trustee, registrar, transfer agent, or the like, warrants to a purchaser for value of the certificated security or a purchaser for value of an uncertificated security to whom the initial transaction statement has been sent, if the purchaser is without notice of the particular defect, that 1) The certificated security or initial transaction statement is genuine 2) The person’s own participation in the issue or registration of the transfer, pledge, or release of the security is within the person’s capacity and within the scope of the authority received by the person from the issuer; and 3) The person has reasonable grounds to believe the security is in the form and within the amount the issuer is authorized to issue b) Unless otherwise agreed, a person by so pIacing the person’s signature does not assume responsibility for the validity of the security in other respects Part 3. Transfer §28:8-301. Rights acquired by purchaser a) Upon transfer of a security to a purchaser (§28:8-313 the purchaser acquires the rights in the security which the purchaser’s transferor had or had actual authority to convey unless the purchaser’s rights are limited by §28:8-302(d b) A transferee of a limited interest acquires rights only to the extent of the interest transferred. The creation or release of a security interest in a security is the transfer of a limited interest in that security §28:8-302 Bona fide purchaser adverse claim title acquired by bona fide purchaser a) A "bona fide purchaser" is a purchaser for value in good faith and without notice of any adverse claim 1) Who takes delivery of a certificated security in bearer form or in registered form, issued or indorsed to the purchaser or in blank 2) To whom the transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security is registered on the books of the issuer; or 3) To whom a security is transferred under the provisions of paragraph (3 4)(A or (7) of §28:8-313(a b Adverse claim" includes a claim that a transfer was or would be wrongful or that a particular adverse person is the owner of or has an interest in the security c) A bona fide purchaser in addition to acquiring the rights of a purchaser (§28:8-301) also acquires an interest in the security free of any adverse claim d) Notwithstanding §28:8-301(a the transferee of a particular certificated security who has been a party to any fraud or illegality affecting the security, or who as a prior holder of that certificated security had notice of an adverse claim, cannot improve the transferee’s position by taking from a bona fide purchaser §28:8-303 Broker Broker" means a person engaged for all or part of the person’s time in the business of buying and selling securities, who in the transaction concerned acts for, buys a security from, or sells a security to, a § 28:8-301 § 28:8-302 § 28:8-303 10 Enrolled Original customer. Nothing in this article determines the capacity in which a person acts for purposes of any other statute or rule to which the person is subject §28:8-304. Notice to purchaser of adverse claims a) A purchaser (including a broker for the seller or buyer, but excluding an intermediary bank) of a certificated security is charged with notice of adverse claims if 1) The security, whether in bearer or registered form, has been indorsed "for collection" or "for surrender" or for some other purpose not involving transfer; or 2) The security is in bearer form and has on it an unambiguous statement that it is the property of a person other than the transferor. The mere writing of a name on a security is not such a statement b) A purchaser (including a broker for the seller or buyer, but excluding an intermediary bank) to whom the transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security is registered is charged with notice of adverse claims as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d) at the time of registration and which are noted in the initial transaction statement sent to the purchaser or, if the purchaser’s interest is transferred to the purchaser other than by registration of transfer, pledge, or release, the initial transaction statement sent to the registered owner or the registered pledgee c) The fact that the purchaser (including a broker for the seller or buyer) of a certificated or uncertificated security has notice that the security is held for a third person or is registered in the name of or indorsed by a fiduciary does not create a duty of inquiry into the rightfulness of the transfer or constitute constructive notice of adverse claims. However, if the purchaser (excluding an intermediary bank) has knowledge that the proceeds are being used or that the transaction is for the individual benefit of the fiduciary or otherwise in breach of duty, the purchaser is charged with notice of adverse claims §28:8-305. Staleness as notice of adverse claims An act or event that creates a right to immediate performance of the principal obligation represented by a certificated security or sets a date on or after which a certificated security is to be presented or surrendered for redemption or exchange does not itself constitute any notice of adverse claims except in the case of a transfer 1) After 1 year from any date set for presentment or surrender for redemption or exchange; or 2) After 6 months from any date set for payment of money against presentation or surrender of the security if funds are available for payment on that date §28:8-306. Warranties on presentment and transfer of certificated securities; warranties of originators of instructions a) A person who presents a certificated security for registration of transfer or for payment or exchange warrants to the issuer that the person is entitled to the registration, payment, or exchange. But a purchaser for value and without notice of adverse claims who receives a new, reissued, or reregistered certificated security on registration of transfer or receives an initial transaction statement confirming the registration of transfer of an equivalent uncertificated security to the § 28:8-304 § 28:8-305 § 28:8-306 11 Enrolled Original purchaser warrants only that the purchaser has no knowledge of any unauthorized signature (§28:8-311) in a necessary indorsement b) A person by transferring a certificated security to a purchaser for value warrants only that 1) The person’s transfer is effective and rightful 2) The security is genuine and has not been materially altered; and 3) The person knows of no fact which might impair the validity of the security c) If a certificated security is delivered by an intermediary known to be entrusted with delivery of the security on behalf of another or with collection of a draft or other claim against delivery, the intermediary by delivery warrants only the intermediary’s own good faith and authority, even though the intermediary has purchased or made advances against the claim to be collected against the delivery d) A pledgee or other holder for security who redelivers a certificated security received, or after payment and on order of the debtor delivers that security to a third person, makes only the warranties of an intermediary under subsection (c) of this section e) A person who originates an instruction warrants to the issuer that 1) The person is an appropriate person to originate the instruction; and 2) At the time the instruction is presented to the issuer the person who originates the instruction will be entitled to the registration of transfer, pledge, or release f) A person who originates an instruction warrants to any person specifically guaranteeing the person’s signature (§28:8-312(c that 1) The person is an appropriate person to originate the instruction; and 2) At the time the instruction is presented to the issuer A) The person will be entitled to the registration of transfer, pledge, or release; and B) The transfer, pledge, or release requested in the instruction will be registered by the issuer free from all liens, security interests, restrictions, and claims other than those specified in the instruction g) A person who originates an instruction warrants to a purchaser for value and to any person guaranteeing the instruction (§28:8-312(f that: The person is an appropriate person to originate the"(1) instruction 2) and 3) The uncertificated security referred to therein is valid; At the time the instruction is presented to the issuer A) The transferor will be entitled to the registration of transfer, pledge, or release B) The transfer, pledge, or release requested in the instruction will be registered by the issuer free from all liens, security interests, restrictions, and claims other than those specified in the instruction; and C) The requested transfer, pledge, or release will be rightful. 12 Enrolled Original h) If a secured party is the registered pledgee or the registered owner of an uncertificated security, a person who originates an instruction of release or transfer to the debtor or, after payment and on order of the debtor, a transfer instruction to a third person, warrants to the debtor or the third person only that the person is an appropriate person to originate the instruction and, at the time the instruction is presented to the issuer, the transferor will be entitled to the registration of release or transfer. If a transfer instruction to a third person who is a purchaser for value is originated on order of the debtor, the debtor makes to the purchaser the warranties of paragraphs (2 3)(B and (3)(C) of subsection (g) of this section i) A person who transfers an uncertificated security to a purchaser for value and does not originate an instruction in connection with the transfer warrants only that 1) The person’s transfer is effective and rightful; and 2) The uncertificated security is valid j) A broker gives to the broker’s customer and to the issuer and a purchaser the applicable warranties provided in this section and has the rights and privileges of a purchaser under this section. The warranties of and in favor of the broker, acting as an agent, are in addition to applicable warranties given by and in favor of the broker’s customer §28:8-307. Effect of delivery without indorsement; right to compel indorsement If a certificated security in registered form has been delivered to a purchaser without a necessary indorsement the purchaser may become a bona fide purchaser only as of the time the indorsement is supplied; but against the transferor, the transfer is complete upon delivery and the purchaser has a specifically enforceable right to have any necessary indorsement supplied §28:8-308. Indorsements; instructions a) An indorsement of a certificated security in registered form is made when an appropriate person signs on it or on a separate document an assignment or transfer of the security or a power to assign or transfer it or the person’s signature is written without more upon the back of the securit b) An indorsement may be in blank or special. An indorsement in blank includes an indorsement to bearer. A special indorsement specifies to whom the security is to be transferred or who has power to transfer it. A holder may convert a blank indorsement into a special indorsement c) An indorsement purporting to be only of part of a certificated security representing units intended by the issuer to be separately transferable is effective to the extent of the indorsement d) An "instruction" is an order to the issuer of an uncertificated security requesting that the transfer, pledge, or release from pledge of the uncertificated security specified therein be registered e) An instruction originated by an appropriate person is 1) A writing signed by an appropriate person; or 2) A communication to the issuer in any form agreed upon in a writing signed by the issuer and an appropriate person f) If an instruction has been originated by an appropriate person but is incomplete in any other respect, any person may complete it as § 28:8-307 § 28:8-308 13 Enrolled Original authorized and the issuer may rely on it as completed even though it has been completed incorrectly g An appropriate person" in subsection (a) of this section means the person specified by the certificated security or by special indorsement to be entitled to the security h An appropriate person" in subsection (e) or (f) of this section means 1) For an instruction to transfer or pledge an uncertificated security which is then not subject to a registered pledge, the registered owner; or 2) For an instruction to transfer or release an uncertificated security which is then subject to a registered pledge, the registered pledgee i) In addition to the persons designated in subsections (g) and (h) of this section an appropriate person" in subsections (a e and (f) of this section includes 1) If the person designated is described as a fiduciary but is no longer serving in the described capacity, either that person or his successor 2) If the persons designated are described as more than 1 person as fiduciaries and 1 or more are no longer serving in the described capacity, the remaining fiduciary or fiduciaries, whether or not a successor has been appointed or qualified 3) If the person designated is an individual and is without capacity to act by virtue of death, incompetence, infancy, or otherwise, the person~s executor, administrator, guardian, or like fiduciary 4) If the persons designated are described as more than 1 person as tenants by the entirety or with right of survivorship and by reason of death all cannot sign, the survivor or survivors 5) A person having power to sign under applicable law or controlling instruments; and 6) To the extent that the person designated or any of the foregoing persons may act through an agent, the person~s authorized agent j) Unless otherwise agreed, the indorser of a certificated security by the indorser~s indorsement or the originator of an instruction by the indorser~s origination assumes no obligation that the security will be honored by the issuer but only the obligations provided in §28:8-306 k) Whether the person signing is appropriate is determined as of the date of signing and an indorsement made by or an instruction originated by the person does not become unauthorized for the purposes of this article by virtue of any subsequent change of circumstances I) Failure of a fiduciary to comply with a controlling instrument or with the law of the state having jurisdiction of the f~duciary relationship, including any law requiring the fiduciary to obtain court approval of the transfer, pledge, or release, does not render the fiduciaryls indorsement or an instruction originated by the fiduciary unauthorized for the purposes of this article §28:8-309. Effect of indorsement without delivery An indorsement of a certificated security, whether special or in blank, does not constitute a transfer until delivery of the certificated security on which it appears, or, if the indorsement Js on a separate § 28:8-309 Enrolled Original document, until delivery of both the document and the certificated security §28:8-310. Indorsement of certificated security in bearer form An indorsement of a certificated security in bearer form may give notice of adverse claims (§28:8-304) but does not otherwise affect any right to registration the holder possesses §28:8-311. Effect of unauthorized indorsement or instruction Unless the owner or pledgee has ratified an unauthorized indorsement or instruction or is otherwise precluded from asserting its ineffectiveness 1) The owner or pledgee may assert its ineffectiveness against the issuer or any purchaser, other than a purchaser for value and without notice of adverse claims, who has in good faith received a new, reissued, or reregistered certificated security on registration of transfer or received an initial transaction statement confirming the registration of transfer, pledge, or release of an equivalent uncertificated security to the owner or pledgee; and 2) An issuer who registers the transfer of a certificated security upon the unauthorized indorsement or who registers the transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security upon the unauthorized instruction is subject to liability for improper registration (§28:8-404 §28:8-312. Effect of guaranteeing signature, indorsement, or instruction a) Any person guaranteeing a signature of an indorser of a certificated security warrants that at the time of signing 1) The signature was genuine 2) The signer was an appropriate person to indorse (§28:8-308 and 3) The signer had legal capacity to sign b) Any person guaranteeing a signature of the originator of an instruction warrants that at the time of signing 1) The signature was genuine 2) The signer was an appropriate person to originate the instruction (§28:8-308) if the person specified in the instruction as the registered owner or registered pledgee of the uncertificated security was, in fact, the registered owner or registered pledgee of the security, as to which fact the signature guarantor makes no warranty 3) The signer had legal capacity to sign; and 4) The taxpayer identification number, if any, appearing on the instruction as that of the registered owner or registered pledgee was the taxpayer identification number of the signer or of the owner or pledgee for whom the signer was acting c) Any person specially guaranteeing the signature of the originator of an instruction makes not only the warranties of a signature guarantor (subsection (b) of this section) but also warrants that at the time the instruction is presented to the issuer 1) The person specified in the instruction as the registered owner or registered pledgee of the uncertificated security will be the registered owner or registered pledgee; and 2) The transfer, pledge, or release of the uncertificated security requested in the instruction will be registered by the issuer free § 28:8-310 § 28:8-311 § 28:8-312 15 Enrolled Original from all liens, security interests, restrictions, and claims other than those specified in the instruction d) The guarantor under subsections (a) and (b) of this section or the special guarantor under subsection (c) of this section does not otherwise warrant the rightfulness of the particular transfer, pledge, or release e) Any person guaranteeing an indorsement of a certificated security makes not only the warranties of a signature guarantor under subsection (a) of this section but also warrants the rightfulness of the particular transfer in all respects f) Any person guaranteeing an instruction requesting the transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security makes not only the warranties of a special signature guarantor under subsection (c) of this section but also warrants the rightfulness of the particular transfer, pledge, or release in all respects g) No issuer may require a special guarantee of signature (subsection (c) of this section a guarantee of indorsement (subsection (e) of this section or a guarantee of instruction (subsection (f) of this section) as a condition to registration of transfer, pledge, or release h) The foregoing warranties are made to any person taking or dealing with the security in reliance on the guarantee, and the guarantor is liable to the person for any loss resulting from breach of the warranties §28:8-313. When transfer to purchaser occurs; financial intermediary as bona fide purchaser financial intermediary a) Transfer of a security or a limited interest (including a security interest therein) to a purchaser occurs only 1) At the time the purchaser or a person designated by the purchaser acquires possession of a certificated security 2) At the time the transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security is registered to the purchaser or a person designated by the purchaser 3) At the time the purchaser’s financial intermediary acquires possession of a certificated security specially indorsed to or issued in the name of the purchaser 4) At the time a financial intermediary, not a clearing corporation, sends the purchaser confirmation of the purchase and also by book entry or otherwise identifies as belonging to the purchaser A) A specific certificated security in the financial intermediary’s possession B) A quantity of securities that constitute or are part of a fungible bulk of certificated securities in the financial intermediary’s possession or of uncertificated securities registered in the name of the financial intermediary; or C) A quantity of securities that constitute or are part of a fungible bulk of securities shown on the account of the financial intermediary on the books of another financial intermediary 5) With respect to an identified certificated security to be delivered while still in the possession of a third person, not a financial intermediary, at the time that person acknowledges that the person holds for the purchaser 6) With respect to a specific uncertificated security the pledge or transfer of which has been registered to a third person, not 16 § 28:8-313 Enrolled Original a financial intermediary, at the time that person acknowledges that the person holds for the purchaser; 11(7) At the time appropriate entries to the account of the purchaser or a person designated by the purchaser on the books of a clearing corporation are made under §28:8-320; I’(8) With respect to the transfer of a security interest where the debtor has signed a security agreement containing a description of the security, at the time a written notification, which, in the case of the creation of the security interest, is signed by the debtor (which may be a copy of the security agreement) or which, in the case of the release or assignment of the security interest created pursuant to this paragraph, is signed by the secured party, is received by A) A financial intermediary on whose books the interest of the transferor in the security appears; ’(B) A third person, not a financial intermediary, in possession of the security, if it is certificated C) A third person, not a financial intermediary, who is the registered owner of the security, if it is uncertificated and not subject to a registered pledge; or ’(D) A third person, not a financial intermediary, who is the registered pledgee of the security, if it is uncertificated and subject to a registered pledge 9) With respect to the transfer of a security interest where the transferor has signed a security agreement containing a description of the security at the time new value is given by the secured party; or 10) With respect to the transfer of a security interest where the secured Party is a financial intermediary and the security has already been transferred to the financial intermediary under paragraph (1 2 3 4 or (5) of this subsection, at the time the transferor has signed a security agreement containing a description of the security and value is given by the secured party b) The purchaser is the owner of a security held for the purchaser by a financial intermediary, but cannot be a bona fide purchaser of a security so held except in the circumstances specified in paragraphs (3 4)(A and (7) of subsection (a) of this section. If a security so held is part of a fungible bulk, as in the circumstances specified in paragraphs (4)(B) and (4)(C) of subsection (a) of this section, the purchaser is the owner of a proportionate property interest in the fungible bulk c) Notice of an adverse claim received by the financial intermediary or by the purchaser after the financial intermediary takes delivery of a certificated security as a holder for value or after the transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security has been registered free of the claim to a financial intermediary who has given value is not effective either as to the financial intermediary or as to the purchaser. However, as between the financial intermediary and the purchaser, the purchaser may demand transfer of an equivalent security as to which no notice of adverse claim has been received d) A "financial intermediary" is a bank, broker, clearing corporation, or other person (or the nominee of any of them) which in the ordinary course of its business maintains security accounts for its customers and is acting in that capacity. A financial intermediary may have a security interest in securities held in account for its customer. 17 Enrolled Original "§28:8-314. Duty to transfer, when completed a) Unless otherwise agreed, if a sale of a security is made on an exchange or otherwise through brokers 1) The selling customer fulfills the duty to transfer at the time the selling customer A) Places a certificated security in the possession of the selling broker or a person designated by the broker B) Causes an uncertificated security to be registered in the name of the selling broker or a person designated by the broker C) If requested, causes an acknowledgment to be made to the selling broker that a certificated or uncertificated security is held for the broker; or D) Places in the possession of the selling broker or of a person designated by the broker a transfer instruction for an uncertificated security, providing the issuer does not refuse to register the requested transfer if the instruction is presented to the issuer for registration within 30 days thereafter; and 2) The selling broker, including a correspondent broker acting for a selling customer, fulfills the brokerts duty to transfer at the time the broker A) Places a certificated security in the possession of the buying broker or a person designated by the buying broker B) Causes an uncertificated security to be registered in the name of the buying broker or a person designated by the buying broker C) Places in the possession of the buying broker, or a person designated by the buying broker, a transfer instruction for an uncertificated security, providing the issuer does not refuse to register the requested transfer if the instruction is presented to the issuer for registration within 30 days thereafter; or D) Effects clearance of the sale in accordance with the rules of the exchange on which the transaction took place b) Except as provided in this section or unless otherwise agreed, a transferor~s duty to transfer a security under a contract of purchase is not fulfilled until the transferor 1) Places a certificated security in form to be negotiated by the purchaser in the possession of the purchaser or of a person designated by the purchaser 2) Causes an uncertificated security to be registered in the name of the purchaser or a person designated by the purchaser; or 3) If the purchaser requests, causes an acknowledgment to be made to the purchaser that a certificated or uncertificated security is held for the purchaser c) Unless made on an exchange, a sale to a broker purchasing for the broker’s own account is within subsection (b) of this section and not within subsection (a) of this section §28:8-315. Action against transferee based upon wrongful transfer a) Any person against whom the transfer of a security is wrongful for any reason, including the person~s incapacity, as against anyone except a bona fide purchaser, may 1) Keclaim possession of the certificated security wrongfully transferred; § 28:8-314 § 28:8-315 Enrolled Original 2) Obtain possession of any new certificated security representing all or part of the same rights 3) Compel the origination of an instruction to transfer to the person or a designee an uncertificated security constituting all or part of the same rights; or 4) Have damages b) If the transfer is wrongful because of an unauthorized indorsement of a certificated security the owner may also reclaim or obtain possession of the security or a new certificated security, even from a bona fide purchaser, if the ineffectiveness of the purported indorsement can be asserted against the owner under the provisions of this article on unauthorized indorsements (§28:8-311 c) The right to obtain or reclaim possession of a certificated security or to compel the origination of a transfer instruction may be specifically enforced and the transfer of a certificated or uncertificated security enjoined and a certificated security impounded pending the litigation §28:8-316. l~urchaser~s right to requisites for registration of transfer, pledge, or release on books Unless otherwise agreed, the transferor of a certificated security or the transferor, pledgor, or pledgee of an uncertificated security on due demand must supply the purchaser with any proof of the transferor~s authority to transfer, pledge, or release or with any other requisite necessary to obtain registration of the transfer, pledge, or release of the security; but if the transfer, pledge, or release is not for value, a transferor, pledgor, or pledgee need not do so unless the purchaser furnishes the .necessary expenses, l~ailure within a reasonable time to comply with a demand made gives the purchaser the right to reject or rescind the transfer, pledge, or release §28:8-317. Creditors~ rights a) Subject to the exceptions in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, no attachment or levy upon a certificated security or any share or other interest represented thereby that is outstanding is valid until the security is actually seized by the officer making the attachment or levy, but a certificated security that has been surrendered to the issuer may be reached by a creditor by legal process at the issuer’s chief executive office in the United States b) An uncertificated security registered in the name of the debtor may not be reached by a creditor except by legal process at the issuer’s chief executive office in the United States c) The interest of a debtor in a certificated security that is in the possession of a secured party not a financial intermediary or in an uncertificated security registered in the name of a secured party not a financial intermediary (or in the name of a nominee of the secured party) may be reached by a creditor by legal process upon the secured party d) The interest of a debtor in a certificated security that is in the possession of or registered in the name of a financial intermediary or in an uncertificated security registered in the name of a financial intermediary may be reached by a creditor by legal process upon the financial intermediary on whose books the interest of the debtor appears e) Unless otherwise provided by law, a creditor’s lien upon the interest of a debtor in a security obtained pursuant to subsection (c) or (d) of this section is not a restraint on the transfer of the security, 19 § 28:8-316 § 28:8-317 Enrolled Original free of the lien, to a third party for new value; but in the event of a transfer, the lien applies to the proceeds of the transfer in the hands of the secured party or financial intermediary, subject to any claims having priority f) A creditor whose debtor is the owner of a security is entitled to aid from courts of appropriate jurisdiction, by injunction or otherwise, in reaching the security or in satisfying the claim by means allowed at law or in equity in regard to property that cannot readily be reached by ordinary legal process §28:8-318. No conversion by good faith conduct An agent or bailee who in good faith (including observance of reasonable commercial standards if the agent or bailee is in the business of buying, selling, or otherwise dealing with securities) has received certificated securities and sold, pledged, or delivered them or has sold or caused the transfer or pledge of uncertificated securities over which the agent or bailee had control according to the instructions of the principal of the agent or bailee, is not liable for conversion or for participation in breach of fiduciary duty although the principal had no right so to deal with the securities §28:8-319. Statute of frauds A contract for the sale of securities is not enforceable by way of action or defense unless 1) There is some writing signed by the party against whom enforcement is sought, or by the party’s authorized agent or broker, sufficient to indicate that a contract has been made for sale of a stated quantity of described securities at a defined or stated price 2) Delivery of a certificated security or transfer instruction has been accepted, or transfer of an uncertificated security has been registered and the transferee has failed to send written objection to the issuer within 10 days after receipt of the initial transaction statement confirming the registration, or payment has been made, but the contract is enforceable under this provision only to the extent of the delivery, registration, or payment 3) Within a reasonable time a writing in confirmation of sale or purchase and sufficient against the sender under paragraph (1) of this section has been received by the party against whom enforcement is sought and the party has failed to send written objection to its contents within 10 days after its receipt; or 4) The party against whom enforcement is sought admits in the party’s pleading, testimony, or otherwise in court that a contract Was made for the sale of a stated quantity of described securities at a defined or stated price §28:8-320. Transfer or pledge within central depository system a) In addition to other methods, a transfer, pledge, or release of a security or any interest therein may be effected by the making of appropriate entries on the books of a clearing corporation reducing the account of the transferor, pledgor, or pledgee and increasing the account of the transferee, pledgee, or pledgor by the amount of the obligation or the number of shares or rights transferred, pledged, or released, if the security is shown on the account of a transferor, pledgor, or pledgee on the books of the clearing corporation, is subject to the control of the clearing corporation; and 1) If certificated, § 28:8-318 § 28:8-319 § 28:8-320 20 Enrolled Original A) Is in the custody of the clearing corporation, another clearing corporation, a custodian bank, or a nominee of any of them; and B) Is in bearer form or indorsed in blank by an appropriate person or registered in the name of the clearing corporation, a custodian bank, or a nominee of any of them; or 2) If uncerti£icated, is registered in the name of the clearing corporation, another clearing corporation, a custodian bank, or nominee of any of them b) Under this section entries may be made with respect to like securities or interests therein as a part of a fungible bulk and may refer merely to a quantity of a particular security without reference to the name o£ the registered owner, certificate or bond number, or the like, and, in appropriate cases, may be on a net basis taking into account other transfers, pledges, or releases of the same security c) A transfer under this section is effective (§28:8-313) and the purchaser acquires the rights of the transferor (§28:8-301 A pledge or release under this section is the transfer of a limited interest. If a pledge or the creation of a security interest is intended, the security interest is perfected at the time when both value is given by the pledgee and the appropriate entries are made (§28:8-321 A transferee or pledgee under this section may be a bona fide purchaser (§28:8-302 d) A transfer or pledge under this section is not a registration of transfer under Part 4 e) That entries made on the books of the clearing corporation as provided in subsection (a) of this section are not appropriate does not affect the validity or effect of the entries or the liabilities or obligation of the clearing corporation to any person adversely affected thereby §28:8-321. Enforceability; attachment; perfection; and termination of security interests a) A security interest in a security is enforceable and can attach only if it is transferred to the secured party or a person designated by the party pursuant to a provision of §28:8-313(a b) A security interest so transferred pursuant to agreement by a transferor who has rights in the security to a transferee who has given value is a perfected security interest, but a security interest that has been transferred solely under subparagraph (A) of section 28:8-313(a)(4) becomes unperfected after 21 days unless, within that time, the requirements for transfer under any other provision of §28:8-313(a) are satisfied c) A security interest in a security is subject to the provisions of Article 9, but 1) No filing is required to perfect the security interest; and 2) No written security agreement signed by the debtor is necessary to make the security interest enforceable, except as provided in paragraph (8 9 or (10) of §28:8-313(a The secured party has the rights and duties provided under §28:9-207, to the extent they are applicable, whether or not the security is certificated, and, if certificated, whether or not it is in the party’s possession d) Unless otherwise agreed, a security interest in a security is terminated by transfer to the debtor or a person designated by the debtor pursuant to a provision of §28:8-313(a If a security is thus 28;8-321 21 Enrolled Original transferred, the security interest, if not terminated, becomes unperfected unless the security is certificated and is delivered to the debtor for the purpose of ultimate sale or exchange or presentation, collection, renewal, or registration of transfer. In that case, the security interest becomes unperfected after 21 days unless, within that time, the security (or securities for which it has been exchanged) is transferred to the secured party or a person designated by the party pursuant to a provision of §28:8-313(a Part 4. Registration 328:8-401. Duty of issuer to register a transfer, pledge, or release a) If a certificated security in registered form is presented to the issuer with a request to register a transfer or an instruction is presented to the issuer with a request to register a transfer, pledge, or release, the issuer shall register the transfer, pledge, or release as requested if 1) The security is indorsed or the instruction was originated by the appropriate person or persons (§28:8-308 2) Reasonable assurance is given that those indorsements or instructions are genuine and effective (§28:8-402 3) The issuer has no duty as to adverse claims or has discharged the duty (§28:8-403 4) Any applicable law relating to the collection of taxes has been complied with; and 5) The transfer, pledge, or release is in fact rightful or is to a bona fide purchaser b) If .an issuer is under a duty to register a transfer, pledge, or release of a security, the issuer is also liable to the person presenting a certificated security or an instruction for registration or the issuer’s principal for loss resulting from any unreasonable delay in registration or from failure or refusal to register the transfer, pledge, or release §28:8-402. Assurance that indorsements and instructions are effective a) The issuer may require the following assurance that each necessary indorsement of a certificated security or each instruction (328:8-308) is genuine and effective 1) In all cases, a guarantee of the signature (§28:8-312(a) and (b of the person indorsing a certificated security or originating an instruction including, in the case of an instruction, a warranty of the taxpayer indentification number or, in the absence thereof, other reasonable assurance of identity 2) If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by an agent, appropriate assurance of authority to sign 3) If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by a fiduciary, appropriate evidence of appointment or incumbency 4) If there is more than 1 fiduciary, reasonable assurance that all who are required to sign have done so; and 5) If the indorsement is made or the instruction is originated by a person not covered by any of the foregoing, assurance appropriate to the case corresponding as nearly as may be to the foregoing b) A "guarantee of the signature" in subsection (a)(1) of this section means a guarantee signed by or on behalf of a person reasonably 22 § 28:8-401 § 28:8-402 Enrolled Original believed by the issuer to be responsible. The issuer may adopt standards with respect to responsibility if they are not manifestly unreasonable c Appropriate evidence of appointment or incumbency" in subsection (a)(3) of this section means 1) In the case of a fiduciary appointed or qualified by a court, a certificate issued by or under the direction or supervision of that court or an officer thereof and dated within 60 days before the date of presentation for transfer, pledge, or release; or 2) In any other case, a copy of a document showing the appointment or a certificate issued by or on behalf of a person reasonably believed by the issuer to be responsible or, in the absence of that document or certificate, other evidence reasonably deemed by the issuer to be appropriate. The issuer may adopt standards with respect to the evidence if they are not manifestly unreasonable. The issuer is not charged with notice of the contents of any document obtained pursuant to this paragraph except to the extent that the contents relate directly to the appointment or incumbency d) The issuer may elect to require reasonable assurance beyond that specified in this section, but if it does so and, for a purpose other than that specified in subsection (c)(2) of this section, requires and obtains a copy of a will, trust, indenture, articles of co-partnership, by-laws, or other controlling instrument, it is charged with notice of all matters contained therein affecting the transfer, pledge, or release §28:8-403. Issuer’s duty as to adverse claims a) An issuer to whom a certificated security is presented for registration shall inquire into adverse claims if 1) A written notification of an adverse claim is received at a time and in a manner affording the issuer a reasonable opportunity to act on it prior to the issuance of a new, reissued, or reregistered certificated security, and the notification identifies the claimant, the registered owner, and the issue of which the security is a part, and provides an address for communications directed to the claimant; or 2) The issuer is charged with notice of an adverse claim from a controlling instrument it has elected to require under §28:8-402(d b) The issuer may discharge any duty of inquiry by any reasonable means, including notifying an adverse claimant by registered or certified mail at the address furnished by the issuer or, if there be no such address, at the issuer’s residence or regular place of business that the certificated security has been presented for registration of transfer by a named person, and that the transfer will be registered unless within 30 days from the date of mailing the notification, either 1) An appropriate restraining order, injunction, or other process issues from a court of competent jurisdiction; or 2) There is filed with the issuer an indemnity bond, sufficient in the issuer’s judgment to protect the issuer and any transfer agent, registrar, or other agent of the issuer involved from any loss it or they may suffer by complying with the adverse claim c) Unless an issuer is charged with notice of an adverse claim from a controlling instrument which it has elected to require under §28:8-402(d) or receives notification of an adverse claim under subsection (a) of this section, if a certificated security presented for registration is indorsed by the appropriate person or persons the issuer is under no duty to inquire into adverse claims. In particular: § 28:8-403 23 Enrolled Original 1) An issuer registering a certificated security in the name of a person who is a fiduciary or who is described as a fiduciary is not bound to inquire into the existence, extent, or correct description of the fiduciary relationship; and thereafter the issuer may assume without inquiry that the newly registered owner continues to be the fiduciary until the issuer receives written notice that the fiduciary is no longer acting as such with respect to the particular security 2) An issuer registering transfer on an indorsement by a fiduciary is not bound to inquire whether the transfer is made in compliance with a controlling instrument or with the law of the state having jurisdiction of the fiduciary relationship, including any law requiring the fiduciary to obtain court approval of the transfer; and 3) The issuer is not charged with notice of the contents of any court record or file or other recorded or unrecorded document even though the document is in its possession and even though the transfer is made on the indorsement of a fiduciary to the fiduciary or to the fiduciary’s nominee d) An issuer is under no duty as to adverse claims with respect to an uncertificated security except 1) Claims embodied in a restraining order, injunction, or other legal process served upon the issuer if the process was served at a time and in a manner affording the issuer a reasonable opportunity to act on it in accordance with the requirements of subsection (e) of this section 2) Claims of which the issuer has received a written notification from the registered owner or the registered pledgee if the notification was received at a time and in a manner affording the issuer a reasonable opportunity to act on it in accordance with the requirements of subsection (e) of this section 3) Claims (including restrictions on transfer not imposed by the issuer) to which the registration of transfer to the present registered owner was subject and were so noted in the initial transaction statement sent to the registered owner; and 4) Claims as to which an issuer is charged with notice from a controlling instrument it has elected to require under §28:8-402(d e) If the issuer of an uncertificated security is under a duty as to an adverse claim, the issuer discharges that duty by 1) Including a notation of the claim in any statements sent with respect to the security under §28:8-408(c f and (g and 2) l~efusing to register the transfer or pledge of the security unless the nature of the claim does not preclude transfer or pledge subject thereto f) If the transfer or pledge of the security is registered subject to an adverse claim, a notation of the claim must be included in the initial transaction statement and all subsequent statements sent to the transferee and pledgee under §28:8-408 g) Notwithstanding subsections (d) and (e) of this section, if an uncertificated security was subject to a registered pledge at the time the issuer first came under a duty as to a particular adverse claim, the issuer has no duty as to that claim if transfer of the security is requested by the registered pledgee or an appropriate person acting for the registered pledgee unless: Enrolled Original 1) The claim was embodied in legal process that expressly provides otherwise 2) The claim was asserted in a written notification from the registered pledgee 3) The claim was one as to which the issuer was charged with notice from a controlling instrument it required under §28:8-402(d) in connection with the pledgee’s request for transfer; or 4) The transfer requested is to the registered owner §28:8-404. Liability and nonliability for registration a) Except as provided in any law relating to the collection of taxes, the issuer is not liable to the owner, pledgee, or any other person suffering loss as a result of the registration of a transfer, pledge, or release of a security if 1) There were on or with a certificated security the necessary indorsements or the issuer had received an instruction originated by an appropriate person (§28:8-308 and 2) The issuer had no duty as to adverse claims or has discharged the duty (§28:8-403 b) If an issuer has registered a transfer of a certificated security to a person not entitled to it, the issuer on demand shall deliver a like security to the true owner unless I) The registration was pursuant to subsection (a) of this section 2) The owner is precluded from asserting any claim for registering the transfer under §28:8-405(a or 3) The delivery would result in overissue, in which case the issuer’s li.ability is governed by §28:8-104 c) If an issuer has improperly registered a transfer, pledge, or release of an uncertificated security, the issuer on demand from the injured party shall restore the records as to the injured party to the condition that would have obtained if the improper registration had not been made unless 1) The registration was pursuant to subsection (a) of this section; or 2) The registration would result in overissuo, in which case the issuer’s liability is governed by §28:8-104 §28:8-405. Lost, destroyed, and stolen certificated securities a) If a certificated security has been lost, apparently destroyed, or wrongfully taken, and the owner fails to notify the issuer of that fact within a reasonable time after the owner has notice of it and the issuer registers a transfer of the security before receiving notification, the owner is precluded from asserting against the issuer any claim for registering the transfer under §28:8-404 or any claim to a new security under this section b) If the owner of a certificated security claims that the security has been lost, destroyed, or wrongfully taken, the issuer shall issue a new certificated security or, at the option of issuer, an equivalent uncertificated security in place of the original security if the owner 1) So requests before the issuer has notice that the security has been acquired by a bona fide purchaseri 2) l~iles with the issuer a sufficient idemnity bond; and 3) Satisfies any other reasonable requirements imposed by the issuer. § 28:8-404 § 28:8-405 25 Enrolled Original c) If, after the issue of a new certificated or uncertificated security, a bona fide purchaser of the original certificated security presents it for registration of transfer, the issuer shall register the transfer unless registration would result in overissue, in which event the issuer’s liability is governed by §28:8-104. In addition to any rights on the indemnity bond, the issuer may recover the new certificated security from the person to whom it was issued or any person taking under the person except a bona fide purchaser or may cancel the uncertificated security unless a bona fide purchaser or any person taking under a bona fide purchaser is then the registered owner or registered pledgee thereof §28:8-406. Duty of authenticating trustee, transfer agent, or registrar a) If a person acts as authenticating trustee, transfer agent, registrar, or other agent for an issuer in the registration of transfers of its certificated securities or in the registration of transfers, pledges, and releases of its uncertificated securities, in the issue of new securities, or in the cancellation of surrendered securities 1) The person is under a duty to the issuer to exercise good faith and due diligence in performing the person’s function; and 2) With regard to the particular functions the person performs, the person has the same obligation to the holder or owner of a certificated security or to the owner or pledgee of an uncertificated security and has the same rights and privileges as the functions performed by the agent §28:8-407. Exchangeability of securities a) No issuer is subject to the requirements of this section unless it regularly maintains a system for issuing the class of securities involved under which both certificated and uncertificated securities are regularly issued to the category of owners, which includes the person in whose name the new security is to be registered b) Upon surrender of a certificated security with all necessary indorsements and presentation of a written request by the person surrendering the security, the issuer, if the issuer has no duty as to adverse claims or has discharged the duty (§28:8-403 shall issue to the person or the person’s designee an equivalent uncertificated security subject to all liens, restrictions, and claims that were noted on the certificated security c) Upon receipt of a transfer instruction originated by an appropriate person who so requests, the issuer of an uncertificated security shall cancel the uncertificated security and issue an equivalent certificated security on which must be noted conspicuously any liens and restrictions of the issuer and any adverse claims (as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d to which the uncertificated security was subject. The certificated security shall be registered in the name of and delivered to 1) The registered owner, if the uncertificated security was not subject to a registered pledge; or 2) The registered pledgee, if the uncertificated security was subject to a registered pledge §28:8-408. Statements of uncertificated securities a) Within 2 business days after the transfer of an uncertificated security has been registered, the issuer shall send to the new registered § 28:8-406 § 28:8-407 § 28:8-408 26 Enrolled Original owner and, if the security has been transferred subject to a registered pledge, to the registered pledgee a written statement containing 1) A description of the issue of which the uncertificated security is a part 2) The number of shares or units transferred 3) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the new registered owner and, if the security has been transferred subject to a registered pledge, the name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered pledgee 4) A notation of any liens and restrictions of the issuer and any adverse claims (as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d to which the uncertificated security is or may be subject at the time of registration or a statement that there are none of those liens, restrictions, or adverse claims; and 5) The date the transfer was registered b) Within 2 business days after the pledge of an uncertificated security has been registered, the issuer shall send to the registered owner and the registered pledgee a written statement containing 1) A description of the issue of which the uncertificated security is a part 2) The number of shares or units pledged 3) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered owner and the registered pledgee 4) A notation of any liens and restrictions of the issuer and any adverse claims (as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d to which the uncertificated security is or may be subject at the time of. registration or a statement that there are none of those liens, restrictions, or adverse claims; and 5) The date the pledge was registered c) Within 2 business days after the release from pledge of an uncertificated security has been registered, the issuer shall send to the registered owner and the pledgee whose interest was released a written statement containing 1) A description of the issue of which the uncertificated security is a part 2) The number of shares or units released from pledge 3) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered owner and the pledgee whose interest was released 4) A notation of any liens and restrictions of the issuer and any adverse claims (as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d to which the uncertificated security is or may be subject at the time of registration or a statement that there are none of those liens, restrictions, or adverse claims; and 5) The date the release was registered d) An "initial transaction statement" is the statement sent to 1) The new registered owner and, if applicable, to the registered pledgee pursuant to subsection (a) of this section 2) The registered pledgee pursuant to subsection (b) of this section; or 3) The registered owner pursuant to subsection (c) of this section. 27 Enrolled Original e) Each initial transaction statement shall be signed by or on behalf of the issuer and must be identified as "Initial Transaction Statement f) Within 2 business days after the transfer of an uncertificated security has been registered, the issuer shall send to the former registered owner and the former registered pledgee, if any, a written statement containing 1) A description of the issue of which the uncertificated security is a part 2) The number of shares or units transferred 3) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the former registered owner and of any former registered pledgee; and 4) The date the transfer was registered g) At periodic intervals no less frequent than annually and at any time upon the reasonable written request of the registered owner, the issuer shall send to the registered owner of each uncertificated security a dated written statement containing 1) A description of the issue of which the uncertificated security is a part 2) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered owner 3) The number of shares or units of the uncertificated security registered in the name of the registered owner on the date of the statement 4) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered pledgee and the number of shares or units subject to the pledge; and 5) A notation of any liens and restrictions of the issuer and any adverse claims (as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d to which the uncertificated security is or may be subject or a statement that there are none of those liens, restrictions, or adverse claims h) At periodic intervals no less frequent than annually and at any time upon the reasonable written request of the registered pledgee, the issuer shall send to the registered pledgee of each uncertificated security a dated written statement containing 1) A description of the issue of which the uncertificated security is a part 2) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered owner 3) The name and address and any taxpayer identification number of the registered pledgee 4) The number of shares or units subject to the pledge; and 5) A notation of any liens and restrictions of the issuer and any adverse claims (as to which the issuer has a duty under §28:8-403(d to which the uncertificated security is or may be subject or a statement that there are none of those liens, restrictions, or adverse claims i) If the issuer sends the statements described in subsections (g) and (h) of this section at periodic intervals no less frequent than quarterly, the issuer is not obligated to send additional statements upon 28 Enrolled Original request unless the owner or pledgee requesting them pays to the issuer the reasonable cost of furnishing them j) Each statement sent pursuant to this section must bear a conspicuous legend reading substantially as follows This statement is merely a record of the rights of the addressee as of the time of its issuance. Delivery of this statement, of itself, confers no rights on the recipient. This statement is neither a negotiable instrument nor a security See. 5. Article 9 of title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 28:9-103 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (3)(a) is amended by inserting the phrase other than uncertificated securities after the word "intangibles 2) A new subsection (6) is added to read as follows 6) Choice of law The law (including conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction of organization of the issuer governs the perfection and the effect of perfection or nonperfection of a security interest in uncertificated securities b) Section 28:9-105(1)(i) is amended by striking the word "security" and inserting the phrase "certificated security" in its place c) Section 28:9-203(1) is amended to read as follows 1) Subject to the provisions of §28:4-208 on the security interest of a collecting bank, §28:8-321 on security interests in securities, and §28:9-113 on a security interest arising under the article on sales, a security interest is not enforceable against the debtor or third parties with respect to the collateral and does not attach unless a) the collateral is in the possession of the secured party pursuant to agreement, or the debtor has signed a security agreement that contains a description of the collateral and in addition, when the security interest covers crops growing or to be grown or timber to be cut, a description of the land concerned b) value has been given; and c) the debtor has rights in the collateral d) Section 28:9-302(1)(f) is amended by inserting the phrase "or in securities (§28:8-321 after the phrase "collecting bank (§28:4-208 e) Section 28:9-304 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (1) is amended by striking the phrase "money or instruments" and inserting the phrase "money, certificated securities, or instruments" in its place 2) Subsection (4) is amended by inserting the phrase other than certificated securities after the word "instruments 3) Subsection (5) is amended by inserting the phrase other than a certificated security after the word "instrument f) Section 28:9-305 is amended by inserting the phrase other than certificated securities after the word "instruments g) Section 28:9-309 is amended as follows 1) By amending the section heading to read as follows Protection of purchasers of instruments, documents, and securities and (2) By striking the phrase section 28:8-301 and inserting the phrase section 28:8-302 in its place. § 28:9-103 § 28:9-105 § 28:9-203 28:9-302 28:9-304 § 28:9-305 § 28:9-309 29 Enrolled Original (h) Section 28:9-312(7) is amended by striking the phrase "by filing or the taking of possession" and inserting the phrase "by filing, the taking of possession, or under section 28:8-321 on securities" in its place. Sec. 6. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Kegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal R,e gulations. of Columbia APPROVED: November 25, 1992 § 28:9-312 30 I~ Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, Bill 9-20 10-6-92 Approved all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCILMEMBER CNMN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTF00T CRAWFORD ~SON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting J TI FICATIO N REC O R D ¯ ’~cretary to t6e Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY ROLA~ SMITHL JR. THOMAS, SR Date Reading, 11-4-92 ApprovedVOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Evans [q ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER CN}IN. WILSON JARVI S BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT ,CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANS ON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B ’CERTIFICATION ~’ecretary to the/Council RECORD AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. N.V Present, not voting Date [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A,B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~IMN WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON C~,O£P NATHANSON, EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. AB. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD couNcIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. NV. A.B Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
