<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-200">
  <num type="law">9-200</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1993-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-200.pdf">D.C. Law 9-200</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 9217</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0390">
      <narrative>Law 9-200, the “District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-390, which was referred to the Committee on Labor. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 6, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-325 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-200 became effective on March 16, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLME T(S) kwiktag ~’ 103 245 997 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-200 "District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-390 on first and second readings, October 6, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 25, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-325, published in the December 11, 1992, edition of the D.C. R ister Vol. 39 page 9217) and transmitted to Congress on January 6, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-200, effective ’March 16 1993 1 d~H~t A. WILSON hairman of the Council ates Counted ~ur~n~ the 3 -deaf Congressional ~ev~e~ Period: danuary gebruary Narch 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,1~,15 Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-325 Codification District of C lumbia Code: Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 25, 1992 To amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to establish a separate contribution surcharge for the purpose of paying interest on loans to the District Unemployment Fund and to create a separate fund for the deposit of the proceeds of the contribution surcharge. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. The District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Star 946; D.C. Code § 46-101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 46-103) is amended by adding a new subsection (1) to read as follows 1)(1) Commencing January 1, 1992, an interest surcharge of 0.1 percentum shall be added to the contribution rate of each employer required to pay contributions by this Act, excepting those reimbursing employers subject to the requirements of subsection (h) of this section 2) All interest surcharges collected under this subsection shall be considered separate from contributions required by subsection (c) of this section and shall be deposited in the Interest Account established by section 14(c) and shall not be credited to the individual accounts of employers 3) No interest surcharge shall be required for any year following the year in which the amount of interest-bearing advances has been reduced to zero; provided, however, that an interest surcharge shall be reimposed by the Director of the Department of Employment Services Director for the calendar year following any year in which an interest-bearing advance remains outstanding on October 1 and where there are not sufficient funds in the Interest Account to pay the interest due for that year b) Section 14 (D.C. Code § 46-115) is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c)(1) There is created a special fund in the General Revenue Fund of the District of Columbia Treasury, which shall be separate from the District Unemployment Fund, to be known as the Interest Account. Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of this Act: Section 46-103 Section 46-115 Enrolled Original A) All interest surcharges collected from employers shall be deposited in the Interest Account; and B) All moneys in the Interest Account shah be used for the payment of interest assessed on interest-bearing advances received under Title XII of the Social Security Act 2) Any moneys deposited in the Interest Account that are unexpended after all interest-bearing advances and interest assessments are paid to a zero balance shall be transferred to the Unemployment Trust Fund upon certification by the Director that the unexpended funds will not be needed to pay interest charges in the next calendar year Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. lumbia APPROVED: November 25, 1992 [] Item on Consent Calendar I~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: COUNCIL OF T}IE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Bill DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 10-6-92 9-390 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Rolark, Crawford and Nathanson [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CIMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD .CROPP ~EVANS AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote JARV I S LIGHTFOOT I~LAS 0N NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting RECORD 2 G, ERTIFICATION Se~creta~r~ t h~ iouncil Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY SMITH L JR. THOMAS, SR Date Reading, 11-4-92 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Approve~ Evans ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER ’ C}D£’q. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N,V, A.B. X Indicates Vote AYE NAY N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent NV Present. not voting M’ecretary to the" Council [] Item on Consent Calendar RECORD Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: E3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CIIHN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N,V. A.B X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A,B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR, MASON THOMAS. SR. NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY NV. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
