<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-234">
  <num type="law">9-234</num>
  <heading type="short">HEALTH-CARE PEER REVIEW ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-355</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1993-03-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-234.pdf">D.C. Law 9-234</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 605</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0355">
      <narrative>Law 9-234 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-355, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and reassigned to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1992, and December 15, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 31, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-365 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-234 became effective on March 17, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 247 240 AN ACT D.C. ACT 9-365 Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 31, 1992 To amend the Medical Records Act of 1978 to strengthen and clarify the immunity to those persons and entities participating in peer review proceedings and the confidentiality of peer review proceedings. BE’ IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Health-Care Peer Review Amendment Act of 1992" See. 2. The Medical Records Act of 1978, effective September 29, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-112; D.C. Code § 32-501 ef seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 32-501) is amended to read as follows Sec. 2. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Group practice" means a collection of health professionals that provides health-care services 2 Health-care facility or agency" means a facility, agency, or other organizational entity as defined in section 2 of the Health-Care and Community Residence Facility, Hospice and Home Care Licensure Act of 1983, effective February 24, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-48; D.C. Code § 32-1301 3 Health professional" means a person required to be licensed or permitted to provide health-care services in the District of Columbia under the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code § 2-3301.1 et seq 4 Health professional association" means a membership organization of health professionals in the District of Columbia having as a purpose the maintenance of high professional standards within the profession practiced by its members 5 Peer review" means the procedure by which health-care faciIities and agencies, group practices, and health professional associations monitor, evaluate, and take actions to improve the delivery, quality, and efficiency of services within their respective facilities, agencies, and professions, including recommendations, consideration of recommendations, actions with regard thereto, and implementation of the actions. The term "peer review" includes, but is not limited to, the following Section 32-501 Enrolled Original A) Matters affecting membership of a health professional on the staff of a health-care facility or agency B) The grant, delineation, renewal, denial, modification, limitation, or suspension of clinical privileges to provide health-care services at a health-care facility or agency C) Matters affecting employment and the terms of employment of a health professional by a health-care facility, agency, or group practice D) Matters affecting membership and terms of membership in a health professional association, including decisions to suspend membership privileges, expel from membership, reprimand or censure a member, or other disciplinary actions E) Review of the qualifications, activities, conduct, or performance of any health professional, including a grievance against a health professional F) Review of the quality, efficiency, or utilization of services provided by a health professional, a health-care facility, agency, or group practice; and G) Review of a health professional’s ability to perform, including allegations of mental or physical impairment, and imposition of programs of education, treatment, or rehabilitation, including monitoring and supervision, or conduct of programs of education 6 Peer review body" means a committee, board, hearing panel or officer, reviewing panel or officer or governing board of a health-care facility or agency, group practice or health professional association that engages in peer review, the health-care facility, agency, group practice or health professional association which establishes or authorizes or is governed by it, and a director, officer, employee, or member of such an entity 7 Primary health record" means the record of continuing care maintained by a health professional, group practice, or health-care facility or agency containing all diagnostic and therapeutic services rendered to an individual patient by that health professional, facility, or agency b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 32-502) is amended to read as follows Sec. 3. Authority to transmit data or information No person, health-care facility or agency, health professional association, or group practice providing any report, note, record, or other data or information, including advice, opinion, or testimony, to a peer review body shall be liable to any other person for damages or equitable relief by reason of providing such a report, note, record, or other data or information, unless the information provided was false and the person or entity providing the information knew the information was false c) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 32-503) is amended to read as follows Sec. 4. Liability for peer review actions or recommendations No peer review body or member thereof, or person acting as its staff, or who participates with or assists such a body or member, operating in the District of Columbia shall be liable to any person for damages or equitable relief by reason of conducting or taking peer review if the peer review was within the scope of the functions of the peer review body and if the peer review body or the member acted in the Section 32-502 Section 32-503 2 Enrolled Original reasonable belief that the peer review was warranted by the facts known after reasonable effort to obtain the facts of the matter d) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 32-505) is amended to read as follows Sec. 6. Use of peer review reports, records, or statements in judicial and administrative proceedings a) Except as otherwise provided by this section 1) The files, records, findings, opinions, recommendations, evaluations, and reports of a peer review body, information provided to or obtained by a peer review body, the identity of persons providing information to a peer review body, and reports or information provided pursuant to section 3 or federal or other District of Columbia law shall be confidential and shall be neither discoverable nor admissible into evidence in any civil, criminal, legislative, or administrative proceeding. Nothing in this paragraph shall preclude use of reports or information provided under section 3 or federal or other District of Columbia law by a board regulating a health profession or the Mayor in proceedings by the board or the Mayor 2) No person who participated in the proceedings of or provided information to a peer review body shall be compelled to testify or give discovery in any civil, criminal, legislative, or administrative proceeding relating to any matter presented or discussed at those proceedings, or any information provided to or obtained by any reports, records, opinion, evaluation, find’ing, or recommendation of the body or its members 3) Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, a court may order a peer review body to provide information in a criminal proceeding in which a health professional is accused of a felony, if the court determines that disclosure is essential to protect the public interest and that the information being sought can be obtained from no other source. In determining whether disclosure is essential to protect the public interest, the court shall consider the seriousness of the offense with which the health professional is charged, the need for disclosure of the party seeking it, and the probative value of the information. If the court orders disclosure, the identity of any patient shall not be disclosed without the consent of the patient or his legal representative, and the information disclosed shall not be used except in the criminal proceeding b) Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, primary health records and other information, documents, or records available from original sources shall not be deemed nondiscoverable or inadmissible merely because they are a part of the files, records, or reports of a peer review body c) This section shall not affect the right of any health professional to discover or to have admitted into evidence the minutes and reports of a peer review body concerning the health professional for the limited purpose of adjudicating the appropriateness of an adverse action affecting the employment, membership, privileges, or association of the health professional by the peer review body Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Section 32 -505 Enrolled Original Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia I~egister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. i Mayor District of Columbia Coun/cil of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December 31, 1992 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B9-355 Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted First Reading, 12-1-92 Approved Cropp, Jarvis~ Thomas [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. C,~MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPp ’ EVANS X Indicates Vote Secre he Council Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~ASON NATHANSON RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B. A8 Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH L JR. THOMAS, SR. Date AYE NAY N.V. [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: I~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted Final Approved all present Reading, 12-15-92 [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CN}fi WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AiB. COUNCIL MEMBER JARVI S ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH. JR. MASON THOMAS SR. NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present, not voting Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B CIIMN. WILSON I,BRA:ZIL CRAWFORD ~ROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LI~HTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY NV. A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
