<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-26">
  <num type="law">9-26</num>
  <heading type="short">REDISTRICTING PROCEDURE AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-158</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-08-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-26.pdf">D.C. Law 9-26</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 4198</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0158">
      <narrative>Law 9-26 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-158, which was referred to the Committee on Regional Authorities and the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 1991, and June 18, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 2, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-53 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag *’ 103 228 001 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-26 "Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Distr~ct of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-158 on first and second readings, June 4, 1991, and June 18, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 2, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-53, published in the July 12, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 4198) and transmitted to Congress on July 9, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that this legislation became effective on the date that the President of the United States signed P. L. 102-105" on August 17, 1991, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-26, effective August 17, 1991 le Council Public Law 102-105 waived the 30-day Congressional Review Period for this Law. AN ACT Codification Z~ Ori in t District of Columbia Code 1992 Supplement) D,C, ACT 9-53 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 2, 1991 To redistrict the wards of the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Redistricting Procedure Act of 1981, effective March 16, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-87; D.C. Code §1-1333) is amended to read as follows Sec. 4. Adoption of election ward boundaries effective January 1, 1992 The Council adopts the following election ward boundaries to be effective January 1, 1992, and to be used in all elections held after February 1, 1992, in the District of Columbia WARD I "Starting at the intersection of Klingle Road, N.W. and Piney Branch Parkway, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Piney Branch Parkway, N.W to Sixteenth Street, N.W thence south along said Sixteenth Street, N.W to Spring Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Spring Road, N.W to New Hampshire Avenue, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along said New Hampshire Avenue, N.W to Rock Creek Church Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Rock Creek Church Road, N.W to Park Place, N.W thence in a southerly direction along said Park Place, N.W to Michigan Avenue, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Michigan Avenue, N.W to First Street, N.W thence south along said First Street, N.W to Bryant Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along said Bryant Street, N.W to Second Street, N.W thence south along said Second Street, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W thence in a westerly direction along said Florida Avenue, N.W to Seventh Street, N.W thence south along said Seventh Street, N.W to S Street, N.W thence west along said S Street, N.W to Eighteenth Street, N.W thence north along said Eighteenth Street, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W thence in a southwesterly direction along said Florida Avenue, N.W to Massachusetts Avenue, N.W thence in a northwesterly direction along said Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to Sheridan Circle, N.W thence in a southwesterly direction along the southern boundary of Sheridan Circle to Twenty-Third Street, N.W thence is southerly direction along said Twenty-Third Street, N.W to Section 1-1333 q Street N.W thence following said Q Street, N.W in a westerly direction to the center line of Rock Creek; thence in a generally northern direction along said Rock Creek to Connecticut Avenue, N.W thence in a northwesterly direction along said Connecticut Avenue, N.W to the northern boundary of the National Zoological Park; thence in an easterly direction along the northern boundary of said National Zoological Park to Rock Creek; thence along said Rock Creek to Klingle Road, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along said Klingle Road, N.W to the point of beginning at the intersection of said Klingle Road, N.W. and Piney Branch Parkway, N.W WARD II "Starting at the intersection of the center line of Q Street, N.W and the center line of Rock Creek; thence east along said Q Street, N.W to Twenty-Third Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along said Twenty-Third Street, N.W to Sheridan Circle; thence in a southeasterly direction along the southern boundary of said Sheridan Circle to Massachusetts Avenue, N.W thence in a southerly direction along said Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W thence in a northerly direction along said Florida Avenue N.W to Eighteenth Street, N.W thence south along Eighteenth Street, N.W to S Street, N.W thence east along said S Street, N.W to Seventh Street, N.W thence north along said Seventh Street, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Florida Avenue, N.W to New Jersey Avenue, N.W thence in a southerly direction along said New Jersey Avenue, N.W to New York Avenue, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said New York Avenue, N.W to North Capitol Street; thence south along said North Capitol Street to Massachusetts Avenue, N.W thence northwesterly along said Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to Fourth Street, N.W thence south along said Fourth Street, N.W to H Street, N.W thence west along said H Street, N.W to Sixth Street, N.W thence south along said Sixth Street, N.W to Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W thence southeasterly along said Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W to Constitution Avenue, N.W thence east along said Constitution Avenue, N.W to North Capitol Street; thence south along said North Capitol Street and along a line extending south through the Capitol grounds to South Capitol Street; thence south along said South Capitol Street and continuing the projection of South Capitol Street south to the center line of the Anacostia River; thence in a southwesterly direction along the center line of said Anacostia River and the projection of that center line to the Commonwealth of Virginia-District of Columbia boundary line at the Commonwealth of Virginia shore of the Potomac River; thence in a northwesterly direction along said Commonwealth of Virginia-District of Columbia boundary line to its intersection with an extension of the Whitehaven Parkway; thence in a northeasterly direction along said extension of Whitehaven Parkway to Reservoir Road, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along said Whitehaven Parkway, N.W to Foxhall l~oad, N.W thence north along said Foxhall Road, N.W to W Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said W Street, N.W and along a westerly line extending W Street, N.W through Glover Archbold Park to the eastern boundary of Glover Archbold Park; thence in a southerly direction along said eastern boundary of Glover Archbold Park to the southern boundary of the eastern leg of Glover Archbold Park; thence in an easterly direction along the southern boundary of the 2 eastern leg of Glover Archbold Park to Whitehaven Parkway, N.W thence east along Whitehaven Parkway, N.W to Thirty-Fifth Street, N.W thence in a northerly direction along said Thirty-Fifth Street, N.W to Wisconsin Avenue, N.W thence in a southeasterly direction along said Wisconsin Avenue, N.W to Whitehaven Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Whitehaven Street, N.W to the northwest boundary of Dumbarton Oaks Park; thence in an easterly direction along said northwest boundary of Dumbarton Oaks Park to Whitehaven Street, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Whitehaven Street, N.W to Massachusetts Avenue, N.W thence in a southeasterly direction along said Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to the center line of Rock Creek; thence in a southeasterly direction along said center line of Rock Creek to the point of beginning at its intersection with Q Street, N.W WARD III "Starting at the intersection of the center line of Rock Creek with the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line; thence in a southerly direction along Rock Creek to the intersection of the center line of Rock Creek and the extension of the northern boundary of the National Zoological Park; thence in a westerly direction along said northern boundary of the National Zoological Park to Connecticut Avenue, N.W thence in a southeasterly direction along Connecticut Avenue, N.W to the center line of Rock Creek; thence along the center line of Rock Creek to its intersection with the center line of Massachusetts Avenue, N.W thence in a northwesterly direction along said Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to Whitehaven Street, N.W thence west along said Whitehaven Street, N.W to the northwestern boundary of Dumbarton Oaks Park; thence in a westerly direction along said northwestern boundary of said Dumbarton Oaks Park to Whitehaven Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along said Whitehaven Street, N.W to Wisconsin Avenue, N.W thence in a northwesterly direction along said Wisconsin Avenue, N.W to Thirty-Fifth Street, N.W thence south along said Thirty-Fifth Street, N.W to Whitehaven Parkway N.W thence west along said Whitehaven Parkway N.W to the southern boundary of the eastern leg of Glover Archbold Park; thence in a westerly direction along said southern boundary of the eastern leg of Glover Archbold Park to a point where it intersects with the eastern boundary of Glover Archbold Park; thence in a northerly direction along said eastern boundary of Glover Archbold Park to an easterly line extending W Street, N.W. through Glover Archbold Park; thence westerly along the extended line of W Street, N.W to W Street, N.W thence west along W Street, N.W to Foxhall Road, N.W thence in a southeasterly direction along said Foxhall Road, N.W to Whitehaven Parkway, N.W thence in a southwesterly direction along said Whitehaven Parkway, N.W to Reservoir Road, N.W thence following an extension of said Whitehaven Parkway, N.W in a southwesterly direction to the Commonwealth of Virginia-District of Columbia boundary line at the Commonwealth of Virginia shore of the Potomac River; thence in a northwesterly direction along said Commonwealth of Virginia-District of Columbia boundary line where it follows the Commonwealth of Virginia shore of the Potomac River to the western corner of the District of Columbia; thence in a northeasterly direction along the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line to the point of beginning at its intersection with the center line of Rock Creek WARD IV "Starting at the intersection of the center line of Rock Creek with the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line; thence in a southerly direction along said Rock Creek to Klingle Road, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along said Klingle Road, N.W to Piney Branch Parkway, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Piney Branch Parkway, N.W to Sixteenth Street, N.W thence south along said Sixteenth Street, N.W to Spring Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Spring Road, N.W to New Hampshire Avenue, N.W thence in a northeasterly direction along said New Hampshire Avenue, N.W to Rock Creek Church Road, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Rock Creek Church Road, N.W to Park Place, N.W thence in a southerly direction along said Park Place, N.W to Michigan Avenue, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said Michigan Avenue, N.W and N.E to Harewood Road, N.E thence in a northerly direction along said Harewood Road, N.E to Taylor Street, N.E thence east along said Taylor Street, N.E to Hawaii Avenue, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along said Hawaii Avenue, N.E to Fort Torten Drive, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along said Fort Torten Drive, N.E to Bates Road, N.E thence in an easterly direction along said Bates Road, N.E to the center line of the railroad right of way; thence in a northerly direction along the center line of said railroad right of way to Riggs Road, N.E thence in an easterly direction along said Riggs Road, N.E to South Dakota Avenue, N.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said South Dakota Avenue, N.E to Kennedy Street, N.E thence in an easterly direction along said Kennedy Street, N.E to the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line; thence in a northwesterly direction along said boundary line to the northern corner of the District of Columbia; thence in a southwesterly direction along said State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line to the point of beginning at its intersection with the center line of l~ock Creek WARD V "Starting at the intersection of First Street, N.W and Michigan Avenue, N.W thence south along said First Street, N.W to Bryant Street, N.W thence in a westerly direction along said Bryant Street, N.W to Second Street, N.W thence south on said Second Street, N.W to Florida Avenue, N.W thence in a westerly direction along said Florida Avenue, N.W to New Jersey Avenue, N.W thence in a southerly direction along said New Jersey Avenue, N.W to New York Avenue, N.W thence in an easterly direction along said New York Avenue, N.W and N.E to Florida Avenue, N.E thence in an easterly direction along said Florida Avenue, N.E to Benning Road, N.E thence in an easterly direction along said Benning Road, N.E to the center line of the Anacostia River; thence in a northerly direction along the Anacostia River to the intersection of its center line with the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line; thence in a northwesterly direction along said boundary line to Kennedy Street, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Kennedy Street, N.E to South Dakota Avenue, N.E thence in a northwesterly direction along said South Dakota Avenue, N.E to Riggs Road, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Riggs Road, N.E to the center line of the railroad right of way; thence in a southerly direction along the center line of said railroad right of way to Bates Road, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Bates Road, N.E to Fort Torten Drive, N.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said Fort Torten Drive, N.E to Hawaii Avenue, N.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said Hawaii Avenue, N.E to Taylor Street, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Taylor Street, N.E to Harewood Road, N.E thence in a southerly direction along said Harewood Road, N.E to Michigan Avenue, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Michigan Avenue, N.E and N.W to the point of beginning at its intersection with First Street WARD VI "Starting at the corner of North Capitol Street and New York Avenue, N.W thence south along said North Capitol Street to Massachusetts Avenue, N.W thence northwesterly along said Massachusetts Avenue, N.W to Fourth Street, N.W thence south along said Fourth Street, N.W to H Street, N.W thence west along said H Street, N.W to Sixth Street, N.W thence south along Sixth Street, N.W to Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W thence southeasterly along Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W to Constitution Avenue, N.W thence east along said Constitution Avenue, N.W to North Capitol Street; thence south along said North Capitol Street along a line extending south through the Capitol grounds to South Capitol Street; thence south along said South Capitol Street and continuing the projection of South Capitol Street south to the center line of the Anacostia River; thence in a northeasterly direction along said center llne of the Anacostia River to the westerly (southbound) roadway of the Eleventh Street Bridge; thence in a southerly direction along said westerly (southbound) roadway of the Eleventh Street Bridge to the center line of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Right of Way; thence in a southwesterly direction along the center line of said railroad right of way to W Street, S.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said W Street, S.E to Martin Luther King Jr. Avenue, S.E thence along Martin Luther King Jr. Avenue, S.E to Morris Road, S.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said Morris Road, S.E to Erie Street, S.E thence in an easterly direction along said Erie Street, S.E to Fort Place, S.E thence in a northeasterly direction along said Fort Place, S.E to Bruce Place, S.E thence in a northeasterly direction along said Bruce Place, S.E to the eastern boundary of Fort Stanton Park; thence in a northeasterly direction along said eastern boundary of Fort Stanton Park to Good Hope Road, S.E thence in an easterly direction along said Good Hope Road, S.E to Altamont Street, S.E thence north along said Altamont Street, S.E to Naylor Road, S.E thence in a northwesterly direction along said Naylor Road, S.E to Twenty-Fifth Street, S.E thence north along said Twenty-Fifth Street, S.E to Minnesota Avenue, S.E thence in a northerly direction along said Minnesota Avenue, S.E to M Place, S.E thence west along M Place, S.E and extending M Place, S.E west to the Anacostia Freeway; thence north along said Anacostia Freeway to the Conrail railroad tracks; thence south along said Conrail railroad tracks, to the center line of the Anacostia River; thence ~n a northerly direction along the center line of said Anacostia River to Benning Road, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Benning Road, N.E to Florida Avenue, N.E thence in a westerly direction along said Florida Avenue, N.E to New York Avenue, N.E thence in a southwesterly direction along said New York Avenue, N.E to the point of beginning at the corner of North Capitol Street and New York Avenue, N.N WARD VII "Starting at the intersection of the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line and the center line of the Anacostia River; thence in a southerly direction along the center line of said Anacostia River to the Conrail railroad tracks; thence in a northerly direction along said Conrail railroad tracks to the Anacostia Freeway thence south along said Anacostia Freeway to the extension of M Place, S.E thence east along M Place, S.E to Minnesota Avenue, S.E thence south along said Minnesota Avenue, S.E to Twenty-Fifth Street, S.E thence south along said Twenty-Fifth Street, S.E to Naylor Road, S.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said Naylor Road, S.E to the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line; thence in a northeasterly direction along said State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line to the eastern corner of the District of Columbia; thence in a northwesterly direction along the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line to the point of beginning at its intersection with the center line of the Anacostia River WARD VIII "Starting at the intersection of the Commonwealth of Virginia-District of Columbia boundary line on the Commonwealth of Virginia shore of the Potomac River with the projection of the center line of the Anacostia River; thence in a northeasterly direction along the center line of said Anacostia River to the western (southbound) roadway of the Eleventh Street Bridge; thence in a southerly direction along said western (southbound) roadway of the Eleventh Street Bridge to the center line of the Baltimore and Ohio ttailroad right of way; thence in a southwesterly direction along the center line of said railroad right of way to W Street, S.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said W Street, S.E to Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E thence in a southwesterly direction along said Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E. to Morris Road, S.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said Morris Road, S.E to Erie Street, S.E thence in an easterly direction along said Erie Street, S.E to Fort Place, S.E thence in a northeasterly direction along said Fort Place, S.E to Bruce Place, S.E thence in a northeasterly direction along said Bruce Place, S.E to the eastern boundary of Fort Stanton Park; thence in a northeasterly direction along said eastern boundary of Fort Stanton Park to Good Hope Road, S.E thence in an easterly direction along said Good Hope Road, S.E to Altamont Street, S.E thence north along said Altamont Street, S.E to Naylor Road, S.E thence in a southeasterly direction along said Naylor Road, S.E to the State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line; thence in a southwesterly direction along said State of Maryland-District of Columbia boundary line to the southern corner of the District of Columbia on the Commonwealth of Virginia shore of the Potomac River; thence along the Commonwealth of Virginia-District of Columbia boundary line to the point of beginning, at its intersection with the projection of the center line of the Anacostia River Except where otherwise indicated, the boundary line is the center of the street Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c}(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1)}, and publication in either the District of Columbia Kegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 2, 1991 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading: Approved B9-158 Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. CHMN. WILSON BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD ~LASON .CROP P NATHAN S ON EVANS RAY COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B JARV]- S } COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. SMITH JR. THOMAS, SR. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to th Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted F-trial Read±ng N.V Present, not voting Date 06-18-91 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all presentAbsent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER CN}II WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY 1 NV. A.B. X Indicates Vote AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V,COUNCILMEMBER JARVI$ LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting ROLARK SMITH. THOMAS, SR. CERTIFICATION RECORD Seclr~’&amp;amp;ry to the Council Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B’. CH WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP ~ANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER J’A~IS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN$ON RAY A.B Absent "AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N,V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
