<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-34">
  <num type="law">9-34</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA GROSS RECEIPTS AND TOLL TELECOMMUNICATION SERVICE TAX TEMPORARY AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-221</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-08-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-34.pdf">D.C. Law 9-34</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 4223</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0221"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLME T(S) kwiktag 103 246 583 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-34 "District of Columbia Gross Receipts and Toll Telecommunication Service Tax Temporary Amend- ment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-221 on firs~ and second readings, June 4, 1991, and June 18, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 2, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-61, published in the July 12, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 4223) and transmitted to Congress on July 9, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that this legislation became effective on the date that the President of the United States signed P. L. 102-105" on August 17, 1991, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-34, effective August 17, 1991. Chairman of the Council Public Law 102-105 waived the 30-day Congressional Review Period for this Law. AN ACT En lecl Oril l Codification District of Columbia Code (1992 Supplement) D,C, ACT 9-61 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTI~ICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 2, 1991 To amend, on a temporary basis, An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes and the Toll Telecommunication Service Tax Act of 1989 to increase the gross receipts tax for public utilities and the toll telecommunications service tax to 9.7% and to amend the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act to exempt from sales tax the sales of residential public utility services. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Gross Receipts and Toll Telecommunication Service Tax Temporary Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 6(5)(A)(ii) of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and three, and for other purposes, approved July 1, 1902 (32 Star. 619; D.C. Code §47-2501(a)(2 is amended by striking the number "6.7 and inserting the number "9.7 in its place. Note, Section 47-2501 Sec. 3. Section 3 of the Toll Telecommunication Service Tax Act of 1989, effective September 20, 1989 (D.C. Law 8-26; D.C. Code §47-3902 is amended by striking the number "6.7 and inserting the number "9.7 in its place. Note, Section 47-3902 Sec. 4. Section 128 of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Star. 115; D.C. Code §47-2005 is amended by adding a new subsection (y) to read as follows y) Sales of residential public utility services and commodities by a gas, electric lighting, or telephone company. Note, Section 47-2005 Sec. 5. Sections 2, 3, and 4 of the District of Columbia Gross Receipts and Toll Telecommunication Service Tax Temporary Amendment Act of 1991 shall apply to 1) Sales determined from meters read after June 30, 1991, in the case of an electric lighting or gas company; and (2) Sales from bills rendered after June 30, 1991, in the case of a telephone or toll telecommunication company. Note, Sections 47-2501 and 47-3902 Sec. 6 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Keorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Kegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Kegulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Cl~airman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 2, 1991 [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B9-221 DOCKET NO: Adopted First Readinq, 06-04-91 Approved Recorded vote on request all presentAbsent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER CNMN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROLAI~Ii SMITH L JR. THOMAS, SR. NAY X Indicates Vote A,B Absent NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD q ~’ c retary t~£~b~e C~o u no il Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, Date 06-18-91 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.8, CN~iN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B, JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent N,V Present, not voting Item on Consent Calendar CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY OLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.B, C;I WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP ~VANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
