<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-41">
  <num type="law">9-41</num>
  <heading type="short">PHYSICIANS FREE CLINIC ASSISTANCE PROTECTION AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-42</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-08-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-41.pdf">D.C. Law 9-41</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 4979</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0042">
      <narrative>Law 9-41 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-42, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 1991, and July 2, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 24, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-78 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT kwiktag 103 247 742 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-41 "Health Care Professional Volunteer Assistance Protection Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-42 on first and second readings, June 4, 1991, and July 2, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 24, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-78, published in the August 9, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 4979) and transmitted to Congress on July 25, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that this legislation became effective on the date that the President of the United States signed P. L. 102-105" on AugU’st 17, 1991, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-41, effective August 17, 1991. Chairman of the Council Public Law 102-105 waived the 30-day Congressional Review Period for this Law. AN ACT D,C, ACT 78 1992 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to authorize a free clinic the option to bill a third-party insurer, with the written consent of a client, and to amend the Good Samaritan Act of the District of Columbia by extending limited immunity to physicians, nurses, and nurse-midwives who volunteer their services in free clinics in the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Health Care Professional Volunteer Assistance Protection Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. The Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code §i-308.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(2 D.C. Code §1-308.1(2 is amended by adding a new subparagraph (G) to read as follows G) Accepts third-party payments from health insurance providers for their services only where the patient consents in writing to the filing of a claim for benefits to which the patient is eligible b) Subsection 2(2)(E D.C. Code §1-308.1(2)(E is amended by striking the phrase "high-risk prenatal care c) Section 3(a D.C. Code §1-308.2(a is amended by adding at the end of the third sentence except negligence claims for which the clinic is immune pursuant to section 2 of An Act to relieve physicians of liability for negligent medical treatment at the scene of an accident in the District of Columbia, approved November 8, 1965 (79 Star. 1302; D.C. Code §2-1344 Section 1-308.1 Section 1-308.1 Section 1-308.2 Sec. 3. An Act to relieve physicians of liability for negligent medical treatment at the scene of an accident in the District of Columbia, approved November 8, 1965 (79 Star. 1302; D.C. Code §2-1344 is amended by adding a new section 2 to read as follows Sec. 2. Health care professional volunteer assistance protection a) A licensed physician, registered nurse, or nurse-midwife certified or practicing in the specialty of obstetrics or gynecology who in good faith provides health care or treatment at a free health clinic operating lawfully in the District of Columbia without the expectation of receiving or intending to receive compensation shall not be liable in civil damages for any act or omission in the course of rendering the health Section 2-1344 Enrolled Originai care or treatment, unless the act or omission is an intentional wrong or manifests a wilfull or wanton disregard for the health or safety of others b) A licensed physician, registered nurse, or nurse-midwife providing medical care or assistance in obstetrics or gynecology in accordance with subsection (a) shall provide and shah require his or her prospective client to sign a written statement witnessed by 2 persons in which the parties agree to the rendering of the health care or treatment e) The immunity provided in subsection (a) of this section shall apply to any claim, arising out of health care or treatment given under subsection (a) of this section against 1) District of Columbia public health clinics; and (2) a free clinic, and the District of Columbia as an indemnifier of such a free clinic, which meets the eligibility requirements of section 2(2) of the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code §i-308.1(2 See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental P~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Kegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Kegulations. the District of Columbia COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 6-4-91 present Approved Bill 9-42 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. tAB C~HN. WILSON x BRAZIL x _CRAWFORD x CROPP x EVANS x X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~SON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N,V. A.B. X X X x N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD (8 2/ 3 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROLAP4K SMITH JR. THOMAS SR. X NAY N.V. X X Secretaky,’~o the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Readinq, 7-2-91 I VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER Cf {N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X X X X X X Indicates Vote Approved 8 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBERI AYE NAY N.V. JARV I S x 0L ARK x LIGHTFOOT x SMITH. JR. x MASON x THOMAS SR. x NATHANSON x RAY x A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Oeoncil Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C11 WILSON JARVIS ROLARK BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR, CRAWFORD .MASON THOMAS o SR R OPP NATHANSON ~VANS AY X Indic’ates Vote A.B Absent N,V Present not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY N.V, Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
