<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-53">
  <num type="law">9-53</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 Application Deadline and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-53.pdf">D.C. Law 9-53</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 6587</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 9-53, the “Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 Application Deadline and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-293. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 11, 1991, and October 1, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-95 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-53 became effective December 10, 1991.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 247 437 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-53 "Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 Application Deadline and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-293 on first and second readings, September 11, 1991, and October I, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 23, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-95, published in the November 1, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 6587) and transmitted to Congress on October 29, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that this legislation became effective on the date that the President of the United States signed P. L. 102-205" on December I0, 1991, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-53, effective December I0, 1991. I J h~r mA~n Wol ~StO~e Council Public Law 102-205 waived the 30-day Congressional Review Period for this Law. AN ACT D.C, ACT 9-95 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTI~ICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 23, 1991 To amend, on a temporary basis, the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 and the Real Property Tax Rates for Tax Year 1987 Act of 1986 to extend the deadline for filing the application for the homestead deduction and senior citizen property tax relief, to provide for refunds of overpayments of property taxes, to forgive penalties; and to amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to extend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act for 5 years. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act shall be cited as the "Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 Application Deadline and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 3(e) of the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977, effective February 28, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-45; D.C. Code §47-850(e is amended by adding a new paragraph (4A) to read as follows 4A)(A) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, for the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, the application required by paragraph (3) of this subsection shall be properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991 B) Any application properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991, shall apply to the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, and for succeeding tax years until the tax year for which quinquennial filing of the application is required pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, provided that the property remains eligible for the deduction C) Notwithstanding any other provision of law if a residential real property owner properly completes and files an application by September 30, 1991, for the deduction provided for under subsection (c)(1) of this section and qualifies for the deduction for the full tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, or if any residential real property owned by a cooperative housing association for which an application is properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991, for the deduction provided for under subsection (d)(2) of this section qualifies for the deduction for the full tax year-b~eginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, then i) The real property shall be classified as Class 1 property for the full tax year; Note, Section 47-850 Emtltled Original ii) The deduction for the 2rid half of the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, shall be reflected in the 2nd half tax bill which is due and payable by March 31, 1992 iii) The difference between the original 1st half tax bill that did not reflect the deduction provided for under subsection (c}(1) or (d)(2) of this section and the 1st half tax due based on the deduction shall be refunded by January 15, 1992, if already paid when due by September 16, 1991; and iv) No penalties or interest shall be owed by a taxpayer on the difference between the original tax bill that did not reflect the deduction provided for under subsection (c)(1) or (d)(2) of this section and the tax due based on the deduction Sec. 3. 1987 Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-153; D.C. Code §47-863 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c)(1) For the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, the application for the tax relief provided for under subsection (a) of this section shall be properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991 2) An application filed by September 30, 1991, shall apply to the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, and for succeeding tax years until the tax year for which quinquennial filing of the application is required pursuant to the regulations implementing the deduction authorized by subsection (a) of this section, provided that the property remains eligible for the tax relief 3) If a residential real property owner who takes advantage of the extended filing period provided for in this section qualifies for the senior citizen’s property tax relief provided for under subsection (a) of this section, the tax relief for the 2rid half of the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, shall be reflected in the 2nd half tax bill which is due and payable by March 31, 1992 4) The difference between the original 1st half tax bill that did not reflect the senior citizen’s property tax relief and the 1st half tax due based on the senior citizen’s property tax relief will be refunded by January 15, 1992, if already paid when due by September 16, 1991 5) No penalties or interest shall be owed by a taxpayer on the difference between the original tax bill that did not reflect the senior citizen property tax relief and the tax due based on the tax relief Section 5 of the Real Property Tax Rates for the Tax Year Note, Section 47-863 Sec. 4. Section 7(b) of the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code §1-308.1 note is amended to read as follows b) This act shall expire 10 years after its having taken effect Note, Sectio~ 1-308.1 See. 5 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental ILeorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat~ 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and Enrolled Odeinal publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 23, 1991 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Adopted First Reading,’ Approved 9-293 Recorded vote on request Absent: Nathanson ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER C~MN WILSON BRAZIL _CRAW~0RD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY NV. I X Indicates Vote A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~LASON NATHAN S ON RAY A.B Absent AYE I NAY N.V.A.B. Secret~’(o the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.v. ROLAt~ SMIT JR. I~-[ONAS, SR. Date Adopted Final Reading, 10-1-91 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT ’ OUNCIL MEMBER /AYE NAY N.V, A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AY~ NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER~l~q’.’ WIL’~ON ’[ ’ JARVIS ROLAR BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH- JR. CRAWFORD MASON O~S, SR. CROPP NATHANSON X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent N.V.’ Present, not voting" CERTIFICATION RECORD Secre to the Council Date AYE NAY N,V, Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: m VOICEVOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A:’B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CII WILSON JARVIS ROLA. RK BRAZIL LIGHTFO0~ SMI.TH, JR, CRAWFORD MASON THOMAS, SR ’ BVA~S RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent NV Present, not votin~l CERTIFICATION RECORD l u AYE NAY N.V. A.B. Secretary to the Council Date AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 and the Real Property Tax Rates for Tax Year 1987 Act of 1986 to extend the deadline for filing the application for the homestead deduction and senior citizen property tax relief, to provide for refunds of overpayments of property taxes, to forgive penalties; and to amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to extend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act for 5 years. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act shall be cited as the "Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 Application Deadline and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1991 See. 2. Section 3(e) of the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977, effective February 28, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-45; D.C. Code §47-850(e is amended by adding a new paragraph (4A) to read as follows 4A)(A) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (i) of this subsection, for the tax year beginning July I, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, the application required b paragraph (3) of this subsection 8¢ptemb~r 30, 1~1 hal] apply to th~ tax y~ar b~glnning July 1, 1991, and ~nding Jun~ 30, 1992, and for succeeding tax v~ars until th~ tax toV~arparagraphf°r whieh(3]quinqu~nnialo[ ~h{ filing of th~ application is r~uir~d V~I~t ¯ Note, Sectio~ 47-850 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend, on a temporary basis, the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 and the Real Property Tax Rates for Tax Year 1987 Act of 1986 to extend the deadline for filing the application for the homestead deduction and senior citizen property tax relief, to provide for refunds of overpayments of property taxes, to forgive penalties; and to amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to extend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act for 5 years. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act shall be cited as the "Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977 Application Deadline and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 3(e) of the Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977, effective February 28, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-45; D.C. Code §47-850(e is amended by adding a new paragraph (4A) to read as follows 4A)(A) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, for the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, the application required by paragraph (3) of this subsection shall be properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991 B) Any application properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991, shall apply to the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, and for succeeding tax years until the tax year for which quinquennial filing of the application is required pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, provided that the property remains eligible for the deduction C) Notwithstanding any other provision of law if a residentlal real property owner properly completes and files an application by September 30, 1991, for the deduction provided for under subsection (c)(1) of this section and qualifies for the deduction for the full tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, or if any residential real property owned by a cooperative housing association for which an application is properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991, for the deduction provided for under subsection (d)(2) of this section qualifies for the deduction for the full tax year-b.eginning July i, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, then i) The real property shall be classified as Class i property for the full tax year; Note, Sectiol 47-850 Original ii) The deduction for the 2nd half of the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, shall be reflected in the 2nd half tax bill which is due and payable by March 31, 1992 iii) The difference between the original 1st half tax bill that did not reflect the deduction provided for under subsection (c)(1) or (d)(2) of this section and the 1st half tax due based on the deduction shall be refunded by January 15, 1992, if already paid when due by September 16, 1991; and iv) No penalties or interest shall be owed by a taxpayer on the difference between the original tax bill that did not reflect the deduction provided for under subsection (c)(1) or (d)(2) of this section and the tax due based on the deduction Sec. 3. 1987 Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-153; D.C. Code §47-863 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c)(1) For the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, the application for the tax relief provided for under subsection (a) of this section shall be properly completed and filed by September 30, 1991 2) An application filed by September 30, 1991, shall apply to the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, and for succeeding tax years until the tax year for which quinquennial filing of the application is required pursuant to the regulations implementing the deduction authorized by subsection (a) of this section, provided that the property remains eligible for the tax relief 3) If a residential real property owner who takes advantage of the extended filing period provided for in this section qualifies for the senior citlzen~s property tax relief provided for under subsection (a) of this section, the tax relief for the 2nd half of the tax year beginning July 1, 1991, and ending June 30, 1992, shall be reflected in the 2nd half tax bill which is due and payable by March 31, 1992 4) The difference between the original 1st half tax bill that did not reflect the senior citizen’s property tax relief and the 1st half tax due based on the senior citizen’s property tax relief will be refunded by January 15, 1992, if already paid when due by September 16, 1991 5) No penalties or interest shall be owed by a taxpayer on the difference between the original tax bill that did not reflect the senior citizen property tax relief and the tax due based on the tax relief Section 5 of the Real Property Tax Rates for the Tax Year Note, Section 47-863 Sec. 4. Section 7(b) of the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code §1-308.1 note is amended to read as follows b) This act shall expire l0 years after its having taken effect Note, Sectio 1-308.1 Sec. 5 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 star, 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and Enrolled Odiinal publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day o~ its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia COt.~M’CIL OF THE Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Bill 9-293 Adopted First Reading/ 9-]]-9] Approved ’Recorded vote on request Absent: Nathanson COUNCILMEMBER CHMN. WILSON ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY NV. AB. COUNCI’EMEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOO,T MASON NATHANSoN RAY X Indicates Vote ’ Absent BRAZIL CRAWFOR ¢ROPP .EVANS AYE NAY NV. A.8. N.V’ Present, not votin9 CERTIFICATION RECORD ’ Secret ’o ~he Council Adopted Final Approved Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: ]~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. ROLAP$&amp;lt SMITH L JR. THOMAS, SR. Date Readinq 10-1-91 Absent: all present r~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT ’ COU’NCILMEMBER AYE !NA’~ N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER’ AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. ’C WILSON JARVIS .R0_LARK BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH JR. CRAWFOKD MASON THOMAS, SR. CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Abse0t NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Sec ~e~u ncil 1Date Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. cOUNCiL MEMBER CU I£SON BRAZIL CRAWFORD EVAN£ NAY" N.y. X Ind,:ates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHT,FOOT MASON N,ATHAN$ON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY u N.V.A.B I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, ROLARK SMITH JR, THOMAS. SR. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
