<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-65">
  <num type="law">9-65</num>
  <heading type="short">REDISTRICTING PROCEDURE AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991 CLARIFICATION AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-314</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-03-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-65.pdf">D.C. Law 9-65</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 8</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0314">
      <narrative>Law 9-65 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-314, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 20, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-116 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 248 572 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-65 "Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991 Clarification and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-314 on first and second readings, November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 20, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-116, published in the January 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 8) and transmitted to Congress on January 7, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-65, effective March 11, 1992 j.~LSON hairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 2,3,4,5,6,9,10 Btttlllttd Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-i16 IN TIIE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 20, 1991 To amend the Redistricting Procedure Act of 1981, as amended by the Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991, to clarify the legal description of the boundary between Wards 2 and 6; and to amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to extend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act for 5 years. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991 Clarification and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Redistricting Procedure Act of 1991, effective August 17, 1991 (D.C. Law 9-26; to be codified at D.C. Code §1-1333 is amended by striking the phrase "thence south along said South Capitol Street and continuing the projection of South Capitol Street south to the center line of the Anacostia River wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "thence south along said South Capitol Street and continuing southeasterly along said South Capitol Street to the midpoint of the Frederick Douglass Memorial Bridge center line of the Anacostia River in its place. Sec. 3. Section 7(b) of the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code §1-308.1 note is amended to read as follows b) This act shall expire 10 years after its having taken effect Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of New Section 1-333 Section 1-308.1 Ol’iginal Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Ch. CouI~.i of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: December 20, 199’1 [] Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLIAMB[A Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Readinq, 11-5-91 Approved Bill 9-314 all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~MN. WILSON JARVI S BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD ~LASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD I Secret ry~o the Council [~ Item on Consent Calendar ~{ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request AYE NAY NV. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER ROLAP/&amp;lt; SMITH JR. THOMAS SR. N.V Present, not voting ~ate Adopted Final Approved Reading, 12-3-91 i AYE NAY N.V. Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. CH}£~I. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting Secretary~to][h~ Cduncil item on Consent Calendar CERTIFICATION RECORD A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR. Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. I A.B. CII WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD ~ROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN$ON PAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V PresenL not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD 7 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR A.Bo Secretary to the Council Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 ,O E C 9 1991 The Honorable Sharon Pratt Kelly Mayor of the District of Columbia District Building, Room 520 1350 Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W. Washington, D.C. 20004 Re: Bill 9-314 Redistrictinq Procedure Amendment Act of 1991 Clarification and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Amendment Act of 1991 and Repore_ Date of Council Action: l 2-3-91 Dear Mayor Kelly: The above named enacted bill i-s hereby transmitted in accordance with Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this act is the report of the committee having jurisdiction over that matter. S "n~c~rely, j rman of the Council Enc] osures Original AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Redistricting Procedure Act of 1981, as amended by the Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991, to clarify the legal description of the boundary between Wards 2 and 6; and to amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to extend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act for 5 years. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Redistricting Procedure Amendment Act of 1991 Clarification and Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 Extension Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 4 of the Redistricting Procedure Act of 1991, effective August 17, 1991 (D.C. Law 9-26; to be codified at D.C. Code §1-1333 is amended by striking the phrase "thence south along said South Capitol Street and continuing the projection of South Capitol Street south to the center line of the Anacostia River wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "thence south along said South Capitol Street and continuing southeasterly along said South Capitol Street to the midpoint of the Frederick Douglass Memorial Bridge center line of the Anacostia River in its place. Sec. 3. Section 7(b) of the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code §1-308.1 note is amended to read as follows b) This act shall expire i0 years after its having taken effect Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §i-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of New Section 1~-333 Section I- 308.1 Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. u~f the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER C~MN. WILSON BRAZIL COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKETNO: Bill Adopted First Readinq, 11-5-91 Approved _CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY NV. AB COUNCIL MEMBER X Indicates Vote Secret~cil Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. CN WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS 9-314 X Indicates Vote JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER J AYE NAY N.V. ROt,AP~ SMITH JR. THOMAS, SR. A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Date Adopted Final Reading, 12-3-91. Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. JARVIS ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH. JR. MASON THOMAS~ SR. NATHANSON RAY A,B Absent N.V Present, not voting Secretary~g/~he Council C Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CH WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD ~ROPP EVANS X Indicates’ Vote CERTIFICATION RECORD Date COUNCILMEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN$ON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V PresenL nol vo~ing J J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. AB. CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
