<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-67">
  <num type="law">9-67</num>
  <heading type="short">Health-Care Decisions Amendment Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-03-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-67.pdf">D.C. Law 9-67</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 12</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0041">
      <narrative>Law 9-67, the “Health-Care Decisions Amendment Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-41, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 20, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-118 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-67 "Health-Care Decisions Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-41 on first and second readings, November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 20, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-118, published in the January 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 12) and transmitted to Congress on January 7, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-67, effective March II, 1992 J//JJ~N A. WILSON L ,airman of the Council Dates Counted During. the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 2,3,4,5,6,9,10 AN ACT Codif cation D, C, ACT 9-ii8 Di d ofColurnbisCods t Supplement IN THE COUNCIL OF TttE DISTttlCT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 20, 1991 To a~nend chapter 22 of title 21 of the District of Columbia Code to add a religious superior to the list of persons who can give substituted consent for a member of a religious order or a diocesan priest. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Health-Care Decisions Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Chapter 22 of title 21 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 21-2202 is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (5A) is added to read as follows 5A Member of a religious order or diocesan priest" means an unmarried adult who, by vow or other bond of commitment, voluntarily undertakes a style of living under the rule and direction of a religious order or community that has been established for religious purposes and has been recognized and approved as a religious order or community by a church 2) A new paragraph (7) is added to read as follows 7 Religious Superior" means a bishop or a member of a religious order who, under the approved constitution, laws, statutes, bylaws, or rules of the religious order or community, exercises authority over the particular community or unit of the religious order to which the member of the religious order or community belongs b) Section 21-2210(a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the word "or" after the word "patient 2) A new paragraph (5A) is added to read as follows SA) A religious superior of the patient, if the patient is a member of a religious order or a diocesan priest; or Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Section 21-2202 Section 21-2210 Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal ~e gul ations. Counc~ Of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED December 20, 1991 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO q, Item on Consent Calendar ]~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: X] VOICE VOTE: Bill 9-41 Adopted First Reading, ii-5-91 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. WILSON JARVIS ROT,AI~&amp;lt; BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH L JR CRAWFORD &amp;gt;LASON THOMAS, SR. CROPP NATHANSON EVANS X Indicates Vote AB Absent N.V Present, not votincj CERTIFICATION RECORD v Secreta~y’~o the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Date Reading, 12-3-91 AYE NAY NV. Absent: all present C~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER -G WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent N.V Present, not votin0 CERTIFICATION RECORD Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A,B. COUNCIL MEMBER C[IIv WILSON JARVIS ~RA~IL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CR 0 PP NATHAN S ON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not votin~j CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
