<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-77">
  <num type="law">9-77</num>
  <heading type="short">Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Acupuncture Practice Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-03-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-77.pdf">D.C. Law 9-77</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 669</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0018">
      <narrative>Law 9-77, the “Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 Acupuncture Practice Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-18, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 1991, and January 7, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 28, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-134 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-77 became effective on March 20, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENGROSSMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 247 493 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICE OF THE GENERAL COUNSEL WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 TRANSMITTAL OF ENGROSSED LEGISLATION Short Title: Bill #9-18 Health Occupations Revision Act of 198B~Ac~upuncture Practice Amendment Act of 1991 cc: Councilmember Ray (with attachment j ’ i i R:&amp;gt;~o [’ :J lt Legi sl a~cive Court Date of Transmittal Received by LSD Staff Date of Receipt cc: Codification Counsel Received by Codification Counsel Date of Receipt Rev, I/2/91 4/BACCUPU 01 A BILL 02 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 03 04 O5 To amend the Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to permit the 06 practice of acupuncture as a treatment for substance abuse and 07 alcoholism by persons registered as acupuncture therapists who work 08 under direct collaboration of a physician licensed to practice 09 acupuncture or a licensed acupuncturist. 10 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL 01 THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, Ii That this act may be cited as the "Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 12 Acupuncture Practice Amendment Act of 1991 13 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act 14 of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Code 15 §2-3309.1 is amended to add a new section 903 to read as follows: 16 "Sec. 903. Registered [Acupuncture Therapist] acupuncture 17 therapist. 18 a) For the purposes o£ this section registered acupuncture 19 therapist" means a person who has successfully completed a program in 20 acupuncture therapy approved by the Advisory Committee on Acupuncture 21 and the Board of Medicine for the specific purpose of treating drug and 22 alcohol abuse in a [-] clinical setting and who does not otherwise possess 23 the credentials or qualifications for the practice of acupuncture as 01 required by section 504 [of this act]. 02 b) A person who is engaged as an acupuncture therapist in the 03 District shall register with the Mayor, renew the registration as required by rule, and pay the required registration fee established by the Mayor. 05 c) Any person registered to practice as an acupuncture therapist 06 shall practice under the direct collaboration of a person licensed to 07 practice acupuncture or a physician licensed to practice acupuncture. 08 d) The Mayor, in accordance with the provisions of [Title] title 09 I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved 10 October 21, 1968 (62 Stat. 1204; D.C. Code §1-1501 et seq shall issue 11 rules setting forth the standards of education and experience required to 12 qualify for registration as an acupuncture therapist 13 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of 14 Congressional review folowoing approval by the Mayor (or in the evant 15 of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia 15 to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of 17 Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved 18 December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication 19 in either the District of Columbia l~egister, the District of Columbia 20 Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. 21</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
