<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-97">
  <num type="law">9-97</num>
  <heading type="short">Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Temporary Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-05-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-97.pdf">D.C. Law 9-97</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 9-97, the “Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Temporary Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-351. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 20, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-124 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-97 became effective on May 7, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 247 253 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-97 "Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Temporary Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-351 on first and second readings, November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 20, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-124, published in the January 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol 39 page 22) and transmitted to Congress on January 7, 1992 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(2) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-97, effective May 7, 1992 C~T~an of the Council Dates Counted During the 60-day Cong~e~ssional Review Period: January February March April May 21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,II,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,28,29,30 1,4,5,6 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-124 Emoll Origimli IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 20, 1991 To provide, on a temporary basis, a civil process for merchants in the District of Columbia to recover damages resulting from fraud, shoplifting, or theft. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Temporary Act of 1991 See. 2. Definitions. For purposes of this act, the term 1 Fraud" shall have the same meaning as that term is used in section 121 of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code § 22-3821 2 Juvenile" means a person under 18 years of age 3 Merchant" means a person who does or would sell, lease (to or transfer, either directly or indirectly, consumer goods or services, or a person who does or would supply the goods or services which are or would be the subject matter of a trade practice 4 Shoplifting" shall have the same meaning as that term has in section l13(a) of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crime Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code §22-3813(a 5 Theft" shall have the same ~neaning as that term has in section 111 of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crime Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code §22-3811 See. 3. Liability and Damages a) A person who commits an offense of fraud, shoplifting, or theft from a merchant shall be civilly liable to the merchant for treble the amount of actual damages; and (1) The retail value of any goods or merchandise stolen if the goods or merchandise are not recovered 2) The loss of value of the goods or merchandise stolen if the goods or merchandise are recovered; or (3) A minimum of $50 in damages, whichever is greater b) The parent or guardian shall be liable for any acts or offenses committed by a juvenile under this act. Note, Sections 3-401, 2273813 Enrolled Odginal See. 4. Criminal Proceedings a) The recovery of damages from the alleged offender shall not prohibit criminal prosecution of the alleged offender b) The recovery of civil damages by a merchant or a finding of liability under this act shall not be admissible in a criminal proceeding c) A conviction or plea of guilty of fraud, shoplifting, or theft is not a prerequisite to the maintenance of a civil action authorized by this act. See. 5. MerchanCs Options a) A merchant who suffers damages as a result of fraud, shoplifting, or theft, may recover the damages by submitting a written demand to the alleged offender or the parent or guardian of a juvenile alleged offender b) The written demand shall 1) Be delivered or mailed to the alleged offender or parent or guardian of a juvenile alleged offender, at least 30 days prior to the filing of any suit for damages 2) Specify the alleged criminal conduct and the damages incurred as a result of the conduct 3) Specify the amount which the merchant is entitled to recover under this act and that if payment of this amount is made in accordance with the written demand or the terms of a written agreement between the merchant and the alleged offender or the parent or guardian of the juvenile alleged offender, within 30 days of the date of service of the written demand, the merchant cannot bring suit for damages; and (4) Specify that if payment of the specified amount is not made, an agreement of payments is not reached, or payments are not made in accordance with the terms of an agreement, within 30 days of the date of service of the demand, the merchant may bring a suit for damages c) When the merchant receives payment of the specified amount or payment in accordance with the agreement for payments, the merchant shall deliver or mail an acknowledgement of payment letter to the alleged offender within 5 business days of receipt of payment. Sec. 6. Jurisdiction. A suit for damages and penalties may be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. See. 7. Attorneys Fees. Attorney’s fees and costs shall be awarded under this act without regard to ability to pay. Sec. 8 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto as provJ.ded in in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental ILeorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 Emotled Original (b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect or upo~ the effective date of the Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Act of 1991, whichever occurs first. C District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVI~D: December 20, 1991 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Bill Adopted First Reading, 11-5-91 9-351 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present I S~cr~tary to dC’oun~cil Item on Consent Calendar [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHMN. WILSON ] JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD ~LAS ON CROP P I NATHAN S ON EVANS 1 RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting Date CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Reading, 12-3-91 AYE NAY COUNCIL MEMBER CN~N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Approved all present NAY N.V. A,B, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A,B, JARVI S LIGHTFOOT VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent N.V Present, not votingX Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER ROLAP~K SMITH JR. THOMAS SR ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CERTIFICATION RECORD iSecretary tO ’h4. C~r~cil Item on Consent Calendar ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CII WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON RT~AN RAY X Indicates Vote AYE NAY A,B Absent AYE NAY N.V, A,B. COUNCILMEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR. THOMA SR. N.V PresenL not votinL CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
