<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-98">
  <num type="law">9-98</num>
  <heading type="short">Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-05-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-98.pdf">D.C. Law 9-98</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 678</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0152">
      <narrative>Law 9-98, the “Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 19-152, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 3, 1991, and January 7, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 28, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-138 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-98 became effective on May 16, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 246 983 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-98 "Merchant’s Civil Recovery for Criminal Conduct Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-152 on first and second readings, December 3, 1991, and January 7, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 28, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-138, published in the February 7, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 678) and transmitted to Congress on January 30, 1992 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(2) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-98, effective May 16, 1992 ¯ O~N~A. I~ I LSON__J Dates Counted During the 60-da~/Congressional Review Period: january 30,31 February 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 March April May 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26, 27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,28,29,30 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-138 Enrolled Original New Chapter 4A, Title 3 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 28, 1992 To provide a civil process for merchants in the District of Columbia to recover damages resulting from fraud, shoplifting, or theft. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Merchant’s Civil l~ecovery for Criminal Conduct Act of 1992 See. 2. Definitions. For purposes of this act, the term 1 Fraud" shall have the same meaning as that term is used in section 121 of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code §22-3821 2 Juvenile" means a person under 18 years of age 3 Merchant" means a person who does or would sell, lease (to or transfer, either directly or indirectly, consumer goods or services, or a person who does or would supply the goods or services which are or would be the subject matter of a trade practice 4 Shoplifting" shall have the same meaning as that term has in section l13(a) of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crime Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code §22-3813(a 5 Theft" shall have the same meaning as that term is used in section 111 of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crime Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Code §22-3811 Sec. 3. Liability and Damages a) Any one who commits an offense of fraud, shoplifting, or theft from a merchant shall be civilly liable to the merchant for treble the amount of actual damages; and (1) The retail value of any goods or merchandise stolen if the goods or merchandise are not recovered 2) The loss of value of the goods or merchandise stolen if the goods or merchandise are recovered; or (3) A minimum of $50 in damages, whichever is greater b) The parent or guardian shall be liable for any acts or offenses committed by a juvenile under this act. New Section 3-441 New Section 3-442 Enrolled Original Sec. 4. Criminal Proceedings a) The recovery of damages from the alleged offender shall prohibit criminal prosecution of the alleged offender b) The recovery of civil damages by a merchant or a finding of liability under this act shall not be admissible in a criminal proceeding c) A conviction or plea of guilty of fraud, shoplifting, or theft is not a prerequisite to the maintenance of a civil action authorized by this act. Sec. 5. MerchantVs Options a) A merchant who suffers damages as a result of fraud, shoplifting, or theft, may recover the damages by submitting written demand to the alleged offender or the parent or guardian of a juvenile alleged offender b) The written demand shall 1) Be delivered or mailed to the alleged offender or parent or guardian of a juvenile alleged offender, at least 30 days prior to the filing of any suit for damages 2) Specify the alleged criminal conduct and the damages incurred as a result of the conduct 3) Specify the amount which the merchant is entitled to receive under this act and that if payment of this amount is made in accordance with the written demand or the terms of a written agreement between the merchant and the alleged offender or the parent or guardian of the juvenile alleged offender, within 30 days of the date of service of the demand, the merchant may bring a suit of damages c) When the merchant receives payment of the specified amount or payment in accordance with the agreement for payments, the merchant shall deliver or mail an acknowledgement or payment letter to the alleged offender within 5 business days of receipt of payment. Sec. 6. Jurisdiction. A suit for damages and penalties may be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Sec. 7. Attorneys Fees. Attorneys fees and costs shall be awarded under this act without regard to ability to pay. See. 8. Effective Date. This act shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(2 and New Section 3-443 New Section 3-444 New Section 3-445 New Section 3-446 Enrolled Original publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. District o1 Columbia APPROVED: January 28, 1992 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B9-152 Adopted First Reading, 12-3-91 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: All Present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHHN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD ~IAS ON CROPP NATHANSON EVAN$ RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROLA~I{ S~IITH L JR HON_&amp;amp;S, SR. NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote AB Absent NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD I "Secretary t~le’Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Lightfoot ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CH} WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N.Y. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.Y. A.B X Indicates Vote Secretal the ~ouncil Item on Consent Calendar JARV LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. N.V Present, not voting AYE NAY ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. C~I WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP E~ANS x Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR. AYE NAY Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§27-101"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§27-102"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§27-103"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§27-104"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§27-105"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§27-106"/>
  </section>
</document>
