<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-99" flag="true">
  <num type="law">9-99</num>
  <heading type="short">Well-Child Care Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-05-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-99.pdf">D.C. Law 9-99</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 2142</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 9-99, the “Well-Child Care Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-81, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 4, 1992, and March 3, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 23, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-171 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-99 became effective on May 21, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag* 103 247 562 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-99 "Well-Child Care Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-81 on first and second readings, February 4, 1992, and March 3, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 23, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-171, published in the April 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 2142) and transmitted to Congress on March 25, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-99, effective May 21, 1992 ’WI LSON Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: March April May 25,26,27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,28,29,30 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20 Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-171 CodificaUon Oi=tr of Columbia Code t 3 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MARCH 23, 1992 To amend the Newborn Health Insurance Act of 1979 to require individual and group health insurance policies to cover preventive and primary care for minor children up to 18 years of age. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Well-Child Care Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. The Newborn Health Insurance Act of 1979, effective October 20, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-33; D.C. Code §35-1101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-1102) is amended to read as follows Sec. 3. The coverage for dependent children up to 18 years of age shall include 1) Coverage for injury or sickness, including the necessary care and treatment of medically diagnosed congenital defects, birth abnormalities, and prematurity; and 2) Coverage for preventive and primary care services, including physical examinations, measurements, sensory screening, neuropsychiatric evaluation, and development screening, which coverage shall include unlimited visits for cbildren up to the age 12 years and 3 visits per year for minor children ages 12 years up to 18 years of age. Preventive and primary care services shall also include, as recommended by the physician, hereditary and metabolic screening at birth, immunizations, urinalysis, tuberculin tests, and hematocrit, hemoglobin, and other appropriate blood tests, including tests to screen for sickle hemoglobinopathy b) Section 5 (D.C. Code, §35-1104) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place and by adding new subsections (d e and (f) to read as follows d) to all individual subscriber contracts and group certificates issued or delivered in the District of Columbia by Group Hospitalization and Medical Services, Inc e) to all for-profit as well as non-profit indemnity type health insurers issuing or delivering individual indemnity type accident and sickness health insurance policies and group certificates in the District of Columbia; and f) to health insurance certificates, except those described in section 3(2 that are delivered within the District of Columbia from group Section 35-1102 Section 35-II04 Enrolled Original health insurance policies which are sold outside of the District of Columbia c) A new section 6 is added to read as follows Sec. 6. Exclusions Specifically excluded from the coverage requirements of this act are Medicare Supplement insurance policies, accident only policies, dread disease policies, student accident policies, nursing home policies, and home health care policies Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental georganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia 1Kegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Re gulation s" Chair m~~fj Counci the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: March 23, 1992 New Section 35-1105 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUIMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Adopted First Readinq, 2-4-92 Approved Bill 9-81 Recorded vote on request Absent: Thomas ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT fCOUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B COUNCIL MEMBERCNMN. WILSON JARVIS I RAZIL LIGHTFOOT ~CRAW~O L~SO~ CROPP NAT~SON ~VANS ~L X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD it e: L C o n etca~le n~d tat~re C°uncil ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLAI lt; SMITH JR. THOMAS~ SR. I Date Reading: 3-3-92 N.V, IAB,] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CK WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent NV Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR. CERTIFICATION RECORD IteL ~n- C onS::rt~’n°d};e c°uncil Date NAY NV. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER C[[~EX WII, S 0N JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT C RAWF 0 RD MAS ON CROPP NAT.HANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR. AYE NAY Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
