<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>20-108.01</num>
  <heading>Effect of fraud and evasion.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever fraud has been perpetrated in connection with any proceeding or in any statement filed under this title or if fraud is used to avoid or circumvent the provisions or purposes of this title, any person injured thereby may obtain appropriate relief against the perpetrator of the fraud or restitution from any person (other than a bona fide purchaser) benefiting from the fraud, whether innocent or not. Any proceeding must be commenced within 2 years after the discovery of the fraud, but no proceeding may be brought against one not a perpetrator of the fraud later than 5 years after the time of commission of the fraud. This section has no bearing on remedies relating to fraud practiced on a decedent during lifetime that may affect the succession to the decedent’s estate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the remedy provided in subsection (a) of this section, nothing in this title shall be construed to validate any document with respect to which there was any misrepresentation, fraudulent act, or illegal provision in connection with its execution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to the remedy provided in subsection (a) of this section, any person convicted of a fraudulent act in connection with the collection, administration, distribution, or closing of an estate under this title and who thereby obtains property of another or causes another to lose property, shall be subject to the penalties set forth in section 122 of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 4-164">D.C. Law 4-164</cite>; <cite path="§22-3222">§ 22-3222</cite>).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-241" type="History">Mar. 21, 1995, D.C. Law 10-241, § 3(i), 42 DCR 63</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of § 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-241">D.C. Law 10-241</cite>, see § 2 of the Probate Reform Act of 1994 Emergency Amendment Act of 1995 (D.C. Act 11-79, June 28, 1995,  42 DCR 3452).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 20-108.1.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 32(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> provided that the section designation of <cite path="§20-108.1" proof="true">§ 20-108.1</cite> of the District of Columbia Official Code is redesignated as <cite path="§20-108.01">§ 20-108.01</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 10-241: Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-241">D.C. Law 10-241</cite>, as amended by § 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-54">D.C. Law 11-54</cite>, provided that the act shall be applicable to estates of decedents who died on or after July 1, 1995.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
