<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-1003.01</num>
  <heading>Grounds for involuntary discharge, transfer, or relocation by facility.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless a resident and his or her representative consent otherwise, a facility may discharge the resident, transfer the resident to another facility, or relocate the resident from one part or room of the facility to another only:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If essential to meet that resident’s documented health-care needs or to be in accordance with his or her prescribed level of care;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If essential to safeguard that resident or one or more other residents from physical or emotional injury;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>On account of nonpayment for his or her maintenance, after reasonable and appropriate notice, except as prohibited by subsection (b) of this section and 42 U.S.C. § 1395 et seq. and 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If essential to meet the facility’s reasonable administrative needs and no practicable alternative is available; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>If the facility is closing or officially reducing its licensed capacity.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No facility that is a District Medicaid provider may discharge, transfer, or relocate a resident on account of his or her conversion from private-pay or Medicare to Medicaid status, or on account of a temporary hospitalization if payment or reimbursement for his or her bed continues to be made available.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-108">Apr. 18, 1986, D.C. Law 6-108, § 301, 33 DCR 1510</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-145">Apr. 29, 2010, D.C. Law 18-145, § 4(b), 57 DCR 1834</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="44-504">44-504</cite> and § <cite root="44-1003.03">44-1003.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 32-1431.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-145">D.C. Law 18-145</cite>, in subsec. (a)(3), substituted “maintenance, after reasonable and appropriate notice,” for “maintenance,”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
