<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-1001.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Administrator” means the person who is responsible for the day-to-day operation and management of a facility, including, in the case of a community residence facility, the Residence Director of the facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Affiliate” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>With respect to a partnership, each partner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>With respect to a corporation, each officer and director and each stockholder who directly or indirectly owns or controls 10% or more of any class of securities issued by the corporation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>With respect to an individual:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Each parent, child, grandchild, spouse, sibling, first cousin, aunt, and uncle of the individual, whether the relationship arises by blood, marriage, or adoption;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Each partnership in which the individual or an affiliate of the individual is a partner, and each other partner in that partnership; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Each corporation in which the individual or an affiliate of the individual is an officer, director, or stockholder who directly or indirectly owns or controls 10% or more of any class of securities issued by the corporation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2A)</num>
    <text>“Assisted Living Residence” shall have the same meaning as given the term in § <cite path="§44-102.01">44-102.01</cite>(4).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Community residence facility” means that term as it is defined in § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(4).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Facility” means a nursing home, Assisted Living Residence, or community residence facility operating in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Long-Term Care Ombudsman” means the person designated under 42 U.S.C. § 3027(a)(12) to perform the mandated functions of the Long-Term Care Ombudsman program in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Nursing home” means that term as it is defined in § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(3).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Person” means an individual or individuals, an agency, a corporation, a partnership, the District government, or any other organizational entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Resident” means a resident of a facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Resident’s representative” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any person who is knowledgeable about a resident’s circumstances and has been designated by that resident to represent him or her;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any person other than a facility who has been appointed by a court either to administer a resident’s financial or personal affairs or to protect and advocate for a resident’s rights; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The Long-Term Care Ombudsman or his or her designee, if no person has been designated or appointed in accordance with subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-108" type="History">Apr. 18, 1986, D.C. Law 6-108, § 101, 33 DCR 1510</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-218" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-218, § 602(a), 36 DCR 534</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-127" type="History">June 24, 2000, D.C. Law 13-127, § 1404(a), 47 DCR 2647</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-703.02">7-703.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-127">D.C. Law 13-127</law-cite> added a new paragraph (2A) defining “Assisted Living Residence” and in par. (6) added the phrase “, Assisted Living Residence,” after the phrase “nursing home”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to Law 6-108, see Mayor’s Order 87-47, February 17, 1987.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
