<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-1002.04</num>
  <heading>Notice and hearing requirements; ex parte appointment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The court shall hold a hearing on a petition filed under § <cite path="§44-1002.03">44-1002.03</cite> within 10 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after it is filed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The petitioner (if he or she is not the licensee) shall ensure that the licensee or administrator of the facility is served with notice of the hearing date and a copy of the petition:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>In accordance with court rules, at least 5 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) before the hearing; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>By a notice conspicuously posted inside or on the front door of the facility at least 3 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) before the hearing, if the petitioner files with the court a sworn statement setting forth in detail his or her diligent but unsuccessful efforts to find the licensee or administrator and serve process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon filing a petition with the court, a petitioner other than the District shall serve notice of the hearing date and a copy of the petition on the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. No later than 5 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after receiving a copy of the petition, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall, to the extent allowable under federal law, make available to the petitioner for his or her use in the proceedings certified copies of all licensure and Medicare/Medicaid certification reports within the custody of the District government that document conditions in the facility within the previous 2 years.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The court may appoint a receiver immediately upon the filing of a petition under § <cite path="§44-1002.03">44-1002.03</cite> if it finds probable cause to believe a condition or practice in a facility poses an immediate danger of death or life-threatening injury to the residents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>In the event of an ex parte appointment under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the petitioner (if he or she is not the licensee) shall ensure that the licensee or administrator of the facility is served with notice of the hearing date and copies of the petition, any supporting affidavit(s), and the order of appointment:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>By personal service within 24 hours after the appointment; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>By a notice conspicuously posted inside or on the front door of the facility within 48 hours after the appointment, if the petitioner files with the court a sworn statement setting forth in detail his or her diligent but unsuccessful efforts to find the licensee or administrator and serve process.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-108" type="History" path="§204">Apr. 18, 1986, D.C. Law 6-108, § 204, 33 DCR 1510</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 67, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1414.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
