<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-105.05</num>
  <heading>Representation and resolution of grievances and complaints.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A resident shall have the right to the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To designate a person as his or her surrogate or to have their guardian,  or advance directives or surrogate health decision maker, act for them if for  any reason the resident cannot act for him or herself;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To uncoerced consent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To present grievances and complaints without fear of threat of  retaliation and have them acknowledged and acted upon promptly with due  respect to the provisions of this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To have access to an internal grievance and complaint procedure for any  denial of services or rights provided for under this chapter and to an  external review process by an independent person or entity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>To address grievances and complaints to representatives of the Office of  the Long-Term Care Ombudsman of the District of Columbia pursuant to Chapter 7  of Title 7 or other representative;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>To appoint a specially designated person or attorney to represent the  resident in any grievance or complaint, procedure, or appeal process who shall  have access to all necessary and relevant books and records of the ALR; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>To organize and participate in and hold meetings of resident groups in  the ALR and invite staff or visitors to the meetings and have a designated  staff person to assist and respond to written requests resulting from the  meetings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The ALR shall maintain complete written records of the filing and disposition of all grievances, complaints, and appeals.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Appeals under this section may be taken pursuant to subchapter XII of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-127" type="History" path="ยง505">June 24, 2000, D.C. Law 13-127, ยง 505, 47 DCR 2647</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
