<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-1206</num>
  <heading>Substance abuse prevention campaign.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish and implement a public education campaign intended to prevent substance abuse.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The public education campaign shall incorporate, at a minimum, the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The dissemination of statistics and other information that illustrate the  dangers of drug use and alcohol abuse;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The dissemination of information about the symptoms of substance abuse  and dependence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The dissemination of information about methods to treat substance abuse  and the availability and cost of treatment facilities in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The dissemination of literature designed for different age groups and  levels of education published by the District government for distribution on a  regular basis at public places deemed appropriate by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A series of print, audio, and audiovisual substance abuse education  messages to be provided on a continuing basis to all newspapers, magazines,  radio and television stations, and other mass communications media in the  District for use as public service announcements or advertisements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Community forums offered by the District government in conjunction with  professional organizations, community organizations, or individual volunteers  to be conducted on a regular basis at schools, recreation centers, civic and community centers, and other similar facilities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>A speaker’s bureau of qualified personnel available to speak, lead  discussions, and present written or audiovisual material at school and  community programs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All print, audio, and audiovisual material distributed in conjunction with the public education campaign shall include the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of appropriate treatment facilities in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall implement the public education campaign in a manner that promotes the coordination of efforts by participating agencies and the District of Columbia Public Schools.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-80" type="History" path="§7">Mar. 15, 1990, D.C. Law 8-80, § 7, 36 DCR 8469</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1606.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
