<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-105.04</num>
  <heading>Accommodation of needs.</heading>
  <text>A resident shall have the right to the following:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>To receive adequate and appropriate services and treatment with  reasonable accommodation of individual needs and preferences consistent with  their health and physical and mental capabilities and the health or safety of  other residents;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>To have access to appropriate health and social services, including  social work, home health, nursing, rehabilitative, hospice, medical, dental,  dietary, counseling, and psychiatric services in order to attain or maintain  the highest practicable physical, mental and psychosocial well-being;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>To remain in the current setting, forgoing a recommended transfer to  obtain additional services as contracted for by the resident or secure  additional services in a manner acceptable to the ALR;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>To engage in a shared responsibility agreement with the ALR which is  acceptable to the resident and the ALR and does not violate any applicable  law;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>To refuse to participate in any service once the potential consequences  of such participation have been explained and a shared responsibility  agreement has been reached, if necessary, between the resident, the surrogate,  and the ALR;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>To be free of physical restraints at all times; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>To be free of chemical restraints.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-127" type="History">June 24, 2000, D.C. Law 13-127, ยง 504, 47 DCR 2647</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
