<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-1712</num>
  <heading>Penalties; prosecutions; actions to enjoin.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person violating any provision of this chapter, or regulation made pursuant thereto, or filing, or causing to be filed, an application or report pursuant to this chapter, or regulation made pursuant thereto, containing any false or fraudulent statement, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500, or by imprisonment of not more than 60 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Prosecutions for violations of this chapter, or the regulations made pursuant thereto, shall be conducted in the name of the District of Columbia by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia or any of his assistants.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia, or any of his assistants, is hereby empowered to maintain an action or actions in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the name of the District of Columbia to enjoin any person from soliciting in violation of this chapter or in violation of any regulation made pursuant to this chapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the Attorney General, in the course of an investigation to determine whether to bring a court action under this section, has reason to believe that a person may have information, or may be in possession, custody, or control of documentary material, relevant to the investigation, the Attorney General may issue in writing and cause to be served upon the person, a subpoena or subpoenas requiring the person to give oral testimony under oath, or to produce records, books, papers, contracts, electronically-stored data and other documentary material for inspection and copying.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Information obtained pursuant to this authority to subpoena is not admissible in a later criminal proceeding against the person who provided the information.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Attorney General may petition the Superior Court of the District of Columbia for an order compelling compliance with a subpoena issued pursuant to this authority to subpoena.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Civil fines, penalties, and fees may be imposed as alternative sanctions for any infraction of the provisions of this chapter, or any rules or regulations issued under the authority of this chapter, pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2. Adjudication of any infraction of this chapter shall be pursuant to Chapter 18 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 10, 1957, 71 Stat. 281, Pub. L. 85-87, § 13</annotation>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 571, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(c)(10)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-42">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42,§ 438, 32 DCR 4450</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 69, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191">Mar 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 70, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-4">June 12, 2007, D.C. Law 17-4, § 4, 54 DCR 4085</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 2-712.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 2-2112.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in subsec. (c), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-4">D.C. Law 17-4</cite>, in subsec. (c), designated the existing text as par. (1) and added pars. (2), (3), and (4).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
