<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-1002.03</num>
  <heading>Petitions for receivership.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the availability of any other remedy, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia may, in the name of the District and based on one or more of the grounds listed in § <cite path="§44-1002.02">44-1002.02</cite>, petition the court to appoint a receiver for any facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the availability of any other remedy, a resident, a resident’s representative, the Long-Term Care Ombudsman, or any other advocate representing the interests of a facility’s residents may, based on one or more of the grounds listed in § <cite path="§44-1002.02">44-1002.02</cite>(2) through (6), submit a written request asking the Attorney General for the District of Columbia to petition the court to appoint a receiver for any facility. If the Attorney General for the District of Columbia denies the request or does not file a petition within 5 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) after receiving a request, the requestor may file with the court a petition for the appointment of a receiver.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The licensee of any facility may, based on one or more of the grounds listed in § <cite path="§44-1002.02">44-1002.02</cite>, petition the court to appoint a voluntary receiver for that facility.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-108" type="History" path="§203">Apr. 18, 1986, D.C. Law 6-108, § 203, 33 DCR 1510</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 67, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§44-1002.04">44-1002.04</cite>, § <cite path="§44-1002.05">44-1002.05</cite>, § <cite path="§44-1002.07">44-1002.07</cite>, and § <cite path="§44-1002.10">44-1002.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1413.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
