<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-1003.03</num>
  <heading>Hearing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Whenever a facility decides to involuntarily discharge, transfer, or relocate a resident, that resident, his or her representative, or the Long-Term Care Ombudsman may contest the decision by mailing a written hearing request to the Mayor and notifying the administrator or facility staff of the request:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Within 7 calendar days after receiving notice of a proposed discharge or transfer to another facility; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Within 5 calendar days after receiving notice of a proposed relocation within the facility.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the resident or resident’s representative mails the hearing request from the facility, the day he or she places it in the facility’s outgoing mail or gives it to a member of the facility staff for mailing shall be considered the date of mailing for purposes of the 7-day and 5-day time limits. In all other cases, the postmark date shall be considered the date of mailing.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A timely hearing request shall stay the discharge, transfer, or relocation unless a condition set forth in § <cite path="§44-1003.02">44-1003.02</cite>(b)(1) and (2) develops in the interim.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall hold a hearing at the resident’s facility within 5 calendar days, and shall render a decision within 7 calendar days, after a timely hearing request is received. The facility shall have the burden of proof unless the ground for the proposed discharge, transfer, or relocation is a prescribed change in the resident’s level of care, in which case the person(s) responsible for prescribing that change shall have the burden of proof and the resident shall have the right to challenge the level of care determination at the hearing. A hearing held under this section may not be used by the resident to litigate or relitigate Medicaid eligibility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor finds that the existence of a ground listed in § <cite path="§44-1003.01">44-1003.01</cite>(a) has been proven by clear and convincing evidence, the resident shall not be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Discharged or transferred from the facility before the 22nd calendar day following his or her receipt of the notice required by § <cite path="§44-1003.02">44-1003.02</cite>(a) or the 5th calendar day following his or her notification of the hearing decision, whichever is later, unless a condition set forth in § <cite path="§44-1003.02">44-1003.02</cite>(b)(1) and (2) develops in the interim; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Relocated within the facility before the 8th calendar day following his or her receipt of the notice required by § <cite path="§44-1003.02">44-1003.02</cite>(a) or the 3rd calendar day following his or her notification of the hearing decision, whichever is later, unless a condition set forth in § <cite path="§44-1003.02">44-1003.02</cite>(b)(1) and (2) develops in the interim.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-108" type="History" path="§303">Apr. 18, 1986, D.C. Law 6-108, § 303, 33 DCR 1510</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-218" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-218, § 602(c), 36 DCR 534</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Long-term care ombudsman program, ombudsman duties, see § <cite path="§7-702.04">7-702.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-702.04">7-702.04</cite> and § <cite path="§44-1003.04">44-1003.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1433.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-108">D.C. Law 6-108</cite>, see Mayor’s Order 86-129, August 8, 1986.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-108">D.C. Law 6-108</cite>, “Nursing Home and Community Residence Facility Residents’ Protection Act of 1985.”, see Mayor’s Order 88-230, October 19, 1988.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
