<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-1707</num>
  <heading>Representations as to finding by Mayor in regard to registration certificate or solicitor card prohibited.</heading>
  <text>No person shall make or cause to be made any representation that the issuance of a certificate of registration or of a solicitor information card is a finding by the Mayor:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>That the statements contained in the registrant’s application are true and accurate;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>That the application does not omit a material fact; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>That the Mayor has in any way passed upon the merits or given approval to such solicitation.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-87" type="History">July 10, 1957, 71 Stat. 281, Pub. L. 85-87, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 2-707.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 2-2107.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
