<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-232.01</num>
  <heading>AED program for Department of Parks and Recreation facilities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall develop and implement an AED program for each recreation facility. The program shall meet the requirements of § <cite path="§44-232">44-232</cite>, and, in addition, ensure that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At least one AED is provided on-site at each recreation facility;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An individual trained in the operation and use of an AED, pursuant to a training program approved under subsection (c) of this section, is present during the recreation facility’s hours of operation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each AED is maintained, operated, and tested according to the manufacturers’ guidelines by conducting periodic inspections and annual maintenance of each AED.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall develop guidelines for the program, including requirements that written records be maintained documenting:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The maintenance and testing of each AED; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That each Department of Parks and Recreation employee assigned to the recreation facility has successfully completed a training program approved under subsection (c) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall approve training programs required under this section in accordance with the requirements of § <cite path="§44-232">44-232</cite>. The training programs may be conducted by a private or public entity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The training programs shall be in conjunction with health training provided to Department of Parks and Recreation employees, as well as refresher training, as required.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall comply with this section within 45 days of March 25, 2009. The Mayor shall expand the AED program to a new recreation facility within 45 days of its opening.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-278" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-278, § 3a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-362" type="History">as added Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-362, § 2(c), 56 DCR 1211</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§44-231">44-231</cite> and § <cite path="§44-232">44-232</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">Sections 2 to 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-213">D.C. Law 17-213</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) ‘Automated external defibrillator’ or ‘AED’ or ‘defibrillator’ means a medical device heart monitor and defibrillator that:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(A) Has received approval from the United States Food and Drug Administration of its premarket notification filed pursuant to section 501(k) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, approved October 10, 1962 (76 Stat. 794;  21 U.S.C. § 360(k));</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(B) Is capable of recognizing the presence or absence of ventricular fibrillation or rapid ventricular tachycardia, and determining, without intervention by an operator, whether defibrillation should be performed; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(C) Upon determining that defibrillation should be performed, automatically charges and requests delivery of an electrical impulse to an individual’s heart.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) ‘Certificate’ means a certificate issued by the Mayor to an authorized recreational facility.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(3) ‘Recreation facility’ means staffed Department of Parks and Recreation facilities.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“Sec. 3. AED program.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(a) The Mayor shall develop and implement an AED program for each recreation facility within 45 days of the effective date of this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(b) The program required under subsection (a) of this section shall include provisions that:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) Ensure that an AED is provided on-site; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) An individual trained in the operation and use of an AED is present during hours of operation.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(c) The Mayor shall establish guidelines for periodic inspections and annual maintenance of the automated external defibrillators to ensure each AED is maintained, operated, and tested according to manufacturers’ guidelines, including:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) Written records of the maintenance and testing of each AED are maintained, as required; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) Proof that each individual who operates an AED for the authorized recreational facility has successfully completed an educational training course in conjunction with health training already received by Department of Parks and Recreation employees and refresher training, as required.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(d) The Mayor shall issue and renew certificates to recreation facilities that meet the requirements of this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(e) The Mayor shall approve educational and training programs required under this section that:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) Are conducted by any private or public entity;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) Include training in cardiopulmonary resuscitation; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(3) May include courses from nationally recognized entities, such as the American Heart Association, the American Red Cross, and the National Safety Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(f) The Mayor shall make best efforts to use uniform equipment pursuant to this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“Sec. 4. Immunities.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(a) In addition to any other immunities available under statutory or common law, an authorized recreation facility is not civilly liable for any act or omission in the provision of automated external defibrillation if the authorized facility:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(1) Satisfied the requirements for making automated external defibrillation available under section 3; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(2) Possesses a valid certificate at the time of the act or omission.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">“(b) The AED program established under this act shall include tort immunity pursuant to section 4 of the Public Access to Automated External Defibrillator Act of 2001, effective April 27, 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-278">D.C. Law 13-278</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§44-233">44-233</cite>).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">Section 6(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-213">D.C. Law 17-213</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 4 of AED Installation for Safe Recreation and Exercise Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-392, May 21, 2008,  55 DCR 6272).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 4 of AED Installation for Safe Recreation and Exercise Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-459, July 28, 2008,  55 DCR 8726).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
