<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-204</num>
  <heading>Qualifications of technical personnel.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A clinical laboratory performing only waived tests shall employ testing personnel who meet the qualifications set out in rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§44-213">44-213</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A clinical laboratory performing moderately complex tests shall employ a laboratory director, a technical consultant, a clinical consultant, and testing personnel. A person may function in more than one of these capacities if he or she meets the qualifications specified in this chapter and in rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§44-213">44-213</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The laboratory director, technical consultant, clinical consultant, and testing personnel shall meet the qualifications as specified in rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§44-213">44-213</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A clinical laboratory performing highly complex tests shall employ a laboratory director, a general supervisor, a technical supervisor, a clinical consultant, and testing personnel. A person may function in more than one of these capacities if he or she meets the qualifications specified in this chapter and in rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§44-213">44-213</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The laboratory director, general supervisor, technical supervisor, clinical consultant, and testing personnel shall meet qualifications as specified in rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§44-213">44-213</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In addition to the requirements set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection, a clinical laboratory that performs highly complex tests in the subspecialty of cytology shall employ a cytology general supervisor, a cytology technical supervisor, and a cytotechnologist. A person may function in more than one of these capacities if he or she meets the qualifications specified in this chapter and in rules issued pursuant to § <cite path="§44-213">44-213</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-182" type="History">Mar. 16, 1989, D.C. Law 7-182, § 5, 35 DCR 7718</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 5012(d), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1504.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</law-cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 5012(d) of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
