<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-413</num>
  <heading>Administrative appeal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Following reconsideration by the SHPDA, or if the SHPDA denies a request for consideration, or has not granted a request for reconsideration pursuant to § <cite path="§44-412">44-412</cite>(a) within 30 days after the request for reconsideration, the final decision of the SHPDA on the application for a certificate of need may be appealed by the SHCC, the applicant, or any previously appearing persons to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Office of Administrative Hearings shall review the record and any additional evidence presented on behalf of the parties to the appeal. It shall take due account of the presumption of official regularity, the experience, and specialized competence of the SHPDA, and the purposes of this chapter. The Office of Administrative Hearings must make its written decision within 45 days of the conclusion of its review. The decision must be provided to the applicant, the SHPDA, the person requesting the hearing, and to any other person upon request. The decision of the Office of Administrative Hearings shall be considered the final decision of the SHPDA.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any contested case hearing required by § <cite path="§2-509">2-509</cite>, shall be conducted by the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-191" type="History" path="§14">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-191, § 14, 43 DCR 4535</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 17, 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 64(b), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-363.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “to the Office of Administrative Hearings” for “to the Board of Appeals and review established by Organization Order 112, dated August 11, 1955 (C.O. 55-1500) (‘Board of Appeals and Review’)”, and deleted the last sentence which read: “This appeal must be made within 30 days of the date of the SHPDA’s final decision on reconsideration issued under 44-412(d) or, if the SHPDA does not grant a request for reconsideration, within 30 days of the date it denies a request for reconsideration.”; and, in subsecs. (b) and (c), substituted “Office of Administrative Hearings” for “Board of Appeals and Review”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
