<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-420</num>
  <heading>Fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The SHPDA shall collect application fees from persons that request a certificate of need. The fee required for an application shall be the greater of 3% of the proposed capital expenditure or $5,000, with a maximum of $300,000. The SHPDA is authorized to establish a fee schedule for certain data, analyses and reports published by the SHPDA from the HPDS. The annual user fee for private hospitals shall be $4 per inpatient admission, based on the previous calendar year’s admission data, to be paid to the SHPDA on a quarterly basis, in lieu of a certificate of need application fee. The certificate of need application fee for any project receiving funds through the Medical Homes DC initiative, as operated by the District of Columbia Primary Care Association, shall be $5,000. User fees may also be established for other classes of facilities by regulation. SHPDA may adjust a user fee periodically to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index issued by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the maximum application fee that may be collected from Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, for facilities located in Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919, related to the acquisition of Greater Southeast Community Hospital shall be $300,000.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-191" type="History" path="§21">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-191, § 21, 43 DCR 4535</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 2002(d), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-149" type="History">Apr. 22, 2004, D.C. Law 15-149, § 2(h), 51 DCR 2802</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-116" type="History">Mar. 20, 2008, D.C. Law 17-116, § 2, 55 DCR 1280</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-167" type="History">June 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-167, § 3, 55 DCR 5178</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§44-402">44-402</cite> and § <cite path="§44-420.01">44-420.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-370.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</law-cite> substituted “3% of the proposed capital expenditure or $5,000, with a maximum of $300,000” for “1% of the proposed capital expenditure or $2, 000, with a maximum of $25,000”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-149">D.C. Law 15-149</law-cite> added three new sentences at the end to read: “The annual user fee for private hospitals shall be $4 per inpatient admission, based on the previous calendar year’s admission data, to be paid to the SHPDA on a quarterly basis, in lieu of a certificate of need application fee. User fees may also be established for other classes of facilities by regulation. SHPDA may adjust a user fee periodically to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index issued by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-116">D.C. Law 17-116</law-cite> inserted “The certificate of need application fee for any project receiving funds through the Medical Homes DC initiative, as operated by the District of Columbia Primary Care Association, shall be $5,000.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-167">D.C. Law 17-167</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a); and added subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-19">D.C. Law 15-19</law-cite>, June 21, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 5463).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 3 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-71">D.C. Law 17-71</law-cite> designated the existing text as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b) to read as follows: “(b) Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the maximum application fee that may be collected from Specialty Hospitals of America, LLC, or certain of its subsidiary entities, for facilities located in Lots 3 and 4, Square 5919, related to the acquisition of Greater Southeast Community Hospital shall be $300,000.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-71">D.C. Law 17-71</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(d) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(d) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-49, March 28, 2003,  50 DCR 2943).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-87, May 19, 2003,  50 DCR 4325).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2002(d) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(g) of Health Services Planning and Development Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-322, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1581).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-168, October 19, 2007,  54 DCR 10978).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Health Services Planning Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-234, December 27, 2007,  55 DCR 238).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of East of the River Hospital Revitalization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-249, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1255).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Health Services Planning Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-319, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3430).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
