<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-506</num>
  <heading>Provisional and restricted licenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>As an alternative to denial, nonrenewal, suspension, or revocation of a license when a facility or agency has numerous deficiencies or a serious single deficiency with respect to the standards to be established under § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3), the Mayor may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Issue a provisional license if the facility or agency is taking appropriate ameliorative action in accordance with a mutually agreed upon timetable; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Issue a restricted license that prohibits the facility or agency from accepting new patients/clients/residents or delivering certain specified services that it would otherwise be authorized to deliver, if appropriate ameliorative action is not forthcoming.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>As provided in § <cite path="§44-505">44-505</cite>(a), provisional licenses may be issued to new facilities and agencies in order to afford the Mayor sufficient time and evidence to evaluate whether a new facility or agency is capable of complying with the provisions of this subchapter, rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter, and other applicable provisions of law.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Provisional licenses may be granted for a period not exceeding 90 days, and may be renewed no more than once.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any provisional license issued pursuant to this section shall be issued as a provisional Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement or a provisional Public Health: Human Services facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic business license system as set forth in subchapter I-A of Chapter 28 of Title 47.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If a facility is issued a restricted or provisional license, the Department of Health may, if appropriate, appoint a temporary manager or monitor in accordance with a mutually agreed upon timetable or until the facility becomes compliant with § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3) and (h-1).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-48" type="History">Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48, § 7, 30 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2003(aa)(3), 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-38" type="History">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-38, § 3(ee)(3), 50 DCR 6913</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-145" type="History">Apr. 29, 2010, D.C. Law 18-145, § 3(c), 57 DCR 1834</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 112, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§44-505">44-505</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1306.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-38">D.C. Law 15-38</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement or a provisional Public Health: Human Services Facility endorsement to a basic business license under the basic” for “Class A Public Health: Health Care Facility endorsement or a provisional Public Health: Human Services facility endorsement to a master business license under the master”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-145">D.C. Law 18-145</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(ee)(3) of Streamlining Regulation Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-145, August 11, 2003,  50 DCR 6896).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Because of the enactment of subchapter II of this chapter by <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-238">D.C. Law 12-238</cite> and the designation of the preexisting text as subchapter I, “subchapter” has been substituted for “act” twice near the end of (b).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 112 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> amended subsection (e) of this section by striking the phrase “with § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3)” and inserting the phrase “with section 8(a)(3) [of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-48">D.C. Law 5-48</cite>]” in its place. The legislative intent was to substitute in the phrase “with section 5(a)(3),” codified as § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3), rather than the phrase “with section 8(a)(3),” and has been implemented accordingly.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
