<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-505</num>
  <heading>Inspections.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To ensure that each new facility and agency will be in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter, rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter, and all other applicable laws and rules, the Mayor shall conduct an on-site inspection prior to a facility’s or agency’s initial licensure. Instead of issuing a full-year license to a new facility or agency, the Mayor may issue a provisional license under § <cite path="§44-506">44-506</cite> pending satisfactory completion of additional, follow-up inspections.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After initial licensure the Mayor shall conduct an on-site inspection as a precondition to licensure renewal, except that the Mayor may accept accreditation by a private accrediting body, federal certification for participation in a health-insurance or medical assistance program, or federal qualification of a health maintenance organization as evidence of, and in lieu of inspecting for, compliance with any or all of the provisions of this subchapter and rules adopted pursuant to this subchapter that incorporate or are substantially similar to applicable standards or conditions of participation established by that body or the federal government. Acceptance of private accreditation by the Mayor shall be contingent on the facility’s or agency’s:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notifying the Mayor of all survey and resurvey dates no later than 5 days after it receives notice of these dates;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Permitting authorized government officials to accompany the survey team; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Submitting to the Mayor a copy of the certificate of accreditation, all survey findings, recommendations, and reports, plans of correction, interim self-survey reports, notices of noncompliance, progress reports on correction of noncompliances, preliminary decisions to deny or limit accreditation, and all other similar documents relevant to the accreditation process, no later than 5 days after their receipt by the facility or agency or submission to the accrediting body.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An authorized government official may enter the premises of a facility or agency during operating hours for the purpose of conducting an announced or unannounced inspection to check for compliance with any provision of this subchapter, rule adopted pursuant to this subchapter, or other provision of District of Columbia law. In conducting an inspection, the official shall make every effort not to disrupt the normal operations of the facility or agency and its staff.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a facility or agency loses private accreditation or federal certification, it shall give the Mayor written notice of the loss within 5 calendar days. If in such a case accreditation or certification was accepted in lieu of an inspection under subsection (b) of this section, the Mayor shall immediately upon notification:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Convert the facility’s or agency’s license to a provisional or restricted license under § <cite path="§44-506">44-506</cite> pending satisfactory completion of an inspection conducted by the Mayor; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Suspend the facility’s or agency’s license based upon a finding that loss of accreditation or certification was prompted by existing deficiencies that constitute an immediate or serious and continuing danger to the health, safety, or welfare of its patients/clients/residents.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may, prior to a hearing, suspend the license of any facility or agency or convert its license to a provisional or restricted license if he or she determines that existing deficiencies constitute an immediate or serious and continuing danger to the health, safety, or welfare of its patients/clients/residents.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Upon the suspension or conversion of a license pursuant to this subsection, the Mayor shall immediately give the facility or agency written notice of the action, including a copy of the order of suspension or conversion, a statement of the grounds for the action, and notification that the facility or agency has 7 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) from the day written notice is received to request an expedited, preliminary review hearing. If the facility or agency fails to communicate, either orally or in writing, a timely request for a preliminary review hearing, the order of suspension or conversion shall remain in effect until terminated by the Mayor or an unexpedited hearing is held pursuant to procedures adopted under § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>. Upon receipt of a timely request for an expedited, preliminary review hearing, the Mayor shall within 72 hours (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) provide a hearing to review the reasonableness of the suspension or conversion order. At this hearing, the Mayor shall have the burden of establishing a prima facie case of immediate or serious and continuing endangerment. The suspension or conversion order shall be either affirmed or vacated at the hearing. In the event an order is affirmed, it shall, unless extended, remain in effect for no longer than 30 calendar days, during which time a final hearing shall be scheduled to consider the appropriateness of revocation or continuing restrictions on licensure. Before expiration of a suspension or conversion order, an extension may be granted for a period not to exceed an additional 30 calendar days upon agreement of all the parties or for good cause shown.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall have the authority, upon a showing of undue hardship and if not inconsistent with other provisions of this chapter or deleterious to the public health and safety, to grant variances with respect to the standards to be established under § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3) and (h-1). The Mayor shall maintain a public record listing all variances granted under this subsection and containing a complete written explanation of the basis for each variance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-48" type="History" path="§6">Feb. 24, 1984, D.C. Law 5-48, § 6, 30 DCR 5778</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-26" type="History">Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-26, § 2(e), (f), 32 DCR 3615</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-145" type="History">Apr. 29, 2010, D.C. Law 18-145, § 3(b), 57 DCR 1834</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§44-103.06">44-103.06</cite>, § <cite path="§44-104.04">44-104.04</cite>, § <cite path="§44-112.01">44-112.01</cite>, § <cite path="§44-501">44-501</cite>, § <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>, and § <cite path="§44-506">44-506</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1305.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-145">D.C. Law 18-145</law-cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “§ <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3) and (h-1)” for “§ <cite path="§44-504">44-504</cite>(a)(3)”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Because of the enactment of subchapter II of this chapter by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-238">D.C. Law 12-238</law-cite> and the designation of the preexisting text of Chapter 5 as subchapter I, “subchapter” has been substituted for “act” twice in the first sentence of (a)-(c).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
