<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-601</num>
  <heading>Findings.</heading>
  <text>The Council finds and declares the following:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Charitable healthcare entities hold all their assets in trust, and those assets are irrevocably dedicated, as a condition of their tax-exempt status, to the specific charitable purposes set forth in the articles of incorporation of the entities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The public is the beneficiary of that trust.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Healthcare entities have a substantial and beneficial effect on the quality of life of the people of the District of Columbia, providing as part of their charitable mission a large list of services to low-income families and the poor, elderly, and people with disabilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Transfers of the assets of healthcare entities, such as by sale, joint venture, or other sharing of assets, to for-profit entities directly affect the charitable uses of those assets and may adversely affect the public as the beneficiary of the charitable assets.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia is entrusted by common law to bring actions on behalf of the public in the event of a breach of the charitable trust of a healthcare entity and to represent the public in the sale or other transfer of the assets of a healthcare entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>It is in the best interest of the public to ensure that the public interest is fully protected whenever the assets or operations of a healthcare entity are transferred, directly or indirectly, from a charitable trust to a for-profit or mutual benefit entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The approval by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia of any transfer of assets or operations is necessary to ensure the protection of these trusts.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-32" type="History">Oct. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-32, § 2, 44 DCR 4819</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 34, 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 66, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 71, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-551.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in par. (3), substituted “people with disabilities” for “disabled”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
