<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-606</num>
  <heading>Process of review.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall approve or disapprove a conversion within 60 days of receiving a request from the applicable agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Prior to issuing a decision, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall publish the request in at least two newspapers of general publication and may hold a public hearing to receive public testimony. Notice of a public hearing shall be published at least 10 days prior to the hearing. The Attorney General for the District of Columbia may increase the number days of review provided such request will not unnecessarily delay the applicable agency’s decision. The Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall hold a public hearing if requested by any interested person. The Attorney General for the District of Columbia may request or subpoena additional information or witnesses, require and administer oaths, require sworn statements, take depositions, and use related discovery procedures for the purpose of the public hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall employ the services of an independent expert to assess the value of the charitable assets. If the conversion is approved, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia may issue conditions and recommendations regarding the charitable assets. The costs of the review required by this section shall be assessed against the applicant.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-32" type="History">Oct. 23, 1997, D.C. Law 12-32, § 7, 44 DCR 4819</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 66, 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-556.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</law-cite> substituted “Attorney General for the District of Columbia” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
