<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-661.07</num>
  <heading>Multi-hospital systems, closure, merger, and new hospitals.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a hospital system conducts, operates, or maintains more than one hospital licensed by the Department of Health, the hospital system shall pay the fee for each hospital separately.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter, if a hospital system or person ceases to conduct, operate, or maintain a hospital that is subject to a fee under ยง <cite root="44-661.03">44-661.03</cite>, as evidenced by the transfer or surrender of the hospital license, the fee for the DFY in which the cessation occurs shall be adjusted by multiplying the fee computed under ยง <cite root="44-661.03">44-661.03</cite> by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of days in the year during which the hospital system or person conducted, operated, or maintained the hospital, and the denominator of which is 365.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Immediately upon ceasing to conduct, operate, or maintain a hospital, the hospital system or person shall pay the fee for the year as so adjusted, to the extent not previously paid.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter, a hospital system or person who conducts, operates, or maintains a hospital, upon notice by the Department, shall pay the fee computed under ยง <cite root="44-661.03">44-661.03</cite> and subsection (a) of this section in installments on the due date stated in the notice and on the regular installment due dates for the DFY occurring after the due dates of the initial notice.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, ยง 5068, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
