<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-661.05</num>
  <heading>Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For visits and services beginning October 1, 2015, quarterly Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments shall be made to each private hospital.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each payment will be equal to the hospital’s DFY 2013 outpatient Medicaid payments divided by the total in District private hospital DFY 2013 outpatient Medicaid payments multiplied by 1/4 of the total outpatient private hospital access payment pool.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The total outpatient private hospital access payment pool is equal to the total available spending room under the private hospital outpatient Medicaid upper payment limit for DFY 2016.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A private hospital that is also a Disproportionate Share Hospital (“DSH”) will receive no more in Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments than the available room under its District-adjusted, hospital-specific DSH limit.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments that would otherwise exceed a private DSH’s adjusted DSH limit shall be distributed to the remaining private hospitals consistent with each private hospital’s relative share of DFY 2013 outpatient Medicaid payments.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For visits and services beginning October 1, 2015, outpatient hospital access payments shall be made to the United Medical Center.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each payment will be equal to one quarter of the total outpatient public hospital access payment pool.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The total outpatient public hospital access payment pool is equal to the lesser of the total available spending room under the District­operated hospital outpatient Medicaid upper payment limit for DFY 2016, and the United Medical Center District-adjusted Medicaid DSH limit.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The quarterly Medicaid outpatient hospital access payments shall be made within 15 business days after the end of each DFY quarter for the Medicaid visits and services rendered during that quarter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No payments shall be made under this section until such time that the federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services approves the Medicaid State Plan amendment authorizing the Medicaid payments described in this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Medicaid payment methodologies authorized under this chapter shall not be altered in any way unless such alteration is necessary to gain federal approval from the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History" path="§5066">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 5066, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
