<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>44-751</num>
  <heading>In general.</heading>
  <text>Subject to the provisions of § <cite path="§44-752">44-752</cite> [repealed], the Administrator of General Services and the Commissioner of the District of Columbia are directed to convey, without monetary consideration, to the Columbia Hospital for Women and Lying-in Asylum, Washington, District of Columbia, a corporation created by the Act of June 1, 1866 (14 Stat. 55), all right, title, and interest of the United States and of the District of Columbia in and to those pieces or parcels of land in the District of Columbia, described as follows, together with all improvements thereon and appurtenances thereto:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>All that piece or parcel of land situate and lying in the City of Washington in the District of Columbia and known as part of square no. 25, as laid down and distinguished on the plat or plan of said City, as follows: Beginning at the southeast corner of said square and running thence north with 24th Street 231 feet and 7 inches; thence west 230 feet and 6 inches; thence north to M Street 231 feet and 10 inches; thence west with M Street 215 feet and 6 inches to 25th Street; thence south with 25th Street 263 feet and 5 inches; thence east 200 feet; thence south to L Street 200 feet; thence east with L Street 246 feet to the beginning; and being the property conveyed to the United States of America by deed dated October 17, 1876, from the Columbia Hospital for Women and Lying-in Asylum, recorded in liber 836, folio 159, of the land records of the District of Columbia; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>All that piece or parcel of land situate and lying in the City of Washington in the District of Columbia on the northeast corner of L and 25th Streets Northwest, being a part of original square no. 25, as follows: Beginning at the southwest corner of said square and running thence east with the line of said L Street 200 feet for a corner; thence north 200 feet for a corner; thence west 200 feet for a corner; and thence south 200 feet to the place of beginning; containing 40,000 square feet of ground, more or less, and being the property conveyed to the United States of America by deed dated July 6, 1872, from the Columbia Hospital for Women and Lying-in Asylum and Edward Maynard, recorded in liber 811, folio 481 of the land records of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 82-2-ch486" path="§1">June 28, 1952, 66 Stat. 287, ch. 486, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264,§ 32, 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§44-753">44-753</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-120.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 32-323.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
