<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>44-662.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Health Care Finance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Hospital” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite root="44-501">44-501</cite>(a)(1) but excludes any hospital operated by the federal government and any specialty hospital, as defined by the District of Columbia’s Medicaid State Plan (“State Plan”), or a hospital that is reimbursed under a specialty hospital reimbursement methodology under the State Plan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Hospital system” means any group of hospitals licensed separately but operated, owned, or maintained by a common entity.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Inpatient net patient revenue” means the amount calculated in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles for hospitals as derived from each hospital’s filed Hospital and Hospital Health Care Complex Cost Report (Form CMS-2552-10), filed for the period ending between October 1, 2012, and June 30, 2013, using the references below:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The sum of: Worksheet G-2; Column 1; Lines 1, 2, 3, 4, 16 and 18.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Minus: The ratio of the sum of Worksheet G-2; Column 1; Lines 5, 6, and 7 divided by Worksheet G-2; Column 1; Line 17 multiplied by Worksheet G-2; Column 1; Line 18.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Divided by: Worksheet G-2; Column 3; Line 28</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Multiplied by: Worksheet G-2; Column 1; Line 3</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Medicaid” means the medical assistance programs authorized by Title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq.) (“Social Security Act”), and by § <cite root="1-307.02">1-307.02</cite>, and administered by the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 5072, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) addition of this chapter, see §§ 50<cite root="72-5079">72-5079</cite> of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
