<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-104</num>
  <heading>Bond and oath of Inspector.</heading>
  <text>The said Inspector shall give bond, with 2 sufficient securities, to be approved by the Mayor, in the sum of $2,000, and he shall take and subscribe the following oath or affirmation before a notary public or a judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia: “I do solemnly swear that I will diligently, faithfully, and impartially execute the duties of my office without favor.”</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Leg. Assem., June 25, 1873, ch. 25, § 4</annotation>
      <annotation>July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="47-2829">47-2829</cite> and § <cite root="47-2862">47-2862</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-1004.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-704.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
