<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1225.22</num>
  <heading>Capital accounts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any capital funds of the AWC and the NCRC transferred to the District government shall be transferred to segregated accounts in the General Capital Improvements Fund, which shall be designated specifically for capital projects of the former AWC and NCRC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The segregated accounts shall be under the expenditure authority of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-138">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 302, 55 DCR 1689</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="2-1225.02">2-1225.02</cite>, § <cite root="2-1225.11">2-1225.11</cite>, and § <cite root="2-1225.12">2-1225.12</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</cite>, § 302, added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Sec. 302. Capital accounts.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(a) Any capital funds of the AWC and the NCRC transferred to the District government shall be transferred to segregated accounts in the General Capital Improvements Fund, which shall be designated specifically for capital projects of the former AWC and NCRC.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(b) The segregated accounts shall be under the expenditure authority of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 702(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 302 of National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-71, July 20, 2007,  54 DCR 7390).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 302 of National Capitol Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-152, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10900).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
