<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <num>2-1396</num>
  <heading>Applicability.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-111">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-111, § 7, 53 DCR 2532</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 7074, 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Elections, initiative and referendum, see § <cite root="1-1101.16">1-1101.16</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Government pay equity and training, “equitable job-evaluation technique” and “protected classes” defined, see § <cite root="32-601">32-601</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Health care benefits expansion, limitations of law, see § <cite root="32-710">32-710</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Health occupations, advanced registered nurses, collaboration with licensed health care providers, see § <cite root="3-1206.03">3-1206.03</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Health occupations, revocation, suspension, or denial of license, civil penalties, see § <cite root="3-1205.14">3-1205.14</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Licensure, non-health related occupations, revocation, suspension, or denial of license, civil penalties, see § <cite root="47-2853.17">47-2853.17</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Motor vehicles, no-fault insurance, cancellation, prohibited discrimination, see § <cite root="31-2409">31-2409</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Real estate broker, salespersons, and property managers; licensure, prohibited acts, see § <cite root="47-2853.197">47-2853.197</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Administration, merit system, attorneys employed by District, residency requirement, see § <cite root="1-608.59">1-608.59</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Administration, merit system, career service, career service positions, hiring preference for residents, see § <cite root="1-608.01">1-608.01</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Administration, merit system, continuation of existing laws, see § <cite root="1-632.06">1-632.06</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Administration, merit system, educational service, hiring preference for residents, see § <cite root="1-608.01a">1-608.01a</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Administration, merit system, employment in or appointment to excepted service, residency requirement, see § <cite root="1-609.06">1-609.06</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Cable operator, employment discrimination prohibited, see § <cite root="34-1262.01">34-1262.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
