<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1803.01</num>
  <heading>Jurisdiction to hear appeal.</heading>
  <text>Except as provided in § <cite root="2-1831.16">2-1831.16</cite>, the District of Columbia Board of Appeals and Review shall entertain and determine appeals timely filed by persons aggrieved by orders issued by hearing examiners pursuant to this chapter or by the Mayor, except that appeals involving infractions of subchapter I of Chapter 6 of Title 6, or the District of Columbia Zoning Regulations shall be entertained and determined by the District of Columbia Board of Zoning Adjustment; appeals involving infractions of Chapter 1 of Title 25, or of any regulation issued under the authority of that chapter shall be entertained and determined by the District of Columbia Alcoholic Beverage Control Board; appeals involving infractions of laws governing occupations and professions or of regulations issued under the authority of those laws shall be entertained and determined by the appropriate occupational or professional board or commission; and appeals involving infractions of Chapter 35 of Title 42, or of any regulation issued under the authority of that chapter shall be entertained and determined by the District of Columbia Rental Housing Commission.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-42">Oct. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-42, § 301, 32 DCR 4450</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-237">Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-237, § 2(k), 38 DCR 314</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-76">Mar. 6, 2002, D.C. Law 14-76, § 23(b)(1), 48 DCR 11442</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="2-1803.02">2-1803.02</cite> and § <cite root="2-1831.16">2-1831.16</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-2721.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-76">D.C. Law 14-76</cite> substituted “Except as provided in § <cite root="2-1831.16">2-1831.16</cite>, the” for “The” in the first sentence.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <annotation>Title 25, referred to in this section, was amended and enacted by <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-298">D.C. Law 13-298</cite>, effective May 3, 2001. Chapter 1 of former Title 25 embraced all sections in that title. For current provisions of Title 25, see § <cite root="25-101">25-101</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
