<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1010</num>
  <heading>Acquisition of land — Appropriation; control.</heading>
  <text>There is authorized to be appropriated, each year, in the annual District of Columbia appropriation act, a sum not exceeding $.01 for each inhabitant of the continental United States as determined by the last preceding decennial census, said sum to be used by said Commission for the payment of its expenses and for the acquisition of the lands herein authorized to be acquired by said Commission for the purposes named, the compensation for the land, the expense of surveys, ascertainment of title, condemnation proceedings, if any, and necessary conveyancing to be paid from said appropriations. The funds so appropriated shall be paid from the revenues of the District of Columbia and the general funds of the Treasury in the same proportion as other expenses of the District of Columbia. The land so acquired within the District of Columbia shall be a part of the park system of the District of Columbia and be under control of the Director of the National Park Service. Areas suitable for playground purposes may, in the discretion of said Commission, be assigned to the control of the Mayor of the District of Columbia for playground purposes. The land so acquired outside the District of Columbia shall be controlled as determined by agreement between said Commission and the proper officers of the States of Maryland and Virginia, such agreements to be subject to the approval of the President.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-1-ch270" path="§12">June 6, 1924, 43 Stat. 463, ch. 270, § 12</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 26, 1925, 43 Stat. 983, ch. 339, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 10, 1933, Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 2, 1934, 48 Stat. 389, ch. 38, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 791, ch. 949, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1012.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2010.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1007">2-1007</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
