<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1009</num>
  <heading>Acquisition of land — Authorization.</heading>
  <text>Said Commission or a majority thereof is authorized and directed to acquire such lands as in its judgment shall be necessary and desirable in the District of Columbia and adjacent areas in Maryland and Virginia, within the limits of the appropriations made for such purposes, for suitable development of the National Capital park, parkway, and playground system. Said Commission is authorized to acquire such lands by purchase when they can be acquired at prices reasonable in the judgment of said Commission, otherwise by condemnation proceedings, such proceedings to acquire lands within the District of Columbia to be in accordance with the provisions of the Act of August 30, 1890, 26 Stat. 412, ch. 837, the Chief of Engineers of the Army being, for the purposes of this chapter, hereby clothed with all the power vested by the said Act of August 30, 1890, in the Board thereby created. Said Commission is hereby authorized to acquire such lands, located in Maryland or Virginia, either by purchase or condemnation proceedings, by such arrangements as to acquisition and payment for the lands as it shall determine upon by agreement with the proper officials of the States of Maryland and Virginia. In the selection of lands to be acquired the advice of the Commission of Fine Arts shall be requested. The designation of all lands to be acquired by condemnation, all contracts for purchase of lands, and all agreements between said Commission and the officials of the States of Maryland and Virginia shall be subject to the approval of the President of the United States.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 6, 1924, 43 Stat. 463, ch. 270, § 11</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 19, 1952, 66 Stat. 791, ch. 949, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1007">2-1007</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2009.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1011.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Act of August 30, 1890, 26 Stat. 412, ch. 837, created a board to acquire land for the Government Printing Office and established the procedure for such acquisition.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Delegation of functions: The authority of the President under the last sentence of this section was delegated to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, by §  9(4) of Executive Order No. 11609, July 22, 1971, 36 F.R. 13747.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
