<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1102</num>
  <heading>Congressional policy.</heading>
  <text>The Congress further declares that the policy to be followed for the attainment of the objective established by § <cite path="§2-1101">2-1101</cite>, and for the more effective exercise by the Congress, the executive branch of the federal government and the Mayor of the District of Columbia and all other officers and agencies and instrumentalities of the District of Columbia of their respective functions, powers, and duties in respect of the Washington metropolitan region, shall be that all such functions, powers, and duties shall be exercised and carried out in such manner as (with proper recognition of the sovereignty of the State of Maryland and the Commonwealth of Virginia in respect to those areas of the Washington metropolitan region as are situate within their respective jurisdictions) will best facilitate the attainment of such objective of the coordinated development of the areas of the Washington metropolitan region and coordinated management of their public affairs so as to contribute effectively to the solution of the community development problems of the Washington metropolitan region on a unified metropolitan basis.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-527" type="History" path="§3">June 27, 1960, 74 Stat. 223, Pub. L. 86-527, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1302.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2102.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1103">2-1103</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
