<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1210.07</num>
  <heading>Limitations on District’s contribution to reserve account.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall not deposit more than 10% of the total funds deposited in the Capital Access Fund into reserve accounts for capital access loans requiring a 200% match under § <cite path="§2-1210.06">2-1210.06</cite>(d)(3). The 10% limitation under this subsection may be waived at the discretion of the Mayor upon a finding that the total amount of funds deposited in the Capital Access Fund by the District shall result in at least $10 of enrolled loans by financial institutions for each dollar deposited by the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The amount deposited by the Mayor into a reserve account for any single loan recipient shall not exceed $400,000 during a 3-year period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The maximum amount that the Mayor may deposit into a reserve account for each enrolled loan made under this subchapter shall be the greater of $35,000 or an amount equal to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fourteen percent of the enrolled loan amount if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The borrower is financing an enterprise project or is located in, or financing a project, activity, or enterprise in, an area in the District of Columbia Enterprise Zone under section 1400 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 5, 1997 (111 Stat. 863; 26 U.S.C. § 1400); or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The financial institution is a community development financial institution, as defined in section 103(5) of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994, approved September 23, 1994 (108 Stat. 2163; 12 U.S.C. § 4702(5)); or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Seven percent of the loan amount for any other borrower.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-322" type="History">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-322, § 8, 57 DCR 12442</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1210.04">2-1210.04</cite> and § <cite path="§2-1210.06">2-1210.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 8 of Capital Access Program Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-598, November 17, 2010,  57 DCR 11018).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 8 of Capital Access Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-6, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1408).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
