<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1215.10</num>
  <heading>Meetings of members and the Board.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided by this subchapter, meetings of the members shall be held in accordance with the provisions of the bylaws but shall occur at least once each year after the formation of the BID. The bylaws shall specify an officer who shall send each member notice of the time, place, and purposes of the meeting. Notice shall be given at least 21 days in advance of any annual or regularly scheduled meeting and at least 7 days in advance of any other meeting, in one of the following ways:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>First class mail to all members of record at the address of their respective properties and to such other address as may have been designated to the officer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Hand delivered by the officer, or the officer’s agent; provided, that the officer certifies in writing that notice was actually delivered to the member; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Electronically to the member’s email address of record as may have been designated to the officer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All meetings of the Board shall be open to members. Minutes shall be recorded and shall be made reasonably available to all members and the Mayor and the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Meetings may be held by telephone, electronically, or by other means of communication; provided, that all participants can hear or read the proceeding, vote on the matters discussed, and make comments.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-134" type="History" path="§11">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 10, 43 DCR 1684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-26" type="History">renumbered as § 11, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-161" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-161, § 2(j), 61 DCR 10741</annotation>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">Expiration of Law 11-134</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§2-1215.01">§ 2-1215.01</cite>.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(j) of the  Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-582, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1269, 21 STAT 735).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(j) of the  Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-435, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10717, 20 STAT 4154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997,  44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997,  44 DCR 5054).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-23">D.C. Law 12-23</cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-161">D.C. Law 20-161</cite> rewrote (a); and added (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2280.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
