<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1217.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Assessor” means the Office of Taxation and Revenue, or such other person or office responsible for assessing the value of real property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Authority” means the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Available real property tax revenues” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax provided for in Chapter 8 of Title 47 and payments in lieu of real property taxes, exclusive of the special tax provided for in § <cite path="§1-204.81">1-204.81</cite> and pledged to the payment of general obligation indebtedness of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Available sales tax revenue” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax imposed pursuant to Chapter 20 of Title 47, including any penalties and interest charges, exclusive of the portion thereof required to be deposited in the Washington Convention Center Fund established pursuant to § <cite path="§10-1202.08">10-1202.08</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Capital City Business and Industrial Area” means the area beginning at the intersection of New York Avenue, N.E., and 9th Street, N.E., to Montana Avenue, N.E.; north on Montana Avenue, N.E., to W Street N.E.; west on W Street, N.E., to 13th Street, N.E.; northwest on 13th Street, N.E., to Brentwood Road, N.E.; southwest on Brentwood Road, N.E., to 9th Street, N.E.; south on 9th Street, N.E., to New York Avenue, N.E.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Capital City Market Area” means the area beginning at the intersection of Florida Avenue, N.E., and North Capitol Street; southeast on Florida Avenue, N.E., to 12th Street, N.E.; south on 12th Street, N.E., to H Street, N.E.; west on H Street, N.E., to 9th Street, N.E.; north on 9th Street, N.E., to Florida Avenue, N.E.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Capital improvement” means the same under generally accepted accounting principles.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“CFO” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District as established by § <cite path="§1-204.24a">1-204.24a</cite>(a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Collector” means the District of Columbia Treasurer, or such other person or office as is from time to time responsible for the collection of real property taxes and sales taxes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Comprehensive Plan” means the Comprehensive Plan of the District of Columbia adopted by the Council, as amended from time to time.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10A)</num>
    <text>“Contaminated property” means a property abandoned or underutilized because of perceived or actual contamination by hazardous substances; or when the expansion or redevelopment is complicated by perceived or actual contamination by hazardous substances.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Current assessed value” means for any tax year, the assessed value of each lot of taxable real property within a TIF area as then recorded on the land records of the District as of January preceding the tax year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“DD Regulations” means the Downtown Development District Regulations, 11 DCMR § 1700 et seq. (1995).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Development costs” means any or all of the following costs either actual or estimated for a development project:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Costs of studies, surveys, plans and specifications, including professional service costs for architectural, accounting, engineering, legal, marketing, financial and planning services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Property assembly costs, including acquisition or leasing of land and other property, real or personal, or rights or interests in property, demolition of buildings and other structures, remediation of environmental hazards, and the clearing and grading of land;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Costs of preservation, rehabilitation, reconstruction, repair or remodeling of existing public or private buildings, structures and fixtures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Costs of any public works or improvements undertaken by, or at the direction of the District or any other governmental unit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Costs of parking and transportation facilities, stadia, museums, other cultural institutions, educational institutions, retail, entertainment and recreation facilities, telecommunications infrastructure, public plazas, malls, pedestrian walkways and parks that are owned by the District or any other governmental unit or are privately owned but available for use by the general public;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Costs of construction of new public or privately owned housing units and community facilities and costs of preservation, rehabilitation, reconstruction, repair or remodeling of public and private buildings for use as housing units and community facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Costs of maintaining and operating public works and improvements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>Financing costs, including but not limited to all expenses related to the issuance of TIF bonds, interest on TIF bonds, TIF bond reserves, credit enhancements, and costs related to the performance by the District government of its covenants and agreements with the holders of its TIF bonds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(I)</num>
      <text>Working capital and working capital reserves directly related to the development of a project;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(J)</num>
      <text>Administrative costs of the District in issuing TIF bonds pursuant to this subchapter; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(K)</num>
      <text>Relocation, job training, and education costs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Development sponsor” means any organization or person that seeks to undertake, or undertakes, a project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>“Downtown area” means the area of the District addressed by the Downtown Interactive Task Force, being the area with the boundary commencing at the intersection of Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W. and 12th Street, N.W.; north on 12th Street, N.W., to N Street, N.W.; east on N Street, N.W., to New Jersey Avenue, N.W.; southeast on New Jersey Avenue, N.W., to 2nd Street, N.W.; south on 2nd Street, N.W., to Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W.; and northwest on Pennsylvania Avenue, N.W., to the point of commencement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>“Downtown Report” means the Interactive Downtown Task Force Report.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>“Eligible project” means a project that has been certified by the CFO as complying with the requirements set forth in this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>“Georgia Avenue Area” means any square located on or abutting Georgia Avenue, N.W., beginning at the intersection Florida Avenue, N.W., and north on Georgia Avenue, N.W., to Eastern Avenue, N.W.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>“Gross floor area” means gross floor area within the meaning of the Zoning Regulations of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(21)</num>
    <text>“HPRB” means the District of Columbia Historic Preservation Review Board.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(22)</num>
    <text>“Initial assessed value” means the assessed value of each lot of taxable real property within a tax increment area on the date determined by the Council; provided, that the date shall not be earlier than the date on which the Council initially approves the eligible project within the area for the TIF.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(23)</num>
    <text>“Initial sales tax amount” means  the amount of available sales tax revenues  from locations within the tax increment area in the fiscal year determined by the Council; provided, that the fiscal year shall not be earlier than the fiscal year immediately preceding the fiscal year in which the Council initially approves the eligible project within the area for the TIF.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(24)</num>
    <text>“Priority development area” means the downtown area, Capital City Business and Industrial Area; Capital City Market Area; Georgia Avenue Area; any District-designated Foreign Trade Zones or Free Trade Zones as defined under Federal law; any federally-approved Enterprise Zones, Empowerment Zones, or Enterprise Community; Development Zone Areas; and the Southeast Federal Center/Navy Yard Area; and any housing opportunity area, development area, or new or upgraded commercial center designated on the District of Columbia Generalized Land Use Policies Map that is part of the Comprehensive Plan; the Minnesota Avenue area which shall consist of land within the boundary descriptions beginning from East Capitol Street, N.E., to Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E.; the Dix Street area which shall consist of land within the boundary descriptions beginning from 58th Street, N.E. to Eastern Avenue, N.E.; the Nannie Helen Burroughs area which shall consist of land within the boundary descriptions beginning from Eastern Avenue, N.E., to 49th Street, N.E.; the Pennsylvania Avenue area which shall consist of land within the boundary descriptions beginning from Branch Avenue, S.E., to Carpenter Street, S.E.; and the Benning Road area which shall consist of land within the boundary descriptions beginning from East Capitol Street, S.E., to 44th Street, N.E., from Hanna Place, S.E., to Hillside Road, S.E., and from 39th Street, S.E., to 36th Street, S.E.; the Division Avenue area from Eads Street, N.E., to Hayes Street, N.E.; any block, a portion of which is located in the Uptown Arts-Mixed Use Overlay District, as defined in subsection 1900.1 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (11 DCMR § 1900.1); and the census tracts located in the District for which the poverty rate is not less than 10% as determined on the basis of the 1990 census; and contaminated property areas as defined in paragraph (10A) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(25)</num>
    <text>“Project” means any capital improvement undertaken within the priority development area.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(26)</num>
    <text>“Real property tax increment revenues” means the portion of the available real property tax  revenues allocable to one or more tax allocation funds pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(27)</num>
    <text>“Sales tax increment revenues” means the portion of the available sales tax revenues allocable to one or more tax allocation funds pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(28)</num>
    <text>“Southeast Federal Center/Navy Yard Area” means the area beginning at the intersection of Interstate 395/295 (SW/SE Freeway) and the Anacostia River Waterfront, S.W., northwest to 14th Street, S.W.; south on 14th Street, S.W., to the Washington Channel Waterway; east along the Washington Channel Waterway to the Anacostia River eastern banks and adjacent areas encompassing the public housing and residential parcels adjacent to the Navy Yard, 8th Street, S.W., commercial corridor, marine barracks, Buzzard Point area, northern tip of the Naval station, Poplar Point, Anacostia waterfront, portions of the West Campus of Saint Elizabeth’s, and the area surrounding the Anacostia Metro Station.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(29)</num>
    <text>“Special merits” means other economic, cultural, social, or financial factors, apart from the criteria established in this subchapter, that may justify the approval of TIF for a project. The special merits shall be established, by regulation, by the CFO in consultation with the City Administrator or during a control year, as defined in § <cite path="§47-393">47-393</cite>, the Chief Management Officer (“CMO”), and the Director of the Department of Housing and Economic Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(30)</num>
    <text>“TIF” means tax increment financing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(31)</num>
    <text>“TIF area” means any area designated and established for TIF pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(32)</num>
    <text>“TIF bonds” means bonds, notes or other obligations issued pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-143" type="History">Sept. 11, 1998, D.C. Law 12-143, § 2, 45 DCR 3724</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-271" type="History">Apr. 27, 1999, D.C. Law 12-271, § 2(a), 46 DCR 3615</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-128" type="History">June 24, 2000, D.C. Law 13-128, § 2, 47 DCR 2682</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-312" type="History">June 13, 2001, D.C. Law 13-312, § 705(a), 48 DCR 3804</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-144" type="History">May 22, 2002, D.C. Law 14-144, § 2(a), 49 DCR 3600</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 2082(f), 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">National capital region transportation, funding, Metrorail/Metrobus account, excluded funds, see § <cite path="§9-1111.15">9-1111.15</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1217.33a">2-1217.33a</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1217.34a">2-1217.34a</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1217.71">2-1217.71</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1002">6-1002</cite>, § <cite path="§9-1111.15">9-1111.15</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-857.02">47-857.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2293.1.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-128">D.C. Law 13-128</cite>, in subd. (24), deleted “and” following “36th Street, S.E.;”, added a semicolon following “Hayes Street, N.E.”, and added “; any block, a portion of which is located in the Uptown Arts-Mixed Use Overlay District, as defined in  subsection 1900.1 of Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations ( 11 DCMR § 1900.1); and the census tracts located in the District for which the poverty rate is not less than 10% as determined on the basis of the 1990 census.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-312">D.C. Law 13-312</cite> added par. (10A); and, in par. (24), inserted “; and contaminated property areas as defined in paragraph (10A) of this section”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-144">D.C. Law 14-144</cite>, in par. (22), substituted “on the date determined by the Council; provided, that the date shall not be earlier than the date on which the Council initially approves the eligible project within the area for the TIF” for “on the date the tax increment area is established”; and in par. (23), substituted “the fiscal year determined by the Council; provided, that the fiscal year shall not be earlier than the fiscal year immediately preceding the fiscal year in which the Council initially approves the eligible project within the area for the TIF” for “the calendar year immediately preceding the year in which the tax increment area is established”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in par. (4), substituted “Washington Convention Center Fund” for “Washington Convention Center Authority Fund”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Tax Increment Financing Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-139">D.C. Law 14-139</cite>, May 21, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 5056).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 to 15 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-268">D.C. Law 18-268</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Definitions.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“For the purposes of this act, the term:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) ‘Authorized Delegate’ means the City Administrator, the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, the Chief Financial Officer, the District of Columbia Treasurer, or any officer or employee of the executive office of the Mayor to whom the Mayor has delegated any of the Mayor’s functions under this act pursuant to section 422(6) of the Home Rule Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) ‘Available Real Property Tax Increment Revenues’ means, for any fiscal year of the District, with respect to the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project TIF Area, the revenues resulting in that fiscal year from the imposition of the tax under Chapter 8 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, including any penalties and interest charges, exclusive of the special tax provided for in section 481 of the Home Rule Act, pledged to the payment of general obligation indebtedness of the District, minus those same revenues generated in the Real Property Tax Base Year; provided, that such revenues are not otherwise exclusively committed to another purpose.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) ‘Available Sales Tax Increment Revenues’ means, for any fiscal year of the District, with respect to the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project TIF Area, the revenues resulting in that fiscal year from the imposition of the taxes under Chapters 20 and 22 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code, including any penalties and interest charges, exclusive of the portion thereof required to be deposited in the Washington Convention Center Authority Fund established pursuant to section 208 of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective September 28, 1994 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-188">D.C. Law 10-188</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§10-1202.08">10-1202.08</cite>), minus those same revenues generated in the Sales Tax Base Year; provided, that such revenues are not otherwise exclusively committed to another purpose.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) ‘Available Tax Increment’ means the sum of the Available Sales Tax Increment Revenues and Available Real Property Tax Increment Revenue.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) ‘Bond Counsel’ means a firm or firms of attorneys designated as bond counsel from time to time by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) ‘Bonds’ means the District of Columbia revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, and other obligations), in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) ‘Chairman’ means the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) ‘Chief Financial Officer’ means the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) ‘Closing Documents’ means all documents and agreements, other than Financing Documents, that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the Bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) ‘Council’ means the Council of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(11) ‘Development Agreement’ means the development agreement between the District and the Development Sponsor setting for the terms and conditions upon and pursuant to which the District will issue the Bonds and the Development Sponsor will develop the project.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(12) ‘Development Costs’ shall have the same meaning as in section 2(13) of the Tax Increment Financing Authorization Act of 1998, effective September 11, 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-143">D.C. Law 12-143</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1217.01">2-1217.01</cite>(13)).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(13) ‘Development Sponsor’ means Howard Theatre Restoration, Inc., a District of Columbia corporation, or a designee or assignee of, or successor to, Howard Theatre Restoration, L.L.C., approved by the Mayor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(14) ‘District’ means the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(15) ‘Financing Documents’ means the documents, other than Closing Documents, that relate to the financing or refinancing of transactions to be effected through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the Bonds, including any offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(16) ‘Home Rule Act’ means the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 777; D.C. Official Code § 1-201.01 et seq.).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(17) ‘Howard Theatre Parking Garage’ means parking spaces dedicated for the exclusive use by, and in conjunction with, the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project in Lots 21, 66, 67, 68, 97, 814, 815, 855, 857, 858, and 859, Square 441.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(18) ‘Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project’ means the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of Development Costs incurred for the acquisition, leasing, construction, rehabilitating, installing, and equipping of a new mixed-use facility, consisting of a multi-purpose entertainment venue, museum, restaurant, and educational center within the historic building in Lots 90 and 807, Square 441.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(19) ‘Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project TIF Area’ means the area so designated in section 4.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(20) ‘Real Property Tax Base Year’ means the tax year preceding the year in which this act becomes effective and the initial assessed value to be used in making the determination of Available Real Property Tax Revenues of each lot of taxable real property in the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project TIF Area shall be the assessed value in the tax year preceding the year in which this act becomes effective.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(21) ‘Reserve Agreement’ means that certain Reserve Agreement, dated as of April 1, 2002, by and among the District, Wells Fargo Bank Minnesota, N.A., and Financial Security Assurance, Inc.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(22) ‘Sales Tax Base Year’ means the tax year preceding the year in which this act becomes effective.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(23) ‘TIF’ means tax increment financing.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 3. Creation of the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund, which shall be used solely as provided in subsection (d) of this section. The Chief Financial Officer shall deposit into the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund the Available Tax Increment and any other taxes or fees specifically designated by law for deposit in the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, all funds deposited into the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund, and any interest earned on the funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (d) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Mayor may pledge and create a security interest in the funds in the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund, or any sub-account within the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund, for the payment of the costs of carrying out any of the purposes described in subsection (d) of this section without further action by the Council as permitted by section 490(f) of the Home Rule Act. If Bonds are issued, the payment will be made in accordance with the provisions of the Financing Documents entered into by the District in connection with the issuance of the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The funds deposited in the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund may be used to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Secure the repayment of the Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Pay debt service, including principal, premium, if any, and interest on the Bonds; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Finance, refinance, or reimburse the District or the Development Sponsor for costs of the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) If, at the end of any fiscal year of the District following the issuance of the Bonds authorized by this act, the value of cash and investments in the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Fund exceeds the amount of all payments authorized by this act and the Financing Documents, including required deposits into reserve funds, amounts to be set aside for additional series of Bonds issued under this act, and any coverage requirements associated with the sale of the Bonds, during the upcoming fiscal year, the excess shall be transferred to the General Fund of the District of Columbia, unless the District elects to use the excess to redeem Bonds prior to maturity.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 4. Creation of the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project TIF Area.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“There is hereby established the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project TIF Area, which shall consist of the following real property:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Lot 90, Square 441 (with a street address of 620 T Street, N.W.);</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Lot 807, Square 441 (with a street address of 1830 Wiltberger Street, N.W.); and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Howard Theatre Parking Garage.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 5. Bond authorization.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Council approves and authorizes the issuance of one or more series of Bonds in an aggregate amount not to exceed $4 million to fund costs of the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project, including Development Costs, the financing costs and costs of issuance, capitalized interest, establishment of debt service or other reserve funds related to the Bonds, and any other debt program-related costs as determined by the Chief Financial Officer.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Mayor may pay from the proceeds of the Bonds, the costs and expenses incurred by the District of Columbia in issuing and delivering the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 6. Bond details.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor may take any action reasonably necessary or appropriate in accordance with this act in connection with the preparation, execution, issuance, sale, delivery, security for, and payment of the Bonds of each series, including, but not limited to, determinations of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The final form, content, designation, and terms of the Bonds, including a determination that the Bonds may be issued in certificated or book-entry form;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The principal amount of the Bonds to be issued and denominations of the Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The rate or rates of interest or the method for determining the rate or rates of interest on the Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The date or dates of issuance, sale, and delivery of, and the payment of interest on, the Bonds, and the maturity date or dates of the Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) The terms under which the Bonds may be paid, optionally or mandatorily redeemed, accelerated, tendered, called, or put for redemption, repurchase, or remarketing before their respective stated maturities;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) Provisions for the registration, transfer, and exchange of the Bonds and the replacement of mutilated, lost, stolen, or destroyed Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) The creation of any reserve fund, sinking fund, or other fund with respect to the Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) The time and place of payment of the Bonds;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) Procedures for monitoring the use of the proceeds received from the sale of the Bonds to ensure that the proceeds are properly applied and used to accomplish the purposes of the Home Rule Act and this act;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) Actions necessary to qualify the Bonds under blue sky laws of any jurisdiction where the Bonds are marketed; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(11) The terms and types of credit enhancement under which the Bonds may be secured.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Bonds shall contain a legend, which shall provide that the Bonds are special obligations of the District, are without recourse to the District, are not a pledge of, and do not involve, the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than the Available Tax Increment and any other taxes and fees allocated to the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund), do not constitute a debt of the District, and do not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in section 602(a)(2) of the Home Rule Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Bonds shall be executed in the name of the District and on its behalf by the manual or facsimile signature of the Mayor, and attested by the Secretary of the District of Columbia by the Secretary’s manual or facsimile signature.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The Bonds of any series may be issued in accordance with the terms of a trust instrument to be entered into by the District and a trustee or paying agent to be selected by the Mayor, and may be subject to the terms of one or more agreements entered into by the Mayor pursuant to section 490(a)(4) of the Home Rule Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) The Bonds may be issued at any time or from time to time in one or more issues and in one or more series.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(g) The Bonds are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes. The Bonds, the interest thereon, and the income therefrom, and all funds pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of the Bonds, shall at all times be exempt from taxation by the District, except for estate, inheritance, and gift taxes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(h) The District pledges, covenants, and agrees with the holders of the Bonds that, subject to the provisions of the Financing Documents, the District will not limit or alter the basis on which Available Real Property Tax Increment Revenues or Available Sales Tax Increment Revenues are received, allocated, applied, or pledged, will not impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the Bonds, will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders of the Bonds, and will not modify, in any way, the exemptions from taxation provided for in this act, until the Bonds, together with interest thereon, and all costs and expenses in connection with any suit, action, or proceeding by or on behalf of the holders of the Bonds, are fully met and discharged. This pledge and agreement for the District may be included as part of the contract with the holders of the Bonds. This subsection shall constitute a contract between the District and the holders of the Bonds. To the extent that any acts or resolutions of the Council may be in conflict with this act, this act shall be controlling.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(i) Consistent with section 490(a)(4)(B) of the Home Rule Act and notwithstanding Article 9 of Subtitle I of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) A pledge made and security interest created in respect of the Bonds or pursuant to any related Financing Document shall be valid, binding, and perfected from the time the security interest is created, with or without physical delivery of any funds or any property and with or without any further action;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The lien of the pledge shall be valid, binding, and perfected as against all parties having any claim of any kind in tort, contract, or otherwise against the District, whether or not such party has notice; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The security interest shall be valid, binding, and perfected whether or not any statement, document, or instrument relating to the security interest is recorded or filed.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 7. Issuance of the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Bonds of any series may be sold at negotiated upon terms that the Mayor considers to be in the best interests of the District.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Bonds also may be issued as a TIF note to the Development Sponsor and may be held and used as security for debt incurred or to be incurred by the Development Sponsor, an agent of the Development Sponsor, or another party selected by the Development Sponsor.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Mayor or an Authorized Delegate may execute, in connection with each sale of the Bonds, offering documents on behalf of the District, may deem final any such offering document on behalf of the District for purposes of compliance with federal laws and regulations governing such matters, and may authorize the distribution of the documents in connection with the sale of the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Mayor is authorized to deliver executed and sealed Bonds, on behalf of the District, for authentication, and, after the Bonds have been authenticated, to deliver the Bonds to the original purchasers of the Bonds upon payment of the purchase price.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The Bonds shall not be issued until the Mayor receives an approving opinion from Bond Counsel as to the validity of the Bonds of such series and, if the interest on the Bonds is expected to be exempt from federal income taxation, the treatment of the interest on the Bonds for purposes of federal income taxation.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) The District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 6-85">D.C. Law 6-85</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-301.01">2-301.01</cite> et seq.), and subchapter III of Chapter 3 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code shall not apply to any contract that the Mayor may from time to time enter into, or the Mayor may determine to be necessary or appropriate, for purposes of this act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 8. Payment and security.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Except as may be otherwise provided in this act, the principal of, premium, if any, on, and interest on, the Bonds shall be payable solely from proceeds received from the sale of the Bonds, income realized from the temporary investment of those proceeds, receipts and revenues realized by the District from the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund, income realized from the temporary investment of those receipts and revenues prior to payment to the Bond owners, and other funds that, as provided in the Financing Documents, may be made available to the District for payment of the Bonds from sources other than the District, all as provided for in the Financing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) There is further allocated to the payment of debt service on the Bonds the Available Increment. The Available Increment shall be subordinate to the allocation of Available Increment to the Budgeted Reserve (as defined in the Reserve Agreement and as these terms more fully described in the Reserve Agreement) to the extent that the Reserve Agreement continues to apply to the Available Increment and may be used for the payment of debt service on the Bonds to the extent that the revenues allocated in subsection (a) of this section are inadequate to pay debt service on the Bonds. The allocation of Available Increment authorized by this subsection shall be made in compliance with all existing contractual obligations of the District with respect to the Available Increment and shall terminate on the date on which all of the Bonds are paid or provided for and are no longer outstanding pursuant to their terms.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) Payment of the Bonds shall be secured as provided in the Financing Documents and by an assignment by the District for the benefit of the Bond owners of certain of its rights under the Financing Documents and Closing Documents to the trustee for the Bonds pursuant to the Financing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The trustee or paying agent is authorized to deposit, invest, and disburse the proceeds received from the sale of the Bonds pursuant to the Financing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 9. Financing and Closing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor is authorized to prescribe the final form and content of all Financing Documents and all Closing Documents to which the District is a party that may be necessary or appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Mayor is authorized to execute, in the name of the District and on its behalf, the Financing Documents and any Closing Documents to which the District is a party by the Mayor’s manual or facsimile signature.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) If required, the official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the Bonds, the Financing Documents, and the Closing Documents to which the District is a party.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Mayor’s execution and delivery of the Financing Documents and the Closing Documents shall constitute conclusive evidence of the Mayor’s approval, on behalf of the District, of the final form and content thereof.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The Mayor is authorized to deliver the executed and sealed Financing Documents and Closing Documents, on behalf of the District, prior to or simultaneously with the issuance, sale, and delivery of the Bonds, and to ensure the due performance of the obligations of the District contained in the executed, sealed, and delivered Financing Documents and Closing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 10. Limited liability.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Bonds shall be special obligations of the District. The Bonds shall be without recourse to the District. The Bonds shall not be general obligations of the District, shall not be a pledge of, or involve, the faith and credit or the taxing power of the District (other than the Available Tax Increment and any other taxes or fees allocated to the Howard Theatre Redevelopment Project Fund), shall not constitute a debt of the District, and shall not constitute lending of the public credit for private undertakings as prohibited in section 602(a)(2) of the Home Rule Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Bonds shall not give rise to any pecuniary liability of the District and the District shall have no obligation with respect to the purchase of the Bonds.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) No person, including, but not limited to any Bond owner, shall have any claims against the District or any of its elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents for monetary damages suffered as a result of the failure of the District to perform any covenant, undertaking, or obligation under this act, the Bonds, the Financing Documents, or the Closing Documents, or as a result of the incorrectness of any representation in or omission from the Financing Documents or the Closing Documents, unless the District or its elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents have acted in a willful and fraudulent manner.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 11. District officials.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) Except as otherwise provided in section 10 (c), the elected or appointed officials, officers, employees, or agents of the District shall not be liable personally for the payment of the Bonds or be subject to any personal liability by reason of the issuance of the Bonds, or for any representations, warranties, covenants, obligations, or agreements of the District contained in this act, the Bonds, the Financing Documents, or the Closing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The signature, countersignature, facsimile signature, or facsimile countersignature of any official appearing on the Bonds, the Financing Documents, or the Closing Documents shall be valid and sufficient for all purposes notwithstanding the fact that the individual signatory ceases to hold that office before delivery of the Bonds, the Financing Documents, or the Closing Documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 12. Maintenance of documents.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Copies of the specimen Bonds and of the final Financing Documents and Closing Documents shall be filed in the Office of the Secretary of the District of Columbia.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 13. Information reporting.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Within 3 days after the Mayor’s receipt of the transcript of proceedings relating to the issuance of the Bonds, the Mayor shall transmit a copy of the transcript to the Secretary to the Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 14. Authority of the Chief Financial Officer.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, any action taken by the Mayor to implement the provisions of this act shall be consistent with the Chief Financial Officer’s authority under section 424d of the Home Rule Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 15. Fiscal impact of issuance. For the purposes of determining the fiscal impact of this act, the Bonds shall be deemed to be issued under the authority of the Retail Incentive Act of 2004, effective September 8, 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-185">D.C. Law 15-185</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1217.71">2-1217.71</cite> et seq.), as a project within the 7th Street/Georgia Avenue, N.W., Retail Priority Area established pursuant to the Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution of 2007, effective July 10, 2007 (Res. 17-257;  54 DCR 714).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 17(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-268">D.C. Law 18-268</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of §§ 1-2293.1 to 1-2293.11 1981 Ed., see §§ 2-12 of the Tax Increment Financing Authorization Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-353, May 29, 1998,  45 DCR 3701).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Tax Increment Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-562, January 22, 1999,  46 DCR 2104).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Tax Increment Financing Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-282, February 25, 2002,  49 DCR 2305).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(f) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(f) of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Establishment and Appointments — Task Force on Local, Small, and Disadvantaged Business Opportunity Development, see Mayor’s Order 2002-62, April 19, 2002 ( 49 DCR 3720).</text>
    <text type="Mayor's Orders">Amendment of Mayor’s Order 2002-62, dated 3-19-02, Establishment and Appointments — Task Force on Local, Small and Disadvantaged Business Opportunity Development and Appointment, see Mayor’s Order 2002-92, May 24, 2002 ( 49 DCR 4899).</text>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Transfer of powers, duties, and responsibilities from Chief Financial Officer of the District: Section 30(e)(1) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-144">D.C. Law 12-144</cite> provided that the provisions of this subchapter shall continue in full force and effect provided that the Board of Directors of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation shall exercise all functions of the Chief Financial Officer of the District except the duties under § <cite path="§1-2293.5">1-2293.5</cite> § <cite path="§2-1217.05">2-1217.05</cite>, 2001 Ed. and after the date of notice from the Board to the Chief Financial Officer that the Board is ready to assume such functions.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
