<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1217.09</num>
  <heading>Public inspection.</heading>
  <text>The CFO may cause any bond order to be filed for public inspection and cause to be published in a newspaper of general circulation in the District a notice stating the fact and date of such bond order and the place where such bond order has been filed for public inspection and also the date of the first publication of such notice.  The publication also shall contain a notice that any suit, action, or proceeding of any kind or nature in any court questioning the validity of this subchapter or the validity or proper authorization of TIF bonds provided for by the bond order or the validity of any covenants or agreements provided for by said bond order or any financing document securing the TIF bonds authorized by said bond order shall be commenced within 20 days after the first publication of said notice.  If any such notice shall at any time be published and if no suit, action, or proceeding questioning the validity of this subchapter or the validity or proper authorization of TIF bonds provided for by the bond order referred to in said notice, or the validity of any covenants or agreements provided for by said bond order or any financing documents securing the TIF bonds authorized by said bond order shall be commenced or instituted within 20 days after the first publication of said notice, then all residents, taxpayers, and owners of property in the District and all other persons whatsoever shall be forever barred and foreclosed from instituting or commencing any proceeding, questioning the validity of this subchapter, or the validity or proper authorization of such TIF bonds, or the validity of any such covenants, and agreements, and this subchapter shall be conclusively deemed to have been validly enacted by the District and the CFO shall be conclusively deemed to have been authorized to exercise the powers delegated to the CFO under this subchapter, and said TIF bonds, covenants, and agreements shall be conclusively deemed to be valid and binding obligations of the District as provided in this subchapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-143" type="History" path="§10">Sept. 11, 1998, D.C. Law 12-143, § 10, 45 DCR 3724</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2293.9.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of §§ 1-2293.1 to 1-2293.11 1981 Ed. see note to § 2-1217.01.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
