<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1215.05</num>
  <heading>Review of application.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall have 15 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) from the date of the filing of a BID application to conduct a preliminary review of the application to determine if the filing criteria set forth in § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite> have been met and if the application is otherwise in conformity with this subchapter. If the Mayor fails to make a determination that the BID application is either not in conformity with this subchapter or that the BID application requirements have been met within 15 days (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays), such inaction shall constitute an affirmative preliminary determination that the BID application requirements have been met and the Mayor shall schedule, notify, and hold the required public hearing pursuant to § <cite path="§2-1215.06">2-1215.06</cite>. The Mayor may designate the Department of Small and Local Business Development, or a successor thereto, to perform the review functions described by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If the Mayor determines that any of the BID criteria set forth in § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite>(a), except the provisions of § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite>(a)(1), have not been met or that the BID application is not in conformity with this subchapter, the Mayor shall specify the particular items that need to be corrected and notify the applicant that the application can be corrected and resubmitted within 30 days from the date of this notification. If a corrected BID application is not submitted within the 30-day period, the Mayor shall enter an order rejecting the application. If the Mayor determines that the criteria set forth in § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite>(a)(1) have not been met, the Mayor shall notify the applicant that this standard has not been met and the applicant shall not be eligible to resubmit an application for a period of one year from the initial date of submission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Once the Mayor affirmatively determines that the BID application requirements have been met, the Mayor shall issue a notice of preliminary finding to the applicant and to Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-134" type="History">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 5, 43 DCR 1684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-26" type="History">renumbered as § 6, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-161" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-161, § 2(e), 61 DCR 10741</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1215.06">2-1215.06</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.09">2-1215.09</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.51">2-1215.51</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.56">2-1215.56</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.57">2-1215.57</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.58">2-1215.58</cite>, and § <cite path="§2-1215.59">2-1215.59</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2275.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-161">D.C. Law 20-161</cite> substituted “Department of Small and Local Business Development, or a successor thereto” for “Deputy City Administrator for Business Services and Economic Development” in (a).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-23">D.C. Law 12-23</cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997,  44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997,  44 DCR 5054).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  2(e) of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-435, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10717, 20 STAT 4154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  2(e) of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-582, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1269, 21 STAT 735).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">Expiration of Law 11-134</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1215.01">2-1215.01</cite>.</text>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Expiration of Law</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
