<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1215.06</num>
  <heading>Hearing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall hold a public hearing within 45 days of the issuance of his findings pursuant to § <cite path="§2-1215.05">2-1215.05</cite>(b)(2). The Mayor may designate the Department of Small and Local Business Development, or a successor thereto, to perform the functions described by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notice to the public shall be made no less than 21 days prior to the hearing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall advertise the notice of the public hearing along with the notice of preliminary finding in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No fewer than 21 days before the public hearing, the applicant shall send, by first class mail or electronically, notice of the Mayor’s preliminary determination, notice of the public hearing, including the date, time, and place and availability of the BID application for review, and a summary of the application stating the borders of the proposed BID, the BID plan, and the BID taxes to the following, to the extent reasonably ascertainable:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Secretary to the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Each owner of taxable property within the proposed BID area at the address shown in the most recent real property tax assessment records or, at the election of the applicant, another address if it is reasonably determined that the information in the District’s records is dated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Each commercial tenant within the proposed BID area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Each advisory neighborhood commission in which the proposed BID is located; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Each major citizens association covering the area in which the proposed BID is located.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The BID application shall be made available to the public for review during normal business hours on weekdays in at least one location in the proposed BID area designated by the applicant on a publicly accessible web site and at a generally accessible District government office designated by the Mayor. The notice of the public hearing shall describe these locations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall use the public hearing on the proposed BID to determine whether the BID plan meets the purposes of this subchapter and the definition of BID activity in § <cite path="§2-1215.02">2-1215.02</cite>, and all other BID application requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>Within 10 days after the public hearing (excluding Saturdays, Sundays, and holidays) the Mayor shall either:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Register the BID and the nonprofit corporation that submitted the application under § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite> as the BID corporation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Determine that the BID application requirements have not been met or that the BID plan does not meet the purposes of this subchapter and the definition of BID activity in § <cite path="§2-1215.02">2-1215.02</cite>. The Mayor shall specify the particular items that need to be corrected and notify the applicant that he will have 45 days from the date of this notification within which to correct the BID application.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If a corrected BID application is submitted within the 45-day period, and the Mayor affirmatively determines that the corrected application adequately addresses the items that were included in the Mayor’s notification, the Mayor shall register the BID and the nonprofit corporation that submitted the application under § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite> as the BID corporation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>If a corrected BID application is submitted within the 45-day period, and the Mayor affirmatively determines that the corrected application does not adequately address the particular items needing correction that were included in the Mayor’s notification, the Mayor shall issue an order rejecting the registration. This order shall include the findings of fact upon which it is based.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If a corrected BID application is not submitted within the 45-day period, the Mayor shall issue an order rejecting the registration. This order shall include findings of fact.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>If an order of rejection is not issued within 60 days from the date of the public hearing, the BID and the nonprofit corporation that submitted the application under § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite> shall be deemed registered by the Mayor; except that, if the corrected application under subsection (g) of this section is determined by the Mayor to contain substantial changes, the Mayor may extend the review period for 5 business days. After such time the BID and the nonprofit corporation that submitted the application under § <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite> shall be deemed registered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Proceedings and determinations under the provisions of this subchapter shall not be considered contested cases under Chapter 5 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-134" type="History">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 6, 43 DCR 1684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-26" type="History">renumbered as § 7, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 11(b), 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-161" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-161, § 2(f), 61 DCR 10741</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1215.05">2-1215.05</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.07">2-1215.07</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.09">2-1215.09</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.15">2-1215.15</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.18">2-1215.18</cite>, § <cite path="§2-1215.51">2-1215.51</cite>, and § <cite path="§2-1215.56">2-1215.56</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2276.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-161">D.C. Law 20-161</cite> substituted “Department of Small and Local Business Development, or a successor thereto” for “Deputy City Administrator for Business Services and Economic Development” in (a); rewrote (c) and (d); and added “on a publicly accessible website” in (e).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-23">D.C. Law 12-23</cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997,  44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997,  44 DCR 5054).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(f) of the  Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-435, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10717, 20 STAT 4154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(f) of the  Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-582, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1269, 21 STAT 735).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Expiration of Law</heading>
      <text>Expiration of Law 11-134</text>
      <text>See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1215.01">2-1215.01</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Mayor's Orders</heading>
      <text>Registration of Business Improvement District Pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-134">D.C. Law 11-134</cite>, the “Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996.”: See Mayor’s Order 97-153, September 2, 1997 ( 44 DCR 5258).</text>
      <text>Registration of the Golden Triangle Business Improvement District Pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-134">D.C. Law 11-134</cite>, the “Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996.”: See Mayor’s Order 97-202, December 3, 1997 ( 45 DCR 51).</text>
      <text>Registration of the Georgetown Business Improvement District Pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-134">D.C. Law 11-134</cite>, the “Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996.”: See Mayor’s Order 99-33, February 8, 1999 ( 46 DCR 1205).</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
