<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1215.58</num>
  <heading>Capitol Riverfront BID.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Subject to review and approval by the Mayor under the provisions of §§ <cite path="§2-1215.04">2-1215.04</cite> and <cite path="§2-1215.05">2-1215.05</cite>, the formation of the Capitol Riverfront BID, including taxable property within the geographic area set forth in subsection (b) of this section, is hereby authorized and the BID taxes established in subsection (c) of this section are hereby imposed through the expiration date of this subchapter [May 29, 2016] or the termination or dissolution of the BID.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Capitol Riverfront BID shall be comprised of the geographic area bounded by a line beginning at the intersection of an extension south of the center line of 2nd Street, S.W., and the northern bank of the Anacostia River; continuing north along extension of the center line of 2nd Street, S.W., to the center line of 2nd Street, S.W.; continuing north along the center line of 2nd Street, S.W., to the center line of Q Street, S.W.; continuing east along the center line of Q Street, S.W., to the center line of Half Street, S.W.; continuing north along the center line of Half Street, S.W., to the center line of P Street, S.W.; continuing east along the center line of P Street, S.W., to the center line of South Capitol Street; continuing north along the center line of South Capitol Street to the southern boundary of the Southeast-Southwest Freeway (I-395); continuing southeast along the southern boundary of the Southeast-Southwest Freeway (I-395) to the intersection of an extension south of the center line of 15th Street, S.E.; continuing south along the extension of the center line of 15th Street, S.E., to the northern bank of the Anacostia River; continuing southwest along the northern bank of the Anacostia River to the center line of 2nd Street, S.W.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The BID taxes for the taxable properties in the Capitol Riverfront BID shall be:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>$0.16 per square foot for commercial buildings greater or equal to 8,000 square feet, and $0.09 per $100 of assessed value for commercial buildings less than 8,000 square feet; provided, that the BID tax imposed on any such real property shall not exceed $100,000 annually;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>$120 per unit for residential units annually;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>$95 per hotel room annually;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>$0.16 per square foot for land or buildings with existing active industrial, utility, or storage use;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>$0.08 per square foot for real property within the new proposed Frederick Douglass Memorial Bridge right-of-way; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>$0.36 per square foot for unimproved land that is up to 88,000 square feet, $0.065 per square foot for unimproved land that is 88,000 to 200,000 square feet, and $0.18 per square foot for unimproved land that is greater than 200,000 square feet; provided, that the BID tax imposed on any such unimproved land shall not exceed $100,000 annually.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To the extent that a building that is subject to the BID tax is constructed pursuant to a ground lease on land that is exempt from real property taxes, the assessed value of the real property for purposes of the BID tax shall include the value of the building and the leasehold interest, possessory interest, beneficial interest, or beneficial use of the land, and the lessee or user of the land shall be assessed the corresponding BID tax, which shall be a personal liability of the lessee. Delinquencies shall be collected in the same manner as possessory interest taxes under § <cite path="§47-1005.01">47-1005.01</cite> or as otherwise provided in this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A 5% annual increase in the BID taxes over the current tax year rates specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection is authorized subject to the requirements of § <cite path="§2-1215.08">2-1215.08</cite>(b).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the real property located in Square 770, Lot 802, designated as the DOT PILOT Area under the DOT Pilot Revision Emergency Approval Resolution of 2006, effective October 18, 2006 (Res. 16-845; 53 DCR 8970), shall be deemed a taxable property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-134" type="History">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 208</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-27" type="History">as added Oct. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-27, § 2(c), 54 DCR 8020</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, §§ 179, 219, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-161" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-161, § 2, 59 DCR 5704</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-161" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-161, § 2(w), 61 DCR 10741</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§47-857.11">47-857.11</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in subsec. (c)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-161">D.C. Law 19-161</cite> rewrote subsec. (c)(1), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c)(1) The BID taxes for the nonexempt real properties in the Capitol Riverfront BID shall be:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(A) The amount of $0.09 per $100 of the assessed value of real property containing less than 50,000 square feet of gross building area;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(B) The amount of $0.04 per $100 of the assessed value of land and buildings which have a certificate of occupancy or other District license indicating that the land or building has an existing active industrial, utility, or storage use;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(C) The amount of $0.02 per $100 of assessed value of land and buildings located, in whole or in part, within the right-of-way for the realignment of the Frederick Douglass Memorial Bridge;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(D) The amount of $0.12 per square foot of commercial buildings containing 50,000 square feet of gross building area or more; provided, that the BID tax imposed on any such real property shall not exceed $75,000 annually;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(E) The amount of $72 per hotel room annually; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(F) The amount of $96 per unit annually for nonexempt residential properties; provided, that if a residential unit is restricted to residents based upon income pursuant to a federal or District affordable housing program, the BID tax due on the unit shall be computed by applying the percentage of area median income that an eligible household must meet to participate in the affordable housing program for the unit to the amount of the BID tax which would otherwise be due.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-161">D.C. Law 20-161</cite> substituted “taxable” for “nonexempt real” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2(c) of Capitol Riverfront Business Improvement District Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-78, July 27, 2007,  54 DCR 7631).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(w) of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-435, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10717, 20 STAT 4154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(w) of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-582, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1269, 21 STAT 735).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
