<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1226.03</num>
  <heading>Workforce intermediary.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall use a workforce intermediary as the primary means of meeting the hiring requirements of § <cite path="§2-1226.02">2-1226.02</cite>(a)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If prior to July 20, 2007, the former AWC has selected an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary, the Mayor shall continue to use the organization or organizations as a workforce intermediary; provided, that the Mayor may select additional organizations and may terminate the use of the organization or organizations selected by the former AWC.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If prior to July 20, 2007, the former AWC has not selected an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary, then by August 20, 2007, the Mayor shall issue a request for proposals designed to select an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary. Within 120 days after issuing the request for proposals, the Mayor shall select an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “workforce intermediary” means an entity established or chosen by the Mayor, or the former AWC, that is modeled on similar, successful entities in other cities and is designed to meet the hiring goals of § <cite path="§2-1226.02">2-1226.02</cite>(a)(2) by coordinating the needs and capacities of businesses that are creating new jobs in the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone, workforce development organizations that serve residents of the District, and residents of the District who are seeking jobs in the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-138" type="History" path="§403">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 403, 55 DCR 1689</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1225.21">2-1225.21</cite> and § <cite path="§2-1226.02">2-1226.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-55">D.C. Law 19-55</law-cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Establishment of Workforce Intermediary Task Force.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a)(1) By November 1, 2011, the Mayor shall establish a Workforce Intermediary Task Force (”Task Force“) to review best practices for workforce intermediary programs.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Task Force shall review similar programs implemented by the governments of Boston, Minneapolis, San Francisco, and any other cities that have implemented similar programs.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) By January 15, 2012, the Task Force shall recommend to the Mayor and the Council a Workforce Intermediary Program (‘Program’) for the District. The recommendation shall include a review of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The industries, in addition to the construction industry, that should be a focal point of the Program because they are frequently required to enter into first source agreements;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) What would be a reasonable operating budget for the Program, including a cap on administrative costs;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) What would be a reasonable funding mechanism for the Program;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) How the Program would collaborate with multiple District government agencies and community-based organizations to serve job-ready residents as well as residents needing job-training services or adult basic education services;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) The specific performance metrics that should be used to assess the performance of the Program’s process and outcomes;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) The baseline data that would be needed to isolate, to the fullest extent possible, the effects of the Program;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(G) The type of governance structure that would work best for establishing the Program and for the ongoing operations of the Program; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(H) What programmatic and statutory recommendations would be necessary regarding how the Program will interact with the District’s First Source Register program.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b)(1) The recommendations shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. Upon receipt of the recommendations, the Council shall hold a public roundtable or hearing. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the recommendations, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 45-day review period, the recommendations shall be deemed disapproved.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) If the recommendations are disapproved by the Council, the Council’s Committee on Housing and Workforce Development shall transmit a report to the Task Force citing the Council’s concerns and the Task Force shall have 30 days to review the report and re-submit its new recommendations to the Mayor and the Council for approval pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Task Force shall consist of the following 17 members:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The Mayor, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Chairman of the Council, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Chairman of the Council’s Committee on Housing and Workforce Development, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The Director of the Department of Employment Services;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) The Executive Director of the Workforce Investment Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) Two members of the District business community who represent industries that are frequently subject to first source agreements, appointed by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) Two members of the District business community who represent industries that are frequently subject to first source agreements, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) A representative of a District job training or education provider, appointed by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) A representative of a District job training or education provider, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(11) Two representatives of organized labor, appointed by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(12) A representative of organized labor, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(13) A representative of the District philanthropic community or an organization focused on workforce development research, appointed by the Mayor; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(14) A representative of the District philanthropic community or an organization focused on workforce development research, appointed by the Chairman of the Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Mayor and the Chairman of the Council shall serve as co-chairs of the Task Force.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The director of each District agency and instrumentality that engages in capital construction shall advise and assist the Task Force.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-55">D.C. Law 19-55</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</law-cite>, § 404, added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 404. Workforce intermediary.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Mayor shall use the workforce intermediary as the primary means of meeting the hiring requirements of section 403(a)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b)(1) If prior to July 20, 2007, the former AWC has selected an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary, the Mayor shall continue to use the organization or organizations as a workforce intermediary; provided, that the Mayor may select additional organizations and may terminate the use of the organization or organizations selected by the former AWC.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) If prior to July 20, 2007, the former AWC has not selected an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary, then within 30 days after July 20, 2007, the Mayor shall issue a request for proposals designed to select an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary. Within 120 days after issuing the request for proposals, the Mayor shall select an organization or organizations to serve as a workforce intermediary.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) For the purposes of this section, the term ‘workforce intermediary’ means an entity established by the Mayor or the former AWC and modeled on similar, successful entities in other cities, to meet the hiring goals of section 403(a)(2) by coordinating the needs and capacities of businesses that are creating new jobs in the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone, workforce development organizations that serve residents of the District, and residents of the District who are seeking jobs in the Anacostia Waterfront Development Zone.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 702(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 404 of National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-71, July 20, 2007,  54 DCR 7390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 404 of National Capitol Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-152, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10900).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Workforce Intermediary Task Force Establishment Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-131, August 2, 2011,  58 DCR 6789).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Workforce Intermediary Task Force Establishment Second Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-167, October 11, 2011,  58 DCR 8900).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
