<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1225.42</num>
  <heading>Further exercise of eminent domain at Skyland Shopping Center.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council affirms the findings made in section 2 of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation Eminent Domain Clarification and Skyland Eminent Domain Approval Amendment Act of 2004, effective April 5, 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-286">D.C. Law 15-286</cite>; 52 DCR 859) (“Skyland Eminent Domain Act”).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may exercise eminent domain in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter II of Chapter 13 of Title 16 to acquire properties in the Skyland Eminent Domain Area for the purpose of redeveloping the Skyland Shopping Center in order to achieve the public purposes set forth in section 2(a)(15) of the Skyland Eminent Domain Act.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “Skyland Eminent Domain Area” means: Square 5632, Lot 1; Square 5632, Lot 3; Square 5632, Lot 4; Square 5632, Lot 5; Square 5632, Lot 802; Square 5633, Lot 800; Square 5633, Lot 801; Square 5641, Lot 0010; Square 5641, Lot 0011; Square 5641, Lot 0012; Square 5641, Lot 0013; Square 5641, Lot 0819; Square 5641N, Lot 0012; Square 5641N, Lot 0013; Square 5641N, Lot 0014; Square 5641N, Lot 0015; Square 5641N, Lot 0016; Square 5641N, Lot 0017; Square 5641N, Lot 0018; Square 5641N, Lot 0019; Square 5641N, Lot 0020; Square 5641N, Lot 0021; Square 5641N, Lot 0022; Square 5641N, Lot 0023; Square 5641N, Lot 0024; Square 5641N, Lot 0025; Square 5641N, Lot 0026; Square 5641N, Lot 0027; Square 5641N, Lot 0028; Square 5641N, Lot 0029; Square 5641N, Lot 0030; Square 5641N, Lot 0031; Square 5641N, Lot 0033; Parcel 02130052; Parcel 02130060; Parcel 02130061; Parcel 02140062; Parcel 02140088; Parcel 02140104; Parcel 02140182; Parcel 02140187; Parcel 02140189; Parcel 02140190; Parcel 02140196; and any other parcel or property located within the geographic area bounded by a line beginning at a point at the intersection of the northerly line of Good Hope Road, S.E., with the northerly line of Alabama Avenue, S.E., and running northwesterly along said line of Good Hope Road, S.E., extended, to intersect a point on the east line of Naylor Road, S.E.; thence northwesterly along said line of Naylor Road to a point at the northwesterly corner of Lot 801 in Square 5633; thence northeasterly along the northerly line of said lot and square to a point at the westernmost corner of Parcel 213/52; thence continuing northeasterly along the northerly line of said Parcel 213/52 to a point at the southwesterly corner of Parcel 213/60; thence northwesterly along the arc of a curve, deflecting to the right, along the westerly line of said Parcel 213/60 to a point at the northernmost corner of said Parcel 213/60; thence southeasterly along the easterly lines of said Parcels 213/60 and 213/52 to a point at the northwesterly corner of Lot 33 in Square North of Square 5641; thence easterly along the north property lines of said Lot 33 and Lots 16 through 31, both inclusive, in Square north of Square 5641 to a point at the northeast corner of said Lot 31 in said square; thence south along the east line of said Lot 31 in said square to a point at the southeast corner thereof; thence westerly along the south lines of said Lots 31, 30, 29, 28, 27, 26, 25, 24, 23 and 22 in said square to a point at the southwest corner of said Lot 22 to intersect a line drawn northwesterly from the northeast corner of Lot 12 in Square North of Square 5641; thence southeasterly along said line drawn and the east line of said Lot 12 in said square to a point at the southeast corner thereof to a point that intersects a line drawn northwesterly from the northeast corner of Lot 13 in Square 5641; thence southeasterly along said line drawn and the east line of said Lot 13 in said square to a point at the southeast corner thereof; thence southwesterly along the south property lines of Lots 13 and 12 in Square 5641 to a point that intersects a line drawn northwesterly from the northeast corner of Lot 819 in Square 5641; thence southeasterly along said line drawn and the east line of said Lot 819 in said square to a point at the southeast corner of said Lot 819 in said square, on the north line of Alabama Avenue, S.E.; and thence southwesterly along the arc of a circle deflecting to the right along said line of Alabama Avenue, to the point of beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-138" type="History">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 602, 55 DCR 1689</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 2032 to 2036 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 2032 to 2036 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 2 of the Skyland Eminent Domain Act, referred to in subsections (a) and (b), is <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-286">D.C. Law 15-286</cite>, § 2, noted in § <cite path="§2-1219.19">2-1219.19</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
