<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1210.08</num>
  <heading>District’s rights with respect to reserve accounts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited in a reserve account shall be the property of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The District shall earn interest on the amount of contributions made by the District, the borrower, and the financial institution to a reserve account. The District shall withdraw monthly or quarterly from a reserve account the amount of the interest earned by the District and shall deposit the amount withdrawn into the Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the amount in a reserve account exceeds 33% of the balance of the financial institution’s outstanding enrolled loans, the Mayor may withdraw the excess amount and deposit the amount in the Fund. A withdrawal of money under this subsection shall not reduce an active reserve account to an amount that is less than $200,000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District shall withdraw from a reserve account the total amount in the account, including any interest earned on the account, and deposit the amount in the Fund when:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A financial institution is no longer eligible to participate in the program or a participation agreement entered into under this subchapter expires without renewal by the financial institution;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The financial institution has no outstanding enrolled loans;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The financial institution has not made a capital access loan within the preceding 24 months; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The financial institution fails to submit a report or other document requested by the District within the time or in the manner prescribed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-322" type="History" path="§9">Mar. 12, 2011, D.C. Law 18-322, § 9, 57 DCR 12442</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 9 of Capital Access Program Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-598, November 17, 2010,  57 DCR 11018).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 9 of Capital Access Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-6, February 11, 2011,  58 DCR 1408).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
