<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1217.31</num>
  <heading>Gallery Place Project tax and fee abatements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Development Sponsor” means Gallery Place Holdings LLC, a Delaware limited liability company, and its successors and assigns.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Gallery Place Project” means the acquisition, construction, installing, and equipping of a mixed-use complex located on Square 454, Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877, 878; the portion of the public alley that reverted to former Lot 820 (which is currently known as Lot 866), and former Lot 821 (which is currently known as Lot 867) pursuant to the Plat of Alley Closing filed with the Surveyor of the District of Columbia in Liber 17 at folio 74; and the portions of the public alley that will revert to Lots 41, 824, 838, 857, 877 and 878, all in Square 454, pursuant to the alley closing approved by the Closing of Public Alleys in Square 454 and Square 455, S.O. 98-194, Act of 1999, effective October 22, 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-48">D.C. Law 13-48</cite>; 46 DCR 6768), and consisting of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An approximately 60,000-square-foot multiplex cinema;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A mixed-use facility providing for retail stores, dining, entertainment, a health and fitness club, offices, and related facilities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A market-rate housing complex consisting of approximately 170 residential units;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A parking garage containing approximately 850 parking spaces; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Other ancillary improvements.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All fees to be paid, and any deposits to be made, by or on behalf of the Development Sponsor in connection with the Gallery Place Project under § <cite path="§6-661.01">6-661.01</cite> are hereby waived.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The amount of all taxes, fees, and deposits exempt, abated, or waived under subsection (b) of this section, §§ <cite path="§45-922">45-922</cite>(24), <cite path="§47-902">47-902</cite>(17), <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>(26), and <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>(32), shall not exceed, in the aggregate, $7 million.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>In accordance with § <cite path="§9-401.06">9-401.06</cite> providing a permanent form of government for the District of Columbia the Mayor shall expend up to $2 million to improve and repair the streets, sewers, alleys, sidewalks, curbs, and gutters abutting the Gallery Place Project. All assessments upon abutting property for the cost of improvements to such streets, sewers, alleys, sidewalks, curbs, and gutters, including any expenses of assessment, shall be waived.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-241" type="History" path="§2">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-241, § 2, 48 DCR 610</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-213" type="History">Oct. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-213, § 40, 49 DCR 8140</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">The subpart heading was added by the Codification Counsel as part of the codification of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-110">D.C. Law 20-110</cite>, §§ <cite path="§21-211">21-211</cite> as Subpart 5 of this part.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§42-1102">42-1102</cite>, § <cite path="§47-902">47-902</cite>, § <cite path="§47-1002">47-1002</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-2005">47-2005</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
