<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1225.01</num>
  <heading>Dissolution of the boards of directors.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of Directors of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation (“NCRC”) and the Board of Directors of the RLA Revitalization Corporation (“RLARC”), established by §§ <cite path="§2-1219.01">2-1219.01</cite> [repealed] and 2-1219.31 [repealed], respectively, are dissolved. The Mayor shall succeed to the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the boards of directors of the NCRC and the RLARC.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Board of Directors of the Anacostia Waterfront Corporation (“AWC”), established by § <cite path="§2-1223.05">2-1223.05</cite> [repealed], and the boards of directors of its subsidiaries, the Southwest Waterfront Development Corporation (“SWDC”) and the Southwest Waterfront Holdings Corporation (“SWHC”), are dissolved. The Mayor shall succeed to the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the board of directors of the AWC and its subsidiaries.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-138" type="History">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 101, 55 DCR 1689</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</cite>, § 101, added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 101. Dissolution of the boards of directors.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The Board of Directors of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation (‘NCRC’) and the Board of Directors of the RLA Revitalization Corporation (‘RLARC’), established by sections 4 and 30a, respectively, of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation Act of 1998, effective September 11, 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-144">D.C. Law 12-144</cite>; D.C. Official Code §§ <cite path="§2-1219.03">2-1219.03</cite> and <cite path="§2-1219.31">2-1219.31</cite>), are dissolved. The Mayor shall succeed to the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the boards of directors of the NCRC and the RLARC.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) The Board of Directors of the Anacostia Waterfront Corporation (‘AWC’), established by section 105 of the Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Act of 2004, effective December 7, 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-219">D.C. Law 15-219</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1223.05">2-1223.05</cite>), and the boards of directors of its subsidiaries (the Southwest Waterfront Development Corporation (‘SWDC’) and the Southwest Waterfront Holdings Corporation (‘SWHC’)) are dissolved. The Mayor shall succeed to the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the boards of directors of the AWC and its subsidiaries.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 702(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101 of National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-71, July 20, 2007,  54 DCR 7390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 101 of National Capitol Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-152, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10900).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority—National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Act of 2007, see Mayor’s Order 2008-137, October 20, 2008 ( 55 DCR 12507).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Mayor's Orders">Registration of the Capitol Riverfront Business Improvement District Pursuant to the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-134">D.C. Law 11-134</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1215.01">2-1215.01</cite> et seq. (2006 Supp.)), see Mayor’s Order 2007-183, August 8, 2007 ( 54 DCR 11619).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 801 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-138">D.C. Law 17-138</cite> provided: “This act shall sunset on September 30, 2008, if the fiscal effect of this act has not been included in an approved budget and financial plan.”</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">According to the Budget Director to the Council of the District of Columbia, <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-138">D.C. Law 17-138</cite> was funded under D.C. Act 17-409.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 305(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> repealed section 801 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-138">D.C. Law 17-138</cite>. Section 305(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> provided that the section shall apply as of September 29, 2009.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
