<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1217.35a</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this subpart, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Authorized Delegate” means the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, the Chief Financial Officer, the Treasurer, or any officer, or employee of the executive office of the Mayor to whom the Mayor has delegated any of the Mayor’s functions under this subpart pursuant to § <cite path="§1-204.22">1-204.22</cite>(6).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Available Increment” shall have the same meaning as set forth in the Reserve Agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Available Real Property Tax Revenues” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax provided for in Chapter 8 of Title 47, inclusive of any penalties and interest charges, exclusive of the special tax provided for in § <cite path="§1-204.81">1-204.81</cite> pledged to payment of general obligation indebtedness of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Available Sales Tax Revenues” means the revenues resulting from the imposition of the tax provided for in Chapter 20 of Title 47, including penalty and interest charges, exclusive of the portion thereof required to be deposited in the Washington Convention Center Fund established pursuant to § <cite path="§10-1202.08">10-1202.08</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Available Tax Increment” means the sum of the Available Sales Tax Revenues and Available Real Property Tax Revenues generated in the Skyland TIF Area in any fiscal year of the District minus the sum of Available Sales Tax Revenues and Available Real Property Tax Revenues generated in the Skyland TIF Area in the base year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Bond Counsel” means a firm or firms of attorneys designated as bond counsel from time to time by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Bonds” means the District of Columbia revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations (including refunding bonds, notes, and other obligations), in one or more series, authorized to be issued pursuant to this subpart.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“CBE Agreement” means an agreement governing certain obligations of the Developer under subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of this title [§ <cite path="§2-218.01">2-218.01</cite> et seq.], including the equity and development participation requirements set forth in § <cite path="§2-218.49a">2-218.49a</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Certified Business Enterprise” means a business enterprise or joint venture certified pursuant to subchapter IX-A of Chapter 2 of this title [§ <cite path="§2-218.01">2-218.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Chairman” means the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Chief Financial Officer” means the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia established by § <cite path="§1-204.24">1-204.24</cite>(a)(1).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Closing Documents” means all documents and agreements, other than Financing Documents, that may be necessary and appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver the Bonds, and includes agreements, certificates, letters, opinions, forms, receipts, and other similar instruments.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Council” means the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Debt Service” means principal, premium, if any, and interest on the Bonds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“Developer” means Skyland Holdings, LLC, a Delaware limited liability company, with a business address of 8405 Greensboro Drive, Suite 830, McLean, VA 22102-5121, or its successor, or one of its affiliates or assignees approved by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>“Development Costs” has the same meaning as in § <cite path="§2-1217.01">2-1217.01</cite>(13).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>“Development Sponsor” means Skyland Holdings, LLC, a District of Columbia limited liability company, or any other entity that undertakes the development of the project with the approval of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(18)</num>
    <text>“Financing Documents” means the documents, other than Closing Documents, that relate to the financing or refinancing of transactions to be effected through the issuance, sale, and delivery of the Bonds, including any offering document, and any required supplements to any such documents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(19)</num>
    <text>“First Source Agreement” means an agreement with the District governing certain obligations of the Developer pursuant to § <cite path="§2-219.03">2-219.03</cite>, and Mayor’s Order 83-265, dated November 9, 1983, regarding job creation and employment generated as a result of the construction on the Property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(20)</num>
    <text>“Home Rule Act” means Chapter 2 of Title 1 [§ 1-201.01 et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(21)</num>
    <text>“Project” means the financing, refinancing, or reimbursing of Development Costs incurred for the acquisition, construction, installing, and equipping of a mixed-use project consisting of retail and residential space, and parking in the Skyland TIF Area.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(22)</num>
    <text>“Property” means the real property known as the Skyland Shopping Center and adjacent parcels, including any area within public alleys as hereinafter closed, and known for tax and assessment purposes as Square 5632, Lot 0001; Square 5632, Lot 0003; Square 5632, Lot 0004; Square 5632, Lot 0005; Square 5632, Lot 0802; Square 5633, Lot 0800; Square 5633, Lot 0801; Square 5641, Lot 0010; Square 5641, Lot 0011; Square 5641, Lot 0012; Square 5641, Lot 0013; Square 5641, Lot 0819; Square 5641N, Lot 0012; Square 5641N, Lot 0013; Square 5641N, Lot 0014; Square 5641N, Lot 0015; Square 5641N, Lot 0016; Square 5641N, Lot 0017; Square 5641N, Lot 0018; Square 5641N, Lot 0019; Square 5641N, Lot 0020; Square 5641N, Lot 0021; Square 5641N, Lot 0022; Square 5641N, Lot 0023; Square 5641N, Lot 0024; Square 5641N, Lot 0025; Square 5641N, Lot 0026; Square 5641N, Lot 0027; Square 5641N, Lot 0028; Square 5641N, Lot 0029; Square 5641N, Lot 0030; Square 5641N, Lot 0031; Square 5641N, Lot 0033; Parcel 0213/0052; Parcel 0213/0060; Parcel 0213/0061; Parcel 0214/0062; Parcel 0214/0088; Parcel 0214/0104; Parcel 0214/0182; Parcel 0214/0187; Parcel 0214/0189; Parcel 0214/0190; and Parcel 0214/0196.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(23)</num>
    <text>“Reserve Agreement” means that certain Reserve Agreement, dated as of April 1, 2002, by and among the District, Wells Fargo Bank Minnesota, N.A., and Financial Security Assurance, Inc.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(24)</num>
    <text>“TIF” means tax increment financing.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-110" type="History">June 21, 2014, D.C. Law 20-110, § 101, 61 DCR 4315</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
