<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1215.13</num>
  <heading>Annual report of BID corporation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board of each BID corporation shall file an annual report with the Mayor and the Council in compliance with subsection (b) of this section and financial statements with the CFO in compliance with subsection (c) of this section in such forms and at such times as are prescribed by regulations promulgated under this subchapter. The requirement for filing of an annual report shall commence in the first full fiscal year after BID registration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each annual report shall include, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A financial statement for the preceding year, including a balance sheet, statement of income and loss, and such other information as is reasonably necessary to reflect the BID’s actual financial performance. Such statements shall be certified by the treasurer of the BID corporation and shall be prepared on a cash basis or an accrual basis in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles consistently applied;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A proposed operating budget for the then current fiscal year; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A narrative statement or chart showing the results of operations in comparison to stated goals and objectives.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each financial statement package submitted to the CFO shall include, at a minimum, a financial statement, budget, and narrative statement in the same form as required by subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A copy of each annual report shall be sent to the Council, to any Advisory Neighborhood Commission in which any portion of the BID is located, and to all members in the BID, in each case by first class mail, personal delivery, or electronically. Annual reports shall also be posted on BID websites.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In connection with the filing of each annual report, each BID corporation shall allow its books and records to be open for inspection by the Mayor, the CFO, and the Council during reasonable working hours for such period of time as is prescribed by regulations promulgated under this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-134" type="History" path="§14">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 13, 43 DCR 1684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-26" type="History">renumbered as § 14, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-161" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-161, § 2(l), 61 DCR 10741</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2283.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-161">D.C. Law 20-161</law-cite> substituted “mail, personal delivery, or electronically. Annual reports shall also be posted on BID websites” for “mail or by personal delivery” in (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 12-23">D.C. Law 12-23</law-cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997,  44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997,  44 DCR 5054).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(l) of the  Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-435, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10717, 20 STAT 4154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(l) of the  Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-582, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1269, 21 STAT 735).</annotation>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">Expiration of Law 11-134</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1215.01">2-1215.01</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
