<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1217.73</num>
  <heading>Retail Priority Areas.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall identify areas within the District where:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>There exist barriers to entry that impede Retail Development Projects; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The proceeds of Bonds may be used to eliminate these barriers to entry and promote Retail Development Projects.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The Mayor may designate additional Retail Priority Areas by submitting to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding weekends, holidays, and periods of Council recess, a proposed resolution, which:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Designates one or more Retail Priority Areas;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>States the maximum aggregate principal amount of Bonds that may be issued with respect to each Retail Priority Area; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>States the latest date by which the Bonds may be issued with respect to each Retail Priority Area.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>In addition to the resolution, the Mayor shall submit to the Council information supporting the Mayor’s determinations concerning the use of TIF to promote retail development in each Retail Priority Area, including findings of the CFO that the proposed Retail Priority Area is not inconsistent with the financial plan and budget for the fiscal year of the District and does not exceed the limitations set forth in <cite path="§2-1217.72|(a)">§ 2-1217.72(a)</cite>.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed resolution within the 45-day period of review, excluding weekends, holidays, and periods of Council recess, the proposed resolution shall be deemed approved.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to Retail Priority Areas that may be approved pursuant to subsection (a) of this section:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Downtown Retail Priority Area is designated as a Retail Priority Area;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The issuance of Bonds with respect to the Downtown Retail Priority Area, not to exceed the aggregate principal amount of $25 million, is approved;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The latest date for the issuance of such Bonds is September 30, 2015; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The base year for the calculation of Available Sales Tax Revenues shall be the fiscal year beginning October 1, 2002 and the base year for the calculation of Available Real Property Tax Revenues shall be the fiscal year beginning October 1, 2003.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b-1)</num>
    <text>The maximum aggregate principal amount of bonds that may be issued with respect to the Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E., Retail Priority Area, approved by the Council in section 3(6) of the Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution of 2007, effective July 10, 2007 (Res. 17-257; 54 DCR 7194), is increased from $10 million to $15 million.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall prepare and deliver an annual report to the Council each year on January 1st through the year ending September 30, 2015. The annual report shall contain a listing and description of each Retail Development Project approved as a TIF Area pursuant to this subchapter. Each listing shall contain specific information about the nature of the Retail Development Project, the use of the proceeds of the Bonds, the projected Tax Increment Revenues attributable to each listed TIF Area, and any other information the Council may request regarding such TIF Areas.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor determines that a Retail Priority Area is no longer necessary, the Mayor may abolish the Retail Priority Area; provided, that if any Bonds are outstanding with respect to any TIF Area therein, the Mayor shall take no action to abolish the Retail Priority Area or that otherwise will adversely affect the security of the holders of the Bonds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall identify potential Retail Priority Areas. Within 180 days of September 8, 2004, the Mayor shall submit to the Council resolutions designating as Retail Priority Areas the following areas:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Columbia Heights;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Georgia Avenue;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Minnesota/Benning;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Shaw; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>H Street, NE Corridor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>There is established the Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following area: Beginning at the intersection of Fourth Street, N.E., and Franklin Street, N.E.; thence east on Franklin Street NE to 15th Street, N.E.; thence north on 15th Street, N.E., to Girard Street, N.E.; thence east on Girard Street, N.E., to 17th Street, N.E.; thence north on 17th Street, N.E., to Brentwood Road, N.E.; thence northeast on Brentwood Road N.E., to 18th Street, N.E.; thence north on 18th Street, N.E., to Irving Street, N.E.; thence east on Irving Street, N.E., to Rhode Island Avenue, N.E.; thence north along the western boundary of the property at the northeast corner of 20th Street, N.E., and Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., to its northwest corner; thence northeast along the rear boundaries of all properties with frontage along the north side of Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., to the northeast corner of the property at the northwest corner of Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., and Eastern Avenue, N.E.; thence southeast along the eastern boundary of property at the corner of Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., and Eastern Avenue, N.E., to its southeast corner; thence continuing southeast to the southeast corner of the property at the southwest corner of Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., and Eastern Avenue, N.E.; thence southwest along the rear boundaries of all properties with frontage along the south side of Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., to Montana Avenue, N.E.; thence southeast along Montana Avenue, N.E., to Downing Street, N.E.; thence southwest along Downing Street, N.E., to Bryant Street, N.E.; thence west along Bryant Street, N.E., to 13th Street, N.E.; thence southeast along 13th Street, N.E., to its end at W Street, N.E.; thence west along a line extending W Street, N.E., west to the continuation of W Street, N.E., and continuing west along W Street, N.E., to Brentwood Road, N.E.; thence southwest along Brentwood Road, N.E., to its end at T Street, N.E.; thence southwest to the intersection of a line extending Fourth Street, N.E., south and a line extending R Street, N.E., east; thence north along line extending Fourth Street, N.E., to Fourth Street, N.E., and continuing north along Fourth Street, N.E., to the point of beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>There is established the Bladensburg Road, N.E., Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following area: Beginning at the intersection of Holbrook Street, N.E., and Mount Olivet Road, N.E.; thence east on Mount Olivet Road, N.E., to Bladensburg Road, N.E.; thence south on Bladensburg Road, N.E., to 17th Street, N.E.; thence south on 17th Street, N.E., to H Street, N.E.; thence east on H Street, N.E., to 19th Street, N.E.; thence south on 19th Street, N.E., to Benning Road, N.E.; thence east on Benning Road, N.E. to Oklahoma Avenue, N.E.; thence southwest on Oklahoma Avenue, N.E. to Clagett Place, N.E.; thence northwest on Clagett Place, N.E. to 20th Street, N.E.; thence northwest along the rear boundaries of all properties with frontage along the southwest side of Benning Road, N.E. to 19th Street, N.E.; thence south on 19th Street, N.E. to Gales Street, N.E.; thence northwest on Gales Street, N.E. to 15th Street, N.E.; thence west on G Street, N.E. to 14th Street, N.E.; thence north on 14th Street, N.E. to Florida Avenue, N.E.; thence west on Florida Avenue, N.E., to Holbrook Street, N.E.; thence north on Holbrook Street, N.E., to the point of beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>There is established the North Capitol Street Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following area: Beginning at the intersection of New York Avenue, N.W., and First Street, N.W.; thence north along First Street, N.W., to Florida Avenue, N.W.; thence northwest along Florida Avenue, N.W., to Second Street, N.W.; thence north along Second Street, N.W., to Rhode Island Avenue, N.W.; thence northeast along Rhode Island Avenue, N.W., to First Street, N.W.; thence north along First Street, N.W., to Michigan Avenue, N.W.; thence in a westerly direction along Michigan Avenue, N.W., to Park Place, N.W.; thence north along Park Place, N.W., to Irving Street, N.W.; thence northeast along Irving Street, N.W., to Kenyon Street, N.W.; thence west along Kenyon Street, N.W., to Park Place, N.W.; thence north along Park Place, N.W., to Rock Creek Church Road, N.W.; thence northeast along Rock Creek Church Road, N.W., to Harewood Road, N.W.; thence southeast along Harewood Road, N.W., to North Capitol Street; thence south along North Capitol Street to Irving Street, N.E.; thence east along Irving Street, N.E., to Michigan Avenue, N.E.; thence southwest along Michigan Avenue N.E., to North Capitol Street; thence south along North Capitol Street to Rhode Island Avenue, N.E.; thence northeast along Rhode Island Avenue, N.E., to Lincoln Road, N.E.; thence south along Lincoln Road, N.E., to R Street, N.E.; thence east along R Street, N.E., and continuing east along a line extending R Street, N.E., to the east to its intersection with the WMATA railroad tracks; thence southwest along the WMATA railroad tracks to New York Avenue, N.E.; thence southwest along New York Avenue, N.E., to New York Avenue, N.W., and continuing southwest along New York Avenue, N.W., to the point of beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>There is established the Connecticut Avenue Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots abutting Connecticut Avenue, N.W., beginning at the intersection of Connecticut Avenue , N.W., and Macomb Street, N.W., thence north on Connecticut Avenue, N.W., to its intersection with Western Avenue, N.W.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>There is established the Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following area: Beginning at the intersection of the center line of Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E., and Minnesota Avenue, N.E.; thence northeast along Minnesota Avenue, N.E., to Sheriff Road, N.E.; thence east along Sheriff Road, N.E., to 44th Street, N.E.; thence south along 44th Street, N.E., to Jay Street, N.E.; thence east along Jay Street, N.E., to 46th Street, N.E.; thence south along 46th Street, N.E., to Hayes Street, N.E.; thence east along Hayes Street, N.E., to 54th Place, N.E.; thence northeast along 54th Place, N.E., to 55th Street, N.E.; thence northeast along 55th Street, N.E., to Jay Street, N.E.; thence southeast along Jay Street, N.E., to Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E.; thence east along Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E., to Eastern Avenue, N.E.; thence southeast along Eastern Avenue, N.E., to Foote Street, N.E.; thence west along Foote Street, N.E., to 55th Street, N.E.; thence south along 55th Street, N.E., to Eads Street, N.E.; thence west along Eads Street, N.E., to the Marvin Gaye Park Trail, and continuing east along the Marvin Gaye Park Trail, to the point of the beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>There is established the New York Avenue, N.E., Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following area: Beginning at the intersection of New York Avenue, N.E., and Florida Avenue, N.E.; thence southeast on Florida Avenue, N.E., to West Virginia Avenue, N.E.; thence northeast on West Virginia Avenue, N.E. to 17th Street, N.E.; thence southeast on 17th Street. N.E.; thence continuing northeast on 17th Street, N.E. to Montana Avenue, N.E., thence southeast on Montana Avenue, N.E. to Bladensburg Road, N.E.; thence northeast on Bladensburg Road, N.E. to New York Avenue, N.E.; thence east on New York Avenue, N.E.; thence continuing northeast on New York Avenue, N.E.; thence continuing southeast on New York Avenue, N.E. to Fort Lincoln Drive, N.E.; thence north on Fort Lincoln Drive, N.E.; thence continuing northwest on Fort Lincoln Drive, N.E.; thence continuing southwest on Fort Lincoln Drive, N.E. to 33rd Place, N.E.; thence continuing southwest on 33rd Place, N.E. to South Dakota Avenue, N.E.; thence northwest on South Dakota Avenue, N.E. to Channing Place, N.E.; thence west on Channing Place, N.E. to Bladensburg Road, N.E.; thence southwest on Bladensburg Road, N.E. to Queens Chapel Road, N.E.; thence northwest on Queens Chapel Road to Channing Street, N.E.; thence west on Channing Street, N.E. to 21st Place, N.E., thence south on 21st Place, N.E. to Bryant Street, N.E., thence west on Bryant Street, N.E. to Lawrence Street, N.E., then southwest on Lawrence Street, N.E. to Edwin Street, N.E., thence northwest on Edwin Street, N.E.; thence continuing southwest on Edwin Street, N.E. to Montana Avenue, N.E., thence continuing northwest on Montana Avenue, N.E. to W Street, N.E., thence southwest on W Street, N.E., thence west along a line extending W Street, N.E., west to the continuation of W Street, N.E., and continuing west along W Street, N.E., to Brentwood Road, N.E.; thence southwest along Brentwood Road, N.E., to its end at T Street, N.E.; thence southwest to the intersection of a line extending Fourth Street, N.E., south and a line extending R Street, N.E., east; thence west on R Street, N.E. to Eckington Place, N.E., thence southwest on Eckington Place, N.E., to Florida Avenue, N.E., thence southeast on Florida Avenue, N.E. and continuing southeast until the point of beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(l)</num>
    <text>There is established the Good Hope Road, S.E., Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots abutting Good Hope Road , S.E., beginning at the intersection of Good Hope Road, S.E., and Anacostia Drive, S.E., thence southeast on Good Hope Road, S.E., to its intersection with Naylor Road, S.E.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(m)</num>
    <text>There is established the U Street/14th Street Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots within or abutting the boundary of the following area: Beginning at the intersection of T Street, N.W., and 11th Street, N.W.; thence west on T Street, N.W., to 19th Street, N.W.; thence north on 19th Street, N.W., to Columbia Road, N.W.; thence northeast on Columbia Road, N.W., to 18th Street, N.W.; thence northwest on Adams Mill Road, N.W., to Lanier Place, N.W.; thence northeast on Lanier Place, N.W. to Ontario Road, N.W.; thence northeast on Columbia Road, N.W., to Mount Pleasant Street, N.W.; thence northwest on Mount Pleasant Street, N.W., to Park Road, N.W.; thence southeast on Park Road, N.W., to 14th Street, N.W.; thence north on 14th Street, N.W., to Spring Road, N.W.; thence southeast on Spring Road, N.W., to 13th Street, N.W.; thence south on 13th Street, N.W., to Monroe Street, N.W.; thence South on 11th Street, N.W., to Kenyon Street, N.W.; thence west on Kenyon Street, N.W. to 13th. Street, N.W.; thence south on 13th Street, N.W. to V Street, N.W.; thence east on V Street, N.W., to 11th Street, N.W.; thence south on 11th Street, N.W., to the point of beginning.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(n)</num>
    <text>There is established the Tenleytown Retail Priority Area, which shall consist of the parcels, squares, and lots abutting Wisconsin Avenue, N.W., beginning at the intersection of Wisconsin Avenue, N.W., and Tenley Circle, N.W., thence north on Wisconsin Avenue, N.W., to its intersection with Western Avenue, N.W.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-185" type="History" path="§4">Sept. 8, 2004, D.C. Law 15-185, § 4, 51 DCR 5941</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223" type="History">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 7112(c), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 2152, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-288" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-288, § 2, 60 DCR 2325</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 8032(b), 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 2094, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-262" type="History">May 2, 2015, D.C. Law 20-262, § 2, 62 DCR 15116</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, §§  2023, 7011, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 8031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title VIII of the act may be cited as the “Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Area Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite> and amendment of this section, see § 7016(i) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2023 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-65, May 22, 2015,  62 DCR 6865, 21 DCSTAT 1444).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see <cite doc="D.C. Act 21-6">§§ 2 and 3 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-6, Feb. 23, 2015,  62 DCR 2474, 21 DCSTAT 805)</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010a, repealing <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite>, see § 2(k) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-587, January 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1294, 21 STAT 758).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite>, see § 7010a of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2094 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010a, repealing <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite>, see § 2(k) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784 , 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 2094(c), see § 2(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-461, November 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11784, 20 STAT 4368).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite>, see § 7010a of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2094 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2094 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of The Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution of 2007, effective July 10, 2007 (Res. 17-257;  54 DCR 7194), see § 8033 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8032(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of The Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution of 2007, effective July 10, 2007 (Res. 17-257;  54 DCR 7194), see § 8033 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8032(b) of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2152 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2152 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 7112(c) and 7113 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the H Street, N.E., Retail Priority Area Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 21-1">D.C. Law 21-1</cite>, June 4, 2015,  62 DCR 4550).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7010a, see § 2(j) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(d) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-179">D.C. Law 20-179</cite>, March 7, 2015, 62 DCR 424).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “within or abutting the boundary of the following area” for “within the following area” in (f), (g), (h), (j), and (k); rewrote (i), (l), and (m); and added (n).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-262">D.C. Law 20-262</cite> added (m).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> rewrote (g); and added (k) and (l).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (f), (g), (h), (i), and (j).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> substituted “$25 million” for “$30 million” in (b)(2); and added (b-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “September 30, 2015” for “4 years from the date that the Mayor establishes the Rules of Operation for the Downtown Retail Priority Area”; and, in subsec. (c), substituted “September 30, 2015” for “December 31, 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-1217.74">§ 2-1217.74</cite> and <cite path="§7-1671.06">§ 7-1671.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7011 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite>.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite>: Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-288">D.C. Law 19-288</cite> added a subsection (f).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7113 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided: “Sec. 7113. Applicability. Section 7112(c) shall apply as of November 21, 2009.”</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 17-257 was amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>, § 8033.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 17-257, the “Great Streets Neighborhood Retail Priority Areas Approval Resolution of 2007”, was approved effective July 10, 2007.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 16-430, the “Children’s Museum Project Retail Priority Area Approval Resolution of 2006”, was approved effective January 18, 2006.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-776, the “Rhode Island Place Project Retail Priority Area Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective December 7, 2004.</text>
    <text type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-775, the “Fort Lincoln Washington Gateway Project Retail Priority Area Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved effective December 7, 2004.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
