<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1217.110</num>
  <heading>Bond security.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The bonds issued pursuant to this subchapter are declared to be issued for essential public and governmental purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The District does hereby pledge to and covenant and agree with the holders of any bonds that, subject to the provisions of the Financing Documents, the District will not limit or alter the basis upon which Available Real Property Tax Revenues are allocated, applied, and pledged pursuant to this subchapter; will not impair the contractual obligations of the District to fulfill the terms of any agreement made with the holders of the bonds; will not in any way impair the rights or remedies of the holders of the bonds; and will not modify in any way the exemptions from District taxation provided for in this subchapter, until the bonds, together with interest thereon, are fully met and discharged. To the extent that any acts or resolutions of the Council may be in conflict with this subchapter, this subchapter shall be controlling.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>It is the intention of the Council that a pledge made in respect of the bonds shall be valid and binding from the time the Available Real Property Tax Revenues or other funds are deposited in the QZAB Pledged Account; that when deposited in the QZAB Pledge Account, the money or property so pledged and deposited shall immediately be subject to the lien of the pledge without physical delivery or further act; and that the lien of the pledge shall be valid and binding as against all parties having any claim of any kind against the District, whether or not the parties have notice of the lien. This subchapter, any resolution adopted pursuant to this subchapter, any trust agreement, or any other instrument by which a pledge is created do not need to be recorded or filed under any provisions of the Uniform Commercial Code to be valid, binding, and effective against the parties.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-28" type="History" path="ยง10">Oct. 18, 2005, D.C. Law 16-28, ยง 10, 52 DCR 8093</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
