<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1225.41</num>
  <heading>Eminent domain.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The repeal of subchapter X of this chapter, under section 103(a) of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-138">D.C. Law 17-138</cite>; 55 DCR 1689) shall not impair or affect the validity of the acquisition by the NCRC or the RLARC of any properties nor shall the repeal affect the authority under which properties were previously taken, or for which condemnation proceedings were initiated, under § <cite path="§2-1219.19">2-1219.19</cite> [repealed].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Condemnation proceedings initiated by the NCRC or the RLARC under § <cite path="§2-1219.19">2-1219.19</cite> [repealed] may be continued or reinstituted by the Mayor in the name of the District and the Mayor may rely upon the authority pursuant to which the NCRC or the RLARC acted as well as the findings previously made by the Council and by the NCRC or the RLARC in connection with the condemnation proceedings or the authority granted to the Mayor pursuant to § <cite path="§16-1311">16-1311</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-138" type="History" path="§601">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-138, § 601, 55 DCR 1689</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</cite>, § 501, added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 501. Eminent domain.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) The repeal of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation Act of 1998, effective September 11, 1998 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-144">D.C. Law 12-144</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1219.01">2-1219.01</cite> et seq.) (’NCRC Act’), under section 103(a) shall not impair or affect the validity of the acquisition by the NCRC or the RLARC of any properties nor shall the repeal affect the authority under which properties were previously taken, or for which condemnation proceedings were initiated, under section 20 of the NCRC Act (D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-1219.19">2-1219.19</cite>).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Condemnation proceedings initiated by the NCRC or the RLARC under section 20 of the NCRC Act may be continued or reinstituted by the Mayor in the name of the District and the Mayor may rely upon the authority pursuant to which the NCRC or the RLARC acted as well as the findings previously made by the Council and by the NCRC or the RLARC in connection with the condemnation proceedings or the authority granted to the Mayor pursuant to D. C. Official Code § <cite path="§16-1311">16-1311</cite>.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 702(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-53">D.C. Law 17-53</cite> provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 501 of National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-71, July 20, 2007,  54 DCR 7390).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 501 of National Capitol Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-152, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10900).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
