<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1203.02</num>
  <heading>Functions.</heading>
  <text>The Economic Development Liaison Office shall perform the following functions:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Develop and support programs to ensure local business development and the participation of small and disadvantaged businesses in public and private economic development activities;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Assist businesses in their procedural relationships with the District government, including, but not limited to, the expediting of administrative processes, such as approval of necessary permits, zoning actions, street closings, and other relevant District administrative actions;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive in the administration and supervision of the Office of Planning;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive in the administration and supervision of the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive in the administration and supervision of the District of Columbia Small and Local Business Opportunity Commission, established by § <cite path="§2-218.21">2-218.21</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive in the administration and supervision of the Office of Motion Pictures and Television Development;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive in the coordination of activities of the Zoning Commission with other economic development activities of the District government;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive and the Chief Financial Officer in the transfer payment of all taxes collected on behalf of business improvement districts;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Assist the Executive in the coordination of activities between the Executive and the Department of Housing and Community Development, the National Capital Revitalization Corporation, the President of the United States District of Columbia Task Force, the Washington Convention and Sports Authority, the Washington Convention and Visitors Association, the Hotel Association of Washington, the Restaurant Association of Washington, the D.C. Committee to Promote Washington, the D.C. Chamber of Commerce, the D.C. Building Industries Association, the Federal City Council, and the Committee of 100 on the Federal City; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>With appropriated funds, distribute the one-time grant of $13.5 million to the Canal Park Development Association for construction of Canal Park, issue one-time grants in accordance with section 8002(h) of the Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Support Act of 2008, effective August 16, 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite>; 55 DCR 7598), and issue grants or loans as may be necessary to implement projects that are part of the New Communities Initiative; provided, that any grant issued pursuant to this paragraph shall constitute an agreement making grants-in-aid for the purposes of Unit A of Chapter 3 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1833, 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-91">Apr. 7, 2006, D.C. Law 16-91, § 137, 52 DCR 10637</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-219">Aug. 16, 2008, D.C. Law 17-219, § 2005, 55 DCR 7598</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, §§ 2082(e), 2251, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-2207.2.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-91">D.C. Law 16-91</cite>, in par. (5), substituted “District of Columbia Small and Local Business Opportunity Commission, established by § <cite path="§2-218.21">2-218.21</cite>” for “Office of Local Business Opportunity Administration”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite>, in par. (8), deleted “and” from the end; in par. (9), substituted “; and” for a period at the end; and added par. (10).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite>, in par. (9), substituted “Washington Convention and Sports Authority” for “Washington Convention Center Authority”; and, in par. (10), substituted “issue grants or loans as may be necessary to implement projects that are part of the New Communities Initiative” for “issue grants as may be necessary to implement only the human capital projects that are part of the New Communities Initiative”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of §§ 1-2207.1 through 1-2207.3 1981 Ed., see note to § 2-1203.01.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) addition of Chapter 1-A 1981 Ed., see notes following § 2-1203.01.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of July Other-Type Supplemental Appropriations Approval and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-106, July 27, 2007,  54 DCR 8217).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2082(e) of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2251 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 2082(e), 2251 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 2004 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-219">D.C. Law 17-219</cite> provided that subtitle B of title II of the act may be cited as the “Continuation of Economic Development Grant Authority Amendment Act of 2008”.</text>
      <text>Short title: Section 2250 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</cite> provided that subtitle Z of title II of the act may be cited as the “New Communities Financial Assistance Amendment Act of 2009”.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Application of Law 12-175: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1203.01">2-1203.01</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
