<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1215.03</num>
  <heading>BID formation.</heading>
  <text>Each BID shall be organized as a nonprofit corporation under the laws of the District and shall be subject to all applicable District and federal laws and regulations. Each owner of a taxable property and each commercial tenant within a BID, whether such owner or commercial tenant is an owner or commercial tenant at the time the BID is established or at any time thereafter when the BID is in existence, shall be a member of the BID corporation from such time as the BID corporation becomes registered pursuant to this subchapter and until such time as such member’s ownership or tenancy within the BID area is terminated or the BID corporation is terminated or dissolved.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-134" type="History">May 29, 1996, D.C. Law 11-134, § 3, 43 DCR 1684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-26" type="History">renumbered as § 4, Oct. 8, 1997, D.C. Law 12-26, § 2, 44 DCR 4320</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-161" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-161, § 2(c), 61 DCR 10741</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2273.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-161">D.C. Law 20-161</cite> added “of a taxable property” in the second sentence.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 12-23">D.C. Law 12-23</cite>, September 23, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-89, June 19, 1997,  44 DCR 3747), and § 2 of the Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-146, August 12, 1997,  44 DCR 5054).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the  Business Improvement Districts Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-435, Oct. 7, 2014, 61 DCR 10717, 20 STAT 4154, 20 STAT 4154).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(c) of the  Business Improvement Districts Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-582, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1269, 21 STAT 735).</annotation>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">Expiration of Law 11-134</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1215.01">2-1215.01</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
