<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1201.04</num>
  <heading>Executive Director.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Office shall be headed by an Executive Director (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the Mayor. The Director shall devote his full time to the duties of his Office, and shall appoint qualified staff including a “Business Ombudsman” charged primarily with the implementation of the functions provided in § <cite path="§2-1201.03">2-1201.03</cite>. The annual compensation of the Director shall be determined in accordance with Chapter 51 of Title 5, United States Code (relating to the classification of government employees and related matters), but shall be no less than a GS-16, step 1 or equivalent compensation pursuant to the provisions of subchapter XI of Chapter 6 of Title 1.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In order to best carry out his duties and responsibilities and to serve the people of the District in the promotion of business economic development, the Director may engage in programs and projects jointly with a private person, firm, corporation, or association, and may enter into contracts under terms to be mutually agreed upon to carry out such programs and projects not including acquisition of land or buildings. Such contracts may be negotiated and shall not be subject to the provisions of § <cite path="§2-225.05">2-225.05</cite> [repealed], insofar as such provisions relate to competitive bidding.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-97" type="History">Mar. 29, 1977, D.C. Law 1-97, § 5, 23 DCR 9532b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(x), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Effective date of this section, see § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2204.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1354.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>References in Text</heading>
      <text>“GS-16, step 1”, referred to in subsection (a), is contained in the General Schedule which is set out under  § 5332 of Title 5, United States Code.</text>
      <text>Section 2-225.05, referred to in subsection (b), was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-259">D.C. Law 11-259</cite>, § 405,  44 DCR 1423, effective April 12, 1997.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Transfer of Functions">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1201.02">2-1201.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-173">D.C. Law 7-173</cite>, the “Supermarket Tax Incentive Amendment Act of 1988”, see Mayor’s Order 89-84, April 24, 1989.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Because of the codification of <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-89">D.C. Law 5-89</cite> as subchapter II of Chapter 22 of Title 1 subchapter IV of Chapter 12 of Title 2, 2001 Ed., and the designation of the preexisting text as subchapter I, “subchapter” has been substituted for “chapter” near the beginning of the first sentence of subsection (a).</text>
      <text>Office of Business and Economic Development abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§2-1201.02">2-1201.02</cite>.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
