<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1312</num>
  <heading>Appointment of Executive Director; compensation; staff.</heading>
  <text>The Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the Mayor from a list of 3 or more names submitted to him or her by the Commission. The Director shall devote his or her full time to the duties of the Office. The salary of the Director shall be fixed in accordance with subchapter X-A of Chapter 6 of Title 1. He or she shall have such staff as is approved in the District of Columbia budget and federal or private grants, plus any temporary staff approved by the Office of Budget and Resource Development.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-86" type="History" path="§302">Sept. 29, 1976, D.C. Law 1-86, title III, § 302, 23 DCR 2543</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(u), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-274" type="History">Apr. 5, 2005, D.C. Law 15-274, § 2, 52 DCR 827</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Effective date of this section, see § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2312.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-1912.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-274">D.C. Law 15-274</law-cite>, in the first sentence, substituted “a director” for “an Executive Director”; and rewrote the third sentence which had read as follows: “His or her annual compensation shall be fixed in accordance with Chapter 51 of Title 5, United States Code (relating to the classification of government employees and related matters), but shall be not lower than a GS 15, step 1 or equivalent compensation pursuant to the provisions of subchapter XI of Chapter 6 of Title 1.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“GS 15, step 1,” referred to in the third sentence of this section, is contained in the General Schedule set out under  § 5332 of Title 5, United States Code.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
