<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-132</num>
  <heading>Electrical Engineer; electrical inspectors.</heading>
  <text>There is hereby established, under the direction of the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the office of Electrical Engineer, and the Mayor of said District is hereby authorized and directed to appoint an Electrical Engineer, and said Electrical Engineer shall be an expert electrician, possessing a thorough knowledge of the most modern methods for the production, use, and control of electricity and electrical appliances, construction, wiring, and insulation, as well as such executive ability and adaptability to office work as is requisite for the efficient management of the said office. And the Mayor is authorized and directed to appoint 2 electrical inspectors to assist in the work required by the authority of §§ <cite path="§2-131">2-131</cite> to 2-133, who shall perform such clerical duties as may be required by the Mayor.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 58-2-ch1602" path="§3">Apr. 26, 1904, 33 Stat. 307, ch. 1602, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1020.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-721.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
