<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1313</num>
  <heading>Functions of Director.</heading>
  <text>In order to carry out the purpose of this chapter, the Director shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Serve as an advocate for the Latino community in the District of Columbia;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Assist community organizations and the Commission in developing and submitting grant applications;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Provide information and technical assistance with respect to programs and services for the Latino community to the Mayor, the Commission on Latino Community Development, the Council, other District of Columbia agencies and departments, and the community;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Respond to recommendations and policy statements from the Commission within 30 days of written submission unless extended by mutual agreement of the Commission and the Office;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>File an annual report on the operation of the Office with the Mayor, the Council, and the Commission;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Identify areas of need for service or improvement of service and bring them to the attention of the Mayor and Commission, with suggestions for meeting such needs, including conducting or funding research and demonstration projects to test such suggestions;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Carry responsibility for assuring necessary control, evaluation, audit, and reporting on programs funded through the Office;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Accept volunteer services and funds from public and private sector to supplement the budget in carrying out the planning duties and responsibilities of the Office;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Meet with the Spanish Program Coordinators within each department and agency of the District of Columbia government having such offices as a group, at least once a month to coordinate activities within the government involving the Latino community; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Issue grants to organizations that provide services to Latino residents of the District of Columbia or in furtherance of the mission of the Office or the purposes of this chapter; provided, that grants shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1 [§ <cite path="§1-328.11">1-328.11</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-86">Sept. 29, 1976, D.C. Law 1-86, title III, § 303, 23 DCR 2543</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 1052, 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 1062, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1329">2-1329</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-2313.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 6-1913.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in par. (8), deleted “and” from the end; substituted “; and” for a period at the end of par. (9), and added par. (10).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added “provided, that grants shall be administered pursuant to the requirements set forth in part B of subchapter XII-A of Chapter 3 of Title 1” in (10).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-149">D.C. Law 18-149</cite>, in par. (8), deleted “and” from the end; in par. (9), substituted “; and” for a period at the end; and added par. (10) to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(10)(A) Issue grants not to exceed $3.7 million in the aggregate to organizations that provide services to Latino residents of the District of Columbia in furtherance of the mission of the Office or the purposes of this act.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(B) Notwithstanding D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-368.06">47-368.06</cite>, grants that may be issued pursuant to this paragraph include grants made with funds the Office receives through an intra-District transfer, a memorandum of understanding, or a reprogramming from an agency that does not have grantmaking authority.”.</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-149">D.C. Law 18-149</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Office on Latino Affairs Grant-Making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-312, February 22, 2010,  57 DCR 1643).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1052 of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1062 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 1062 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <text>Short title: Section 1051 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite> provided that subtitle F of title I of the act may be cited as the “Office on Latino Affairs Grant-Making Authority Amendment Act of 2010”.</text>
      <text>Section 1061 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle G of Title I of the act may be cited as the “Community Affairs Grant-Making Authority Authorization Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
