<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1402.66</num>
  <heading>Arrest records.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An individual may request production of his or her arrest record for the purposes of determining eligibility for sealing or expunging that record pursuant to Chapter 8 of Title 16 [§  16-801 et seq.], or similar sealing statutes in the District or in another jurisdiction, and may request production of his or her arrest record for filing a sealing or expungement motion.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The District may charge the individual a nominal fee for processing this request.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For the purposes of this subsection, an “arrest record” shall contain a listing of all adult arrests, regardless of the disposition of each arrest, and regardless of the date on which the arrest, conviction, or completion of the sentence occurred.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person who requires an individual to produce any arrest record or any copy, extract, or statement thereof pursuant to this subsection other than for the purpose of filing a sealing or expungement motion shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or imprisoned for not more than 10 days.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An individual may request production of his or her arrest record or authorize another person to request production of his or her arrest record for any other purpose.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The District may charge the individual a nominal fee for processing this request.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>For purposes of this subsection, an “arrest record” shall contain a listing only of adult convictions for which the sentence was completed not more than 10 years before the date on which the records were requested and forfeitures of collateral in a court proceeding that have occurred not more than 10 years before the date on which the record was requested; provided, that forfeitures of collateral in a court proceeding shall not include any forfeiture of collateral that was made pursuant to the post-and-forfeit procedure, as that term is defined in § <cite path="§5-335.01">5-335.01</cite>(a).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-38" type="History">Dec. 13, 1977, D.C. Law 2-38, title II, § 266, 24 DCR 6038</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-319" type="History">June 15, 2013, D.C. Law 19-319, § 3, 60 DCR 2333</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-186" type="History">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-186, § 3, 61 DCR 12108</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-243" type="History">Apr. 24, 2015, D.C. Law 20-243, §  4, 61 DCR 8320</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2530.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2276.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-319">D.C. Law 19-319</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-186">D.C. Law 20-186</cite> redesignated (a)(1) through (3) as (a)(1)(A) through (a)(1)(C); and added (a)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-243">D.C. Law 20-243</cite> added “provided, that forfeitures of collateral in a court proceeding shall not include any forfeiture of collateral that was made pursuant to the post-and-forfeit procedure, as that term is defined in § <cite path="§5-335.01">5-335.01</cite>(a)” in (b)(1)(C).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
