<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1411.03</num>
  <heading>Functions.</heading>
  <text>The functions of the Office shall be to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Educate the public, including District residents and employers, about Unit A of this chapter (“Human Rights Act”);</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Undertake investigations and public hearings on racial, religious, or ethnic group tensions, prejudice, intolerance, bigotry, disorder, and on any form of unlawful discrimination pursuant to the Human Rights Act;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Receive, review, and investigate complaints of unlawful discrimination in employment, housing, public accommodations, or educational institutions;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Receive and investigate complaints of violations of § <cite path="§32-501">32-501</cite> et seq. and § <cite path="§32-1201">32-1201</cite> et seq. and take appropriate enforcement action regarding these complaints;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>Mediate complaints of unlawful discrimination in employment, housing, public accommodations, or educational institutions to help parties to a complaint reach a voluntary settlement;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>Conciliate complaints of unlawful discrimination in employment, housing, public accommodations, or educational institutions, after the Office has made a finding of probable cause to believe that an act of unlawful discrimination has occurred, to help the parties to a complaint reach a voluntary settlement;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>Certify a complaint to the Office of the Corporation Counsel for legal action needed, in the Director’s judgment, to preserve the status quo or to prevent irreparable harm to a party to the complaint;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>Forward to the Commission on Human Rights, for a hearing, decision, and order, any complaint that has resulted in a finding of probable cause by the Office; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>Issue, adopt, promulgate, amend, and rescind such rules and procedures as the Director deems necessary to effectuate the provisions of this subtitle, in accordance with procedures promulgated pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-38" type="History">Oct. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 13-38, § 204, 46 DCR 6373</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 8, 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</cite> added par. (9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) addition of subchapter IV, see notes following § <cite path="§2-1411.01">2-1411.01</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
