<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1565.02</num>
  <heading>Establishment and duties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Youth Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Youth Council members shall advise the Council of the District of Columbia (“Council”) by:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Commenting upon legislation and policies that impact on youth;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Presenting issues and recommendations to improve the lives of youth;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Monitoring the programs and policies that affect youth to ensure that they are achieving the intended results; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Working with other youth organizations in the District to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide mutual support;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Collaborate on shared issues and interests;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Advise one another on ways to increase the effectiveness of their organizations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Assist in the start-up of new youth organizations, including youth organizations for each ward of the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Prepare youth for leadership positions by providing appropriate training; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Create more youth and adult partnerships.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Youth Council shall conduct periodic seminars for members regarding leadership, government, and the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Youth Council shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Set its own priorities;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Determine the function of its subcommittees;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Establish standards of conduct;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Establish ministerial procedures; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Determine its needs for the convening of meetings.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Youth Council members shall review and consider the procedures and rules of the Council, as they may be appropriate for the Youth Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Beginning one year after its first meeting and every year thereafter, the Youth Council shall publish a report of its activities, recommendations, and accomplishments, which shall be:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Distributed to the Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Placed on the Internet;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Distributed to each public library, and the library of each public and public charter school; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Made available to the public upon request.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Youth Council shall meet at least 4 times a year, including at least one public hearing on issues of importance to youth.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-251" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-251, § 3, 55 DCR 9247</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1565.01">2-1565.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
