<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1585</num>
  <heading>Executive Working Group.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Youth Development Plan Executive Working Group (“Working Group”), that shall advise its chair on the youth development plan. The chair of the Working Group shall be the Deputy Mayor for Children, Youth, Families and Elders (“chair”). The other members of the Executive working group shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Current members of the Youth Development Plan’s executive steering committee, including the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and, the Superintendent of the District of Columbia Public Schools, the City Administrator, and the President of the District of Columbia Children and Youth Investment Trust Corporation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director of the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A member of the Council, as designated the Council Chairman;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Adolescent youths, to be selected by the chair of the Executive Working Group as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A member of the Mayor’s Youth Advisory Council,</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A system-involved youth who may be a youth who is legally a ward of, or committed to the care of the District of Columbia, or who is under the care of, the Department of Mental Health, and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>At least one youth who resides in the District;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>At least one representative from the Department of Parks and Recreation, as selected by the chair;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>At least one representative from the Department of Youth Rehabilitative Services, as selected by the chair;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>At least one representative from the Child and Family Services Agency, as selected by the chair;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>At least one representative from the Metropolitan Police Department, as selected by the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety &amp; Justice;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Representatives from other governmental agencies and instrumentalities as selected by the chair; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>At least 2 District residents who have demonstrated an interest in youth violence or youth development in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The operations of the Working Group shall be subject to the discretion of the chair; provided, that Working Group shall meet at least twice a year. The chair of the Working Group shall work to ensure that the Group receives meaningful, informed feedback and input from its youth members.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-192" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-192, § 1156, 53 DCR 6899</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-1582">2-1582</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1156 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-477, August 8, 2006,  53 DCR 7068).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1156 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-499, October 23, 2006,  53 DCR 8845).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 1156 of Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-1, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1165).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 602 of Crime Bill Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-129, June 29, 2009,  56 DCR 5495).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
