<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1517.32</num>
  <heading>Early childhood and school-based behavioral health comprehensive plan.</heading>
  <text>By March 30, 2013, the Mayor shall submit a comprehensive plan to the Council for the expansion of early childhood and school-based behavioral health programs and services by the 2016-2017 school year. At minimum, the plan shall:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Establish a strategy to enhance behavioral health services in all public schools and public charter schools, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The implementation of programs that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Include interventions for families of students with behavioral health needs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Reduce aggressive and impulsive behavior; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Promote social and emotional competency in students; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The expansion of school-based mental health services as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>By the 2014-2015 school year, services are available to at least 50% of all public and public charter school students;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>By the 2015-2016 school year, services are available to at least 75% of all public and public charter school students; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>By the 2016-2017 school year, services are available to all public and public charter school students;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Include an analysis of whether current health education standards align with actual behavioral health needs of youth and any recommendations for proposed changes; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Provide recommendations for the expansion of behavioral health programs and services at child development facilities.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-141" type="History">June 7, 2012, D.C. Law 19-141, § 203, 59 DCR 3083</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, § 601, see § 4112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, § 601, see § 4112 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 4111 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle K of Title IV of the act may be cited as the “South Capitol Street Memorial Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> originally provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite>, § 7004, provided that the applicability of only §§ 302(b)(1), 304, and 502(a) are contingent upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 601 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>, § 4112, provided that §§ 302(b)(1)(A) and (C) and 304(b)(1)(D) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> shall apply to public charter schools upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register. Section 302(b)(1)(A) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added § <cite path="§38-203">38-203</cite>(i)(A-i); Section 302(b)(1)(C) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added § <cite path="§38-203">38-203</cite>(i)(B-i); and Section 304(b)(1)(D) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-141">D.C. Law 19-141</cite> added 5 DCMR § A2103(c)(6).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
