<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1563</num>
  <heading>Composition of the Youth Council.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Youth Council shall be composed of 32 youth from various geographic sectors of the District, and shall include members who represent youth with special needs, as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Three members shall be from each of the 8 wards in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Four members shall be presently under an order of commitment to the District’s juvenile justice system, at least one of whom presently resides in a group home; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Four members shall be presently in the District’s foster care system; at least one of whom shall reside in a group home.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Membership of the Youth Council shall reflect a broad range of diversity encompassing relevant differences in ethnicity, location of residency within the District, religion, and gender.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Members of the Youth Council shall have been a District resident for at least one year, not including time residing in a college dormitory, prior to their application to serve on the Youth Council. College students shall be eligible to participate on the Youth Council, if they have been a District resident, living outside a college dormitory, for at least one year prior to their application to serve on the Youth Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Youth applying to participate on the Youth Council shall have:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A sincere interest in, and motivation to work for the community;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A background of community-based activity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A general knowledge of activities and needs in the sector of the community which they are selected to represent;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>An ability to bring creative perspectives about youth issues and concerns to the Youth Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The ability to work patiently and constructively in a group setting;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The ability to responsibly fulfill commitments; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>An interest in the development of leadership skills.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-145">June 25, 2002, D.C. Law 14-145, § 4, 49 DCR 4063</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
