<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-1702</num>
  <heading>Establishment of District of Columbia Office of Public Records Management, Archival Administration, and Library of Governmental Information.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the District of Columbia Office of Public Records Management, Archival Administration, and Library of Governmental Information within the Office of the Secretary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The head of the Office shall be the Public Records Administrator of the District of Columbia who shall be appointed by the Mayor. The Administrator shall be qualified by training and experience in records and archives management. Other staff shall be appointed as necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Subject to the approval of the Mayor, the Administrator is authorized to adopt, alter, and use a seal which shall establish the authenticity or true copy of any public record in the Administrator’s custody. A true copy shall then have the same force and effect as the original.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall issue rules and regulations to implement the provisions of this chapter pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of this title. The Mayor shall submit the proposed rules and regulations to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve the proposed rules and regulations, by resolution, within the 45-day period, the proposed rules and regulations shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-19">Sept. 5, 1985, D.C. Law 6-19, § 3, 32 DCR 3590</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-235">Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-235, § 2(b), 38 DCR 302</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-175">June 13, 2008, D.C. Law 17-175, § 2(b), 55 DCR 5387</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="2-1701">2-1701</cite> and § <cite root="2-1706">2-1706</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-2902.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-175">D.C. Law 17-175</cite>, in subsec. (e), added the second and third sentences.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Office of Public Records Management, Archival Administration, and Library of Government Information established: See Mayor’s Order 86-28, February 11, 1986.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
