<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-1831.17</num>
  <heading>Advisory Committee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Advisory Committee to the Office of Administrative Hearings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Advisory Committee shall consist of the following 8 persons:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Chairman of the Council or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Corporation Counsel or his or her designee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Two agency heads appointed by the Mayor, or their designees, from agencies with cases coming before the Office of Administrative Hearings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Two members of the District of Columbia Bar, appointed by the Mayor, neither of whom shall be employed by the District of Columbia government; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A member of the public, appointed by the Mayor, who is not a member of the District of Columbia Bar.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall chair the Advisory Committee, or may designate an Advisory Committee Chair from among its members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A member of the Advisory Committee may not receive compensation for service on the Advisory Committee, but is entitled to reimbursement for travel expenses in accordance with applicable law and regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Advisory Committee shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise the Chief Administrative Law Judge in carrying out his or her duties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Identify issues of importance to Administrative Law Judges and agencies that should be addressed by the Office;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Review issues and problems relating to administrative adjudication;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Review and comment upon the policies and regulations proposed by the Chief Administrative Law Judge; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Make recommendations for statutory and regulatory changes that are consistent with advancing the purposes of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Advisory Committee shall meet at a regular time and place to be determined by the committee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Chief Administrative Law Judge shall confer with the Advisory Committee at its meetings and shall provide such information as the Advisory Committee lawfully may request.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-76" type="History" path="ยง20">Mar. 6, 2002, D.C. Law 14-76, ยง 20, 48 DCR 11442</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
