<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-209.04</num>
  <heading>Reciprocal police mutual aid agreements — Supervision of non-District police in District; enforcement of District laws by non-District police.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall be responsible for directing the activities of all policemen and other officers and agents coming into the District pursuant to any such reciprocal agreement, and the Mayor is empowered to authorize all policemen and other officers and agents from outside the District to enforce the laws applicable in the District to the same extent as if they were duly authorized officers and members of the Metropolitan Police force of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-587">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1150, Pub. L. 90-587, § 4</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 1-1128.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 1-823.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
