<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-218.48</num>
  <heading>Enforcement and penalties for breach of subcontracting plan.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For any subcontracting plan required by law, the beneficiary shall be deemed to have breached the subcontracting plan for utilization of small or certified business enterprises in the performance of a contract if the beneficiary:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fails to submit subcontracting plan monitoring or compliance reports or other required subcontracting information in a reasonably timely manner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submits a monitoring or compliance report or other required subcontracting information containing a materially false statement; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fails to meet the subcontracting requirements pursuant to § <cite path="§2-218.46">2-218.46</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A contractor that is found to have breached a subcontracting plan for utilization of certified business enterprises shall be subject to the imposition of penalties, including monetary fines, pursuant to §  2-218.63.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2348, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-207">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-207, § 2(j), 55 DCR 6107</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-141">Apr. 20, 2010, D.C. Law 18-141, § 2(j), 57 DCR 1485</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-159">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-159, § 2(c), 57 DCR 3006</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-108">June 10, 2014, D.C. Law 20-108, § 2(y), 61 DCR 3892</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-218.12">2-218.12</cite> and § <cite path="§2-218.75">2-218.75</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-207">D.C. Law 17-207</cite> substituted “certified business enterprises” for “local, small, or disadvantaged businesses” in two places.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-141">D.C. Law 18-141</cite> rewrote the section, which had read as follows: “The willful breach by a contractor of a subcontracting plan for utilization of certified business enterprises in the performance of a contract, the failure to submit any required subcontracting plan monitoring or compliance report, or the deliberate submission of falsified data may be enforced by the Department through the imposition of penalties, including monetary fines of $15,000 or 5% of the total amount of the work that the contractor was to subcontract to certified business enterprises, whichever is greater, for each such breach, failure, or falsified submission.”</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-159">D.C. Law 18-159</cite>, in subsec. (a), deleted “or” from the end of par. (1), rewrote par. (2), and added par. (3).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> deleted “willful” preceding “breach” in the section heading; rewrote (a); repealed (b); and in (c), substituted “willfully” preceding “breached” and substituted “fines, pursuant to § <cite path="§2-218.63">2-218.63</cite>” for “fines of $15,000 or 5% of the total amount of the work that the contractor was to subcontract to certified business enterprises, whichever is greater, for each breach.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-96">D.C. Law 17-96</cite>, January 29, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 3403).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2348 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-156, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10919).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-251, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1259).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>: Section 4(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that applications pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be subject to the provisions of the act.</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that, except as provided in § <cite path="§2-218.46">2-218.46</cite>(f), contracts existing or pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be affected by the provisions of the act.</text>
      <text>Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7005.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
