<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-219.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this part, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Beneficiary” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The signatory to a contract executed by the Mayor which involves any District of Columbia government funds, or funds which, in accordance with a federal grant or otherwise, the District government administers and which details the number and description of all jobs created by a government-assisted project or contract for which the beneficiary is required to use the First Source Register;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A recipient of a District government economic development action including contracts, grants, loans, tax abatements, land transfers for redevelopment, or tax increment financing that results in a financial benefit of $300,000 or more from an agency, commission, instrumentality, or other entity of the District government, including a financial or banking institution which serves as the repository for $1 million or more of District of Columbia funds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A retail or commercial tenant that is a direct recipient of a District government economic development action, including contracts, grants, loans, tax abatements, land transfers for public redevelopment, or tax increment financing in excess of $300,000.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Employment agreement” means the contract referred to in paragraph (1) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“All jobs” means any union and non-union managerial, nonmanagerial professional, nonprofessional, technical or nontechnical position including: clerical and sales occupations, service occupations, processing occupations, machine trade occupations, bench work occupations, structural work occupations, agricultural, fishery, forestry, and related occupations, and any other occupations as the Department of Employment Services may identify in the Dictionary of Occupational Titles, United States Department of Labor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“First Source Register” means the Department of Employment Services Automated Applicant Files, which consists of the names of unemployed District residents registered with the Department of Employment Services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Government-assisted project or contract” means any construction or non-construction project or contract receiving funds or resources from the District of Columbia, or funds or resources which, in accordance with a federal grant or otherwise, the District of Columbia government administers, including contracts, grants, loans, tax abatements or exemptions, land transfers, land disposition and development agreements, tax increment financing, or any combination thereof, that is valued at $300,000 or more.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Unemployed District resident” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any unemployed resident of the District of Columbia who does not receive unemployment compensation benefits pursuant to Chapter 1 of Title 51, and who lives within the boundaries of the advisory neighborhood commission in which the government-assisted project or contract is located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any unemployed resident of the District of Columbia who does not receive unemployment compensation benefits pursuant to Chapter 1 of Title 51; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Any other unemployed resident of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Hard to employ” means a District resident who is confirmed by a District of Columbia government agency as:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>An ex-offender who has been released from prison within the last 10 years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A participant of the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A participant of the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Living with a permanent disability verified by the Social Security Administration or District vocational rehabilitation program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Unemployed for 6 months or more in the last 12-month period;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Homeless;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>A participant or graduate of the Transitional Employment Program established by § <cite path="§32-1331">32-1331</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(H)</num>
      <text>An individual who qualified for inclusion in the Work Opportunity Tax Credit Program as certified by the Department of Employment Services.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Direct labor costs” means all costs, including wages and benefits, associated with the hiring and employment of personnel assigned to a process in which payroll expenses are traced to the units of output and are included in the cost of goods sold.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Indirect labor costs” means all costs, including wages and benefits, that are part of operating expenses and are associated with the hiring and employment of personnel assigned to tasks other than producing products.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Workforce Act” means the Workforce Intermediary Establishment and Reform of the First Source Amendment Act of 2011 [<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-84">D.C. Law 19-84</cite>].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-93" type="History">June 29, 1984, D.C. Law 5-93, § 2, 31 DCR 2545</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-175" type="History">Mar. 15, 1985, D.C. Law 5-175, § 2, 32 DCR 746</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-210" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-210, § 2(a), 40 DCR 19</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-118" type="History">June 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-118, § 302(a), 53 DCR 2602</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 113, 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-84" type="History">Feb. 24, 2012, D.C. Law 19-84, § 2(a), 58 DCR 11170</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Economic development zone incentives, businesses qualifying for tax incentives, see § <cite path="§6-1504">6-1504</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-218.50">2-218.50</cite>, § <cite path="§2-219.03">2-219.03</cite>, § <cite path="§2-219.32">2-219.32</cite>, § <cite path="§2-219.33">2-219.33</cite>, § <cite path="§2-219.34">2-219.34</cite>, § <cite path="§2-353.01">2-353.01</cite>, § <cite path="§6-1504">6-1504</cite>, § <cite path="§10-1601.04">10-1601.04</cite>, § <cite path="§10-1601.05">10-1601.05</cite>, and § <cite path="§47-1818.07">47-1818.07</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1161.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-118">D.C. Law 16-118</cite> rewrote par. (1), which had read as follows: “(1) ‘Beneficiary’ means the signator to a contract executed by the Mayor which involves any District of Columbia government funds, or funds which, in accordance with a federal grant or otherwise, the District of Columbia government administers, or the applicant for any street or alley closing pursuant to Chapter 2 of Title 9, and which details the number and description of all jobs created by a government-assisted project for which the beneficiary is required to use the First Source Register.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in the lead-in language.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-84">D.C. Law 19-84</cite> rewrote pars. (1) and (5); in par. (3), substituted “union and non-union managerial, nonmanagerial” for “managerial, nonmanagerial,”; in par. (6), substituted “government-assisted project or contract” for “government-assisted project”; and added pars. (7) to (10).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-55">D.C. Law 19-55</cite> added a section to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 2. Establishment of Workforce Intermediary Task Force.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a)(1) By November 1, 2011, the Mayor shall establish a Workforce Intermediary Task Force (”Task Force“) to review best practices for workforce intermediary programs.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Task Force shall review similar programs implemented by the governments of Boston, Minneapolis, San Francisco, and any other cities that have implemented similar programs.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) By January 15, 2012, the Task Force shall recommend to the Mayor and the Council a Workforce Intermediary Program (”Program“) for the District. The recommendation shall include a review of:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(A) The industries, in addition to the construction industry, that should be a focal point of the Program because they are frequently required to enter into first source agreements;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(B) What would be a reasonable operating budget for the Program, including a cap on administrative costs;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(C) What would be a reasonable funding mechanism for the Program;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(D) How the Program would collaborate with multiple District government agencies and community-based organizations to serve job-ready residents as well as residents needing job-training services or adult basic education services;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(E) The specific performance metrics that should be used to assess the performance of the Program’s process and outcomes;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(F) The baseline data that would be needed to isolate, to the fullest extent possible, the effects of the Program;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(G) The type of governance structure that would work best for establishing the Program and for the ongoing operations of the Program; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(H) What programmatic and statutory recommendations would be necessary regarding how the Program will interact with the District’s First Source Register program.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b)(1) The recommendations shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. Upon receipt of the recommendations, the Council shall hold a public roundtable or hearing. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the recommendations, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 45-day review period, the recommendations shall be deemed disapproved.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) If the recommendations are disapproved by the Council, the Council’s Committee on Housing and Workforce Development shall transmit a report to the Task Force citing the Council’s concerns and the Task Force shall have 30 days to review the report and re-submit its new recommendations to the Mayor and the Council for approval pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(c) The Task Force shall consist of the following 17 members:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) The Mayor, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) The Chairman of the Council, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) The Chairman of the Council’s Committee on Housing and Workforce Development, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) The Director of the Department of Employment Services;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(5) The Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, or his designee;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) The Executive Director of the Workforce Investment Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(7) Two members of the District business community who represent industries that are frequently subject to first source agreements, appointed by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(8) Two members of the District business community who represent industries that are frequently subject to first source agreements, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(9) A representative of a District job training or education provider, appointed by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(10) A representative of a District job training or education provider, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(11) Two representatives of organized labor, appointed by the Mayor;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(12) A representative of organized labor, appointed by the Chairman of the Council;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(13) A representative of the District philanthropic community or an organization focused on workforce development research, appointed by the Mayor; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(14) A representative of the District philanthropic community or an organization focused on workforce development research, appointed by the Chairman of the Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(d) The Mayor and the Chairman of the Council shall serve as co-chairs of the Task Force.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) The director of each District agency and instrumentality that engages in capital construction shall advise and assist the Task Force.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-55">D.C. Law 19-55</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Workforce Intermediary Task Force Establishment Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-131, August 2, 2011,  58 DCR 6789).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Workforce Intermediary Task Force Establishment Second Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-167, October 11, 2011,  58 DCR 8900).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-118">D.C. Law 16-118</cite>, the “Way to Work Amendment Act of 2006”, see Mayor’s Order 2006-122, September 27, 2006 ( 53 DCR 9313).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Additional Functions relating to First Source Employment Compliance to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, see Mayor’s Order 2011-47, February 23, 2011 ( 58 DCR 1665).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
