<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-214.01</num>
  <heading>Establishment of the Minority and Women-Owned Business Assessment Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established the Minority and Women-Owned Business Assessment Program (“Program”) within the Department of Small and Local Business Development (“Department”). The Program shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Analyze the current state of businesses owned or controlled by minorities or women qualifying as Certified Business Enterprises (“CBE”) as that term is defined in subchapter IX-A of this chapter [<cite path="§2-218.01">§ 2-218.01</cite> et seq.], including counting the number of businesses that have applied for CBE certification and the number that have been certified as CBEs since the inception of the CBE program;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Record and track the number of businesses owned or controlled by minorities or women that have been awarded government contracts under the procurement process utilized by the District; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Assess the findings and investigate and recommend ways to encourage businesses owned or controlled by minorities or women to compete in the procurement process utilized by the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall submit the findings and recommendations of the Program to the Chairman of the Council’s Committee on Economic Development in the form of a report or reports. Specific steps for implementing the recommendations shall accompany the report or reports.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “minority” shall include Asian, Pacific Islander, African American or Black, Native American or Native Hawaiian, and Hispanic or Latino.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-136" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 26, 2008, D.C. Law 17-136, § 2, 55 DCR 1685</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
