<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-218.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Agency” means an agency, department, office, board, commission, authority, or other instrumentality of the District government, with or without legal existence separate from that of the District government.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1A)</num>
    <text>“Agency contracting officer” means the contracting officer of an agency or government corporation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1B)</num>
    <text>“Beneficiary” means a business enterprise that is the prime contractor or developer on a government-assisted project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1C)</num>
    <text>“Business enterprise” means a business entity organized for profit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1D)</num>
    <text>“Certified business enterprise” means a local business enterprise certified pursuant to <cite path="2|2|IX-A|D">part D of this subchapter</cite> [<cite path="§2-218.31">§  2-218.31</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1E)</num>
    <text>“Certified joint venture” means a joint venture certified pursuant to <cite path="§2-218.39a">§ 2-218.39a</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1F)</num>
    <text>“Certified equity participant” means a single-purpose legal entity created to participate in real estate development projects and includes members that are small investors or disadvantaged investors.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(1G)</num>
    <text>“Commercially useful function” means work performed by a certified business enterprise in a particular transaction that, consistent with industry practices and other relevant considerations, has a necessary and useful role in the transaction. The certified business enterprise shall be responsible for the execution of the work of the contract and carry out its responsibility by actually performing, managing, and supervising the work involved. The certified business enterprise shall be responsible, with respect to materials and supplies used on the contract, for negotiating price, determining quality and quantity, ordering the materials and installing (where applicable) and paying for the material itself.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Commission” means the District of Columbia Small and Local Business Opportunity Commission, established by <cite path="§2-218.21">§ 2-218.21</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Department” means the Department of Small and Local Business Development, established by <cite path="§2-218.11">§ 2-218.11</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the Department of Small and Local Business Development.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Disadvantaged business enterprise” means a business enterprise as described in <cite path="§2-218.33">§ 2-218.33</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5A)</num>
    <text>“Disadvantaged investor” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A disadvantaged business enterprise pursuant to <cite path="§2-218.33">§ 2-218.33</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A District-domiciled economically disadvantaged individual as determined by regulations promulgated by the Department.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5B)</num>
    <text>“District gross receipts” means all income derived from any activity whatsoever from sources within the District, other than income a local business enterprise derives from an ownership or beneficial interest in other local business enterprises, whether compensated in the District or not, before the deduction of any expense whatsoever connected with the production of the income; provided, that the calculation of the income shall not include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The collection of federal or local taxes on motor vehicle fuel; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Fees retained by a retail establishment under <cite path="§8-102.03|(b)|(1)">§ 8-102.03(b)(1)</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“District of Columbia Supply Schedule” or “DCSS” means the District of Columbia’s multiple award schedule procurement program for providing commercial products or services to District government agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Economically disadvantaged individual” means an individual whose ability to compete in the free enterprise system is impaired because of diminished opportunities to obtain capital and credit as compared to others in the same line of business where such impairment is related to the individual’s status as socially disadvantaged. An individual is socially disadvantaged if the individual has reason to believe that the individual has been subjected to prejudice or bias because of his or her identity as a member of a group without regard to his or her qualities as an individual.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Enterprise zone” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The area of the District designated as the District of Columbia Enterprise Zone under 26 U.S.C. § 1400); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An economic development zone designated by the Mayor and approved by the Council pursuant to §§ <cite path="§6-1501">6-1501</cite> through <cite path="§6-1504">6-1504</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Expendable budget” means the total appropriated budget of an agency, reduced by such funding sources, object classes, objects, and other items, including any contract, the value of which does not lend itself to performance by a small or certified business enterprise, as shall be identified by the Department through rulemaking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9A)</num>
    <text>“Government-assisted project” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A contract executed by an agency on behalf of the District or pursuant to statutory authority that involves District funds or, to the extent not prohibited by federal law, funds that the District administers in accordance with a federal grant or otherwise;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A project funded in whole or in part by District funds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A project that receives a loan or grant from a District agency;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>A project that receives bonds or notes or the proceeds from bonds or notes issued by a District agency, including tax increment financing or payment in lieu of tax bonds or notes, but not including industrial revenue bonds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A project that receives District tax exemptions or abatements that are specific to the project and not to the nature of the entity undertaking the project, such as a religious institution or nonprofit corporation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>A development project conducted pursuant to a disposition under <cite path="§10-801">§ 10-801</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Joint venture” means a combination of property, capital, efforts, skills, or knowledge of 2 or more persons or businesses to carry out a single project.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Local business enterprise” means a business enterprise as described in <cite path="§2-218.31">§ 2-218.31</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12A)</num>
    <text>“Local manufacturing business enterprise” means a business enterprise as described in <cite path="§2-218.39">§ 2-218.39</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Longtime resident business” means a business enterprise that has been continuously eligible for certification as a local business enterprise, as defined in <cite path="§2-218.31">§ 2-218.31</cite>, for 20 consecutive years, or a small business enterprise, as defined in <cite path="§2-218.32">§ 2-218.32</cite>, for 15 consecutive years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13A)</num>
    <text>“Material change” means a change in a business’:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Ownership;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Address; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Size, if certified as a small business enterprise as defined in <cite path="§2-218.32">§ 2-218.32</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13B)</num>
    <text>“Qualified”  means a business enterprise deemed by the Department to have the capability  to perform the work that has been issued a certificate of registration  issued pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Regional governmental entity” means an organization that represents the District and surrounding local or state governments.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“Resident-owned business” means a local business enterprise owned by an individual who is, or a majority number of individuals who are, subject to personal income tax solely in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16)</num>
    <text>“Small business enterprise” means a business enterprise as described in <cite path="§2-218.32">§ 2-218.32</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(16A)</num>
    <text>“Small investor” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A small business enterprise pursuant to <cite path="§2-218.32">§ 2-218.32</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A District-domiciled individual with a net worth that does not exceed the limit set by the Department for investors.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(17)</num>
    <text>“Veteran-owned business enterprise” means a business enterprise as described in <cite path="§2-218.38">§ 2-218.38</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History" path="§2302">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2302, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 15, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-266" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-266, § 2(a), 54 DCR 829</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-207" type="History">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-207, § 2(a), 55 DCR 6107</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-141" type="History">Apr. 20, 2010, D.C. Law 18-141, § 2(a), 57 DCR 1485</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-108" type="History">June 10, 2014, D.C. Law 20-108, § 2(b), 61 DCR 3892</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-234" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-234, § 2(a), 62 DCR 458</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-465, Nov. 6, 2014, 61 DCR 11830, 20 STAT 4399).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-379, July 15, 2014,  61 DCR 7793).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-251, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1259).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-156, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10919).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-575, December 19, 2006,  54 DCR 24).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-513, October 25, 2006,  53 DCR 9091).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2302 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Small and Certified Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-150">D.C. Law 20-150</cite>, Dec. 17, 2014,  61 DCR 8318).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-96">D.C. Law 17-96</cite>, January 29, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 3403).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-214">D.C. Law 16-214</cite>, March 6, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 2761).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-234">D.C. Law 20-234</cite> rewrote (9A)(D); redesignated former (13A) as (13B); and added (13A).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> rewrote (1); added (1A) and (1B); redesignated former (1A) and (1B) as (1C) and (1D); rewrote (1D); added (1E), (1F), (1G), (5A), (5B), (9A), (13A), and (16A); rewrote (9); repealed (10); substituted “business enterprise as” for “business as” in (12A) and (17); and substituted “business enterprise that” for “business which” in (13).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-266">D.C. Law 16-266</cite>, in par. (13), inserted “, or a small business enterprise, as defined in <cite path="§2-218.32">§ 2-218.32</cite>, for 15 consecutive years” following “for 20 consecutive years”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in par. (1), substituted “or commission” for “commission, or instrumentality”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-141">D.C. Law 18-141</cite> added pars. (12A) and (17); and, in par. (15), substituted “subject to personal income tax solely in the District of Columbia” for “subject to personal income tax in the District of Columbia”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-207">D.C. Law 17-207</cite> added pars. (1A) and (1B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§2-218.35">§ 2-218.35</cite>, <cite path="§2-218.36">§ 2-218.36</cite>, <cite path="§2-218.37">§ 2-218.37</cite>, <cite path="§2-218.39a">§ 2-218.39a</cite>, <cite path="§2-351.04">§ 2-351.04</cite>, <cite path="§10-1601.04">§ 10-1601.04</cite>, and <cite path="§38-2973.04">§ 38-2973.04</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7005.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that, except as provided in <cite path="§2-218.46|(f)">§ 2-218.46(f)</cite>, contracts existing or pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be affected by the provisions of the act.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>: Section 4(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that applications pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be subject to the provisions of the act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
