<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-213.01</num>
  <heading>Automatic data processing — Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Automatic data processing” means the use of computers for the dissemination, storage, retrieval, and reporting of information associated with an administrative or managerial function.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Automated data system” means a set of logically related computer programs designed to accomplish specific objectives or functions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Computer” means an electromechanical device capable of accepting information and data, performing logical and arithmetical operations, and reporting the results.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Hardware” means input and output devices, arithmetic and control circuits, and memory devices.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Information systems” means a single network or networks of steps for processing information that is associated with a particular operation or a set of related operations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Information systems technology” means the applied science associated with the development of networks for the processing of information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Software” means the procedures, instructions, code sets, assemblers, compilers, and all other associated supporting processes required to run a computer program on the equipment itself.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-168" type="History">Mar. 15, 1985, D.C. Law 5-168, § 2, 32 DCR 721</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1134.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary establishment of an Office of the Chief Technology Officer, see § 1412 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-401, July 13, 1998,  45 DCR 4794), and see § 1412 of the Fiscal Year 1999 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-564, January 12, 1999,  46 DCR 669).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">Section 2101 of D.C. Act 12-564 provided for the application of the act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Establishment of Office of the Chief Technology Officer: Section 1812 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-175">D.C. Law 12-175</cite> established, in the Executive Branch of the government of the District of Columbia, an Office of the Chief Technology Officer under the supervision of a Chief Technology Officer, who shall carry out the functions and authorities assigned to that office.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
