<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-218.12</num>
  <heading>Director of the Department of Small and Local Business Development.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department shall be under the supervision of a Director who shall carry out the functions and authorities assigned to the Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall appoint the Director with the advice and consent of the Council.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director shall have full authority over the Department and all functions and personnel assigned to the Department, including the power to re-delegate to other employees and officials of the Department such powers and authority as in the judgment of the Director are warranted in the interests of efficiency and sound administration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Director shall monitor the accomplishment of the requirements of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Director shall have the authority to enforce the provisions of this subchapter and may impose fines, fees, penalties, and other remedial actions for violations of § <cite path="§2-218.63">2-218.63</cite> or the regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The Director shall establish within the Department, oversee, and administer such divisions, offices, or other units as may be necessary or appropriate to perform the functions and duties of the Department.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The Director may take such other actions as are necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 2312, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-207">July 18, 2008, D.C. Law 17-207, § 2(b), 55 DCR 6107</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-141">Apr. 20, 2010, D.C. Law 18-141, § 2(b), 57 DCR 1485</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-108">June 10, 2014, D.C. Law 20-108, § 2(c), 61 DCR 3892</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-207">D.C. Law 17-207</cite>, in subsecs. (d) and (f), substituted “certified” for “local, small, and disadvantaged”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-141">D.C. Law 18-141</cite> added subsec. (g).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> deleted “in contracting and procurement performed by any government corporation involved in the development of a commercial ballpark or soccer stadium and in all projects exceeding $10 million in value” from the end of (c); repealed (d), (e), and (f); rewrote (g); and added (h) and (i).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-96">D.C. Law 17-96</cite>, January 29, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 3403).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2312 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-156, October 18, 2007,  54 DCR 10919).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-251, January 23, 2008,  55 DCR 1259).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>, § 4(c), see § 7005 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite>:</text>
      <text>Section 4(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that applications pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be subject to the provisions of the act.</text>
      <text>Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that, except as provided in § <cite path="§2-218.46">2-218.46</cite>(f), contracts existing or pending as of June 10, 2014, shall not be affected by the provisions of the act.</text>
      <text>Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 4(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-108">D.C. Law 20-108</cite> was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7005.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
