<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-219.04b</num>
  <heading>Establishment of a workforce intermediary pilot program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By April 1, 2012, the Mayor shall establish a workforce intermediary pilot program for Fiscal Year 2012 based on Council and Mayor-approved recommendations made by the Workforce Intermediary Task Force established by the Workforce Intermediary Task Force Establishment Second Emergency Act of 2011, effective October 18, 2011 (D.C. Act 19-167; 58 DCR 8900), or succeeding legislation.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The workforce intermediary pilot program shall act as an intermediary between employers and training providers to provide employers with qualified District resident job applicants.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The workforce intermediary pilot program shall have a start-up budget not to exceed $2 million, which shall be funded by all funds deposited in the District of Columbia Jobs Trust Fund (“Fund”), established in § <cite path="§2-219.04c">2-219.04c</cite>, and other existing local funds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Thirty days before the end of the pilot program, the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, in consultation with the Department of Employment Services and the workforce intermediary, shall develop a progress report and recommendations for continued operations of the workforce intermediary that take into account the Council and Mayor-approved recommendations made by the Workforce Intermediary Task Force.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-93">June 29, 1984, D.C. Law 5-93, § 5b</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-84">as added Feb. 24, 2012, D.C. Law 19-84, § 2(e), 58 DCR 11170</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-219.04c">2-219.04c</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
