<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-352.06</num>
  <heading>Procurement training institute.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The CPO shall establish and administer a procurement training institute to facilitate a system of training, continuing education, and certification for District contracting personnel. The procurement training institute may:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Conduct or participate in procurement education and training programs for District employees and others, including persons not employed by the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Conduct, develop, or collaborate with established training or certification programs for the express purpose of providing certifications of proficiency to all participants who successfully complete the designated programs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Conduct research into existing and new methods of procurement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establish and maintain a District procurement library; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(A)</num>
    <text>Establish a tiered core curriculum that sets forth the minimum procurement-related training courses to be completed by District procurement personnel.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(B)</num>
    <text>The tiered core curriculum shall be designed to develop procurement competency along with a uniform training approach for personnel ranging from entry level contract specialist to contracting officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CPO may charge a fee for training conducted by the procurement training institute in accordance with § <cite path="§2-361.03">2-361.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CPO shall require that District contracting personnel be certified and that they maintain a reasonable number of hours of continuing education to maintain their certification.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CPO may allow attendance at a recognized institute to satisfy the certification requirement and the number of hours for continuing education.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-371" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 206, 58 DCR 1185</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">As to applicability of §§ <cite path="§2-352.06">2-352.06</cite>, <cite path="§2-358.03">2-358.03</cite>, and <cite path="§2-361.01">2-361.01</cite>, see § <cite path="§2-362.03">2-362.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-361.03">2-361.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-371">D.C. Law 18-371</cite>, § 1203, see § 7015 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-371">D.C. Law 18-371</cite>, § 1203, see § 7015 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 1203 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-371">D.C. Law 18-371</cite> provided that this section shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
      <text>Section 7015 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-371">D.C. Law 18-371</cite>, § 1203.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
