<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-354.05</num>
  <heading>Emergency procurements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a contract may be awarded through an emergency procurement as defined by rules:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>When there is an imminent threat to the public health, welfare, property, or safety; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To prevent or minimize serious disruption in agency operations.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Emergency procurements shall be made with as much competition as is practicable under the circumstances, based on the judgment and determination of the contracting officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The contracting officer may issue oral orders or notices to proceed to contractors to provide services or goods to the District; provided, that the directive shall be reduced to writing within 3 business days after issuance and funding for the services or goods provided shall be certified by the appropriate fiscal official.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Emergency procurement procedures shall not be used for contracts exceeding 90 days; provided, that if the development time for the good or service exceeds 90 days, the contract shall not exceed 120 days.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The CPO shall make a determination and findings justifying the emergency procurement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Notice of all emergency procurements shall be made available on the Internet no more than 7 days after the contract is awarded. The notice shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The determination and findings required by subsection (e) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A description of the item to be procured;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The designated contractor; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A copy of the contract.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-371" type="History" path="§405">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 405, 58 DCR 1185</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-354.01">2-354.01</cite>, § <cite path="§2-356.02">2-356.02</cite>, and § <cite path="§31-3422">31-3422</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
