<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>2-352.04</num>
  <heading>Duties of the Chief Procurement Officer.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Chief Procurement Officer shall be the chief procurement official of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The CPO shall have the following authority and responsibility:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To serve as the central procurement and contracting officer for the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To identify gaps, omissions, or inconsistencies in procurement laws, rules, and policies, or in laws, rules and policies affecting procurement-related activities, and to recommend changes to laws, rules, and procedures;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To provide overall leadership in the implementation of procurement rules, coordinate all procurement activities of the District government in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, and develop a system of unified and simplified procurement procedures and forms.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To prepare and issue standard specifications for goods, services, and construction required by the District government;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>To establish a standardization program for goods and services when it is determined to be in the best interests of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>To review, monitor, and audit the procurement activities of the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>To prepare, establish, and implement a periodic review process for the evaluation of contractors who provide goods or services to the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>To identify and assess trends and developments in the field of government contracting, including identifying best practices and innovation opportunities for the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>To operate and maintain an electronic procurement system;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>To sell, trade, or otherwise dispose of surplus goods belonging to the District government;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>To establish procedures for the inspection, testing, and acceptance of goods, services, and construction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>To develop guidelines for the recruitment, training, career development, and performance evaluation of all procurement personnel;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>To staff OCP with procurement professionals, including attorneys, dedicated to the formation and administration of contracts on behalf of the entities covered by this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>To create and maintain a transparent Internet site, accessible to the public, providing information on solicitations, contracts, and related laws, rules, and policies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>To promote to the purchase of environmentally preferable products and services; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>To establish certification requirements for contracting personnel.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-371" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, ยง 204, 58 DCR 1185</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
