<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-359.08</num>
  <heading>Claims by contractors against the District government.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All claims by a contractor against the District government arising under or relating to a contract shall be in writing and shall be submitted to the contracting officer for a decision.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 120 days after receipt of a claim, the contracting officer shall issue a decision, whenever possible taking into account factors such as the size and complexity of the claim and the adequacy of the information in support of the claim provided by the contractor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any failure by the contracting officer to issue a decision on a contract claim within the required time period shall be deemed to be a denial of the claim and shall authorize the commencement of an appeal on the claim as otherwise provided in this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>If a contractor is unable to support any part of his or her claim and it is determined that the inability is attributable to a material misrepresentation of fact or fraud on the part of the contractor, the contractor shall be liable to the District government for an amount equal to the unsupported part of the claim in addition to all costs to the District government attributable to the cost of reviewing that part of the contractor’s claim.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Liability under this section shall be determined within 6 years of the commission of the misrepresentation of fact or fraud.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-371" type="History" path="§908">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-371, § 908, 58 DCR 1185</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§2-308.05">2-308.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-360.04">2-360.04</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
