<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-404</num>
  <heading>Report to Congress; appropriations.</heading>
  <text>All settlements entered into by the Mayor of the District of Columbia acting under the terms and provisions of §§ <cite path="§2-402">2-402</cite> to 2-405 shall be presented to the Congress, together with a brief statement of the nature of the claim or suit, the amount claimed, and the amount of the settlement, with a summary of the evidence and circumstances under which the settlement was made. Appropriations for the payment of such settlements are hereby authorized, payment thereof to be made in the same manner as are other expenditures for the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 11, 1929, 45 Stat. 1160, ch. 173, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 31, 1951, 65 Stat. 131, ch. 274, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-114" type="History">Feb. 26, 1981, D.C. Law 3-114, § 2(a), 27 DCR 5628</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1204.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-904.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
