<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-403</num>
  <heading>Refund where assessments held void.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby authorized and empowered to grant relief in claims for refund of taxes paid, or for cancelation of assessments heretofore made and subsequent to September 1, 1916, in such cases where like assessments, or assessments against property of similar character, have been held to be void or erroneous by decision of the courts in the District of Columbia or the Supreme Court of the United States: Provided, that any claims for refunds of taxes paid before February 11, 1929, or for cancellations of assessments before February 11, 1929, shall be filed within 1 year from February 11, 1929.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing contained in §§ <cite path="§2-402">2-402</cite> to 2-405 shall be construed as reducing the period of the statute of limitations.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 70-2-ch173" path="§2">Feb. 11, 1929, 45 Stat. 1160, ch. 173, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1936, 49 Stat. 1921, ch. 804</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1948, 62 Stat. 991, ch. 646, § 32(b)</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 24, 1949, 63 Stat. 107, ch. 139, § 127</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 575, Pub. L. 91-358, title I,§ 157(e)(2)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Real property tax sales, refund of erroneously paid taxes, see § <cite path="§47-1317">47-1317</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1203.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-903.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
