<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-558</num>
  <heading>Legal effectiveness of documents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, any rule, regulation, or document having general applicability and legal effect which has been adopted or enacted by the Commissioner, the Mayor, the District of Columbia Council, an agency, or other instrumentality of the District before March 6, 1979, and which is not published in the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations on or before June 30, 1984, shall not be in effect thereafter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Except in the case of emergency rules or acts, no rule or document of general applicability and legal effect adopted or enacted on or after March 6, 1979, shall become effective until after its publication in the District of Columbia Register, nor shall such rule or document of general applicability and legal effect become effective if it is required by law, other than subchapter I of this chapter or this subchapter, to be otherwise published, until such rule or document of general applicability and legal effect is also published as required by such law.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-614" type="History" path="§308">Oct. 21, 1968, Pub. L. 90-614, title III, § 308</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-153" type="History">as added Mar. 6, 1979, D.C. Law 2-153, § 4, 25 DCR 6960</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-75" type="History">July 1, 1980, D.C. Law 3-75, § 2, 27 DCR 2277</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-41" type="History">Oct. 17, 1981, D.C. Law 4-41, § 2, 28 DCR 3423</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-10" type="History">May 20, 1983, D.C. Law 5-10, § 2, 30 DCR 1793</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-22" type="History">Aug. 2, 1983, D.C. Law 5-22, § 2, 30 DCR 3337</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1538.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1538.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Publication requirement exemption: Section 5 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-300">D.C. Law 16-300</law-cite> provided: “Notwithstanding section 8 of this act and sections 204 and 308(b) of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, effective March 6, 1979 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 2-153">D.C. Law 2-153</law-cite>; D.C. Official Code §§ <cite path="§2-602">2-602</cite> and <cite path="§2-558">2-558</cite>(b)), the text, maps, and graphics of the District elements of the Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, as amended by this act, need not be published in the District of Columbia Register to become effective.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
