<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-611</num>
  <heading>Established; appointment and qualifications of Administrator; duties; compensation of Administrator; authorization of positions and fundings; transfer of property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriated funds.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Part IV D of Organization Order No. 2, Commissioner’s Order No. 67-23, December 13, 1967, creating the Secretariat within the executive office of the Mayor, is amended:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By striking subsection 1. k.; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>By transferring, as provided in this subchapter, to the District of Columbia Office of Documents all of the powers, duties, and functions assigned to the Secretariat under any provision of law relating to the preparation, certification, and publication of the District of Columbia Register and all District of Columbia rules, regulations, codes, ordinances, and any amendments thereto.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There is hereby established within the executive office of the Mayor (created by Organization Order No. 2, dated December 23, 1967) a District of Columbia Office of Documents which shall be under the supervision and control of an Administrator appointed by the Mayor without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Office of Documents shall provide for the prompt preparation, editing, printing, and public distribution of the District of Columbia Register and the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations in accordance with this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Administrator of the District of Columbia Office of Documents (hereinafter also referred to as “Administrator”) shall be a member of the District of Columbia Bar. The Administrator shall appoint such employees within the District of Columbia Office of Documents as may be necessary for the prompt and efficient performance of the functions of the Office and for which sufficient appropriation is authorized and provided.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Administrator shall be paid at a per annum gross rate not to exceed the highest step level of GS-15 of the General Schedule.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>All property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriated funds in the Office of the Secretariat which are currently allotted for legal publications, codification, and the District of Columbia Register functions shall be transferred to the District of Columbia Office of Documents. All rules, regulations, documents, and other materials assembled or developed by the Mayor’s municipal code compilation project shall be transferred to the Office of Documents.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-153" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 6, 1979, D.C. Law 2-153, § 2, 25 DCR 6960</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-111" type="History">Mar. 3, 2010, D.C. Law 18-111, § 1021, 57 DCR 181</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 1114(a), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Administration, administrative procedure, “administrator” defined, see § <cite path="§2-551">2-551</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Office of documents, responsibility for publication of District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, see § <cite path="§2-552">2-552</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§2-551">2-551</cite> and § <cite path="§2-552">2-552</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1611.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-1611.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</law-cite> repealed subsec. (f), which had read as follows: “(f) No fewer than 7 funded and authorized positions and the attendant funding totaling at least $150,000 for salaries and personnel benefits for such positions shall be transferred by the Mayor to the District of Columbia Office of Documents.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</law-cite> substituted “the District of Columbia Register and the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations” for “District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, the District of Columbia Register, and the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1021 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Second Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-207, October 15, 2009,  56 DCR 8234).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1021 of Fiscal Year Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-260, January 4, 2010,  57 DCR 345).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 1020 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-111">D.C. Law 18-111</law-cite> provided that subtitle C of title I of the act may be cited as the “Documents Amendment Act of 2009”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
