<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-631</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Disability” means, with respect to an individual:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>A physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one or more of the major life activities of that individual;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>A record of such an impairment; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Being regarded as having such an impairment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Internet publication” means any information posted to an official web site of a public body, except for archival documents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Policies” means official instructions and guiding principles issued by a public body for the implementation of its programs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Public body” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§2-502">2-502</cite>(18A).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Publications” means any written material issued by a public body, either for internal or external use, and does not include internet publications, policies, rules, regulations, and signage.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Regulation” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§2-502">2-502</cite>(17).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Rule” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§2-502">2-502</cite>(6).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Signage” means any poster on paper larger than 8 1/2 inches by 11 inches issued by a public body and any signs regardless of size made of any material other than paper and posted or issued by a public body.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-169" type="History" path="§2">Sept. 29, 2006, D.C. Law 16-169, § 2, 53 DCR 6223</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
