<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>2-810</num>
  <heading>Authorization of appropriations.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Authorization. —</heading>
    <text>Necessary amounts are authorized to be appropriated—</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>To enable the Mayor of the District of Columbia to provide additional municipal services in the District of Columbia during the inaugural period, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Employment of personal services without regard to Chapters 33 and 51 and <cite path="5|58|III" proof="true">subchapter III of Chapter 58 of Title 5</cite> [of the U.S. Code];</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Travel expenses of enforcement personnel, including sanitarians, from other jurisdictions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The hiring of the means of transportation;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Meals for policemen, firemen, and other municipal employees;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>The cost of removing and relocating streetcar loading platforms, construction, rent, maintenance, and expenses incident to the operation of temporary public comfort stations, first-aid stations, and information booths; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Other incidental expenses in the discretion of the Mayor; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To enable the Secretary of the Interior to provide meals for the members of the United States Park Police during the inaugural period.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Payment. —</heading>
    <text>Amounts appropriated under:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a)(1) of this section are payable in the same way as other appropriations for the expenses of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a)(2) of this section are payable in the same way as other appropriations for the expenses of the Department of the Interior.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 105-225" type="History" path="§510">Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1265, Pub. L. 105-225, § 510</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“Chapters 33 and 51 and <cite path="5|58|III" proof="true">subchapter III of Chapter 58 of Title 5</cite>,” referred to in (a)(1)(A), are references to Title 5 of the U.S. Code.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-1060.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
