<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>15-311</num>
  <heading>Property subject to levy.</heading>
  <text>The writ of fieri facias may be levied on all goods and chattels of the debtor not exempt from execution, and upon money, bills, checks, promissory notes, or bonds, or certificates of stock in corporations owned by the debtor, and upon his money in the hands of the marshal or his deputy or other officer or person charged with the execution of the writ. A writ of fieri facias issued from the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or the Superior Court of the District of Columbia upon a judgment entered in such court may be levied on all legal leasehold and freehold estates of the debtor in land, but only after such judgment has been filed and recorded in the office of the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-241" type="History">Dec. 23, 1963, 77 Stat. 526, Pub. L. 88-241, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-493" type="History">July 5, 1966, 80 Stat. 264, Pub. L. 89-493, § 12</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-745" type="History">Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1178, Pub. L. 89-745,§ 5</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-263" type="History">Mar. 11, 1968, 82 Stat. 42, Pub. L. 90-263, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 553, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 144(7)</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Disability insurance benefits, exemption from execution, see § <cite path="§31-4716.01">31-4716.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Exemptions from executions generally, see § <cite path="§15-101">15-101</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Fraternal benefit association benefits, exemption from execution, see § <cite path="§31-5711">31-5711</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Group life policies and proceeds exemption from execution, see § <cite path="§31-4717">31-4717</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Notary’s official seal and documents, exemption from execution, see § <cite path="§1-1206">1-1206</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Public assistance exemption from assignment or execution, see § <cite path="§4-217.01">4-217.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Seizure by execution of goods located on leased premises, payment of rent due as prerequisite, see § <cite path="§42-3216">42-3216</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Teacher retirement annuities, exemption from assignment or execution, see § <cite path="§38-2001.17">38-2001.17</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Unemployment compensation benefits, partial exemption from execution, see § <cite path="§51-118">51-118</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Wrongful death damages, exemption from appropriation for payment of debts and liabilities, see § <cite path="§16-2703">16-2703</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 15-311.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 15-311.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
