<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-1117</num>
  <heading>Evasive business tactics.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Commissioner finds that the conduct of any other business conceals a violation or evasion of this chapter, any rule or regulation adopted under this chapter, or any law regulating mortgage loan lending in the District, the Commissioner may issue a written order to a licensee or person required to be licensed under this chapter to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Stop doing business at any place in which the other business is conducted or solicited; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Stop doing business in association or conjunction with the other business.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A licensee or person required to be licensed under this chapter who violates an order of the Commissioner issued under this section shall be subject to the penalties provided by § <cite path="§26-1118">26-1118</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may request the Attorney General of the District of Columbia to take appropriate action for the enforcement of an order issued under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-155" type="History">Sept. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-155, § 18, 43 DCR 4213</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-38" type="History">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-38, § 2(k), 56 DCR 4290</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-1119">26-1119</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-1017.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-38">D.C. Law 18-38</cite> substituted “Commissioner” for “Superintendent”; in subsecs. (a) and (b), substituted “licensee or person required to be licensed under this chapter” for “licensee”; and, in subsec. (c), substituted “Attorney General” for “Corporation Counsel”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
