<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-1206</num>
  <heading>Review of applications.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Prior to deciding whether to grant approval of the application under § <cite path="§26-1202">26-1202</cite>, § <cite path="§26-1203">26-1203</cite>, or § <cite path="§26-1205">26-1205</cite>, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall accept public comment on the application and shall hold a public hearing on the application, according to procedures established by rules issued by the Superintendent [Commissioner].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent [Commissioner] shall make either a favorable or unfavorable recommendation on the application, explain the reasons for his or her recommendation, and submit to the Council his or her recommendation and explanation, a copy of the application, and any other relevant information or submissions within 90 days after receipt of the application. The Superintendent [Commissioner] may extend this 90-day period for up to an additional 60 days. No application required by § <cite path="§26-1202">26-1202</cite>, § <cite path="§26-1203">26-1203</cite>, or § <cite path="§26-1205">26-1205</cite>, shall be complete unless it is accompanied by an application fee in an amount to be established by the Superintendent [Commissioner] and made payable to the District of Columbia Treasurer. No entity required to obtain issuance shall commence operations until the applicant has submitted evidence that the insurance has been obtained.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Council may adopt a resolution disapproving the Superintendent’s [Commissioner’s] recommendation within 45 days, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess, after receipt of the Superintendent’s [Commissioner’s] recommendation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Council fails to adopt a resolution disapproving the Superintendent’s [Commissioner’s] recommendation within the 45-day period, the Superintendent’s [Commissioner’s] recommendation shall be deemed approved.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-175" type="History">Oct. 12, 1988, D.C. Law 7-175, § 7, 35 DCR 6133</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-906.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
