<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-1401.23</num>
  <heading>Conservator; appointment; bond and security; qualifications; expenses.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If any of the grounds under § <cite path="§26-1401.19">26-1401.19</cite> authorizing a request for the appointment of a receiver exist or if the Commissioner determines that it is necessary to conserve the assets of a universal bank for the benefit of the depositors, investors, or other creditors of the bank or for the benefit of the general public, the Commissioner may petition the Superior Court to appoint a conservator for a universal bank.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall be reimbursed out of the assets of the conservatorship, as expenses, for all sums expended by the Department in connection with the conservatorship.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All expenses of a conservatorship shall be paid out of the assets of the universal bank upon the approval of the Commissioner, shall be a first charge upon the assets of the universal bank, and shall be paid in full before a final distribution or payment of dividends to creditors or shareholders of the universal bank.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-308" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, § 223, 48 DCR 3244</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-42" type="History">Oct. 26, 2001, D.C. Law 14-42, § 15, 48 DCR 7612</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 49, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-42">D.C. Law 14-42</law-cite> substituted “, as expenses,” for “, as expenses” in subsec. (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</law-cite>, in subsec. (a), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 15 of Technical Amendments Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-108, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7622).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
