<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-1301</num>
  <heading>Manner of formation; purposes.</heading>
  <text>Corporations may be formed within the District of Columbia for the purposes hereinafter mentioned in the following manner: Any number of natural persons, citizens of the United States, not less than 25, may associate themselves together to form a company for the purpose of carrying on, in the District of Columbia, any 1 of the 3 classes of business herein specified, to wit: (1) a safe deposit, trust, loan, and mortgage business; (2) a title insurance, loan, and mortgage business; or (3) a security, guarantee, indemnity, loan, and mortgage business; provided, that the capital stock of any of said companies shall not be less than $1,000,000 except as otherwise provided in § <cite path="§31-2502.13">31-2502.13</cite>, and that any of said companies may also do a storage business when their capital stock amounts to the sum of not less than $1,200,000.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1303, ch. 854, § 715</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-399" type="History">Apr. 16, 1966, 80 Stat. 121, Pub. L. 89-399, § 1(b)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 24(a), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-702.01">26-702.01</cite>, § <cite path="§26-710">26-710</cite>, § <cite path="§26-1304">26-1304</cite>, § <cite path="§26-1309">26-1309</cite>, § <cite path="§26-1310">26-1310</cite>, and § <cite path="§26-1313">26-1313</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-401.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 26-301.</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">Pursuant to Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1992, effective January 20, 1993, unless another date was designated by the Mayor under Sec V of the Plan, the D.C. Office of Banking and Financial Institutions (“OBFI”) is hereby transferred from the Deputy Mayor for Economic Development (“DMED”) control center to a separate OBFI control center/responsibility center. OBFI will continue to be administered by the Superintendent and will remain a part of the economic development cluster reporting to the Mayor.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">[Reserved].</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
