<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-1116</num>
  <heading>Advertising.</heading>
  <text>No mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage loan originator, or loan officer required to be licensed under this chapter shall use, or cause to be published, any advertisement which:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Contains any false, misleading, or deceptive statement or representation; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Identifies the mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage loan originator, or loan officer by any name other than the name set forth on the license issued by the Superintendent [Commissioner].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-155" type="History">Sept. 9, 1996, D.C. Law 11-155, § 17, 43 DCR 4213</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-38" type="History">July 18, 2009, D.C. Law 18-38, § 2(j), 56 DCR 4290</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-1016.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-38">D.C. Law 18-38</cite>, in the introductory language, substituted “mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage loan originator, or loan officer” for “mortgage lender or mortgage broker”; and, in par. (2), substituted “mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage loan originator, or loan officer” for “lender or broker”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>Section 2(j) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-350">D.C. Law 17-350</cite>, in the lead-in text, substituted “mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage loan originator, or loan officer” for “mortgage lender or mortgage broker”; and, in par. (2), substituted “mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage loan originator, or loan officer” for “lender or broker”.</text>
      <text>Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-350">D.C. Law 17-350</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Mortgage Lender and Broker Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-617, December 22, 2008,  56 DCR 189).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(j) of Mortgage Lender and Broker Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-31, March 16, 2009,  56 DCR 2327).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-38">D.C. Law 18-38</cite> provided: “Sec. 3. Applicability. Except for section 2(c)(1), (g), (j), and (o), this act shall not apply until the Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking has promulgated rules implementing this act.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
