<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-1152.02</num>
  <heading>Insufficient repayment ability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A lender shall not make a covered loan if the borrower, at the time that the covered loan is closed, cannot reasonably be expected to make the scheduled payments. For purposes of making this determination:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The lender’s consideration shall include the ability to make any payments for mortgage insurance premiums, escrow deposits, or direct payment of real estate taxes and property insurance premiums (in addition to the payments of interest and principal) and the employment status of the borrower. The lender may consider the current and expected income, current obligations, and other financial resources of the borrower (other than the borrower’s equity in the dwelling which secures repayment of the loan).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The lender shall not consider the borrowers’ equity interest in the residential real property which secures repayment of the covered loan; provided, that the borrower’s equity interest in the residential real property which secures repayment of the covered loan may be considered by the lender in determining whether to approve the loan as part of the evaluation of the borrower’s likelihood of default.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In the case of a covered loan which includes payment terms under which the aggregate amount of the scheduled payments will not fully amortize the outstanding principal balance, the lender’s determination of the ability of the borrowers to make an expected balloon payment at the scheduled maturity date may include consideration of the borrowers’ equity interest in the residential real property and the borrowers’ ability, based on current market conditions, to refinance the covered loan without penalty, hardship, or material loss of equity.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A lender shall not include or add a borrower to the covered loan who did not own or reside in the residential real property securing the covered loan prior to the covered loan transaction for the purpose of increasing the income and ability of the borrowers owning or residing in the residential real property to make all the scheduled payments of interest, principal, and mortgage insurance premiums, and escrow deposits for, or direct payment of, real estate taxes and property insurance premiums, unless the included or added borrower separately confirms in writing to the lender that the borrower expects and commits to make or substantially contribute to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The scheduled payments on the covered loan; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Escrow deposits for or direct payment of real estate taxes and property insurance premiums.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The requirements of subsection (a) of this section shall only apply to borrowers whose gross income, as reported on the loan application which the lender relied upon in making the credit decision, does not exceed 120% of median family income. For purposes of this subsection, the median family income shall be the most recent estimate made by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development at the time the application is received. For purposes of determining gross income under this section, only the income of the borrower shall be considered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The current and expected income, current debts, current assets, and employment of the borrowers shall be verified by the lender in accordance with standard residential mortgage lending industry practices to underwrite a loan secured by a residential lien instrument. For the purposes of this subsection, the lender shall be deemed to have followed standard residential mortgage lending industry practices if the lender verified the borrowers’ current and expected income and current debts in accordance with the verification guidelines and practices of the Federal National Mortgage Association, Federal Home Loan Corporation, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, or U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude the utilization of other standard industry verification practices accepted by applicable regulatory authorities.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-132" type="History" path="§202">May 7, 2002, D.C. Law 14-132, § 202, 49 DCR 2551</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-1153.01">26-1153.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 202 of Home Loan Protection Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-295, March 1, 2002,  49 DCR 2534).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
