<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-131.04</num>
  <heading>Satellite device or point-of-sale terminal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A District bank, federal bank, out-of-state bank, District credit union, federal credit union, or out-of-state credit union which has established a satellite device or point-of-sale terminal in the District shall make the satellite device or point-of-sale terminal available on a nondiscriminatory basis for use by any other bank or credit union; provided, the establishing bank or credit union may require the other bank or credit union to pay a non-discriminatory and reasonably proportionate share of all acquisition, installation, and operating costs for the satellite device or point-of-sale terminal. The satellite device or point-of-sale terminal shall identify with equal prominence all of the banks, credit unions, or networks which use the satellite device or point-of-sale terminal.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A District bank, federal bank, out-of-state bank, District credit union, federal credit union, or out-of-state credit union which has established in the District an automated teller machine which is not a satellite device may permit any other bank or credit union to use the automated teller machine; provided, that if such permission is granted:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The automated teller machine which is not a satellite device shall be made available on a nondiscriminatory basis for use by any other bank or credit union; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The establishing bank or credit union may require a payment by the other bank or credit union of a nondiscriminatory and reasonably proportionate share of all acquisition, installation, and operating costs; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The automated teller machine shall identify with equal prominence all of the banks, credit unions, and networks which use the automated teller machine.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of subsections (a) and (b) of this subsection, the proportionality of the charge shall be based on the number of transactions processed at the satellite device or point-of-sale terminal.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-308" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, ยง 504, 48 DCR 3244</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
