<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-1022</num>
  <heading>Enforcement.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may institute an administrative cease and desist proceeding if the Superintendent [Commissioner] determines that a licensee or person required to have a license under this chapter or an authorized delegate has violated, is violating, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter or any rule, regulation or order imposed by the Superintendent [Commissioner], or written agreement entered into with the Superintendent [Commissioner] pursuant to this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A cease and desist proceeding shall be initiated by the issuance of a notice of charges which shall contain a statement of facts describing the alleged violations.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The notice of charges shall set a date, time, and place at which a hearing will be held to determine whether a cease and desist order should be issued against a licensee or person required to have a license. The hearing date shall be no earlier than 30 days and no later than 60 days, after the date of service of the notice, unless otherwise prescribed by the Superintendent [Commissioner] or the hearing officer.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A cease and desist order may require the person licensed, or required to be licensed, or authorized delegate to cease and desist the violation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may issue and serve upon the licensee, or person required to be licensed, or authorized delegate a final cease and desist order if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The licensee or person or authorized delegate agrees to settle the proceeding by consenting to the order as negotiated by the Superintendent [Commissioner], prior to the commencement of the hearing;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The licensee or person or authorized delegate served with the notice of charges fails to appear at the hearing, in which case the licensee or person or authorized delegate shall be deemed to have consented to the order as issued; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Substantial evidence in the hearing record supports the determination of the Superintendent [Commissioner] that the violation or violations specified in the notice of charges has transpired.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A final cease and desist order shall become effective 10 days after the service of the order in accordance with subsection (d) of this section, except that a final cease and desist order which has been issued upon consent shall become effective upon the date specified in the order. A final cease and desist order shall remain in effect until it is stayed, modified, terminated, or set aside by the Superintendent [Commissioner] or a reviewing court.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-140" type="History">July 18, 2000, D.C. Law 13-140, ยง 23, 47 DCR 3431</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
