<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-232</num>
  <heading>Exchange of securities or real estate for federal bonds.</heading>
  <text>Any building association incorporated or unincorporated, organized and existing under the laws of the District of Columbia, to do or now doing, in the District of Columbia, a building association business, is authorized and empowered to exchange mortgages or deeds of trust or the notes or bonds secured thereby or other obligations and liens secured on real estate or any real estate which it may have or hold, for the bonds of the Home Owners’ Loan Corporation created pursuant to the authority of the Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933, approved June 13, 1933, and said association is hereby authorized to carry said bonds as an asset at the par value of said bonds.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 56-2-ch854" path="§56">Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 854, § 56</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 27, 1934, 48 Stat. 506, ch. 96</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-710">26-710</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-517.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 26-416.</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">The Home Owners’ Loan Corporation, referred to in this section, was dissolved by the Act of June 30, 1953, 67 Stat. 126, ch. 170, § 21.</text>
    <text type="References in Text">The Home Owners’ Loan Act of 1933, approved June 13, 1933, referred to in this section, is codified in Chapter 12 of Title 12, United States Code, and, as amended, is referred to as the “Home Owners’ Loan Act.”.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
