<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-316</num>
  <heading>Revocation and suspension of license.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Superintendent [Commissioner] may revoke any license issued pursuant to this chapter if, after notice and a hearing, the Superintendent [Commissioner] finds that the licensee has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Committed any fraudulent acts, engaged in any dishonest activities, or made any misrepresentation in any business transaction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Been convicted of a felony under the laws of the District or the laws of any state or the United States;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Violated any provisions of the banking laws of the District or any rules or regulations promulgated thereunder, or has violated any other law in the course of dealings as a licensee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Made a material misstatement in the application for a license under this chapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Demonstrated incompetency or untrustworthiness to act as a licensee;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Violated any provision of this chapter or of any implementing regulation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Failed to satisfy any of the criteria for obtaining a license as set out in §§ <cite path="§26-306">26-306</cite>, <cite path="§26-307">26-307</cite>, or 26-308.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A hearing for the purposes of this section shall be held in accordance with subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2. Pending a hearing for the revocation of any license issued pursuant to this chapter, the Superintendent [Commissioner] may suspend the license for a period not to exceed 30 days if the Superintendent [Commissioner] determines that such a suspension is in the public interest and that one or more grounds for revocation of a license, as set forth in subsection (a) of this section, exist.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Whenever the Superintendent [Commissioner] suspends or revokes a license issued pursuant to this chapter, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall immediately execute a written order stating the grounds for the suspension or revocation.  On the date the order is executed, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall serve a copy thereof on the licensee either personally or by mailing the same to the last known address of the licensee.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-111" type="History">May 12, 1998, D.C. Law 12-111, § 17, 45 DCR 1782</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-1116.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
