<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-431.06</num>
  <heading>Rating system for community development performance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner shall establish, by regulation, a system to rate the community development performance of a financial institution. The system shall include the following rating categories:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Outstanding record of performance in meeting the credit needs of its local communities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Highly satisfactory record of performance in meeting the credit needs of its local communities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Satisfactory record of performance in meeting the credit needs of its local communities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Needs to improve record of performance in meeting the credit needs of its local communities; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Substantial noncompliance in meeting the credit needs of its local communities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner shall consider the compliance of the financial institution with the community development plan submitted under § <cite path="§26-431.03">26-431.03</cite> in assessing and rating the community development performance of the financial institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The CFO, when evaluating the community development plan of a deposit-receiving institution shall review the rating category or score assigned to the deposit-receiving institution’s plan by the applicable financial supervisory agency and shall publish the final review on its website.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The CFO shall receive public comments during a 30-day public comment period when reviewing and evaluating the community development plan of a deposit-receiving institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The CFO shall consider in the evaluation done pursuant to subsection (c) of this section whether a deposit-receiving institution is engaged in discriminatory, unfair, or deceptive lending practices as determined by federal agencies under the Equal Credit Opportunity Act, approved October 28, 1974 (88 Stat. 1521; 15 U.S.C. § 1691 et seq.), and the Fair Housing Act, approved September 13, 1988 (82 Stat. 81; 42 U.S.C. §§ 3601 et seq.), and their implementing regulations, or under Chapter 11A of this title [§ <cite path="§26-1151.01et">26-1151.01et</cite> seq.], or Chapter 39 of Title 28 [§ <cite path="§28-3901et">28-3901et</cite> seq.], and their implementing regulations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>To apply for a deposit services contract with the District government, a financial institution must receive at least a “satisfactory” rating on its most recent CRA exam.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-308" type="History" path="§406">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, § 406, 48 DCR 3244</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-226" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-226, § 2(d), 62 DCR 255</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-431.05">26-431.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-226">D.C. Law 20-226</cite> added (c) through (f).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
