<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-551.16</num>
  <heading>Cease and desist order.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may issue and serve upon the financial institution or its affiliate or subsidiary a final cease and desist order if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The party served with the notice of charges fails to appear at the hearing called under <cite path="§26-551.13">§ 26-551.13</cite>; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The record of the hearing held under <cite path="§26-551.13">§ 26-551.13</cite> supports a finding that the violation or unsafe and unsound practice specified in the notice of charges has occurred or reasonably likely to occur.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A final cease and desist order may require that a financial institution or a director, officer, trustee, employee, agent, affiliate, or subsidiary of the financial institution:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Cease and desist from the violation or unsafe or unsound practice or from any activity that will or may result in a violation or unsafe or unsound practice;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Take affirmative action to correct the violation, unsafe or unsound practice, or condition resulting from the violation or unsafe or unsound practice or to avoid a violation or unsafe or unsound practice; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide indemnification, reimbursement, restitution, or any other relief that the Commissioner determines is appropriate.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A final cease and desist order shall become effective 30 days after the service of the order upon the financial institution or its affiliate or subsidiary; provided, that a final cease and desist order which has been issued upon the consent of the Commissioner and a financial institution or other parties shall become effective upon the date specified in the consent order.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A final cease and desist order shall remain in effect until it is stayed, modified, terminated, or set aside by the Commissioner or a court.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>In addition to, or instead of, issuing a final cease and desist order, the Commissioner may enter into an informal enforcement action, such as a supervisory agreement or memorandum of understanding, with the financial institution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-308" type="History" path="§116">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, § 116, 48 DCR 3244</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
