<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>26-551.11</num>
  <heading>Reports on financial institutions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise provided by the District of Columbia Banking Code, the Commissioner shall require each financial institution to submit a financial report on a quarterly basis (“quarterly financial report”). The quarterly financial report shall fully describe the financial condition of the reporting financial institution. The Commissioner may accept the most recent quarterly report filed by the financial institution with its appropriate federal financial institutions agency in the place of a quarterly financial report.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A quarterly financial report shall be filed with the Commissioner within 30 days after the end of each calendar quarter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may require a financial institution to submit a special financial report if the Commissioner determines that a special financial report will assist the Commissioner in ensuring the safe and sound condition and operation of the financial institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A special financial report shall be filed with the Commissioner within 30 days of the receipt of a request for the special financial report from the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A quarterly financial report or a special financial report required under this section shall be signed and certified as accurate by the president or chief executive officer of the reporting financial institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner may accept a report, examination, or other information from a state or federal agency or regulatory body concerning the activities of a financial institution or its affiliate or subsidiary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Commissioner shall prescribe forms to be used to comply with this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-308" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, § 111, 48 DCR 3244</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
