<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-637</num>
  <heading>Registered office and agent.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An international banking corporation authorized to establish and maintain a banking office in the District of Columbia shall have and continuously maintain:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A registered office in the District of Columbia which may, but shall not be required to, be the same as its place of business; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A registered agent, which agent may be either an individual residing in the District of Columbia whose business office is identical with the registered office or a corporation authorized to transact business in the District of Columbia having a business office identical with the registered office.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A registered agent may at any time vacate its office as registered agent by filing with the Commissioner a statement setting forth its resignation and the effective date thereof, which shall not be less than 60 days nor more than 90 days after the date of filing. A copy of the statement shall be served on the international banking corporation by registered or certified mail addressed to the international banking corporation at its principal office, as such is known to the resigning agent, and directed to the attention of the secretary or other comparable officer of the international banking corporation within 5 days after the date of the filing.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An international banking corporation may from time to time change the address of its registered office and shall change its registered agent if the office of the registered agent becomes vacant for any reason, if its registered agent becomes disqualified or incapacitated to act, or if it revokes the appointment of its registered agent. A change of registered office or registered agent may be effected by filing with the Commissioner duplicate originals of a statement setting forth the details with respect to the change and the effective date thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Service of process in a suit, action, or proceeding, or service of a notice or demand required or permitted by law to be served on an international banking corporation, may be made on a licensed international banking corporation by serving the registered agent of the international banking corporation. If a licensed international banking corporation fails to appoint or maintain a registered agent upon whom legal process or a notice or demand may be served, the registered agent cannot with reasonable diligence be found at the registered office of the international banking corporation, or the license of an international banking corporation is revoked, the Commissioner shall be irrevocably authorized as the agent and representative of the international banking corporation to accept service of process or a notice or demand required or permitted by law to be served on the international banking corporation. Service on the Commissioner of any process, notice, or demand for the international banking corporation shall be made by delivering to and leaving with the Commissioner, or with any official having charge of the Department, duplicate copies of the process, notice, or demand. If any process, notice, or demand is served on the Commissioner, the Commissioner shall immediately forward a copy by registered mail to the international banking corporation at its principal office as the same appears on the Department’s records. Nothing in this chapter shall limit or affect the right to serve any process, notice, or demand required or permitted by law to be served upon a foreign corporation in any other manner now or hereafter permitted by law. The Commissioner shall keep a record of all process, notices, and demands served upon the Commissioner under this section, setting forth the time of service and the Commissioner’s action on the service.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-268" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-268, § 8, 48 DCR 1251</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-313" type="History">June 19, 2001, D.C. Law 13-313, § 25, 48 DCR 1873</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-313">D.C. Law 13-313</law-cite>, in subsec. (d), deleted the former fifth sentence which read: “Service on the Commissioner shall be returnable in not less than 30 days.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
