<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-733</num>
  <heading>De novo branching or acquisition of a branch into a state other than the District.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>With the approval of the Superintendent [Commissioner of the Department of Insurance, Securities, and Banking], a District state bank may establish and maintain a de novo branch or acquire a branch in a state other than the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A District state bank (“applicant”) desiring to branch into a state other than the District under this section shall file an application on a form provided by the Superintendent [Commissioner] and pay a branching fee of $500 to the Superintendent [Commissioner]. If, within 30 days after receipt of the application, the Superintendent [Commissioner] determines that the applicant possesses sufficient resources to branch into a state other than the District, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall approve the application.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In reviewing the application, the Superintendent [Commissioner] shall consider the views of the state bank supervisor of the host state where the branch is proposed to be located.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the Superintendent [Commissioner] fails to approve or disapprove an application within 30 days of receipt, the application shall be deemed approved. The Superintendent [Commissioner] may extend this 30-day review period for an additional 30 days upon a showing of good cause.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A District state bank that branches into a state other than the District may exercise, at that branch, all rights and powers permitted to banks chartered by that state unless the Superintendent [Commissioner] determines that the exercise of such rights or powers would threaten the safety and soundness of the District bank.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-142" type="History" path="§4">June 13, 1996, D.C. Law 11-142, § 4, 43 DCR 2159</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-853.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-257">D.C. Law 11-257</cite> amended (a) to read as follows.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) No person shall engage in business as a mortgage lender or mortgage broker, or both, or hold himself or herself out to the public to be a mortgage lender or mortgage broker for 150 days after the effective date of this chapter, unless such person has first obtained a license under this chapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 11-257">D.C. Law 11-257</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Fees credited to the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions Enterprise Fund: Section 1804(3) of D.C. Law 12-60 provided that all fees received pursuant to § 26-853(b) 1981 Ed. shall be credited to the Office of Banking and Financial Institutions Enterprise Fund.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
