<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-802</num>
  <heading>Property in boxes, vaults or held for safekeeping for 2 or more persons; right of access or delivery; liability of bank.</heading>
  <text>When a safety deposit box or vault shall have been hired from any bank, trust company, savings bank, building association, or other banking institution, including national banks, or any other corporation, transacting business in the District of Columbia, in the names of 2 or more persons, including spouses or domestic partners, with the right of access being given to either, or with access to either or the survivor or survivors of said persons, or property is held for safekeeping by any such bank, trust company, savings bank, building association, or other corporation or banking institution, including national banks, for 2 or more persons, including spouses or domestic partners, with the right of delivery being given to either, or with the right of delivery to either or the survivor or survivors of said persons, any one or more of such persons, whether the other or others be living or not, shall have the right of access to such safety deposit box or vault and to remove the contents thereof, or any part of such contents, or to have delivered to him or them, the property so held for safekeeping, or any part thereof, and in case of such removal or delivery the said bank, trust company, savings bank, building association, or other corporation or banking institution, including national banks, shall be exempt from any liability for permitting such access or removal or for the delivery to such person or persons. For the purposes of this section, the term “domestic partner” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3).</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 15, 1928, 45 Stat. 534, ch. 568, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231,§ 25(b), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§26-710">26-710</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 26-202.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 26-202.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</law-cite> substituted “spouses or domestic partners” for “husband and wife”; and added “For the purposes of this section, the term ‘domestic partner’ shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§32-701">32-701</cite>(3).”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
