<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>26-831.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Affiliate” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(1).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Appropriate financial institutions agency” means the federal or state agency with statutory authority over the financial institution activities of a financial institution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Capital” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(6).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Commissioner” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(7).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Department” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(9).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Deposit” means a demand, time, or savings deposit, savings share account, withdrawable or repurchasable share, investment certificate, or other savings account or savings deposit account made by an individual, corporation, partnership, state or federal government unit, or any other government organization, without regard to the location of the depositor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“District of Columbia Banking Code” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(14).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Financial institution” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(18).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Merchant bank” means a financial institution that is chartered or organized under the District of Columbia Banking Code as a merchant bank and is under the authority and supervision of the Commissioner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Subsidiary” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-551.02">26-551.02</cite>(24).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Superior Court” means Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Universal bank” shall have the same meaning as set forth in § <cite path="§26-1401.02">26-1401.02</cite>(28).</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-308" type="History" path="§302">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-308, § 302, 48 DCR 3244</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-166" type="History">June 11, 2004, D.C. Law 15-166, § 2(i), 51 DCR 2817</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-166">D.C. Law 15-166</cite> rewrote pars. (4) and (5) which had read as follows: (4) “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Department of Banking and Financial Institutions. “(5) ‘Department’ means the Department of Banking and Financial Institutions.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(i) of Consolidation of Financial Services Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-381, February 27, 2004,  51 DCR 2653).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
