<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-101">
  <num type="law">9-101</num>
  <heading type="short">Vital Records Adoptive Birth Registration Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-05-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-101.pdf">D.C. Law 9-101</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 2146</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0192">
      <narrative>Law 9-101, the “Vital Records Adoptive Birth Registration Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-192, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 4, 1992, and March 3, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 23, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-173 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-101 became effective on May 21, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>E ROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 246 494 oo 0 AN ACT D, C, ACT 9-173 Enrolled Original Codifioation Disldot of Oolumbla Oo¢lt {_ 1993 Sup IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 23, 1992 To amend section 16-314 of the District of Columbia Code and the Vital ttecords Act of 1981 to allow for the issuance of a new certificate of birth for adopted persons born outside of the United States. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Vital l~ecords Adoptive Birth Registration Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. Section 16-314 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by adding a new subsection (c-l) to read as follows c-l) If the birth of the adoptee occurred outside of the United States, a new certificate of birth shall be made pursuant to section 11 of the Vital l~ecords Act of 1981 See. 3. Section ii of the Vital Records Act of 1981, effective October 8, 1981 (D.C. Law 4-34; D.C. Code §6-210 is amended by adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a--l) The Registrar shall establish a new certificate of birth for an adoptee born outside of the United States, upon receipt of a request from the adopting parents, or the adoptee if 18 years of age or older, and receipt of one of the following documents 1) An adoption form prepared according to section 10; or 2) An adoption decree and the original certificate of birth, or evidence as to the date and place of birth of the adoptee from sources determined by the court to be reliable, prepared according to the laws of the country where the birth occurred Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and Section 16-314 Section 6-210 Enrolled Original publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal ]~egulations C,77 o~ the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: March 23, 1992 @ COL~NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLLqMB~A Council Period Nine Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Readinq, 2-4-92 Approved Evans G ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCILMEMBER C~MN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT ~RAWFORD ~SON CROPP tNATHANSONEVANS RA_Y~ X Indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY [ N.V. A.B ’ Secr~ry to the Council ~{ Iterr/on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER Bill 9-192 CI~IN. WILSON X Indicates Vote AYE NAY !N.V. BRAZIL CRAw~ot@ CROPP E~ANS A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER Secret r~c[ t~e’Council Item o Consent Calendar ROLAPX SMITH, JR. THOMAS SR. N.V Present, not voting ate f ’ Adopted Final Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER JARVI$ LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY CERTIFICATION RECORD 3-3-92 AYE NAY N.V. I A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK. SMITH. JR. THOYLAS SR. AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: r- VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CIIMN, WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP I X Indicates Vote AYE NAY NV. A.B.COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A,B Absent N.V Present, not votm CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCILMEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR AYE NAY I N.V, t NV. A.B. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
