<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-109">
  <num type="law">9-109</num>
  <heading type="short">Pipeline Safety Penal Provisions Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-05-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-109.pdf">D.C. Law 9-109</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 2158</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0339">
      <narrative>Law 9-109, the “Pipeline Safety Penal Provisions Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-339, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 4, 1992, and March 3, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 23, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-181 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-109 became effective on May 21, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 247 198 Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-181 Dlmrlct C le t 9 9~3 j_ t~uppllilmi~t) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MARCH 23, 1992 To amend An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen, and for other purposes to increase the penalties for violations of the regulations of the Public Service Commission governing safety of pipeline facilities and the transportation of gas. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT O1~ COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Pipeline Safety Penal Provisions Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. The second paragraph of Paragraph 85, of Section 8 of An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen, and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1913 (37 Star. 992; D.C. Code §43-306(b is amended to read as follows Any person who violates any regulation issued by the Commission governing safety of pipeline facilities and the transportation of gas, shall be subject to a civil penalty as set forth in the Commission’s regulations, title 15 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (15 DCMP for each violation for each day that violation persists. Civil penalties established by the Commission shall not exceed the maximum civil penalties established by federal laws and regulations governing the safety of pipeline facilities and the transportation of gas Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Celumbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Section 43-306 Enrolled Original Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations f Chairf ’ District of Columbia APPROVED: March 23, 1992 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 2-4-92 Approved Evans ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CHIN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL f LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD ~L&amp;amp;SON !CROPP NATFLMN SON EVANS I RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent COUNCIL MEMBER CN}~N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS Bill AYE NAY N.V. A.B. 9-339 N.V Present, not voting COUNCIL MEMBER ROI, A~.24 SMITH JR. TI-[OEAS, SR. Date ’ /I/’~ CERTIFICATION RECORD Secret~l tnO e Council]~ Item orl Consent Cae d ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.Y. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER Adopted Final Reading, 3-3-92 Approved AYE NAY NV. N.V Present, not voting JARV I LIGHTFOOT MASON NAT HANS ON RAY A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROLARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS SR. Date X indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY N.V NAY NV A.B. ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER ,C~MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP RVANg AYE NAY N.V t X Indicates Vote AB. ICQUNCILMEMBER IJARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD CQUNCILMEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY N V AB. SecretaP/to the Councd Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
