<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-103">
  <num type="law">9-103</num>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-103.pdf">D.C. Law 9-103</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 9-103, the ’Community-Based Residential Facilities Act of 1992“, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-228. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 4, 1992, and March 3, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 23, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-175 and transmitted to Both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-103 became effective on May 21, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENR LLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 246 606 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-103 "Community-Based Residential Facilities Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-228 on first and second readings, February 4, 1992, and March 3, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on March 23, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-175, published in the April 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 2149) and transmitted to Congress on March 25, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-103, effective May 21, 1992. Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: March Apr i 1 May 25,26,27,30,31 1,2,3,6,7,8,9,10,28,29,30 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20 Enrolled Original AN ACT D.C, ACT 9-175 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OIR COLUMBIA RCIL21 To require the Mayor to provide notice to the District of Columbia Board of Education or the governing body of a private or parochial school of the establishment or operation of certain facilities within 400 £eet of a school, or the adjacent school grounds, used for the instruction of minors. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF TtIE DISTRICT O]~ COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Community-Based Residential Facilities Act of 1992 See. 2.(a) The Mayor shall give at least 60 days written notice to the District of Columbia Board of Education or the governing body of a private or parochial school of the proposed establishment of a homeless shelter, correctional facility, halfway house, or drug treatment center, to be located within 400 feet of a school, or adjacent school grounds in the District of Columbia, used for the instruction of minors b) The Mayor shall give great weight to written comments of the District of Columbia Board of Education in. regard to the establishment or current operation of a homeless shelter, correctional facility, halfway house, or drug treatment center located within 400 feet of a District of Columbia public school, or the adjacent school grounds, used for the instruction of minors. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event o veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and Enrolled Original publication in either the District of Columbia ttegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal l~egulations. Chairman~ Council ~5£/the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: March 23, 1992 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLLrMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: 9-228 Adopted First Rea4ingi 2-4-92 Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Evans ROLL CALL VOTE RESUL COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. WILSON BRAZIL ~c .RA~ WFORD CROPP EVANS AY, E ]NAY NV. AIB, X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~SON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting S ~rv to’the CERTIFICATION RECORD ecrr Council i Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final X VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request COUNCIL MEMBER AYE RO1LAP._K SMITH JR THoMAs, SR. Readinq, 3-3-92 NAY N.V. A,B. Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~fN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON C RO P P NATHAN S ON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER N.V Present, not voting ~OLARK ~HITH. JR. THOMAS, SR CERTIFICATION RECORD Secret~-to the Council Item on Consent Calendar AYE ’ \ Date -ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICEVOTE: Recordedvoteonrequest Absent: C ROLL CALLVOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CII WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD EVANS AYE NAY N.V. A.B F X Indicates Vote COUNCILMEMBER-AYE NAY N.V B. COUNCILMEMBER JARVIS ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR, MASON I THOMAS. SR. A.8 Absent N.V Present, not votin~ CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
