<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-128" flag="true">
  <num type="law">9-128</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Commercial Code, Leases, Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-07-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-128.pdf">D.C. Law 9-128</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 3830</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0019">
      <narrative>Law 9-128, the “Uniform Commercial Code, Leases, Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-19, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 7, 1992, and May 6, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 28, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-212 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-128 became effective on July 22, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 247 500 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-128 "Uniform Commercial Code, Leases, Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-19 on first and second readings, April 7, 1992, and May 6, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 28, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-212, published in the June 5, 1992, edition of the DoC. Register Vol. 39 page 3830) and transmitted to Congress on May 29, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-128, effective July 22, 1992 z~7 Chairman of Council Dates Counted During the 30 ongressional Review Period: May 29 June 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26, 29,30 July 1,2,7,8,9,20,21 Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-212 CodifieaUon District of Columbia Oode Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 28, 1992 To enact the Uniform Commercial Code, Article 2A Leases in the District of Columbia and to make conforming amendments in Articles 1 and 9. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code, Leases, Act of 1992 See. 2. Subtitle 1 of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code, the Uniform Commercial Code, is amended as follows a) The analysis is amended by adding after the caption for Article 2, Sales, the following 2A. Leases §§28:2A-101 to 2A-531 b) The following new article is inserted after Article 2 ARTICLE 2A. LEASES Part 1. General Provisions See 28:2A-101. Short title 28:2A-102. Scope 28:2A-103. Definitions and index of definitions 28:2A-104. Leases subject to other laws 28:2A-105. Territorial application of article to goods covered by certificate of title 28:2A-106. Limitation on power of parties to consumer lease to choose applicable law and judicial forum 28:2A-107. Waiver or renunciation of claim or right after default 28: 2A-108. Unconscionability 28:2A-109. Option to accelerate at will Part 2. Formation and Construction of Lease Contract 28 2A-201 "28 2A- 202 "28 2A- 203 "28 2A-204 "28 2A- 205 "28 2A- 206 "28 2A- 207 Statute of frauds. Final written expression: parol or extrinsic evidence. Seals inoperative. Formation in. general. Firm offers. Offer and acceptance in formation of lease contract. Course of performance or practical construction. Enrolled Original "28:2A-208. Modification, rescission, and waiver 28:2A-209. Lessee under finance lease as beneficiary of supply contract 28:2A-210. Express warranties 28:2A-211. Warranties against interference and against infringement; lessee’s obligation against infringement 28:2A-212. Implied warranty of merchantability 28:2A-213. Implied warranty of fitness for particular purpose 28:2A-214. Exclusion or modification of warranties 28:2A-215. Cumulation and conflict of warranties express or implied 28:2A-216. Third party beneficiaries of express and implied warranties 28:2A-217. Identification 28:2A-218. Insurance and proceeds 28:2A-219. l~isk of loss 28:2A-220. Effect of default on risk of loss 28:2A-221. Casualty to identified goods Part 3. Effect of Lease Contract 28:2A-301. Enforceability of lease contract 28:2A-302. Title to and possession of goods 28:2A-303. Alienability of party’s interest under lease contract or of lessor’s residual interest in goods; delegation of performance; transfer of rights 28:2A-304. Subsequent lease of goods by lessor 28:2A-305. Sale or sublease of goods by lessee 28:2A-306. Priority of certain liens arising by operation of law 28:2A-307. Priority of liens arising by attachment or levy on, security interests in, and other claims to goods 28:2A-308. Special rights of creditors 28:2A-309. Lessor’s and lessee’s rights when goods become fixtures 28:2A-310. Lessor’s and lessee’s rights when goods become accessions 28:2A-311. Priority subject to subordination Part 4. Performance of Lease Contract: Repudiated, Substituted, and Excused 28:2A-401. Insecurity: adequate assurance of performance 28:2A-402. Anticipatory repudiation 28:2A-403. l~etraction of anticipatory repudiation 28:2A-404. Substituted performance 28:2A-405. Excused performance 28:2A-406. Procedure on excused performance 28:2A-407. Irrevocable promises: finance le es Part 5. General A. In General 28:2A-501. Default: procedure 28:2A-502. Notice after default 28:2A-503. Modification or impairment of rights and remedies 28:2A-504. Liquidation of damages 28:2A-505. Cancellation and termination and effect of cancellation, termination, rescission, or fraud on rights and remedies 28:2A-506. Statute of limitations 28:2A-507. Proof of market rent: time and place. Enrolled Original "B. Default by Lessor 28:2A-508. Lessee’s remedies 28:2A-509. Lessee’s rights on improper delivery; rightful rejection 28:2A-510. Installment lease contracts: rejection and default 28:2A-511. Merchant lessee’s duties as to rightfully rejected goods 28:2A-512. Lessee’s duties as to rightfully rejected goods 28:2A-513. Cure by lessor of improper tender or delivery replacement 28:2A-514. Waiver of lessee’s objections 28:2A-515. Acceptance of goods 28:2A-516. Effect of acceptance of goods; notice of default, burden of establishing default after acceptance; notice of claim or litigation to person answerable over 28:2A-517. Revocation of acceptance of goods 28:2A-518. Cover; substitute goods 28:2A-519. Lessee’s damages for nondelivery, repudiation, default, and breach of warranty in regard to accepted goods 28:2A-520. Lessee’s incidental and consequential damages 28:2A-521. Lessee’s right to specific performance or replevin 28:2A-522. Lessee’s right to goods on lessor’s insolvency C. Default by Lessee 28:2A-523. Lessor’s remedies 28:2A-524. Lessor’s right to identify goods to lease contract 28:2A-525. Lessor’s right to possession of goods 28:2A-526. Lessor’s stoppage of delivery in transit or otherwise 28:2A-527. Lessor’s rights to dispose of goods 28:2A-528. Lessor’s damages for nonacceptance, failure to pay, repudiation, or other default 28:2A-529. Lessor’s action for the rent 28:2A-530. Lessor’s incidental damages 28:2A-531. Standing to sue third parties for injury to goods 28:2A-532. Lessor’s right to residual interest PART 1. GENERAL PROVISIONS §28:2A-101. Short title This article shall be known and may be cited as the Uniform Commercial Code Leases §28:2A-102. Scope This article applies to any transaction, regardless of form, that creates a lease §28:2A-103. Definitions and index of definitions a) In this article unless the context otherwise requires 1 Buyer in ordinary course of business" means a person who in good faith and without knowledge that the sale to him or her is in violation of the ownership rights or security interest or leasehold interest of a third party in the goods buys in ordinary course from a person in the business of selling goods of that kind but does not include a pawnbroker Buying" may be for cash or by exchange of other property or on secured or unsecured credit and includes receiving goods or documents of title under a pre-existing contract for sale but does not include a transfer in bulk or as security for or in total or partial satisfaction of a money debt 2 Cancellation" occurs when either party puts an end to the lease contract for default by the other party. New Sec. 28:2A-101 New Sec. 28:2A-I02 New Sec. 28:2A-103 Enrolled Original ~1(3 Commercial uniCv means such a unit of goods as by commercial usage is a single whole for purposes of lease and division of which materially impairs its character or value on the market or in use. A commercial unit may be a single article, as a machine, or a set of articles, as a suite of furniture or a line of machinery, or a quantity, as a gross or carload, or any other unit treated in use or in the relevant market as a single whole 4 Conforming" goods or performance under a lease contract means goods or performance that are in accordance with the obligations under the lease contract 5 Consumer lease" means a lease that a lessor regularly engaged in the business of leasing or selling makes to a lessee who is an individual and who takes under the lease primarily for a personal, family, or household purpose, if the total payments to be made under the lease contract, excluding payments for options to renew or buy, do not exceed $25,000 6 ’ault" means wrongful act, omission, breach, or default 7 t~inance lease~v means a lease with respect to which A) The lessor does not select, manufacture, or supply the goods B) The lessor acquires the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods in connection with the lease; and ~I(C) One of the following occurs i) The lessee receives a copy of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods before signing the lease contract ii) The lessee~s approval of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods is a condition to effectiveness of the lease contract iii) The lessee, before signing the lease contract, receives an accurate and complete statement designating the promises and warranties, and any disclaimer of warranties, limitations or modifications of remedies, or liquidated damages, including those of a third party, such as the manufacturer of the goods, provided to the lessor by the person supplying the goods in connection with or as part of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods; or iv) If the lease is not a consumer lease, the lessor, before the lessee signs the lease contract, informs the lessee in writing of the identity of the person supplying the goods to the lessor, unless the lessee has selected that person and directed the lessor to acquire the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods from that person; that the lessee is entitled under this article to the promises and warranties, including those of any third party, provided to the lessor by the person supplying the goods in connection with or as part of the contract by which the lessor acquired the goods or the right to possession and use of the goods; and that the lessee may communicate with the person supplying the goods to the lessor and receive an accurate and complete statement of those promises and warranties, including any disclaimers and limitations of them or of remedies 8 Goods" means all things that are movable at the time of identification to the lease contract, or are fixtures (§28:2A-309 but the term does not include money, documents, instruments, accounts, chattel Enrolled Original paper, general intangibles, or minerals or the like, including oil and gas, before extraction. The term also includes the unborn young of animals. 11(9) IVInstallment lease contracC~ means a lease contract that authorizes or requires the delivery of goods in separate lots to be separately accepted, even though the lease contract contains a clause "each delivery is a separate lease" or its equivalent. I~(10 Lease" means a transfer of the right to possession and use of goods for a term in return for consideration, but a sale, including a sale on approval or a sale or return, or retention or creation of a security interest is not a lease. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublease 11 Lease agreement" means the bargain, with respect to the lease, of the lessor and the lessee in fact as found in their language or by implication from other circumstances including course of dealing or usage of trade or course of performance as provided in this article. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublease agreement 12 Lease contract" means the total legal obligation that results from the lease agreement as affected by this article and any other applicable rules of law. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublease contract 13 Leasehold interest" means the interest of the lessor or the lessee under a lease contract 14 Lessee" means a person who acquires the right to possession and use of goods under a lease. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublessee 15 Lessee in ordinary course of business" means a person who in good faith and without knowledge that the lease to him or her is in violation of the ownership rights or security interest or leasehold interest of a third party in the goods leases in ordinary course from a person in the business of selling or leasing goods of that kind but does not include a pawnbroker Leasing" may be for cash or by exchange of other property or on secured or unsecured credit and includes receiving goods or documents of title under a pre-existing lease contract but does not include a transfer in bulk or as security for or in total or partial satisfaction of a money debt 16) frLessor" means a person who transfers the right to possession and use of goods under a lease. Unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the term includes a sublessor. 11(17 Lessorls residual interest" means the lessor~s interest in the goods after expiration, termination, or cancellation of the lease contract 18 Lien" means a charge against or interest in goods to secure payment of a debt or performance of an obligation, but the term does not include a security interest. II(19 Lot1I means a parcel or a single article that is the subject matter of a separate lease or delivery, whether or not it is sufficient to perform the lease contract. ’I(20 Merchant lessee" means a lessee that is a merchant with respect to goods of the kind subject to the lease 21) 1~Present value~ means the amount as of a date certain of one or more sums payable in the future, discounted to the date certain. The discount is determined by the interest rate specified by the parties Enrolled Original if the rate was not manifestly unreasonable at the time the transaction was entered into; otherwise, the discount is determined by a commercially reasonable rate that takes into account the facts and circumstances of each case at the time the transaction was entered into 22 Purchase" includes taking by sale, lease, mortgage, security interest, pledge, gift, or any other voluntary transaction creating an interest in goods 23 Sublease" means a lease of goods the right to possession and use of which was acquired by the lessor as a lessee under an existing lease 24 Supplier" means a person from whom a lessor buys or leases goods to be leased under a finance lease 25 Supply contract" means a contract under which a lessor buys or leases goods to be leased 26 Termination" occurs when either party pursuant to a power created by agreement or law puts an end to the lease contract otherwise than for default b) Other definitions applying to this article .and the sections in which they appear are Accessions §28:2A-310(a Construction mortgage §28:2A-309(a)(4 Encumbrance §28:2A-309(a 5 Fixture filing §28:2A-309(a)(2 Fixtures §28:2A-309(a)(1) ¯ "Purchase money lease §28:2A-309(a)(3 c) The following definitions in other articles apply to this article Account §28:9-106 Between merchants §28:2-104(3 Buyer §28:2-103(1 a) ¯ "Chattel paper §28:9-105(1)(b Consumer goods §28:9-109(1 Document §28:9-105(1 f Entrusting §28:2-403(3 General intangibles §28:9-106 Good faith §28:2-103(1 b Instrument §28:9-105(1 i Merchant §28:2-104(1 Mortgage §28:9-105(1 j Pursuant to commitment §28:9-105(1)(k Receipt §28:2-103(1)(c) ¯ "Sale §28:2-106(1 Sale on approval §28:2-326 Sale or return §28:2-326 Seller §28:2-103(1 d) ¯ d) In addition Article 1 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article §28:2A-104. Leases subject to other law a) A lease, although subject to this article, is also subject to any applicable 1) Certificate of title statute of the District 2) Certificate of title statute of another jurisdiction (§28:2A-105 or 6 New Sec. 28: 2A- 104 Enrolled Original 3) Consumer protection statute of the District, or final consumer protection decision of a court of the District existing on the effective date of this article b) In case of conflict between this article, other than §§28:2A-105, 28:2A-304(c and 28:2A-305(c and a statute or decision referred to in subsection (a) of this section, the statute controls c) Failure to comply with an applicable law has only the effect specified therein §28:2A-105. Territorial application of article to goods covered by certificate of title Subject to the provisions of §§28:2A-304(c) and 28:2A-305(c with respect to goods covered by a certificate of title issued under a statute of the District or of another jurisdiction, compliance and the effect of compliance or noncompliance with a certificate of title statute are governed by the law (including the conflict of laws rules) of the jurisdiction issuing the certificate until the earlier of (i) surrender of the certificate, or (ii) 4 months after the goods are removed from that jurisdiction and thereafter until a new certificate of title is issued by another jurisdiction §28:2A-106. Limitation on power of parties to consumer lease to choose applicable law and judicial forum a) If the law chosen by the parties to a consumer lease is that of a jurisdiction other than a jurisdiction in which the lessee resides at the time the lease agreement becomes enforceable or within 30 days thereafter or in which the goods are to be used, the choice is not enforceable b) If the judicial forum chosen by the parties to a consumer lease is a forum that would not otherwise have jurisdiction over the lessee, the choice is not enforceable §28:2A-107 aiver or renunciation of claim or right after default Any claim or right arising out of an alleged default or breach of warranty may be discharged in whole or in part without consideration by a written waiver or renunciation signed and delivered by the aggrieved party §28:2A-108. Unconscionability a) If the court as a matter of law finds a lease contract or any clause of a lease contract to have been unconscionable at the time it was made the court may refuse to enforce the lease contract, or it may enforce the remainder of the lease contract without the unconscionable clause, or it may so limit the application of any unconscionable clause as to avoid any unconscionable result b) With respect to a consumer lease, if the court as a matter of law finds that a lease contract or any clause of a lease contract has been induced by unconscionable conduct or that unconscionable conduct has occurred in the collection of a claim arising from a lease contract, the court may grant appropriate relief c) Before making a finding of unconscionability under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the court, on its own motion or that of a party, shall afford the parties a reasonable opportunity to present evidence as to the setting, purpose, and effect of the lease contract or clause thereof, or of the conduct d) In an action in which the lessee claims unconscionability with respect to a consumer lease: New Sec. 28:2A-I05 New Sec. 28: 2A- 106 New Sec. 28:2A-107 New Sec. 28:2A-108 7 nrolled Original 1) If the court finds unconscionability under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees to the lessee 2) If the court does not find unconscionability and the lessee claiming unconscionability has brought or maintained an action he or she knew to be groundless, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees to the party against whom the claim is made 3) In determining attorney’s fees, the amount of the recovery on behalf of the claimant under subsections (a) and (b) of this section is not controlling §28:2A-109. Option to accelerate at will a) A term providing that one party or his or her successor in interest may accelerate payment or performance or require collateral or additional collateral "at will" or "when he or she deems himself or herself insecure" or in words of similar import must be construed to mean that he or she has power to do so only if he or she in good faith believes that the prospect of payment or performance is impaired b) With respect to a consumer lease, the burden of establishing good faith under subsection (a) of this section is on the party who exercised the power; otherwise the burden of establishing lack of good faith is on the party against whom the power has been exercised PART 2. FORMATION AND CONSTRUCTION OF LEASE CONTRACT §28:2A-201. Statute of frauds a) A lease contract is not enforceable by way of action or defense unless 1) The total payments to be made under the lease contract, excluding payments for options to renew or buy, are less than $1,000; or 2) There is a writing, signed by the party against whom enforcement is sought or by that party’s authorized agent, sufficient to indicate that a lease contract has been made between the parties and to describe the goods leased and the lease term b) Any description of leased goods or of the lease term is sufficient and satisfies subsection (a)(2) of this section, whether or not it is specific, if it reasonably identifies what is described c) A writing is not insufficient because it omits or incorrectly states a term agreed upon, but the lease contract is not enforceable under subsection (a)(2) of this section beyond the lease term and the quantity of goods shown in the writing d) A lease contract that does not satisfy the requirements of subsection (a) of this section, but which is valid in other respects, is enforceable 1) If the goods are to be specially manufactured or obtained for the lessee and are not suitable for lease or sale to others in the ordinary course of the lessor’s business, and the lessor, before notice of repudiation is received and under circumstances that reasonably indicate that the goods are for the lessee, has made either a substantial beginning of their manufacture or commitments for their procurement 2) If the party against whom enforcement is sought admits in that party’s pleading, testimony, or otherwise in court that a lease New Sec. 28:2A-109 New Sec. 28: 2A 201 8 Enrolled Original contract was made, but the lease contract is not enforceable under this provision beyond the quantity of goods admitted; or 3) Nith respect to goods that have been received and accepted by the lessee e) The lease term under a lease contract referred to in subsection (d) of this section is 1) If there is a writing signed by the party against whom enforcement is sought or by that party’s authorized agent specifying the lease term, the term so specified 2) If the party against whom enforcement is sought admits in that party’s pleading, testimony, or otherwise in court a lease term, the term so admitted; or 3) A reasonable lease term §28:2A-202. Final written expression: parol or extrinsic evidence Terms with respect to which the confirmatory memoranda of the parties agree or which are otherwise set forth in a writing intended by the parties as a final expression of their agreement with respect to such terms as are included therein may not be contradicted by evidence of any prior agreement or of a contemporaneous oral agreement but may be explained or supplemented 1) By course of dealing or usage of trade or by course of performance; and 2) By evidence of consistent additional terms unless the court finds the writing to have been intended also as a complete and exclusive statement of the terms of the agreement §28:2A-203. Seals inoperative The affixing of a seal to a writing evidencing a lease contract or an offer to enter into a lease contract does not render the writing a sealed instrument and the law with respect to sealed instruments does not apply to the lease contract or offer §28:2A-204. Formation in general a) A lease contract may be made in any manner sufficient to show agreement, including conduct by both parties which recognizes the existence of a lease contract b) An agreement sufficient to constitute a lease contract may be found although the moment of its making is undetermined c) Although one or more terms are left open, a lease contract does not fail for indefiniteness if the parties have intended to make a lease contract and there is a reasonably certain basis for giving an appropriate remedy §28:2A-205. Firm offers An offer by a merchant to lease goods to or from another person in a signed writing that by its terms gives assurance it will be held open is not revocable, for lack of consideration, during the time stated or, if no time is stated, for a reasonable time, but in no event may the period of irrevocability exceed 3 months. Any such term of assurance on a form supplied by the offeree must be separately signed by the offeror §28:2A-206. Offer and acceptance in formation of lease contract a) Unless otherwise unambiguously indicated by the language or circumstances, an offer to make a lease contract must be construed as inviting acceptance in any manner and by any medium reasonable in the circumstances. New Sec. 28:2A-202 New Sec. 28:2A-203 New Sec. 28:2A-204 New Sec. 28:2A-205 New Sec. 28:2A-206 Enrolled Original b) If the beginning of a requested performance is a reasonable mode of acceptance, an offeror who is not notified of acceptance within a reasonable time may treat the offer as having lapsed before acceptance §28:2A-207. Course of performance or practical construction a) If a lease contract involves repeated occasions for performance by either party with knowledge of the nature of the performance and opportunity for objection to it by the other, any course of performance accepted or acquiesced in without objection is relevant to determine the meaning of the lease agreement b) The express terms of a lease agreement and any course of performance, as well as any course of dealing and usage of trade, must be construed whenever reasonable as consistent with each other; but if that construction is unreasonable, express terms control course of performance, course of performance controls both course of dealing and usage of trade, and course of dealing controls usage of trade c) Subject to the provisions of §28:2A-208 on modification and waiver, course of performance is relevant to show a waiver or modification of any term inconsistent with the course of performance §28:2A-208. Modification, rescission, and waiver a) An agreement modifying a lease contract needs no consideration to be binding b) A signed lease agreement that excludes modification or rescission except by a signed writing may not be otherwise modified or rescinded, but, except as between merchants, such a requirement on a form supplied by a merchant must be separately signed by the other party c) Although an attempt at modification or rescission does not satisfy the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, it may operate as a waiver d) A party who has made a waiver affecting an executory portion of a lease contract may retract the waiver by reasonable notification received by the other party that strict performance will be required of any term waived, unless the retraction would be unjust in view of a material change of position in reliance on the waiver §28:2A-209. Lessee under finance lease as beneficiary of supply contract a) The benefit of a supplier’s promises to the lessor under the supply contract and of all warranties, whether express or implied, including those of any third party provided in connection with or as part the supply contract, extends to the lessee to the extent of the lessee’s leasehold interest under a finance lease related to the supply contract, but is subject to the terms of the warranty and of the supply contract and all defenses or claims arising therefrom b) The extension of the benefit a supplier’s promises and of warranties to the lessee (§28:2A-209(1 does not 1) Modify the rights and obligations of the parties to the supply contract, whether arising therefrom or otherwise; or 2) Impose any duty or liability under the supply contract on the lessee c) Any modification or rescission of the supply contract by the supplier and the lessor is effective between the supplier and the lessee unless, before the modification or rescission, the supplier has received notice that the lessee has entered into a finance lease related to the New Sec. 28:2A-207 New Sec 28:2A-208 New Sec. 28:2A-209 10 Enrolled Original supply contract. If the modification or rescission is effective between the supplier and the lessee, the lessor is deemed to have assumed, in addition to the obligations of the lessor to the lessee under the lease contract, promises of the supplier to the lessor and warranties that were so modified or rescinded as they existed and were available to the lessee before modification or rescission d) In addition to the extension of the benefit of the supplier~s promises and of warranties to the lessee under subsection (a) of this section, the lessee retains all rights that the lessee may have against the supplier which arise from an agreement between the lessee and the supplier or under other law §28:2A-210. Express warranties a) Express warranties by the lessor are created as follows 1) Any affirmation of fact or promise made by the lessor to the lessee which relates to the goods and becomes part of the basis of the bargain creates an express warranty that the goods will conform to the affirmation or promise 2) Any description of the goods which is made part of the basis of the bargain creates an express warranty that the goods will conform to the description 3) Any sample or model that is made part of the basis of the bargain creates an express warranty that the whole of the goods will conform to the sample or model b) It is not necessary to the creation of an express warranty that the lessor use formal words, such as "warrant" or "guarantee or that the lessor have a specific intention to make a warranty, but an affirmation merely of the value of the goods or a statement purporting to be merely the lessor~s opinion or commendation of the goods does not create a warranty §28 2A-211. Warranties against interference and against infringement; lessee~s obligation against infringement a) There is in a lease contract a warranty that for the lease term no person holds a claim to or interest in the goods that arose from an act or omission of the lessor, other than a claim by way of infringement or the like, which will interfere with the lessee~s enjoyment of its leasehold interest b) Except in a finance lease there is in a lease contract by a lessor who is a merchant regularly dealing in goods of the kind a warranty that the goods are delivered free of the rightful claim of any person by way of infringement or the like c) A lessee who furnishes specifications to a lessor or a supplier shall hold the lessor and the suppIier harmless against any claim by way of infringement or the like that arises out of compliance with the specifications §28: 2A-212. Implied warranty of merchantability a) Except in a finance lease, a warranty that the goods will be merchantable is implied in a lease contract if the lessor is a merchant with respect to goods of that kind b) Goods to be merchantable must I) Pass without objection in the trade under the description in the lease agreement 2) In the case of fungible goods, be of fair average quality within the description; New Sec. 28: 2A- 2~0 New Sec. 28:2A-211 New Sec. 28:2A-212 11 Enrolled Original 3) Be fit for the ordinary purposes for which goods of that type are used 4) Run, within the variation permitted by the lease agreement, of even kind, quality, and quantity withineach unit and among all units involved 5) Be adequately contained, packaged, and labeled as the lease agreement may require; and 6) Conform to any promises or affirmations of fact made on the container or label c) Other implied warranties may arise from course of dealing or usage of trade §28:2A-213. Implied warranty of fitness for particular purpose Except in a finance lease, if the lessor at the time the lease contract is made has reason to know of any particular purpose for which the goods are required and that the lessee is relying on the lessor~s skill or judgment to select or furnish suitable goods, there is in the lease contract an implied warranty that the goods will be fit for that purpose §28:2A-214. Exclusion or modification of warranties a) Words or conduct relevant to the creation of an express warranty and words or conduct tending to negate or limit a warranty must be construed wherever reasonable as consistent with each other; but, subject to the provisions of §28:2A-202 on parol or extrinsic evidence, negation or limitation is inoperative to the extent that the construction is unreasonable b) Subject to subsection (c) of this ~ection, to exclude or modify the implied warranty of merchantability or any part of it the language must mention "merchantability be by a writing, and be conspicuous. Subject to subsection (c) of this section, to exclude or modify any implied warranty of fitness the exclusion must be by a writing and be conspicuous. Language to exclude all implied warranties of fitness is sufficient if it is in writing, is conspicuous and states, for example There is no warranty that the goods will be fit for a particular purpose c) Notwithstanding subsection (b) of this section, but subject to subsection (d) of this section 1) Unless the circumstances indicate otherwise, all implied warranties are excluded by expressions like "as is or "with all faults or by other language that in common understanding calls the lesseers attention to the exclusion of warranties and makes plain that there is no implied warranty, if in writing and conspicuous 2) If the lessee before entering into the lease contract has examined the goods or the sample or model as fully as desired or has refused to examine the goods, there is no implied warranty with regard to defects that an examination ought in the circumstances to have revealed; and 3) An implied warranty may also be excluded or modified by course of dealing, course of performance, or usage of trade d) To exclude or modify a warranty against interference or against infringement (§28:2A-211) or any part of it, the language must be specific, be by a writing, and be conspicuous, unless the circumstances, including course of performance, course of dealing, or usage of trade, give the lessee reason to know that the goods are being leased subject to a claim or interest of any person. New Sec. 28:2A-213 New Sec.o 28:2A-214 12 Enrolled Original "§28:2A-215. Cumulation and conflict of warranties express or implied Warranties, whether express or implied, must be construed as consistent with each other and as cumulative, but if that construction is unreasonable, the intention of the parties determines which warranty is dominant. In ascertaining that intention the following rules apply 1) Exact or technical specifications displace an inconsistent sample or model or general language of description 2) A sample from an existing bulk displaces inconsistent general language of description 3) Express warranties displace inconsistent implied warranties other than an implied warranty of fitness for a particular purpose §28:2A-216. Third party beneficiaries of express and implied warranties A warranty to or for the benefit of a lessee under this article, whether express or implied, extends to any person who may reasonably be expected to use, consume, or be affected by the goods and who is injured by breach of the warranty. The operation of this section may not be excluded, modified, or limited with respect to injury to the person of an individual to whom the warranty extends, but an exclusion, modification, or limitation of the warranty, including any with respect to rights and remedies, effective against the lessee is also effective against the beneficiary designated under this section §28 2A- 217. Identification Identification of goods as goods to which a lease contract refers may be made at any time and in any manner explicitly agreed to by the parties. In the absence of explicit agreement, identification occurs 1) When the lease contract is made if the lease contract is for a lease of goods that are existing and identified 2) When the goods are shipped, marked, or otherwise designated by the lessor as goods to which the lease contract refers, if the lease contract is for a lease of goods that are not existing and identified or 3) When the young are conceived, if the lease contract is for a lease of unborn young of animals §28:2A-218. Insurance and proceeds a) A lessee obtains an insurable interest when existing goods are identified to the lease contract even though the goods identified are nonconforming and the lessee has an option to reject them b) If a lessee has an insurable interest only by reason of the lessor’s identification of the goods, the lessor, until default or insolvency or notification to the lessee that identification is final, may substitute other goods for those identified c) Notwithstanding a lessee’s insurable interest under subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the lessor retains an insurable interest until an option to buy has been exercised by the lessee and risk of loss has passed to the lessee d) Nothing in this section impairs any insurable interest recognized under any other statute or rule of law e) The parties by agreement may determine that one or more parties have an obligation to obtain and pay for insurance covering the 13 New Sec. 28:2A-215 New Sec. 28:2A-216 New Sec. 28:2A-217 New Sec. 28:2A-218 Enrolled Original goods and by agreement may determine the beneficiary of the proceeds of the insurance §28:2A-219. l~isk of loss a) Except in the case of a finance lease, risk of loss is retained by the lessor and does not pass to the lessee. In the case of a finance lease, risk of loss passes to the lessee b) Subject to the provisions of this article on the effect of default on risk of loss (§28:2A-220 if risk of loss is to pass to the lessee and the time of passage is not stated, the following rules apply 1) If the lease contract requires or authorizes the goods to be shipped by carrier A) And it does not require delivery at a particular destination, the risk of loss passes to the lessee when the goods are duly delivered to the carrier; but B) If it does require delivery at a particular destination and the goods are there duly tendered while in the possession of the carrier, the risk of loss passes to the lessee when the goods are there duly so tendered as to enable the lessee to take delivery 2) If the goods are held by a bailee to be delivered without being moved, the risk of loss passes to the lessee on acknowledgment by the bailee of the lessee’s right to possession of the goods 3) In any case not within paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection, the risk of loss passes to the lessee on the lessee~s receipt of the goods if the lessor, or, in the case of a finance lease, the supplier, is a merchant; otherwise the risk passes to the lessee on tender of delivery §28:2A-220. Effect of default on risk of loss a) Where risk of loss is to pass to the lessee and the time of passage is not stated 1) If a tender or delivery of goods so fails to conform to the lease contract as to give a right of rejection, the risk of their loss remains with the lessor, or, in the case of a finance lease, the supplier, until cure or acceptance 2) If the lessee rightfully revokes acceptance, he or she, to the extent of any deficiency in his or her effective insurance coverage, may treat the risk of loss as having remained with the lessor from the beginning b) Whether or not risk of loss is to pass to the lessee, if the lessee as to conforming goods already identified to a lease contract repudiates or is otherwise in default under the lease contract, the lessor, or, in the case of a finance lease, the supplier, to the extent of any deficiency in his or her effective insurance coverage may treat the risk of loss as resting on the lessee for a commercially reasonable time §28:2A-221. Casualty to identified goods If a lease contract requires goods identified when the lease contract is made, and the goods suffer casualty without fault of the lessee, the lessor, or the supplier before delivery, or the goods suffer casualty before risk of loss passes to the lessee pursuant to the lease agreement or §28:2A-219, then 1) If the loss is total, the lease contract is avoided; and 2) If the loss is partial or the goods have so deteriorated as to no longer conform to the lease contract, the lessee may nevertheless demand inspection and at his or her option either treat the lease contract New Sec. 28:2A-219 New Sec. 28:2A-220 New Sec. 28:2A-221 1~ Enrolled Original as avoided or, except in a finance lease that is not a consumer lease, accept the goods with due allowance from the rent payable for the balance of the lease term for the deterioration or the deficiency in quantity but without further right against the lessor PART 3. EFFECT OF LEASE CONTRACT §28:2A-301. Enforceability of lease contract Except as otherwise provided in this article, a lease contract is effective and enforceable according to its terms between the parties, against purchasers of the goods and against creditors of the parties §28:2A-302. Title to and possession of goods Except as otherwise provided in this article, each provision of this article applies whether the lessor or a third party has title to the goods, and whether the lessor, the lessee, or a third party has possession of the goods, notwithstanding any statute or rule of law that possession or the absence of possession is fraudulent §28:2A-303. Alienability of party’s interest under lease contract or of lessor’s residual interest in goods; delegation of performance; transfer of rights a) As used in this section creation of a security interest" includes the sale of a lease contract that is subject to Article 9, Secured Transactions, by reason of §28 9-102 (1 b b) Except as provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, a provision in a lease agreement which (i) prohibits the voluntary or involuntary transfer, including a transfer by sale, sublease, creation or enforcement of a security interest, or attachment, levy, or other judicial process, of an interest of a party under the lease contract or of the lessor’s residual interest in the goods, or (ii) makes such a transfer an event of default, gives rise to the right and remedies provided in subsection (e) of this section, but a transfer that is prohibited or is an event of default under the lease agreement is otherwise effective c) A provision in a lease agreement which (i) prohibits the creation or enforcement of a security interest in an interest of a party under the lease contract or in the lessor’s residual interest in the goods, or (ii) makes such a transfer an event or default, is not enforceable unless, and then only to the extent that, there is an actual transfer by the lessee of the lessee’s right of possession or use of the goods in violation of the provision or an actual delegation of a material performance of either party to the lease contract in violation of the provision. Neither the granting nor the enforcement of a security interest in (i) the lessor’s interest under the lease contract, or (ii) the lessor’s residual interest in the goods is a transfer that materially impairs the prospect of obtaining return performance by, materially changes the duty of, or materially increases the burden or risk imposed on, the lessee within the purview of subsection (e) unless, and then only to the extent that, there is an actual delegation of a material performance of the lessor d) A provision in a lease agreement which (i) prohibits a transfer of a right to damages for default with respect to the whole lease contract or of a right to payment arising out of the transferor’s due performance of the transferor’s entire obligation, or (ii) makes such a transfer an event of default, is not enforceable, and such a transfer is not a transfer that materially impairs the prospect of obtaining return performance by, materially changes the duty of, or materially increases the burden or risk New Sec. 28:2A-301 New Sec. 28:2A-302 New Sec. 28:2A-303 15 Enrolled Original imposed on, the other party to the lease contract within the purview of subsection (d) of this section e) Subject to subsections (c) and (d) of this section 1) If a transfer is made which is made an event of default under a lease agreement, the party to the lease contract not making the transfer, unless that party waives the default or otherwise agrees, has the rights and remedies described in §28:2A-501(2 2) If paragraph (1) is not applicable and if a transfer is made that (i) is prohibited under a lease agreement, or (ii) materially impairs the prospect of obtaining return performance by, materially changes the duty of, or materially increases the burden or risk imposed on, the other party to the lease contract, unless the party not making the transfer agrees at any time to the transfer in the lease contract or otherwise, then, except as limited by contract i) the transfer is liable to the party not making the transfer for damages caused by the transfer to the extent that the damages could not reasonably be prevented by the party not making the transfer, and (ii) a court having jurisdication may grant other appropriate relief, including cancellation of the lease contract or an injunction against the transfer f) A transfer of "the lease" or of "all my rights under the lease or a transfer in similar general terms, is a transfer of rights, and, unless the language or the circumstances, as in a transfer for security, indicate the contrary, the transfer is a delegation of duties by the transferor to the transferee. Acceptance by the transferee constitutes a promise by the transferee to perform those duties. The promise is enforceable by either the transferor or the other party to the lease contract g) Unless otherwise agreed by the lessor and the lessee, a delegation of performance does not relieve the transferor as against the other party of any duty to perform or of any liability for default h) In a consumer lease, to prohibit the transfer of an interest of a party under the lease contract or to make a transfer an event of default, the language must be specific, by a writing, and conspicuous §28:2A-304. Subsequent lease of goods by lessor a) Subject to §28:2A-303, a subsequent lessee from a lessor of goods under an existing lease contract obtains, to the extent of the leasehold interest transferred, the leasehold interest in the goods that the lessor had or had power to transfer, and, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and §28:2A-527(d takes subject to the existing lease contract. A lessor with voidable title has power to transfer a good leasehold interest to a good faith subsequent lessee for value, but only to the extent set forth in the preceding sentence. If goods have been delivered under a transaction of purchase, the lessor has that power even though 1) The lessor’s transferor was deceived as to the identity of the lessor 2) The delivery was in exchange for a check which is later dishonored 3) It was agreed that the transaction was to be a "cash sale or 4) The delivery was procured through fraud punishable as larcenous under the criminal law b) A subsequent lessee in the ordinary course of business from a lessor who is a merchant dealing in goods of that kind to whom the New Sec. 28:2A-304 16 Enrolled Original goods were entrusted by the existing lessee of that lessor before the interest of the subsequent lessee became enforceable against that lessor obtains, to the extent of the leasehold interest transferred, all of that lessor’s and the existing lessee’s rights to the goods, and takes free of the existing lease contract c) A subsequent lessee from the lessor of goods that are subject to an existing lease contract and are covered by a certificate of title issued under a statute of the District or of another jurisdiction takes no greater rights than those provided both by this and by the certificate of title statute §28:2A-305. Sale or sublease of goods by lessee a) Subject to the provisions of §28:2A-303, a buyer or sublessee from the lessee of goods under an existing lease contract obtains, to the extent of the interest transferred, the leasehold interest in the goods that the lessee had or had power to transfer, and except as provided in subsection (b) and §28:2A-511(d takes subject to the existing lease contract. A lessee with a voidable leasehold interest has power to transfer a good leasehold interest to a good faith buyer for value or a good faith sublessee for value, but only to the extent set forth in the preceding sentence. When goods have been delivered under a transaction of lease the lessee has that power even though 1) The lessor was deceived as to the identity of the lessee 2) The delivery was in exchange for a check which is later dishonored; or 3) The delivery was procured through fraud punishable as larcenous under the criminal law b) A buyer in the ordinary course of business or a sublessee in the ordinary course of business from a lessee who is a merchant dealing in goods of that kind to whom the goods were entrusted by the lessor obtains, to the extent of the interest transferred, all of the lessor’s and lessee’s rights to the goods, and takes free of the existing lease contract c) A buyer or sublessee from the lessee of goods that are subject to an existing lease contract and are covered by a certificate of title issued under a statute of the District of Columbia or of another jurisdiction takes no greater rights than those provided both by this section and by the certificate of title statute §28:2A-306. t~riority of certain liens arising by operation of law If a person in the ordinary course of his or her business furnishes services or materials with respect to goods subject to a lease contract, a lien upon those goods in the possession of that person given by statute or rule of law for those materials or services takes priority over any interest of the lessor or lessee under the lease contract or this article unless the lien is created by statute and the statute provides otherwise or unless the lien is created by rule of law and the rule of law provides otherwise §28:2A-307. l~riority of liens arising by attachment or levy on, security interests in, and other claims to goods a) Except as otherwise provided in §28:2A-306, a creditor of a lessee takes subject to the lease contract b) Except as otherwise provided in subsections (c) and (d) of this section and in §§28:2A-306 and 28:2A-308, a creditor of a lessor takes subject to the lease contract unless: New Sec. 28:2A-305 New Sec. 28:2A-306 New Sec. 28:2A-308 17 Enrolled Original 1) The creditor holds a lien that attached to the goods before the lease contract became enforceable 2) The creditor holds a security interest in the goods and the lessee did not give value and received delivery of the goods without knowledge of the security interest; or 3) The creditor holds a security interest in the goods which was perfected (§28:9-303) before the lease contract became enforceable c) A lessee in the ordinary course of business takes the leasehold interest free of a security interest in the goods created by the lessor even though the security interest is perfected and the lessee knows of its existence d) A lessee other than a lessee in the ordinary course of business takes the leasehold interest free of a security interest to the extent that it secures future advances made after the secured party acquires knowledge of the lease or more than 45 days after the lease contract becomes enforceable, whichever first occurs, unless the future advances are made pursuant to a commitment entered into without knowledge of the lease and before the expiration of the 45-day period §28:2A-308. Special rights of creditors a) A creditor of a lessor in possession of goods subject to a lease contract may treat the lease contract as void if as against the creditor retention of possession by the lessor is fraudulent under any statute or rule of law, but retention of possession in good faith and current course of trade by the lessor for a commercially reasonable time after the lease contract becomes enforceable is not fraudulent b) Nothing in this article impairs the rights of creditors of a lessor if the lease contract (i) becomes enforceable, not in current course of trade but in satisfaction of or as security for a preexisting claim for money, security, or the like, and (ii) is made under circumstances which under any statute or rule of law apart from this article would constitute the transaction a fraudulent transfer or voidable preference c) A creditor of a seller may treat a sale or an identification of goods to a contract for sale as void if as against the creditor retention of possession by the seller is fraudulent under any statute or rule of law, but retention of possession of the goods pursuant to a lease contract entered into by the seller as lessee and the buyer as lessor in connection with the sale or identification of the goods is not fraudulent if the buyer bought for value and in good faith §28:2A-309. Lessor’s and lessee’s rights when goods become fixtures a) In this section 1) Goods are "fixtures" when they become so related to particular real estate that an interest in them arises under real estate law 2) A "fixture filing" is the filing, in the office where a mortgage on the real estate would be filed or recorded, of a financing statement covering goods that are or are to become fixtures and conforming to the requirements of §28:9-402(5 3) A lease is a "purchase money lease" unless the lessee has possession or use of the goods or the right to possession or use of the goods before the lease agreement is enforceable 4) A mortgage is a "construction mortgage" to the extent it secures an obligation incurred for the construction of an improvement New Sec. 28:2A-308 New Sec 28:2A-309 18 Enrolled Original on land including the acquisition cost of the land, if the recorded writing so indicates 5 Encumbrance" includes real estate mortgages and other liens on real estate and all other rights in real estate that are not ownership interests b) Under this article a lease may be of goods that are fixtures or may continue in goods that become fixtures, but no lease exists under this article of ordinary building materials incorporated into an improvement on land c) This article does not prevent creation of a lease of fixtures pursuant to real estate law d) The perfected interest of a lessor of fixtures has priority over a conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real estate if 1) The lease is a purchase money lease, the conflicting interest of the encumbrancer or owner arises before the goods become fixtures, the interest of the lessor is perfected by a fixture filing before the goods become fixtures or within 10 days thereafter, and the lessee has an interest of record in the real estate or is in possession of the real estate; or 2) The interest of the lessor is perfected by a fixture filing before the interest of the encumbrancer or owner is of record, the lessor’s interest has priority over any conflicting interest of a predecessor in title of the encumbrancer or owner, and the lessee has an interest of record in the real estate or is in possession of the real estate e) The interest of a lessor of fixtures, whether or not perfected, has priority over the conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real estate if 1) The fixtures are readily removable factory or office machines, readily removable equipment that is not primarily used or leased for use in the operation of the real estate, or readily removable replacements of domestic appliances that are goods subject to a consumer lease, and before the goods become fixtures the lease contract is enforceable 2) The conflicting interest is a lien on the real estate obtained by legal or equitable proceedings after the lease contract is enforceable 3) The encumbrancer or owner has consented in writing to the lease or has disclaimed an interest in the goods as fixtures; or 4) The lessee has a right to remove the goods as against the encumbrancer or owner. If the lessee’s right to remove terminates, the priority of the interest of the lessor continues for a reasonable time f) Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1) of this section but otherwise subject to subsections (d) and (e) of this section, the interest of a lessor of fixtures, including the lessor’s residual interest, is subordinate to the conflicting interest of an encumbrancer of the real estate under a construction mortgage recorded before the goods become fixtures if the goods become fixtures before the completion of the construction. To the extent given to refinance a construction mortgage, the conflicting interest of an encumbrancer of the real estate under a mortgage has this priority to the same extent as the encumbrancer of the real estate under the construction mortgage. 19 Enrolled Original g) In cases not within the preceding subsections, priority between the interest of a lessor of fixtures, including the lessor’s residual interest, and the conflicting interest of an encumbrancer or owner of the real estate who is not the lessee is determined by the priority rules governing conflicting interests in real estate h) If the interest of a lessor of fixtures, including the lessor’s residual interest, has priority over all conflicting interests of all owners and encumbrancers of the real estate, the lessor or the lessee may (i) on default, expiration, termination, or cancellation of the lease agreement but subject to the lease agreement and this article, or (ii) if necessary to enforce other rights and remedies of the lessor or lessee under this article, remove the goods from the real estate, free and clear of all conflicting interests of all owners and encumbrancers of the real estate, but the lessor or lessee must reimburse any encumbrancer or owner of the real estate who is not the lessee and who has not otherwise agreed for the cost of repair of any physical injury, but not for any diminution in value of the real estate caused by the absence of the goods removed or by any necessity of replacing them. A person entitled to reimbursement may refuse permission to remove until the party seeking removal gives adequate security for the performance of this obligation i) Even though the lease agreement does not create a security interest, the interest of a lessor of fixtures, including the lessor’s residual interest, is perfected by filing a financing statement as a fixture filing for leased goods that are or are to become fixtures in accordance with the relevant provisions of the Article on Secured Transactions (Article 9 §28:2A-310. Lessor’s and Iessee’s rights when goods become accessions a) Goods are "accessions" when they are installed in or affixed to other goods b) The interest of a lessor or a lessee under a lease contract entered into before the goods became accessions is superior to all interests in the whole except as stated in subsection (d) of this section c) The interest of a lessor or a lessee under a lease contract entered into at the time or after the goods became accessions is superior to all subsequently acquired interests in the whole except as stated in subsection (d) of this section, but is subordinate to interests in the whole existing at the time the lease contract was made unless the holders of such interests in the whole have in writing consented to the lease or disclaimed an interest in the goods as part of the whole d) The interest of a lessor or a lessee under a lease contract described in subsection (b) or (c) of this section is subordinate to the interest of 1) A buyer in the ordinary course of business or a lessee in the ordinary course of business of any interest in the whole acquired after the goods became accessions; or 2) A creditor with a security interest in the whole perfected before the lease contract was made to the extent that the creditor makes subsequent advances without knowledge of the lease contract e) When under subsections (b) or (c) and (d) of this section, a lessor or a lessee of accessions holds an interest that is superior to all interests in the whole, the lessor or the lessee may (i) on default, expiration, termination, or cancellation of the lease contract by the other New Sec. 28:2A-310 20 Enrolled Original party but subject to the provisions of the lease contract and this article, or (ii) if necessary to enforce his or her other rights and remedies under this article, remove the goods from the whole, free and clear of all interests in the whole, but he or she must reimburse any holder of an interest in the whole who is not the lessee and who has not otherwise agreed for the cost of repair of any physical injury but not for any diminution in value of the whole caused by the absence of the goods removed or by any necessity for replacing them. A person entitled to reimbursement may refuse permission to remove until the party seeking removal gives adequate security for the performance of this obligation §28:2A-311. Priority subject to subordination Nothing in this article prevents subordination by agreement by any person entitled to priority PART 4. PERFORMANCE OF LEASE CONTRACT: REPUDIATED, SUBSTITUTED, AND EXCUSED §28:2A-401. Insecurity: adequate assurance of performance a) A lease contract imposes an obligation on each party that the other’s expectation of receiving due performance will not be impaired b) If reasonable grounds for insecurity arise with respect to the performance of either party, the insecure party may demand in writing adequate assurance of due performance. Until the insecure party receives that assurance, if commercially reasonable the insecure party may suspend any performance for which he or she has not already received the agreed return c) A repudiation of the lease contract occurs if assurance of due performance adequate under the circumstances of the particular case is not provided to the insecure party within a reasonable time, not to exceed 30 days after receipt of a demand by the other party d) Between merchants, the reasonableness of grounds for insecurity and the adequacy of any assurance offered must be determined according to commercial standards e) Acceptance of any nonconforming delivery or payment does not prejudice the aggrieved party’s right to demand adequate assurance of future performance §28:2A-402. Anticipatory repudiation If either party repudiates a lease contract with respect to a performance not yet due under the lease contract, the loss of which performance will substantially impair the value of the lease contract to the other, the aggrieved party may 1) For a commercially reasonable time, await retraction of repudiation and performance by the repudiating party 2) Make demand pursuant to §28:2A-401 and await assurance of future performance adequate under the circumstances of the particular case; or 3) Resort to any right or remedy upon default under the lease contract or this article, even though the aggrieved party has notified the repudiating party that the aggrieved party would await the repudiating party’s performance and assurance and has urged retraction. In addition, whether or not the aggrieved party is pursuing one of the foregoing remedies, the aggrieved party may suspend performance or, if the aggrieved party is the lessor, proceed in accordance with the provisions of this article on the lessor’s right to identify goods to the New Sec. 28:2A-311 New Sec. 28:2A-401 New Sec. 28:2A-402 21 Enrolled Original lease contract notwithstanding default or to salvage unfinished goods (§28:2A-524 §28:2A-403. l~etraction of anticipatory repudiation a) Until the repudiating party’s next performance is due, the repudiating party can retract the repudiation unless, since the repudiation, the aggrieved party has cancelled the lease contract or materially changed the aggrieved party’s position or otherwise indicated that the aggrieved party considers the repudiation final b) P~etraction may be by any method that clearly indicates to the aggrieved party that the repudiating party intends to perform under the lease contract and includes any assurance demanded under §28:2A-401 c) l~etraction reinstates a repudiating party’s rights under a lease contract with due excuse and allowance to the aggrieved party for any delay occasioned by the repudiation §28:2A-404. Substituted performance a) If without fault of the lessee, the lessor and the supplier, the agreed berthing, loading, or unloading facilities fail or the agreed type of carrier becomes unavailable or the agreed manner of delivery otherwise becomes commercially impracticable, but a commercially reasonable substitute is available, the substitute performance must be tendered and accepted b) If the agreed means or manner of payment fails because of domestic or foreign governmental regulation 1) The lessor may withhold or stop delivery or cause the supplier to withhold or stop delivery unless the lessee provides a means or manner of payment that is commercially a substantial equivalent; and 2) If delivery has already been taken, payment by the means or in the manner provided by the regulation discharges the lessee’s obligation unless the regulation is discriminatory, oppressive, or predatory §28:2A-405. Excused performance Subject to §28:2A-404 on substituted performance, the following rules apply 1) Delay in delivery or nondelivery in whole or in part by a lessor or a supplier who complies with paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection is not a default under the lease contract if performance as agreed has been made impracticable by the occurrence of a contingency the nonoccurrence of which was a basic assumption on which the lease contract was made or by compliance in good faith with any applicable foreign or domestic governmental regulation or order, whether or not the regulation or order later proves to be invalid 2) If the causes mentioned in paragraph (1) of this subsection affect only part of the lessor’s or the supplier’s capacity to perform, he or she shall allocate production and deliveries among his or her customers but at his or her option may include regular customers, not then under contract for sale or lease as well as his or her own requirements for further manufacture. He or she may so allocate in any manner that is fair and reasonable 3) The lessor seasonably shall notify the lessee and in the case of a finance lease the supplier seasonably shall notify the lessor and the lessee, if known, that there will be delay or nondelivery and, if allocation is required under paragraph (2) of this subsection, of the estimated quota thus made available for the lessee. New Sec 28:2A-403 New Sec. 28:2A-404 New Sec. 28:2A-405 22 Enrolled Original "§28:2A-406. Procedure on excused performance a) If the lessee receives notification of a material or indefinite delay or an allocation justified under §28:2A-405, the lessee may by written notification to the lessor as to any goods involved, and with respect to all of the goods if under an installment lease contract the value of the whole lease contract is substantially impaired (§28:2A-510 I) Terminate the lease contract (§28:2A-505(b or 2) Except in a finance lease that is not a consumer lease, modify the lease contract by accepting the available quota in substitution, with due allowance from the rent payable for the balance of the lease term for the deficiency but without further right against the lessor b) If, after receipt of a notification from the lessor under §28:2A-405, the lessee fails so to modify the lease agreement within a reasonable time not exceeding 30 days, the lease contract lapses with respect to any deliveries affected §28:2A-407. Irrevocable promises: finance leases a) In the case of a finance lease that is not a consumer lease, the lessee’s promises under the lease contract become irrevocable and independent upon the lessee’s acceptance of the goods b) A promise that has become irrevocable and independent under subsection (a) of this section 1) Is effective and enforceable between the parties, and by or against third parties including assignees of the parties, and 2) Is not subject to cancellation, termination, modification, repudiation, excuse, or substitution without the consent of the party to whom the promise runs c) This section does not affect the validity under any other law of a covenant in any lease contract making the lessee’s promises irrevocable and independent upon the lessee’s acceptance of the goods. New Sec. 28: 2A-406 New Sec. 28:2A-407 "PART 5. DEFAULT A. IN GENERAL §28:2A-501. Default: procedure a) Whether the lessor or the lessee is in default under a lease contract is determined by the lease agreement and this article b) If the lessor or the lessee is in default under the ]ease contract, the party seeking enforcement has rights and remedies as provided in this article and, except as limited by this article, as provided in the lease agreement c) If the lessor or the lessee is in default under the lease contract, the party seeking enforcement may reduce the party’s claim to judgment, or otherwise enforce the lease contract by self help or any available judicial procedure or nonjudicial procedure, including administrative proceeding, arbitration, or the like, in accordance with this article d) Except as otherwise provided in §28:1-i06(i) or this article or the lease agreement, the rights and remedies referred to in subsections (b) and (c) of this section are cumulative e) If the lease agreement covers both real property and goods, the party seeking enforcement may proceed under this part as to the goods, or under other applicable law as to both the real property and the goods in accordance with that party’s rights and remedies in respect of the real property, in which case this part does not apply. New Sec. 28:2A-501 Enrolled Original "§28:2A-502. Notice after default Except as otherwise provided in this article or the lease agreement, the lessor or lessee in default under the lease contract is not entitled to notice of default or notice of enforcement from the other party to the lease agreement §28:2A-503. Modification or impairment of rights and remedies a) Except as otherwise provided in this article, the lease agreement may include rights and remedies for default in addition to or in substitution for those provided in this article and may limit or alter the measure of damages recoverable under this article b) Resort to a remedy provided under this article or in the lease agreement is optional unless the remedy is expressly agreed to be exclusive. If circumstances cause an exclusive or limited remedy to fail of its essential purpose, or provision for an exclusive remedy is unconscionable, remedy may be had as provided in this article c) Consequential damages may be liquidated under §28:2A-504, or may otherwise be limited, altered, or excluded unless the limitation, alteration, or exclusion is unconscionable. Limitation, alteration, or exclusion of consequential damages for injury to the person in the case of consumer goods is prima facie unconscionable, but limitation, alteration, or exclusion of damages where the loss is commercial is not prima facie unconscionable d) Rights and remedies on default by the lessor or the lessee with respect to any obligation or promise collateral or ancillary to the lease contract are not impaired by this article 328:2A-504. Liquidation of damages a) Damages payable by either party for default, or any other act or omission, including indemnity for loss or diminution of anticipated tax benefits or loss or damage to lessor’s residual interest, may be liquidated in the lease agreement, but only at an amount or by a formula that is reasonable in light of the then anticipated harm caused by the default or other act or omission b) If the lease agreement provides for liquidation of damages and the provision does not comply with subsection (a) of this section, or the provision is an exclusive or limited remedy that circumstances cause to fail of its essential purpose, remedy may be had as provided in this article c) If the lessor justifiably withholds or stops delivery of goods because of the lessee’s default or insolvency (§28:2A-525 or 328:2A-526 the lessee is entitled to restitution of any amount by which the sum of his or her payments exceeds 1) The amount to which the lessor is entitled by virtue of terms liquidating the lessor’s damages in accordance with subsection (a) of this section; or 2) In the absence of those terms, 20 percent of the then present value of the total rent the lessee was obligated to pay for the balance of the lease term, or, in the case of a consumer lease, the lesser of the amount or $500 d) A lessee’s right to restitution under subsection (c) of this section is subject to offset to the extent the lessor establishes 1) A right to recover damages under the provisions of this article other than subsection (a) of this section; and New Sec. 28: 2A-502 New Sec 28:2A-503 New Sec. 28:2A-504 2~ Enrolled Original 2) The amount or value of any benefits received by the lessee directly or indirectly by reason of the lease contract §28:2A-505. Cancellation and termination and effect of cancellation, termination, rescission, or fraud on rights and remedies a) On cancellation of the lease contract, all obligations that are still executory on both sides are discharged, but any right based on prior default or performance survives, and the cancelling party also retains any remedy for default of the whole lease contract or any unperformed balance b) On termination of the lease contract, all obligations that are still executory on both sides are discharged but any right based on prior default or performance survives c) Unless the contrary intention clearly appears, expressions of "cancellation rescission or the like of the lease contract may not be construed as a renunciation or discharge of any claim in damages for an antecedent default d) l~ights and remedies for material misrepresentation or fraud include all rights and remedies available under this article for default e) Neither rescission nor a claim for rescission of the lease contract nor rejection or return of the goods may bar or be deemed inconsistent with a claim for damages or other right or remedy §28:2A-506. Statute of limitations a) An action for default under a lease contract, including breach of warranty or indemnity, must be commenced within 4 years after the cause of action accrued. By the original lease contract the parties may reduce the period of limitation to not less than 1 year b) A cause of action for default accrues when the act or omission on which the default or breach of warranty is based is or should have been discovered by the aggrieved party, or when the default occurs, whichever is later. A cause of action for indemnity accrues when the act or omission on which the claim for indemnity is based is or should have been discovered by the indemnified party, whichever is later c) If an action commenced within the time limited by subsection (a) of this section is so terminated as to leave available a remedy by another action for the same default or breach of warranty or indemnity, the other action may be commenced after the expiration of the time limited and within 6 months after the termination of the first action unless the termination resulted from voluntary discontinuance or from dismissal for failure or neglect to prosecute d) This section does not alter the law on tolling of the statute of limitations nor does it apply to causes of action that have accrued before this article becomes effective §28:2A-507. Proof of market rent: time and place a) Damages based on market rent (§28:2A-519 or §28:2A-528) are determined according to the rent for the use of the goods concerned for a lease term identical to the remaining lease term of the original lease agreement and prevailing at the time of the default b) If evidence of rent for the use of the goods concerned for a lease term identical to the remaining lease term of the original lease agreement and prevailing at the times or places described in this article is not readily available, the rent prevailing within any reasonable time before or after the time described or at any other place or for a different lease term which in commercial judgment or under usage of trade would New Sec. 28:2A-505 New Sec. 28:2A-506 New Sec. 28:2A-507 Enrolled Original serve as a reasonable substitute for the one described may be used, making any proper allowance for the differemce, including the cost of transporting the goods to or from the other place c) Evidence of a relevant rent prevailing at a time or place or for a lease term other than the one described in this article offered by one party is not admissible unless and until he or she has given the other party notice the court finds sufficient to prevent unfair surprise d) If the prevailing rent or value of any goods regularly leased in any established market is in issue, reports in official publications or trade journals or in newspapers or periodicals of general circulation published as the reports of that market are admissible in evidence. The circumstances of the preparation of the report may be shown to affect its weight but not its admissibility B. DEFAULT BY LESSOR §28:2A-508. Lessee’s remedies a) If a lessor fails to deliver the goods in conformity to the lease contract (§28:2A-509) or repudiates the lease contract (§28:2A-402 or a lessee rightfully rejects the goods (§28:2A-509) or justifiably revokes acceptance of the goods (§28:2A-517 then with respect to any goods involved, and with respect to all of the goods if under an installment lease contract the value of the whole lease contract is substantially impaired (§28:2A-510 the lessor is in default under the lease contract and the lessee may i) Cancel the lease contract (§28:2A-505(a 2) Recover so much of the rent and security as has been paid and is just under the circumstances; or 3) Cover and recover damages as to all goods affected whether or not they have been identified to the lease contract (§§28:2A-518 and 28:2A-520 or recover damages for nondelivery (§§28:2A-519 and 28:2A-520 or b) If a lessor fails to deliver the goods in conformity to the lease contract or repudiates the lease contract, the lessee may also 1) If the goods have been identified, recover them (§28:2A-522 or 2) In a proper case, obtain specific performance or replevy the goods (§28".2A-521 c) If a lessor is otherwise in default under a lease contract, the lessee may exercise the rights and pursue the remedies provided in the lease contract, which may include a right to cancel the lease, and in §28: 2A- 519 c d) If a lessor has breached a warranty, whether express or implied, the lessee may recover damages (§28:2A-519(d e) On rightful rejection or justifiable revocation of acceptance, a lessee has a security interest in goods in the lessee’s possession or control for any rent and security that has been paid and any expenses reasonably incurred in their inspection, receipt, transportation, and care and custody and may hold those goods and dispose of them in good faith and in a commercially reasonable manner, subject to §28:2A-527(e f) Subject to the provisions of §28:2A-407, a lessee, on notifying the lessor of the lessee’s intention to do so, may deduct all or any part of the damages resulting from any default under the lease contract from any part of the rent still due under the same lease contract. New Sec. 28:2A-508 26 Enrolled Original "§28:2A-509. Lessee’s rights on improper delivery; rightful rejection a) Subject to the provisions of §28:2A-510 on default in installment lease contracts, if the goods or the tender or delivery fail in any respect to conform to the lease contract, the lessee may reject or accept the goods or accept any commercial unit or units and reject the rest of the goods b) Rejection of goods is ineffective unless it is within a reasonable time after tender or delivery of the goods and the lessee seasonably notifies the lessor §28:2A-510. Installment lease contracts: rejection and default a) Under an installment lease contract a lessee may reject any delivery that is nonconforming if the nonconformity substantially impairs the value of that delivery and cannot be cured or the nonconformity is a defect in the required documents; but if the nonconformity does not fall within subsection (b) of this section and the lessor or the supplier gives adequate assurance of its cure, the lessee must accept that delivery b henever nonconformity or default with respect to one or more deliveries substantially impairs the value of the installment lease contract as a whole, there is a default with respect to the whole. But, the aggrieved party reinstates the installment lease contract as a whole if the aggrieved party accepts a nonconforming delivery without seasonably notifying of cancellation or brings an action with respect only to past deliveries or demands performance as to future deliveries §28:2A-511. Merchant lessee’s duties as to rightfully rejected goods a) Subject to any security interest of a lessee (§28:2A-508(e if a lessor or a supplier has no agent or place of business at the market of rejection, a merchant lessee, after rejection of goods in his or her possession or control, shall follow any reasonable instructions received from the lessor or the supplier with respect to the goods. In the absence of those instructions, a merchant lessee shall make reasonable efforts to sell, lease, or otherwise dispose of the goods for the lessor’s account if they threaten to decline in value speedily. Instructions are not reasonable if on demand indemnity for expenses is not forthcoming b) If a merchant lessee (subsection (a) of this section) or any other lessee (§28:2A-512) disposes of goods, he or she is entitled to reimbursement either from the lessor or the supplier or out of the proceeds for reasonable expenses of caring for and disposing of the goods and, if the expenses include no disposition commission, to such commission as is usual in the trade, or if there is none, to a reasonable sum not exceeding 10% of the gross proceeds c) In complying with this section or §28:2A-512, the lessee is held only to good faith. Good faith conduct hereunder is neither acceptance or conversion nor the basis of an action for damages d) A purchaser who purchases in good faith from a lessee pursuant to this section or §28:2A-512 takes the goods free of any rights of the lessor and the supplier even though the lessee fails to comply with one or more of the requirements of this article §28:2A-512. Lesseels duties as to rightfully rejected goods. 27 New Sec. 28:2A-509 New Sec. 28:2A-510 New Sec. 28:2A-511 New Sec 28:2A-512 Enrolled Original a) Except as otherwise provided with respect to goods that threaten to decline in value speedily (§28:2A-511) and subject to any security interest of a lessee (§28:2A-508(e 1) The lessee, after rejection of goods in the lessee~s possession, shall hold them with reasonable care at the lessor’s or the supplier’s disposition for a reasonable time after the lessee’s seasonable notification of rejection 2) If the lessor or the supplier gives no instructions within a reasonable time after notification of rejection, the lessee may store the rejected goods for the lessor~s or the supplier~s account or ship them to the lessor or the supplier or dispose of them for the lessor~s or the supplier’s account with reimbursement in the manner provided in §28:2A-51I; but 3) The lessee has no further obligations with regard to goods rightfully rejected b) Action by the lessee pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is not acceptance or conversion §28:2A-513. Cure by lessor of improper tender or delivery; replacement a) If any tender or delivery by the lessor or the supplier is rejected because nonconforming and the time for performance has not yet expired, the lessor or the supplier may seasonably notify the lessee of the lessor~s or the supplier’s intention to cure and may then make a conforming delivery within the time provided in the lease contract b) If the lessee rejects a nonconforming tender that the lessor or the supplier had reasonable grounds to believe would be acceptable with or without money allowance, the lessor or the supplier may have a further reasonable time to substitute a conforming tender if he or she seasonably notifies the lessee §28:2A-514. Waiver of lessee~s objections a) In rejecting goods, a lessee~s failure to state a particular defect that is ascertainable by reasonable inspection precludes the lessee from relying on the defect to justify rejection or to establish default 1) If, stated seasonably, the lessor or the supplier could have cured it (§28:2A-513 or 2) Between merchants if the lessor or the supplier after rejection has made a request in writing for a full and final written statement of all defects on which the lessee proposes to rely b) A lessee’s failure to reserve rights when paying rent or other consideration against documents precludes recovery of the payment for defects apparent on the face of the documents §28:2A-515. Acceptance of goods a) Acceptance of goods occurs after the lessee has had a reasonable opportunity to inspect the goods, and 1) The lessee signifies or acts with respect to the goods in a manner that signifies to the lessor or the supplier that the goods are conforming or that the lessee will take or retain them in spite of their nonconformity; or 2) The lessee fails to make an effective rejection of the goods §28: 2A- 509 (b b) Acceptance of a part of any commercial unit is acceptance of that entire unit. New Sec 28:2A-513 New Sec. 28:2A-514 New Sec. 28:2A-515 28 Enrolled Original "§28:2A-516. Effect of acceptance of goods; notice of default; burden of establishing default after acceptance; notice of claim or litigation to person answerable over a) A lessee must pay rent for any goods accepted in accordance with the lease contract, with due allowance for goods rightfully rejected or not delivered b) A lessee’s acceptance of goods precludes rejection o£ the goods accepted. In the case of a finance ]ease, if made with knowledge of a nonconformity, acceptance cannot be revoked because of it. In any other case, if made with knowledge of a nonconformity, acceptance cannot be revoked because of it unless the acceptance was on the reasonable assumption that the nonconformity would be seasonably cured. Acceptance does not of itself impair any other remedy provided by this article or the lease agreement for nonconformity c) If a tender has been accepted 1) Within a reasonable time after the lessee discovers or should have discovered any default, the lessee shall notify the lessor and the supplier, if any, or be barred from any remedy against the party not notified 2) Except in the case of a consumer lease, within a reasonable time after the lessee receives notice of litigation for infringement or the like (§28:2A-211) the lessee shall notify the lessor or be barred from any remedy over for liability established by the litigation; and 3) The burden is on the lessee to establish any default d) If a lessee is sued for breach of a warranty or other obligation for which a lessor or a supplier is answerable over the following apply 1) The lessee may give the lessor or the supplier, or both, written notice of the litigation. If the notice states that the person notified may come in and defend and that if the person notified does not do so, that person will be bound in any action against that person by the lessee by any determination of fact common to the 2 litigations, then unless the person notified after seasonable receipt of the notice does come in and defend, that person is so bound 2) The lessor or the supplier may demand in writing that the lessee turn over control of the litigation including settlement if the claim is one for infringement or the like (§28:2A-211) or else be barred from any remedy over. If the demand states that the lessor or the supplier agrees to bear all expense and to satisfy any adverse judgment, then unless the lessee after seasonable receipt of the demand does turn over control the lessee is so barred e) Subsections (c) and (d) of this section apply to any obligation of a lessee to hold the lessor or the supplier harmless against infringement or the like (§28:2A-211 §28:2A-517. P~evocation of acceptance of goods a) A lessee may revoke acceptance of a lot or commercial unit whose nonconformity substantially impairs its value to the lessee if the lessee has accepted it 1) Except in the case of a finance lease, on the reasonable assumption that its nonconformity would be cured and it has not been seasonably cured; or 2) Without discovery of the nonconformity if the lessee’s acceptance was reasonably induced either by the lessor’s assurances or, New Sec 28:2A-516 New Sec. 28:2A-517 29 Enrolled Original except in the case of a finance lease, by the difficulty of discovery before acceptance b) Except in the case of a financial lease that is not a consumer lease, a lessee may revoke acceptance of a lot or commercial unit if the lessor defaults under the lease contract and the default substantially impairs the value of that lot or commercial unit to the lessee c) If the lease agreement so provides, the lessee may revoke acceptance of a lot or commercial unit because of other defaults by the lessor d) l~evocation of acceptance must occur within a reasonable time after the lessee discovers or should have discovered the ground for it and before any substantial change in condition of the goods which is not caused by the nonconformity. Revocation is not effective until the lessee notifies the lessor e) A lessee who so revokes has the same rights and duties with regard to the goods involved as if the lessee had rejected them §28:2A-518. Cover; substitute goods a) After default by a lessor under the lease contract of the type described in §28:2A-508(a or, if agreed, after other default by the lessor, the lessee may cover by making any purchase or lease of or contract to purchase or lease goods in substitution for those due from the lessor b) Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (§28:2A-504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties §28:1-102(3) and §28:2A-503 if a lessee’s cover is by a lease agreement substantially similar to the original lease agreement and the new lease agreement is made in good faith and in a commercially reasonable manner, the lessee may recover from the lessor as damages (i) the present value, as of the date of the commencement of the term of the new lease agreements, of the rent under the new lease agreement applicable to the period of the new lease which is comparable to the then remaining term of the original lease agreement minus the present value as of the same date of the total rent for the then remaining lease term of the original lease agreement, and (ii) any incidental or consequential damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessor’s default c) If a lessee’s cover is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under subsection (b) of this section, or is by purchase or otherwise, the lessee may recover from the lessor as if the lessee had elected not to cover and §28:2A-519 governs §28:2A-519. Lessee’s damages for nondelivery, repudiation, default, and breach of warranty in regard to accepted goods a) Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (§28:2A-504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties §§28:1-102(c) and 28:2A~503 if a lessee elects not to cover or a lessee elects to cover and the cover is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under §28:2A-518(b or is by purchase or otherwise, the measure of damages for nondelivery or repudiation by the lessor or for rejection or revocation of acceptance by the lessee is the present value as of the date of the default, of the then market rent minus the present value as of the same date of the original rent, computed for the remaining lease term of N6w Sec. 28:2A-518 New Sec. 28:2A-519 30 Enrolled Original the original lease agreement, together with incidental and consequential damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessorVs default b) Market rent is to be determined as of the place for tender or, in cases of rejection after arrival or revocation of acceptance, as of the place of arrival c) Except as otherwise agreed, if the lessee has accepted goods and given notification (§28:2A-516(c the measure of damages for nonconforming tender or delivery or other default by a lessor is the loss resulting in the ordinary course of events from the lessorWs default as determined in any manner that is reasonable together with incidental and consequential damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessor~s default d) Except as otherwise agreed, the measure of damages for breach of warranty is the present value at the time and place of acceptance of the difference between the value of the use of the goods accepted and the value if they had been as warranted for the lease term, unless special circumstances show proximate damages of a different amount, together with incidental and consequential damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessor~s default or breach of warranty §28:2A-520. Lesseels incidental and consequential damages a) Incidental damages resulting from a lessor~s default include expenses reasonably incurred in inspection, receipt, transportation, and care and custody of goods rightfully rejected or goods the acceptance of which is justifiably revoked, any commercially reasonable charges, expenses or commissions in connection with effecting cover, and any other reasonable expense incident to the default b) Consequential damages resulting from a lessor~s default include 1) Any loss resulting from general or particular requirements and needs of which the lessor at the time of contracting had reason to know and which could not reasonably be prevented by cover or otherwise; and 2) Injury to person or property proximately resulting from any breach of warranty §28:2A-521. Lessee~s right to specific performance or replevin a) Specific performance may be decreed if the goods are unique or in other proper circumstances b) A decree for specific performance may include any terms and conditions as to payment of the rent, damages, or other relief that the court deems just c) A lessee has a right of replevin, detinue, sequestration, claim and delivery, or the like for goods identified to the lease contract if after reasonable effort the lessee is unable to effect cover for those goods or the circumstances reasonably indicate that the effort will be unavailing §28:2A-522. Lessee~s right to goods on lessor~s insolvency a) Subject to subsection (b) of this section and even though the goods have not been shipped, a lessee who has paid a part or all of the rent and security for goods identified to a lease contract (§28:2A-217) on making and keeping good a tender of any unpaid portion of the rent and security due under the lease contract may recover the goods identified from the lessor if the lessor becomes insolvent within 10 days after receipt of the first installment of rent and security. New Sec. 28:2A-520 New Sec. 28:2A-521 New Sec. 28:2A-522 31 Enrolled Original b) A lessee acquires the right to recover goods identified to a lease contract only if they conform to the lease contract C. DEFAULT BY LESSEE §28:2A-523. Lessor’s remedies a) If a lessee wrongfully rejects or revokes acceptance of goods or fails to make a payment when due or repudiates with respect to a part or the whole, then, with respect to any goods involved, and with respect to all of the goods if under an installment lease contract the value of the whole lease contract is substantially impaired (§28:2A-510 the lessee is in default under the lease contract and the lessor may 1) Cancel the lease contract (§28:2A-505(a 2) Proceed respecting goods not identified to the lease contract (§28 2A-524 3) Withhold delivery of the goods and take possession of goods previously delivered (§28:2A-525 4) Stop delivery of the goods by any bailee (§28:2A-526 or 5) Dispose of the goods and recover damages (§28:2A-527 or retain the goods and recover damages (§28:2A-528 or in a proper case recover rent (§28:2A-529 or 6) Exercise any other rights or pursue any other remedies provided in the lease contract b) If a lessor does not fully exercise a right or obtain a remedy to which the lessor is entitled under subsection (a) of this section, the lessor may recover the loss resulting in the ordinary course of events from the lessee’s default as determined in any reasonable manner, together with incidental damages, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default c) If a lessee is otherwise in default under a lease contract, the lessor may exercise the rights and pursue the remedies provided in the lease contract which may include a right to cancel the lease. In addition, unless otherwise provided in the lease contract 1) If the default substantially impairs the value of the lease contract to the lessor, the lessor may exercise the rights and pursue the remedies provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section; or 2) If the default does not substantially impair the value of the lease contract to the lessor, the lessor may recover as provided in subsection (b) of this section §28:2A-524. Lessor’s right to identify goods to lease contract a) A lessor aggrieved under §28:2A-523(a) may 1) Identify to the lease contract conforming goods not already identified if at the time the lessor learned of the default they were in the lessor’s or the supplier’s possession or control; and 2) Dispose of goods (§28:2A-527(a that demonstrably have been intended for the particular lease contract even though those goods are unfinished b) If the goods are unfinished, in the exercise of reasonable commercial judgment for the purposes of avoiding loss and of effective realization, an aggrieved lessor or the supplier may either complete manufacture and wholly identify the goods to the lease contract or cease manufacture and lease, sell, or otherwise dispose of the goods for scrap or salvage value or proceed in any other reasonable manner §28:2A-525. Lessor’s right to possession of goods. New Sec. 28:2A-523 New Sec. 28:2A-524 New Sec. 28:2A-525 Enrolled Original a) If a lessor discovers the lessee to be insolvent, the lessor may refuse to deliver the goods b) After a default by the lessee under the lease contract of the type described in §28:2A-523(a) or §28:2A-523(c)(1) or, if agreed, after other default by the lessee, the lessee has the right to take possession of the goods. If the lease contract so provides, the lessor may require the lessee to assemble the goods and make them available to the lessor at a place to be designated by the lessor which is reasonably convenient to both parties. Without removal, the lessor may render unusable any goods employed in trade or business, and may dispose of goods on the lessee’s premises (§28:2A-527 c) The lessor may proceed under subsection (b) of this section without judicial process if it can be done without breach of the peace or the lessor may proceed by action §28:2A-526. Lessor’s stoppage of delivery in transit or otherwise a) A lessor may stop delivery of goods in the possession of a carrier or other bailee if the lessor discovers the lessee to be insolvent and may stop delivery of carload, truckload, planeload, or larger shipments of express or freight if the lessee repudiates or fails to make a payment due before delivery, whether for rent, security or otherwise under the lease contract, or for any other reason the lessor has a right to withhold or take possession of the goods b) In pursuing its remedies under subsection (a) of this section, the lessor may stop delivery until 1) l~eceipt of the goods by the lessee 2) Acknowledgment to the lessee by any bailee of the goods, except a carrier, that the bailee holds the goods for the lessee; or 3) Such an acknowledgment to the lessee by a carrier via reshipment or as warehouseman c)(1) To stop delivery, a lessor shall so notify as to enable the bailee by reasonable diligence to prevent delivery of the goods 2) After notification, the bailee shall hold and deliver the goods according to the directions of the lessor, but the lessor is liable to the bailee for any ensuing charges or damages 3) A carrier who has issued a nonnegotiable bill of lading is not obliged to obey a notification to stop received from a person other than the consignor §28:2A-527. Lessor’s rights to dispose of goods a) After a default by a lessee under the lease contract of the type described in §28:2A-523(a) or §28:2A-523(c) or after the lessor refuses to deliver or takes possession of goods (§28:2A-525 or §28:2A-526 or, if agreed, after other default by a lessee, the lessor may dispose of the goods concerned or the undelivered balance thereof by lease, sale, or otherwise b) Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (§28:2A-504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties (§28:1-102(3) and §28:2A-503 if the disposition is by lease agreement substantially similar to the original lease agreement and the lease agreement is made in good faith and in a commercially reasonable manner, the lessor may recover from the lessee as damages (i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of the commencement of the term of the new lease agreement ii) the present value, as of the same date, of the total rent for the then remaining lease New Sec. 28:2A-526 New Sec. 28:2A-527 Enrolled Original term of the original lease agreement minus the present value, as of the same date, of the rent under the new lease agreement applicable to that period of the new lease term which is comparable to the ten remaining term of the original lease agreement, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under §28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lesseeVs default c) If the lessor’s disposition is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under subsection (b) of this section, or is by sale or otherwise, the lessor may recover from the lessee as if the lessor had elected not to dispose of the goods and §28:2A-528 governs d) A subsequent buyer or lessee who buys or leases from the lessor in good faith for value as a result of a disposition under this section takes the goods free of the original lease contract and any rights of the original lessee even though the lessor fails to comply with one or more of the requirements of this article e) The lessor is not accountable to the lessee for any profit made on any disposition. A lessee who has rightfully rejected or justifiably revoked acceptance shall account to the lessor for any excess over the amount of the lesseers security interest (§28:2A-508(e §28:2A-528. Lessor~s damages for nonacceptance, failure to pay, repudiation, or other default a) Except as otherwise provided with respect to damages liquidated in the lease agreement (§28:2A-504) or otherwise determined pursuant to agreement of the parties (§§28:1-102(3) and 28:2A-503 if a lessor elects to retain the goods or a lessor elects to dispose of the goods and the disposition is by lease agreement that for any reason does not qualify for treatment under §28:2A-527(b or is by sale or otherwise, the lessor may recover from the lessee as damages for a default of the type described in §28:2A-523(c)(1 or, if agreed, for other default of the lessee (i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of default if the lessee has never taken possession of the goods, or, if the lessee has taken possession of the goods, as of the date the lessor repossesses the goods or an earlier date on which the lessee makes a tender of the goods to the lessor ii) the present value as of the date determined under clause (i) of this subsection of the total rent for the then remaining lease term of the original lease agreement minus the present value as of the same date the market rent at the place where the goods are located computed for the same lease term, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under §28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default b) If the measure of damages provided in subsection (a) of this section is inadequate to put a lessor in as good a position as performance would have, the measure of damages is the present value of the profit, including reasonable overhead, the lessor would have made from full performance by the lessee, together with any incidental damages allowed under §28:2A-530, due allowance for costs reasonably incurred and due credit for payments or proceeds of disposition §28:2A-529. Lessor’s action for the rent a) After default by the lessee under the lease contract of the type described in §28:2A-523(a) or §28:2A-523(c) or, if agreed, after other default by the lessee, if the lessor complies with subsection (b) of this section, the lessor may recover from the lessee as damages: New Sec. 28:2A-528 New Sec. 28:2A-529 Enrolled Original 1) For goods accepted by the lessee and not repossessed by or tendered to the lessor, and for conforming goods lost or damaged within a commercially reasonable time after risk of loss passes to the lessee (§28:2A-219 i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of entry of judgment in favor of the lessor ii) the present value as of the same date of the rent for the then remaining lease term of the lease agreement, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under section 28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default; and 2) For goods identified to the lease contract if the lessor is unable after reasonable effort to dispose of them at a reasonable price or the circumstances reasonably indicate that effort will be unavailing i) accrued and unpaid rent as of the date of default ii) the present value as of the date of default of the rent for the remaining lease term of the lease agreement, and (iii) any incidental damages allowed under §28:2A-530, less expenses saved in consequence of the lessee’s default b) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the lessor shall hold for the lessee for the remaining lease term of the lease agreement any goods that have been identified to the lease contract and are in the lessor’s control c) The lessor may dispose of the goods at any time before collection of the judgment for damages obtained pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. If the disposition is before the end of the remaining lease term of the lease agreement, the lessor’s recovery against the lessee for damages is governed by §28:2A-527 or §28:2A-528, and the lessor will cause an appropriate credit to be provided against a judgment for damages to the extent that the amount of the judgment exceeds the recovery available pursuant to §28:2A-527 or §28:2A-528 d) l~ayment of the judgment for damages obtained pursuant to subsection (a) of this section entitles the lessee to the use and possession of the goods not then disposed of for the remaining lease term of and in accordance with the lease agreement e) After a lessee has wrongfully rejected or revoked acceptance of goods, has failed to pay rent then due, or has repudiated (§28:2A-402 a lessor who is held not entitled to rent under this section must nevertheless be awarded damages for nonacceptance under §§28:2A-527 and 28:2A-528 §28:2A-530. Lessor’s incidental damages Incidental damages to an aggrieved lessor include any commercially reasonable charges, expenses, or commissions incurred in stopping delivery, in the transportation, care and custody of goods after the lessee’s default, in connection with return or disposition of the goods, or otherwise resulting from the default §28:2A-531. Standing to sue third parties for injury to goods a) If a third party so deals with goods that have been identified to a lease contract as to cause actionable injury to a party to the lease contract 1) The lessor has a right of action against the third party, and 2) The lessee also has a right o[ action against the third party if the lessee A) Has a security interest in the goods B) Has an insurable interest in the goods; or New Sec. 28: 2A-530 New Sec. 28:2A-531 Enrolled Original C) Bears the risk of loss under the lease contract or has since the injury assumed that risk as against the lessor and the goods have been converted or destroyed b) If at the time of the injury the party plaintiff did not bear the risk of loss as against the other party to the lease contract and there is no arrangement between them for disposition of the recovery, his or her suit or settlement, subject to his or her own interest, is as a fiduciary for the other party to the lease contract c) Either party with the consent of the other may sue for the benefit of whom it may concern §28:2A-532. Lessorls rights to residual interest In addition to any other necessary recovery permitted by this article or other law, the lessor may recover from the lessee an amount that will fully compensate the lessor for any loss or damage to the lessor~s residual interest in the goods caused by the default of the lessee c) Article 1 (General Provisions) is amended as follows 1) §28:1-105 is amended to read as follows §28:1-105. Territorial application of this subtitle; partiesI power to choose applicable law 1) Except as provided hereafter in this section, when a transaction bears a reasonable relation to the District and also to a state or nation, the parties may agree that the law either of the District or of the other state or nation shall govern their rights and duties. Failing such agreement, this subtitle applies to transactions bearing an appropriate relation to this state 2) Where one of the following provisions of this subtitle specifies the applicable law, that provision governs and a contrary agreement is effective only to the extent permitted by the law (including the conflict of laws rules) so specified l~ights of creditors against sold goods. §28:2-402 Applicability of the article on leases. §§28:2A-105 and 28:2A-106 Applicability of the article on bank deposits and collections. §28: 4-102 Bulk transfers subject to the article on bulk transfers. §28:6-106 Applicability of the article on investment securities. §28:9-103 Perfection provisions of the article on secured transactions. §28 9-103 2) §28:1-201(37) is amended to read as follows 37)(a Security interest" means an interest in personal property or fixtures which secures payment or performance of an obligation. The retention or reservation of title by a seller of goods notwithstanding shipment or delivery to the buyer (§28:2-401) is limited in effect to a reservation of a "security interest The term also includes any interest of a buyer of accounts or chattel paper which is subject to Article 9. The special property interest of a buyer of goods on identification of those goods to a contract for sale under §28:2-401 is not a "security interest but a buyer may also acquire a "security interest" by complying with Article 9. Unless a consignment is intended as security, reservation of title thereunder is not a "security interest but a consignment in any event is subject to the provisions on consignment New Sec. 28:2A-532 36 Enrolled Original sales (§28:2-326 Whether a transaction creates a lease or security interest is determined by the facts of each case; however, a transaction creates a security interest if the consideration the lessee is to pay the lessor for the right to possession and use of the goods is an obligation for the term of the lease not subject to termination by the lessee, and i) the original term of the lease is equal to or greater than the remaining economic life of the goods ii) the lessee is bound to renew the lease for the remaining economic life of the goods or is bound to become the owner of the goods iii) the lessee has an option to renew the lease for the remaining economic life of the goods for no additional consideration or nominal additional consideration upon compliance with the lease agreement, or iv) the lessee has an option to become the owner of the goods for no additional consideration or nominal additional consideration upon compliance with the lease agreement b) A transaction does not create a security interest merely because it provides that i) the present value of the consideration the lessee is obligated to pay the lessor for the right to possession and use of the goods is substantially equal to or is greater than the fair market value of the goods at the time the lease is entered into ii) the lessee assumes risk of loss of the goods, or agrees to pay taxes, insurance, filing, recording, or registration fees, or service or maintenance costs with respect to the goods iii) the lessee has an option to renew the lease or to become the owner of the goods iv) the lessee has an option to renew the lease for a fixed rent that is equal to or greater than the reasonably predictable fair market rent for the use of the goods for the term of the renewal at the time the option is to be performed, or v) the lessee has an option to become the owner of the goods for a fixed price that is equal to or greater than the reasonably predictable fair market value of the goods at the time the option is to be performed c) For purposes of this subsection i) Additional consideration is not nominal if (A) when the option to renew the lease is granted to the lessee the rent is stated to be the fair market rent for the use of the goods for the term of the renewal determined at the time the option is to be performed, or (B) when the option to become the owner of the goods is granted to the lessee the price is stated to be the fair market value of the goods determined at the time the option is to be performed. Additional consideration is nominal if it is less than the lessee’s reasonably predictable cost of performing under the lease agreement if the option is not exercised ii Reasonably predictable" and "remaining economic life of the goods" are to be determined with reference to the facts and circumstances at the time the transaction is entered into iii Present value" means the amount as of a date certain of one or more sums payable in the future, discounted to the date certain. The discount is determined by the interest rate specified by 37 Enrolled Original the parties if the rate is not manifestly unreasonable at the time the transaction is entered into; otherwise, the discount is determined by a commercially reasonable rate that takes into account the facts and circumstances of each case at the time the transaction was entered into d) Article 9 (Secured Transactions) is amended 1) By amending the analysis for §28:9-113 by striking the period and inserting "or under article on leases in its place; and (2) By amending §28:9-113 to read as follows §28:9113. Security interests arising under article on sales or article on leases A security interest arising solely under the article on sales (Article 2) or the article on leases (Article 2A) is subject to the provisions of this article except that to the extent that and so long as the debtor does not have or does not lawfully obtain possession of the goods a) no security agreement is necessary to make the security interest enforceable b) no filing is required to perfect the security interest; and c) the rights of the secured party on default by the debtor are governed (i) by the article on sales (Article 2) in the case of a security interest arising solely under such article or (ii) by the article on leases (Article 2A) in the case of a security interest arising solely under such article Sec. 3. Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in §28:602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Kegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the Distriqt of Columbia Municipal Regulations Columbia l~Iayor District ~f Columbia APPROVED: May 28, 1992 Section 28:9-113 38 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: [~ Item on Consent Calendar [~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request [] ROLL COUNCIL MEMBER CI4MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD Absent ALL VOTE RESULT AYE NAY N.V. A.B I X indicates Vote v ~ecr t~y’to-th~ Council Item or~ Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CROPP EVANS B9-19 Adopted First Readinq, 4-7-92 Approved all present COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MA S ON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROI,APt{ SMITH JR. YHOM_A.S, SR. N.V Present, not votin£1 Reading, 5-6-92 CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY[N.V. AB. I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV AB. Clq}IN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MAS ON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not votincjI CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE ROLARK ITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. NAY N.V, ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Q ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. CIIIv~N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD ~ROPP ~VANS X Indicaies Vote COUNCILMEMBER ROCAR~ SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. COUNCILMEMBER IAYE NAY N.V. A.8. IJARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.8 Absent N.V Present, not votin~ AYE NAY t NV CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
