<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-13">
  <num type="law">9-13</num>
  <heading type="short">BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE UNIVERSITY OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COMPENSATION AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-48</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1991-07-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-13.pdf">D.C. Law 9-13</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 3378</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0048">
      <narrative>Law 9-13 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-48, which was referred to the Committee on Education and Libraries. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 9, 1991, and May 7, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 17, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-31 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 247 766 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-13 "Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia Compensation Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-48 on first and second readings, April 9, 1991, and May 7, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 17, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-31, published in the May 31, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 3378) and transmitted to Congress on May 23, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-13, effective July 13, 1991. JOHN A. WILSON Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May 23,24,29,30,31 June 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 July 8,9,10,11,12 AN ACT Codi fi cation District of Columbia Code (1992 Supplement) D, C, ACT 9-31 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 17, 1991 To amend the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act to provide that members of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia may receive only reimbursement for expenses incurred while engaged in service as Trustees. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia Compensation Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. Section 204 of the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act, approved October 26, 197&amp;amp 88 Stato 1426; D.C. Code, sec. 31-1514 is amended to read as follows Sec. 204. Reimbursement of Trustees. Trustees shall serve without compensation except that each Trustee shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred while actually engaged in service as a Trustee, provided that these expenses are properly documented. In no case, however, shall a Trustee receive expense reimbursement that exceeds 000 per annum. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(I) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(I and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Section 31-1514 1 Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chai Coun~t~il of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: May 17, 1991 2 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted First Reading, Approved Lightfoot and Smith Bill 9-48 4-9-91 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CHMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP JARVIS COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSON RAY ROLARK X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting ] Secreta/’y’to the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Reading, 5-7-91 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP JARVIS AYE NAY N.V.COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR kSON THOMAS, SR NATHANSON RAY ROLARK X indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting Secretary to~JJe Council Item on Consent Calendar CERTIFICATION RECORD Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B tHMN. WILSON BRAZ I L C AWFO CROPP JARVIS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER LIGHTFOOT MASO~V NATHANSON RAY ’ ROLARK A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER 8MITH R. THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
