<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-149">
  <num type="law">9-149</num>
  <heading type="short">Environmental Policy and Hazardous and Solid Waste Temporary Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-149.pdf">D.C. Law 9-149</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 9-149, the “Environmental Policy and Hazardous and Solid Waste Temporary Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-522. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 6, 1992, and June 2, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 19, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-229 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-149 became effective on September 10, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN ROLLM ENT (S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-149 "Environmental Policy and Hazardous and Solid Waste Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-522 on first and second readings, May 6, 1992, and June 2, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 19, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-229, published in the July 3, 1992, edition of the D.C~ Register Vol. 39 page 4917) and transmitted to Congress on June 24, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-149, effective i&amp;gt I 7bHT. WILSON ’Chp 2.2_.zf Council Dates Counted Durin9 the 30~l~ay./Congressiona] Review Period; June 24,25,26,29,30 ’ July I ,2,7,8,9,20,21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 August 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12 September 8,9 September 10, 1992. AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-229 Enrolled Original Distriot of Columbia Code 1,.993 ’t~l:~l~ IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 19, 1992 To amend, on a temporary basis, the District of Columbia Environmental Policy Act of 1989, Chapter 3 of title 8 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, and the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977 to require permits and environmental impact statements for the construction and operation of facilities used for the processing and disposal of medical waste and solid waste. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL Ol~ THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Environmental Policy and Hazardous and Solid Waste Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. Section 3 of the District of Columbia Environmental Policy Act of 1989, effective October 18, 1989 (D.C. Law 8-36; D.C. Code § 6-982 is amended as follows a) Paragraph 2 is amended to read as follows 2 Major action" means any action that costs over $1,000,000 and that may have significant impact on the environment. The cost level of $1,000,000 shaI1 be based on 1989 dollars adjusted annually according to the Consumer Price Index. The Mayor shall, subject to the exemptions in section 7, and pursuant to rules issued in accordance with section 10, classify any action that costs less than $1,000,000 as a major action if the action A) Imminently and substantially affects the public health, safety, or welfare; or B) Involves a medical waste facility for which a permit is required by section 4(a) of the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977, effective March 16, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-64; D.C. Code § 6-703(a b) Paragraph 4(B) is amended by adding the phrase "medical waste after the phrase "substances that are Sec. 3. Chapter 3 of title 8 of the District of Columbia Health Regulations, enacted June 29, 1971 (Reg. 71-21; 21 DCMR 700.1 et seq is amended by adding a new section 605a to read as follows Sec. 605a. Permits for Solid Waste Transfer Stations and Medical Waste Facilities a) It shall be unlawful to construct, substantially alter, or operate a solid waste transfer station or medical waste facility, without first obtaining a permit from the Mayor. NO te, Section 6-982 Enrolled Original b) The Mayor is authorized to issue, vary, or modify the terms of any permit, or to suspend, revoke, or deny a permit to achieve the purposes of this act, except that the Mayor may not issue a permit for a period exceeding 10 years. The Mayor may establish the appropriate permit fee to cover the costs associated with its issuance Sec. 4. Section 3(b) of the District of Columbia Hazardous Waste Management Act of 1977, effective March 16, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-64; D.C. Code § 6-702(2 is amended as follows a) By striking the word "those" after the phrase "limited to" and inserting the phrase "medical waste, substances" in its place; and (b) By striking the phrase "as well as" and inserting the word "and" in its place. See. 5 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect. Note, Section 6-702 Ctiairman Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia P2PROVED: June :19 1992 CO[’qWCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL.~BLA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO item on Consent Calendar X ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted First all present Bill 9-522 Reading, 5-6-92 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT tCOUNCIL MEMBERCHMN WILSON BRAZIL .CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N.V A.B. I COUNCI.L MEMBER /JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~SON NATHANSQN X Indicates Vote Secre a~to the Council Ite on Consent Calendar EAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER SMITH L JR. THOMAS, SR. Date VOICE VOTE: Adopted Final Readinq, 6-2-92 Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent: AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCIL MEMBER C~N. WILSON JARVI S BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON ,EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent A.B. COUNCILMEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS~ SR. AYE NAY Date’ CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY NV NIV I AB. ACTION &amp;amp; DAT vOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CII WILSON BRA,ZIL CRAWFORD ~ROPP EVA,~S X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON Puny A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present, not votin COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK S IT THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY N.V CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
