<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-153" flag="true">
  <num type="law">9-153</num>
  <heading type="short">First Degree Murder Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-09-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-153.pdf">D.C. Law 9-153</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 3868</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0118">
      <narrative>Law 9-153, the “First Degree Murder Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-118, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 7, 1992, and May 6, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 28, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-213 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-153 became effective on September 26, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag® 103 247 716 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-153 "First Degree Murder Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-118 on first and second readings, April 7, 1992, and May 6, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 28, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-213, published in the June 5, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register, IVol. 39 page 3868) and transmitted to Congress on May 29, 1992 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(2) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expirec and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-153, effective September 26, 1992. C he Counci 1 Dates Counted During the6 ressional Review Period: May 29 june I ,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24, 25,26,29,30 July I ,2,7,8,9,20,2 1,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 August 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12 September 8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,25 Enrolled Original AN ACT Codification Dlstrl¢l of Columbia Code D~£. ACT .q-215 1993_ Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 28, 1992 To amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to expand the definition of felony murder and to provide for the application of a penalty of life imprisonment without parole for first degree murder. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "First Degree Murder Amendment Act of 1992" Sec. 2. An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Star. 1321; D.C. Code §22-2401, eL seq is amended as follows a) Section 798 (D.C. Code §22-2401) is amended to read as follows Whoever, being of sound memory and discretion, kills another purposely, either of deliberate and premeditated malice or by means of poison, or in perpetrating or attempting to perpetrate any offense punishable by imprisonment in the penitentiary, or without purpose so to do kills another in perpetrating or in attempting to perpetrate any arson, as defined in section 820 or section 821, rape, mayhem, robbery, or kidnaping, or in perpetrating or attempting to perpetrate any housebreaking while armed with or using a dangerous weapon, or in perpetrating or attempting to perpetrate a felony involving a controlled substance, is guilty of murder in the first degree b) Section 801(a D.C. Code §22-2404(a is amended to read as follows a) The punishment of murder in the first degree shall be life imprisonment, except that the court may impose a punishment of life imprisonment without parole in accordance with section 801a. The prosecution shall notify the defendant in writing at least 30 days prior to trial that it intends to seek a sentence of life imprisonment without parole as provided in section 801a, provided that, no person who was less than 18 years of age at the time the murder was committed shall be sentenced to life imprisonment without parole c) Section 801(b D.C. Code §22-2404(b is amended to read as follows b) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person convicted of first-degree murder and upon whom a sentence of life imprisonment is imposed shall be eligible for parole only after the expiration of 30 years from the date of the commencement of the sentence Section 22-2401 Section 22-2404 Section 22-24O4 Enrolled Original (d) A new section 801a is added to read as follows Sec. 801a. Sentencing procedure for first-degree murder a) If a defendant is convicted of first-degree murder, and if the prosecution has given the notice required under section 801(a a separate sentencing procedure shall be conducted as soon as practicable after the trial has been completed to determine whether to impose a sentence of life imprisonment or life imprisonment without possibility of parole b) In determining the sentence, the court shall consider whether, beyond a reasonable doubt, any of the following aggravating circumstances exist 1) The murder was committed in the course of kidnaping or abduction, or an attempt to kidnap or abduct 2) The murder was committed for hire 3) The murder was committed for the purpose of avoiding or preventing a lawful arrest or effecting an escape from custody 4) The murder was especially heinous, atrocious or cruel 5) The murder was a drive-by or random shooting 6) There was more than 1 offense of murder in the first degree arising out of 1 incident; ’I(7) The murder was committed because of the victim’s race, color, religion, national origin or sexual orientation 8) The murder was committed while committing or attempting to commit a robbery, arson, rape, or sexual offense; 11(9) The murder was committed because the victim was or had been a witness in any criminal investigation or judicial proceeding, or the victim was capable of providing or had provided assistance in any criminal investigation or judicial proceeding; or 10) The murder victim was especially vulnerable due to age or a mental or physical infirmity c) The court shall state in writing whether, beyond a reasonable doubt, 1 or more of the aggravating circumstances exist. If the court finds that 1 or more aggravating circumstances exist, a sentence of life imprisonment without parole may be imposed d) If the trial court is reversed on appeal because of error only in the separate sentencing procedure, any new proceeding before the trial court shall pertain only to the issue of sentencing See. 3. This act shall take effect after a 60-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental l~eorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(2 and New Sec. 22-2404.1 Enrolled Original publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. abia Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B 9-118 Adopted First Reading, 4-7-92 Approved all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE NAY I N,V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CNMN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL C~WFO raSON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final Approved AYE NAY NV. A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROI,AP~ SMITH L ~R [_O~£A_S SR. N.V Present, not voting Date Readi.ncj 5-6-92 NAY N.V. Recorded vote on request aZ1 #rese~tAbsent: ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER i AYE NAY NV. t A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CN~iN. WILSON JARVI S BP ZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to th~;ounc v Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR. N.V Present, not voting AYE j NAY Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Q VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent m ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT CQUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. CII WILSON ~BRAZIL CRAWFORD ,CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER J_ARV I,.S LIGHTFOOT AS0N, NATHA_N S ON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J ~COUNCIL MEMBER SMITH, J,R THO .MA SR AYE NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
