<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-202">
  <num type="law">9-202</num>
  <heading type="short">Stable and Reliable Source of Revenues for WMATA Act of 1982 Temporary Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1993-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-202.pdf">D.C. Law 9-202</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 9221</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0583">
      <narrative>Law 9-202, the “Stable and Reliable Source of Revenues for WMATA Act of 1982 Temporary Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-583, which was retained by CounciL. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 7, 1992 and November 4, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-327 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-202 became effective on March 16, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 249 207 C~)UNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-202 "Stable and Reliable Source of Revenues for WMATA Act of 1982 Temporary mendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-583 on first and second readings, July 7, 1992, and November 4, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 25, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-327, published in the December 11, 1992, edition of the D.C; R_~eQister Vol. 39 page 9221) and transmitted to Congress on January 6, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-202, effective March 16, 1993. hairman of the Council Dates Counted During the r30-~y Con~r.e_s.sional Review Period: January 6,20,21.,22,25,26,27 February 2,3,4,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26 March 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-327 Enrolled Original ¯ IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 25, 1992 To allow, on a temporary basis, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority to use debt service payments on outstanding federally guaranteed transit revenue bonds received from the District of Columbia for the refunding of these bonds. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Stable and Reliable Source of Revenues for WMATA Act df 1982 Temporary Amendment Act of 1992 See. 2. for WMATA Act of 1982, effective April 30, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-103; D.C. Code § 1-2466(e is amended as follows a) By striking the phrase in accordance with the following priorities and (b) By amending paragraphs (1)(B) and (C) to read as follows B) An amount equal to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority’s WMATA contribution to the sinking fund established by section 15(a)(1) of the National Capital Transportation Act of 1969 Act approved January 3, 1980 (93 Star. 1321; D.C. Code § 1-2464(a)(1 pursuant to section 15(a)(4) of the Act payable through the year 2014. These funds shall be used by WMATA to make debt service payments on the new bonds issued to refund the local share of the federally guaranteed transit revenue bonds; and C) An amount equal to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority’s contribution to the Bond Interest Fund established by section 15(b)(1) of the Act, approved January 3, 1980 (93 Star. 1321; D.C. Code § 1-2464(b)(1 pursuant to section 15(b)(4) of the Act payable through the year 2014. These funds shall be used by WMATA to make debt service payments on the new bonds issued to refund the local share of the federally guaranteed, transit revenue bonds Section 2(e) of the Stable and Reliable Source of Revenues Note, Section 1-2466 See. 3 a) This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District Enrolled Original of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Kegulations b) This act shall expire on the 225th day of its having taken effect M~yor District of Columbia ~un~ of thin--DiStrict of Columbia APPROVED: November 25 1992 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL~MBiA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Adopted First Bill 9-583 Reading, 7-7-92 Approved all present E3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CF[HN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY. AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting 1 TIFICATION RECORD ’ cretary to ,h Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY SMITH L JR. THOMAS SR Date Final Reading, 11-4-92 VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Approved Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C}D WILSON JARVI S BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B ̄&amp;lt CERTIFICATION ySecretary (o the Council Item on Consent Calendar N.V Present, not voting RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS SR. Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD 9ROPP ~VANS AYE NAY N.V. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ’MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N,V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
