<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-213">
  <num type="law">9-213</num>
  <heading type="short">Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1993-03-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-213.pdf">D.C. Law 9-213</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 25</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0479">
      <narrative>Law 9-213, the “Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-479, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 1992, and December 1, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-342 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-213 became effective on March 17, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 103 248 233 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-213 "Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1992 Dates Counted Durina the 30 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-~79 on first and second readings, November 4, 1992, and December I, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 21, 1992, this legislation was assigned Act Io. 0-342, published in the January 1, 1993, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 40 page 25) and transmitted to Congress on January 13, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-213, effective March 17, 1993. Council -d~Congressional Review Period: January 20,21,22,25,26,27 February 2,3,4,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26 March 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,Ii ,12,15,16 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-342 Enrolled Original Codification District of Columbia Code Supplement IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 21, 1992 To amend the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 to provide the Public Access Corporation the authority to enlarge its Board of Directors to 13 members and to make the names of the members of the Public Access Corporation public information. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Cable Television Communications Act of 1981 Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. Section 30(b) of the Cable Television Communications Act of 1981, effective August 21, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-142; D.C. Code § 43-1829(b is amended as follows a) Paragraph (2) is amended to read as follows 2) The Corporation shall have no less than 3 categories of members, which categories shall include members constituting a 13-member Board of Directors; members constituting a 15-member Board of Overseers; and associate members b) Paragraph (3)(E) is amended to read as follows E) The Board of Directors shall be the governing body of the Corporation and the initial appointments to the Board of Directors shall be for a term of 2 years, after which term the chairperson and 7 members of the Board of Directors shall be elected in accordance with the bylaws of the Corporation. The bylaws of the Corporation shall provide that 2 members of the 13-member Board of Directors shall always be persons nominated by the Mayor and confirmed by the Council; that 2 members of the 13-member Board of Directors shall always be persons nominated by the chairperson of the Council committee having jurisdiction over cable television and confirmed by the Council; and that 1 member of the 13-member Board of Directors shall always be a person nominated by the District’s cable franchisee and confirmed by the Council c) A new paragraph (3)(F) is added to read as follows F) The names of the members of the Corporation shall be public information Section 43-1829 See. 3~ Effective date. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Enrolled Original Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia P~egister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Chairman Council of of Columbia District of Columbia ] APPROVED: December 21, 1992 COL2NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL~MBIA Council Period Nine Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Adopted First Readinq, ii-4-92 Approved Evans 9-479 C ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. i A..B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY j N.V, CHURN. WILSON I JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTF00T CRAWFORD ~LASON .CROPp NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent Secre(~’~ to the Council Item o4Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: CERTIFICATION RECORD A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROT,AP~I SMITH JR THOMAS SR. N.V Present. no[voting Date Adopted Final Reading, 12-1-92 Approved tNV iA.B. Recorded vote on request Absent: Cropp, Jarvis and Thomas ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CK~£ WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X indicates Vote v SeZar,/to the C Item on Consent Calendar COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. JARVI LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR. AYE NV Present, not voting Date NAY N V ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: r VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C.MN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON ffROP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote AB Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N V Present. not voting. CERTIFICATION RECORd COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS. SR. AYE I NAY i N V 1 Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
