<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-243">
  <num type="law">9-243</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Compensation Settlement Review Period Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1993-03-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-243.pdf">D.C. Law 9-243</citation>
      <citation type="register">40 DCR 636</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0662">
      <narrative>Law 9-243, the “District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Compensation Settlement Review Period Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-622, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1992, and December 15, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 5, 1993, it was assigned Act No. 9-377 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-243 became effective on March 17, 1993.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-243 "District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Compensation Settle- ment Review Period Amendment Act of 1992 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-662 on first and second readings, December I, 1992, and December 15, 1992, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 5, 1993, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-377, published in the January 22, 1993, edition of the D.C Register Vol. 40 page 636) and transmitted to Congress on January 15, 1993 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-243, effective March 17, 1993 uncil Dates Counted During the 30-da ~on.~ressional Review Peri.o~d: January February March 20,21,22,25,26,27 2,3,4,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25,26 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,12,15,16 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-377 Enrolled Original _1993 81,11 1 1 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 5, 1.993 To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to provide that Council review of labor relations settlements concerning compensation occur as part of the budget review process. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL O1~ THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 Compensation Settlement Review Period Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. Section 1717 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-618.17 is amended as follows a) Subsection (h) is amended by adding a new sentence to the end to read as follows Management shall give the Council the same prior notice of negotiation proceedings that it gives to all parties to the negotiations b) Subsection (i) is amended to read as follows i)(1) The Mayor shall transmit all settlements, including arbitration awards, to the Council with a budget request act, a supplemental budget request act, a budget amendment act, or a reprogramming, as appropriate. The budget request act, supplemental budget request act, budget amendment act, or reprogramming shall fully fund the settlement for the fiscal year to which it applies 2) At the same time the Mayor transmits a settlement, including any arbitration award, pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Mayor shall also transmit a financial plan that includes proposed funding for both actual and annualization costs of settlements for future fiscal years contained in a multi-year compensation agreement 3) The Mayor shall fully support the passage of settlements by every reasonable means before all legislative bodies, except that the Mayor is not required to support Council approval of an arbitrator’s award, or to support Council approval of a settlement negotiated by the Board of Education, the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia, the Board of Governors of the School of Law, or other independent personnel authority, unless the Mayor participated in the negotiations c) Subsection (j) is amended to read as follows: Section 1-618.17 Enrolled Original j) A settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, shall take effect on the 30th calendar day, excluding days of Council recess, after the Mayor and the Council enact the budget request act, the supplemental budget request act, or the budget amendment act, or approve the reprogramming, as appropriate, that contains the funded settlement, unless prior to the 30th calendar day, the Council accepts or rejects the settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, by resolution. If the Council rejects a settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, then the settlement shall be returned to the parties for renegotiation, with specific reasons for the rejection appended to the document disclosing the rejection of the settlement d) Subsection (k) is amended as follows 1) By inserting the phrase "that has been approved pursuant to this section" after the phrase "including an arbitrator’s award and (2) By adding a new sentence at the beginning of the subsection to read as follows The Mayor shall fully fund in future fiscal year budget requests, any settlement, including an arbitrator’s award, for future fiscal years contained in a multi-year compensation agreement that has been approved pursuant to this section Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations M~yor District of Columbia APPROVED: January 5, 1993 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: B 9- 6 6 2 [] Item on Consent Calendar [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: E] VOICE VOTE: Adopted First Reading, 12-1-92 Approved Recordedvoteonrequest Absent: Cropp, Jarvis,and Thomas [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CNMN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT _CRAWFORD I~LAS ON .CROPP NATHAN S ON EVANS RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLAP/&amp;lt; SMITH L JR. THOMAS, SR. X Indicates Vote Secr ry~to the Council Item on Consent Calendar A,B Absent ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: CERTIFICATION RECORD N.V Present, not voting Date Adopted Final Reading, 12-15-92 Approved All Present AYE NAY NV ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. cm£ WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. JARV I S N.OL ARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR. MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSON RAY A,B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Date [] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. C111v WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
