<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-25">
  <num type="law">9-25</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Amendment Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-08-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-25.pdf">D.C. Law 9-25</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 4196</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 9-25, the “District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Amendment Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-121, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 4, 1991, and June 18, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 2, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-52 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 247 730 i1 0 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-52 Codification District of Columbia Code (1992 Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 2, 1991 To amend the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 to continue conformity on a limited basis with the Tax Reform Act of 1986, as amended by the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Conformity Amendment Act of 1991" Sec. 2. Section 4(bb-1) of Title I of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, approved July 16, 1947 (61 Star. 332; D.C. Code §47-1801.4(28-1 is amended to read as follows bb-1) The term "Internal Revenue Code of 1986" means the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved October 22, 1986 (100 Star. 2085; 26 U.S.C. 1 et seq as amended by the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990, approved November 5, 1990 (104 Star. 1388; Pub. L. No. 101-508 Sec. 3. This act shall apply as of November 5, 1990. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District Section 47-1801 Note, Section 47-1801 of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Cl[~{~’~n- i Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: July 2, 1991 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUIMB[A Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Reading, 06-04-91 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: ¯ Adopted First Approved VOICE VOTE: B9-121 Recorded vote on request Absent: all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESUL COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY CNMN. WILSON BRAZIL _CRAWFORD _CROPP EVANS N.V. A.B COUNC!L M EMBER I AYE JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~LASON NAT HANS 0 N RAY NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLA£1i SMITH L JR. THOMAS SR. AYE NAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ’~’~’ S~e~t a r y ,oC e/e~/C-~oo u~ c~i i Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final Reading, 06-18-91 Date VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request all present Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBERI AYE NAY N.V. AB. I COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. COUNCIL MEMBER ICN}£I. WILSON JARVIS OLARK BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH. JR. CRAWFORD MASON THOMAS, SR. CROP P NATHAN S ON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting AYE NAY N.V Secretary Ii;~the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: CERTIFICATION RECORD Date [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C[IMN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CR OPP NATHANSON ~VANS ~AY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.Y. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR NAY N.V. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
