<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-52">
  <num type="law">9-52</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Law on Notarial Acts Amendment Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1991-12-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-52.pdf">D.C. Law 9-52</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 6585</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0214">
      <narrative>Law 9-52, the “Uniform Law on Notarial Acts Amendment Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-214, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 2, 1991, and October 1, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-94 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 246 570 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-52 "Uniform Law on Notarial Acts Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-214 on first and second readings, July 2, 1991, and October 1, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 23, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-94, published in the November i, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 6585) and transmitted to Congress on October 29, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(i) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that this legislation became effective on the date that the President of the United States signed P. L. 102-205" on December I0, 1991, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-52, effective December 10, 1991. irman of the Council Public Law 102-205 waived the 30-day Congressional Review Period for this Law. Enrolled Orisnal AN ACT D,C. ACT 9-94 Oodifioation of Oo|umbi~ Code Supplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 23, 1991 To amend the Uniform Law on Notarial Acts of 1990 to require a certificate of a notarial act to include an official stamp or seal of office. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Law on Notarial Acts Amendment Act of 1991 Sec. 2. The Uniform Law on Notarial Acts of 1990, effective March 6, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-205; D.C. Code §45-621 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 8(a D.C. Code §45-627(a is amended by striking N0te~ the phrase "may include the official stamp or seal of office and inserting Sec, 45~627 the phrase "shall include the official stamp or seal of office in its place b) Section 9(5 D.C. Code §45-628(5 is repealed. Note, Sec, 45 628 See. 3. This act shall apply as of March 6, 1991. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of 1 Enrolled Orisrlat Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 23, 1991 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE C~N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFOR~ CROPP F, VANE I X Indicates Vote COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COL[MBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OFOFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 7-2-91 Approved Lightfoot and Rolark NAY N.V. I A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~SON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD J Secretdto the Council Adopted Final Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: Bill 9-214 Approved all present AYE NAY N.V. A,B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE SMITH JR. THOMAS, SR. NAY N.V. N.V Present, not voting Date Reading, 10-1-91 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C~N. WILSON JARVIS ROLARK BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH. JR. CRAWFORD MASON THOMAS, SR. CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD I- Secret~lJ to the CouncilItem on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER C[IMN WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent AYE NAY N.V. AB. N.V PresenL not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR Secretary to the Councd Date Enrolled O inal AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Uniform Law on Notarial Acts of 1990 to require a certificate of a notarial act to include an official stamp or seal of office. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Law on Notarial Acts Amendment Act of 1991 See. 2. The Uniform Law on Notarial Acts of 1990, effective March 6, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-205; D.C. Code {}45-621 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 8(a D.C. Code {}45-627(a is amended by striking Note, the phrase "may include the official stamp or seal of office and inserting See, 45~627 the phrase "shall include the official stamp or seal of office in its place b) Section 9(5 D.C. Code {}45-628(5 is repealed. Note, Sec, 45~628 See. 3. This act shall apply as of March 6, 1991. See. 4. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code {}1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of 1 Enrolled Original Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Item on Consent Calendar X; ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: X~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COLLNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLL~MBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE ’ DOCKET NO: Adopted First Reading, 7-2-91 Bill 9-214 Approved Lightfoot and Rolark [3 ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B COUNCIL MEMBER CN~fN. WILSON r JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD ~LASON CROPp NATHANSON ’ EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ’ &amp;lt;’ [ 4ecret/~99 t/~o h~e Counc,i Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final { J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROI,APSK SMITH L JR YHOI’~S SR. Date Reading, 10-1-91 ~[ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Approved Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. A8. CHaiN. WILSON BRAZIL C .WFORD CROPP COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. JA.R, VIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHAN S ON RAY COUNCIL MEMBER 8.0LARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY NV. X Ind=cates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secret~9~ to the Council Item oh Consent Calendar \ Date r~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT coUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.B. COU’NCILMEMBER CHM/q. WILSON JARV!S BRAZIL LIGHTF00T CRAWFO MASON 9ROPP NATHANSON ~VANS AY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. NV Present. not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROLARK SMITH, JR. THOMAS, SR. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
