<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-56">
  <num type="law">9-56</num>
  <heading type="short">Revocable Trust Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-03-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-56.pdf">D.C. Law 9-56</citation>
      <citation type="register">38 DCR 7281</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0053">
      <narrative>Law 9-56, the “Revocable Trust Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-53, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 1, 1991, and November 5, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 25, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-99 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwil(t;~g 103 247 788 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-56 "Revocable Trust Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bil~ No. 9-53 on first and second readings, October I, 1991, and November 5, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 25, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-99, published in the December 6, 1991, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 38 page 7281) and transmitted to Congress on November 26, 1991 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-56, effective March 7, 1992 airman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: November January February March 26,27 21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 2,3,4,5,6 Emolled Origina AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-99 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOVEMBER 25, 1991 To amend the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1980; District of Columbia Real Estate Deed Recordation Tax Act; Real Property Tax Rates for Tax Year 1987 Act of 1986 to grant exemptions from the transfer and deed recordation taxes for certain transfers of real property, without consideration, into or out of a revocable trust and to ensure that a property owner who transfers property into a revocable trust retains eligibility for certain owner occupier tax deductions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Revocable Trust Tax Exemption Amendment Act of 1991 ¯ See. 2. Section 402 of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1980, effective September 13, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-92; D.C. Code §47-902 is amended by adding 3 new paragraphs (12 13) and (14) to read as follows 12) A transfer of bare legal title into a revocable trust, without actual consideration for the transfer, where the transferor is the current beneficiary of the trust 13) A transfer of property to a named beneficiary of a revocable trust by reason of the death of the grantor of the revocable trust; and 14) A transfer of property by the trustee of a revocable trust if the transfer would otherwise be exempt under this section if made by the grantor of the revocable trust Sec. 3. Section 302 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Star. 11; D.C. Code §45-922 is amended by adding 3 new paragraphs (17 18 and (19) to read as follows 17) A deed by a transferor that conveys bare legal title to the trustee of a revocable trust, without consideration for the transfer, where the transferor is the beneficiary of the trust 18) A deed to property transferred to a beneficiary of a revocable trust as the result of the death of the grantor of the revocable trust; and 19) A deed to property transferred by the trustee of a revocable trust if the transfer would otherwise be exempt under this section if made by the grantor of the revocable trust Section 45-.922 Emolted Orilinal Sec. 4. Section 3(e) of the Residential Property Tax ttelief Act of 1977, effective February 28, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-45; D.C. Code §47-850(e is amended by adding a new paragraph (2-a) to read as follows 2-a) The eligibility of any real property for the deduction provided for in this section shall not be affected by the transfer of the real property into a revocable trust, so long as the transfer is without consideration and the property remains the principal residence of the transferor before and after the transfer Section 47-850 Sec. 5. Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-153; D.C. Code §47-863 is amended by adding a new subsection (a-l) to read as follows a-l) A property owner who is otherwise eligible for property tax relief under this section shall not lose the eligibility by virtue of a transfer of the property into a revocable trust, so long as the transfer is without consideration and the owner continues to reside in the property before and after the transfer Section 5 of the Real Property Tax l~ates for Tax Year 1987 Section 47-863 Sec. 6. The Mayor shall, pursuant to title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Star. 1204; D.C. Code §1-1501 et seq issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. Sec. 7. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental tteorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia ttegister, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: November 25, 1991 CO[!NCIL OF TIIE DISTRICT OF COL[~|BIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Bill 9-53 Adopted First Readin.g, 10-1-91 ApprovedVOICE V.OTE: ’Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. C~MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS all present X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~LAS ON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD I Secretary t e Coul~cil Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: COUNCIL MEMBER SMI THe JR. THOMAS SR. AYE NAY Date Adopted Final Reading, ii-5-9] Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CN}~N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting te m o n l o nSseeCnrtetcafr~ t;e cOuncIl CERTIFICATION RECORD Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CII WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON PAY A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.B. N.V PresenL not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS. SR AYE NAY NV. Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
