<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-70">
  <num type="law">9-70</num>
  <heading type="short">MEDICAID SPOUSAL MAINTENANCE NEEDS ALLOWANCE INCREASE ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-39</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-03-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-70.pdf">D.C. Law 9-70</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 18</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0039"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-70 "Medicaid Spousal Maintenance Needs Allowance Increase Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-39 on first and second readings, November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 20, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-121, published in the January 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 18) and transmitted to Congress on January 7, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-70, effective Dates Counted During the 30-day January February March March 11, 1992. j h rman of the Council Congressional Review Period 21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 2,3,4,5,6,9,10 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-i21 IN THE COUNCIL O1~ THE DISTRICT Ol~ COLUMBIA DECEMBER 20, i991 To increase the minimum monthly maintenance needs allowance for an institutionalized Medicaid beneficiary who has a spouse living in the community to the maximum amount allowable under federal law. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Medicaid Spousal Maintenance Needs Allowance Increase Act of 1991’I. See. 2. For purposes of protecting the income of the community spouse of a Medicaid beneficiary who is institutionalized, the Mayor is directed to set the minimum monthly maintenance needs allowance at the maximum level permitted under section 1924 of the Social Security Act, approved July 1, 1988 (102 Star. 758; 42 U.S.C. §1396r-5 and to amend the District of Columbia Medicaid State Plan accordingly. See. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations yor District of Columbia APPROVED: December 20, 1991 ~ltem on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: VOICE V,OTE: COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill 9-39 Adopted First Reading, 11-5-91 Approved present Recorded vote on request Absent: a i 1 ROLL CALL VOTE RESUL COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. CHHN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP .EVANS COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~LASON NATHANSON RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD \ Secretary t~the Council X Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE 7 COUNCIL MEMBER AYE ROI,AI~X SMI TH JR. THOMAS SR VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Date q: Adopted Final Reading, 12-3-91 Approved Absent: all present AYE NAY N.V. A,B. COUNCIEMEMBER AYE NAY NV. A.B, JARV LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.8 Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER NAY N.V Present, not votin9 CERTIFICATION RECORD ’ ’ COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote C}D{N. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS OLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR, u I Se"-cretary 1~ Co"~ncil Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. I A.B. CIIMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAW.FORD 9ROPP £~ANS x Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B. N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD J J J COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMITH, JR, THOMAS, SR Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-307.02a"/>
  </section>
</document>
