<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-71">
  <num type="law">9-71</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia World Cup Soccer Ticket Sales Promotional Amendment Act of 1991</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1992-03-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-71.pdf">D.C. Law 9-71</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 19</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0123">
      <narrative>Law 9-71, the “District of Columbia World Cup Soccer Ticket Sales Promotional Amendment Act of 1991,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-123, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 20, 1991, it was assigned Act No. 9-122 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 246 725 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 9-71 "District of Columbia World Cup Soccer Ticket Sales Promotional Amendment Act of 1991 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 9-123 on first and second readings, November 5, 1991, and December 3, 1991, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 20, 1991, this legislation was assigned Act No. 9-122, published in the January 3, 1992, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 39 page 19) and transmitted to Congress on January 7, 1992 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(I) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 9-71, effective March 11 1992 4~N A. WILSON C/hairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: january February March 21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27,28 2,3,4,5,6,9,10 AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-122 Dist ot Columbia Code 6upplement) IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 20, 1991 To amend the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act to allow a sales tax exemption for tickets sold at the 1994 World Cup Soccer Games. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia World Cup Soccer Ticket Sales Promotional Amendment Act of 1991 See. 2. Section 128 of the District of Columbia Sales Tax Act, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Star. 115; D.C. Code §47-2005) is amended as follows a) Subsection (y) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting or" in its place; and (b) A new subsection (z) is added to read as follows z) Sales of tickets sold for the 1994 World Cup Soccer Games See. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations. Section 47-2005 Cha Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: December 20, 1991 ]~1 Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Adopted First Approved Bill 9-123 Readinq ii-5-91 Absent: all present ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER CRNN. WILSON JARVIS BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD [~LAS ON CROP P NATHAN S ON ¯ EVANS RAY X indicates Vote A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD rt; tca~lYe tr~ tahr e u n~c II ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: all present AYE NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER ROLAP/&amp;lt ’--1 AYE NAY NV. SMITH JR. THOMAS, SR. N.V Present, not votin9 Date Reading, 12-3-91 ROLL CALL VOTE RESt COUNCIL MEMBER CHMN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS IAYE T NAY NV. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARV I S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent AYE NAY NV. A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAYN.V. X Indicates Vote NN Present, not voting ROLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS, SR. CERTIFICATION RECORD Sec tt~tt~ to th~ Council Item on Consent Calendar Date ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B C~,MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD 9ROPP ~VANS X Indicates Vote COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON PAY A.B Absent AYE NAY N.V. A.B, NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ROLARK SMI’I~-], JR. THOMAS. SR Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
