<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-82">
  <num type="law">9-82</num>
  <heading type="short">Condominium Act of 1976 Technical and Clarifying Amendment Act of 1992</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-03-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-82.pdf">D.C. Law 9-82</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 683</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0240">
      <narrative>Law 9-82, the “Condominium Act of 1976 Technical and Clarifying Amendment Act of 1992,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 9-240, which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 17, 1991, and January 7, 1992, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 28, 1992, it was assigned Act No. 9-140 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 9-82 became effective on March 20, 1992.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 246 647 Enrolled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-140 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 28, 1992 To amend the Condominium Act of 1976 to make technical and clarifying amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Condominium Act of 1976 Technical and Clarifying Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. The Condominium Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-89; D.C. Code §1801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 101 (D.C. Code §45-1801) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows a) This act shall apply to all condominiums created in the District of Columbia after the effective date of this act. Sections 103, 104, 105, 106, 203, 206, 207, 208, 209, 230, 305(d 308(a)(1) through (6 308(a)(11) through (16 309, 313, 314, 320, 411, 413, 414, 415, 416, 417, and 102 to the extent necessary in construing any of those sections, shall apply to any condominium and to any horizontal property regime or condominium project created in the District of Columbia before the effective date of this act, except that these sections shall apply only with respect to an event or circumstance that occurs after the effective date of this act and shall not invalidate any existing provision of the condominium instruments of any condominium, horizontal property regime, or condominium project 2) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows c) This act shall supersede the Horizontal Property Act of the District of Columbia tIorizontal Property Act approved December 21, 1963 (77 Star. 449; D.C. Code §45-1701 et seq and Regulation 74-26 of the District of Columbia City Council, enacted October 18, 1974. No condominium shall be established except pursuant to this act after March 28, 1977. This act shall not be construed, however, to affect the validity of any provision of any condominium instrument complying with the requirements of the Horizontal Property Act and recorded prior to March 28, 1977. Except for section 411, title IV shall not apply to any condominium created prior to March 29, 1977. Any amendment to the condominium instruments of any condominium, horizontal property regime, or condominium project created before March 29, 1977, shall be valid and enforceable if the amendment would be per~nitted by this act and if the amendment was adopted in conformity with the procedures and requirements specified by those condominium instruments and by the Section 45-1801 Enrolled Original applicable law in effect when the amendment was adopted. If an amendment grants a person any right, power, or privilege permitted by this act, any correlative obligation, liability, or restriction in this act shall apply to that person 3) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase "The Condominium Amendment Act" and adding the phrase "This act" in its place 4) A new subsection (e) is added to read as follows e) Except as otherwise provided in this act, amendments to this act shall not invalidate any provision of any condominium instrument which was permitted under this act at the time the provision was recorded b) Section 102(d D.C. Code §45-1802(4 is amended by striking the phrase "the Condominium Amendment Act" and adding the phrase "this act" in its place c) Section 107 (D.C. Code §45-1807) is amended by striking the phrase "the Condominium Amendment Act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this act" in its place d) Section 108 (D.C. Code §45-1808) is amended by striking the phrase "the Condominium Amendment Act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this act" in its place e) Section 213 (D.C. Code §45-1823) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (c)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "method prescribed" and adding the phrase "the method prescribed by" in its place 2) Subsection (c)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "the effective date of the Condominium Amendment Act" and adding the phrase "March 8, 1991 in its place f) Section 223(a D.C. Code §45-1833(a is amended in the 2nd sentence by striking the phrase "affect any obligation" and adding the phrase "affect that obligation" in its place g) Section 227 (D.C. Code §45-1837) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "the right conferred" and adding the phrase "the right conferred by this section" in its place 2) Subsection (e) is amended in the lead-in language by striking the phrase "create or 3) Subsection (e)(1) is amended by striking the word "Increase" and adding the phrase "Create or increase" in its place 4) Subsection (e)(5) is amended by striking the phrase "consent to" and adding the phrase "consent of" in its place 5) Subsection (f)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "[two thirds ] h) Section 228 (D.C. Code §45-1838) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (d) is amended in the 1st sentence by striking the phrase "that the common elements of units" and adding the phrase "that all the common elements and units" in its place 2) Subsection (f) is amended in the 5th sentence by striking the phrase "distributed to a unit owner or lien holder as his or her interest may appear" and adding the phrase "distributed to unit owners and lien holders as their interests may appear" in its place, and in the 7th sentence by striking the phrase "for an assessment" and adding the phrase "for any assessment" in its place. Section 45-1802 Section 45-1807 Section 45-1808 Section 45-1823 Section 45-1833 Section 45-1837 Section 45-1838 Original (3) Subsection (g) is amended by striking the phrases "Any lien" and "his or her successor" and adding the phrases "Any liens" and "his or her successors" respectively in their places 4) Subsection (h) is amended in the 1st sentence by striking the phrase "as the unit owner’s or lien/holders’ interests may appear" and adding the phrase "as their interests may appear" in its place i} Section 230 (D.C. Code §45-1839.1) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (e)(2)(B)(iii) is amended by striking the word [ any ] 2) Subsection (e)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "of (this act j) Section 305(d D.C. Code §45-1845(d is amended by adding a sentence at the beginning to read as follows Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of the condominium instruments, this subsection establishes the requirements for the validity of proxies k) Section 313(a)(D.C. Code §45-1853(a is amended to read as follows a) Any assessment levied against a condominium unit in accordance with the provisions of this act and any lawful provision of the condominium instruments shall, from the time the assessment becomes due and payable, constitute a lien in favor of the unit owners’ association on the condominium unit to which the assessment pertains. If an assessment is payable in installments, the full amount of the assessment shall be a lien from the time the 1st installment becomes due and payable 1) The lien shall be prior to any other lien or encumbrance except A) A lien or encumbrance recorded prior to the recordation of the declaration B) A 1st mortgage for the benefit of an institutional lender or a 1st deed of trust for the benefit of an institutional lender on the unit recorded before the date on which the assessment sought to be enforced became delinquent; or C) A lien for real estate taxes or municipal assessments or charges against the unit 2) The lien shall also be prior to a mortgage or deed of trust described in subsection (a 1 B) of this section and recorded after March 7, 1991, to the extent of the common expense assessments based on the periodic budget adopted by the unit owners’ association which would have become due in the absence of acceleration during the 6 months immediately preceding institution of an action to enforce the lien. The provisions of this subsection shall not affect the priority of mechanics’ or materialmen’s lien 1) Section 316(b D.C. Code §45-1856(b is amended to read as follows b) A declarant shall warrant against structural defects in each of the units for 2 years from the date each unit is 1st conveyed to a bona fide purchaser, and all of the common elements for 2 years. The 2 years shall begin as to any portion of the common elements whenever the portion has been completed or, if later 1) If within any additional land or portion thereof that does not contain a unit, at the time the additional land is added to the condominium; Section 45-1839.1 Section 45-1845 Section 45-1853 Section 45-1856 Enrolled Original 2) If within any convertible land or portion thereof that does not contain a unit, at the time the convertible land may no longer be converted 3) If within any additional land or convertible land or portion of either that does contain a unit, at the time the ist unit therein is ist conveyed to a bona fide purchaser; or 4) If within any other portion of the condominium, at the time the Ist unit is ist conveyed to a bona fide purchaser m) Section 317 (D.C. Code § 45-1857) is amended to read as follows A judicial proceeding for breach of any warranty that arises under section 316 shall be commenced within 5 years after the date the warranty period began n) Section 404(a-I D.C. Code §45-1864(a-1 is amended by repealing the text designated as the 2nd paragraph (4) which reads as follows 4) A statement of any services not reflected in the budget which decIarant provides, or expenses which he pays, and which he expects may become at any subsequent time a common expense of the unit owners’ association, and the projected common expense assessment attributable to each of those services or expenses for each time-share estate o) Section 411 (D.C. Code §45-1871) is amended as follows i) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "prior to" and inserting the phrase "on or prior to the 10th business day following" in its place 2) Subsection (a)(1) is amended to read as follows I) Appropriate statements pursuant to section 313(h) and, if applicable, section 315, which need not be in recordable form 3) Subsection (a-l) is amended to read as follows a-1)(J) If the condominium instruments and certificate prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section are not furnished to the purchaser on or prior to the 10th business day following the date of execution of the contract of sale by the purchaser, the purchaser shall have the right to cancel the contract by giving notice in writing to the seller prior to receipt of the condominium instruments and certificate, but not after conveyance under the contract 2) Except as provided pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection, the purchaser shall have the right for a period of 3 business days following the purchaser’s receipt of the condominium instruments and certificate prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, whether or not such receipt occurs within the time period described in subsection (a) of this section, to cancel the contract by giving notice in writing and returning the condominium instruments and certificate to the seller, provided that the purchaser may not so cancel the contract after conveyance under the contract 3) If the purchaser cancels the contract pursuant to paragraphs (1) or (2) of this subsection, the purchaser shall receive back any earnest money or other deposit without delay or deduction 4) From and after the earlier of (i) the expiration of the 3 business-day period for review prescribed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, or an extension of the 3 business-day period agreed to by the parties in a signed writing, or (ii) conveyance under the contact, Section 45-1857 Section 45-1864 Section 45-1871 Enrolled Original if the purchaser has not exercised the right to cancel, the contract shall not be cancellable by the purchaser under this subsection 5) If the condominium instruments and certificate are furnished to the purchaser on or prior to execution of the contract of sale by the purchaser, the 3 business-day period for review prescribed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection shall commence when the contract is executed by the purchaser Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbj,~M’unicipal Regulations. C Co]~nc//1 of the District of Columbia [’/ District of Columbia APPROVED: January 28, 1992 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [~ VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT 9-240 Adopted First Reading~ 12-17-91 Approved all present r COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE CHHN. WILSON JARVI S ROLAP~K BRAZIL LIGHTFOOT SMITH L JR. CRAWFORD ~LASON THOMAS SR. CROPP t NATHANSON EVANS RAY X Indicates Vote A.B Absent NV Present, not votincJ Reading, 0,1-07-92 CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretar tt~e C~uncil Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted Final VOICE VOTE: Approved NAY N.V. Recorded vote on request Absent: Lightfoot [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY ~{]~£q. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. JARVIS ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH. JR. MASON THOMAS SR. NATHANSON RAY X Indicates Vote A.8 Absent N.V Present, not votin~J CERTIFICATION RECORD Se~’ta~y t8 the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: [] VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. C,MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B, i COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR, MASON THOMAS, SR. NATHANSO~ RAY A.8 Absent NV Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD AYE NAY X Indicates Vote Secretary to the Council Date Enrolled Odginal AN ACT Co¢liflca n D.C, ACT 9-140 District of Columbia IN THE COUNCIL O1~ THE DISTRICT 0 COLUMBIA JANUARY 28, 1992 To amend the Condominium Act of 1976 to make technical and clarifying amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Condominium Act of 1976 Technical and Clarifying Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. The Condominium Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-89; D.C. Code {}1801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 101 (D.C. Code §45-1801) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows a) This act shall apply to all condominiums created in the District of Columbia after the effective date of this act. Sections 103, 104, 105, 106, 203, 206, 207, 208, 209, 230, 305(d 308(a)(1) through (6 308(a)(11) through (16 309, 313, 314, 320, 411, 413, 414, 415, 416, 417, and 102 to the extent necessary i construing any of those sections, shall apply to any condominium and to any horizontal property regime or condominium project created in the District of Columbia before the effective date of this act, except that these sections shall apply only with respect to an event or circumstance that occurs afte- the effective date of thi act and shall not invalidate any existing pruvision of the condominium instruments of any condominium, horizontal property regime, or condominium project 2) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows c) This act shall supersede the Horizontal Property Act of the District of Columbia Horizontal Property Act approved December 21, 1963 77 star. 449; D.C. Code {}45-1701 et seq and Regulation 74~26 of the District of Columbia City Council, enacted October 18, 1974. No condominium shall be establlshed except pursuant to this act after March 28, 1977. This act shall not be construed, however, to affect the validity of any provision of any condominium instrument complying with the requirements of the Horizontal Property Act and recorded prior to March 28, 1977. Except for section 411, title IV shall not apply to any condomJnlum created prior to March 29, 1977. Any amendment to the condomlnlum instruments of any condominium, horizontal property regime, or condominium project created before March 29, 1977, shall be valid and enforceable if the amendment would be permitted by this act and if the amendment was adopted in conformity with the procedures and requirements specified by those condominium instruments and by the Section 45-1801 Enrolled Original applicable law in efi~ect when the amendment was adopted. If an amendment grants a person any right, power, or privilege permitted by this act, any correlative obligation, liability, or restriction in this act shall apply, to that person 3) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase "The Condominium Amendment Act" and adding the phrase "This act" in its place 4) A new subsection (e) is added to read as follows e) Except as otherwise provided in this act, amendments to this act shall not invalidate any provision of any condominium instrument which was permitted under this act at the time the provision was recorded b) Section I02(d D.C. Code {}45-1802(4 is amended by striking the phrase "the Condominium Amendment Act" and adding the phrase "this act" in its place c) Section 107 (D.C. Code §45-1807) is amended by striking the phrase "the Condominium Amendment Act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this act" in its place d) Section 108 (D.C. Code §45-1808) is amended by striking the phrase "the Condominium Amendment Act" wherever it appears and adding the phrase "this act" in its place e) Section 213 (D.C. Code §45-1823) is amended as follows i) Subsection (c)(i) is amended by striking the phrase "method prescribed" and adding the phrase "the method prescribed by" in its place 2) Subsection (c)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "the effective date of the Condominium Amendment Act" and adding the phrase "March 8, 1991 in its place f) Section 223(a D.C. Code §45-1833(a is amended in the 2nd sentence by striking the phrase "a£1~ect any obligation" and adding the phrase "affect that obligation" in~ its place g) Section 227 (D.C. Code §45-1837) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "the ¯ right conferred" and adding the phrase "the right conferred by this section" in its place 2) Subsection (e) is amended in the lead-ln language by striking the phrase ’"create or 3) Subsection (e)(1) is amended by striking the word "Increase" and adding the phrase "Create or increase" in its place 4) Subsection (e)(5) is amended by striking the phrase "consent to" and adding the phrase "consent of" in its place 5) Subsection (f)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "[two thirds ]’ h) Section 228 (D.C. Code §45-1838) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (d) is amended in the ist sentence by striking the phrase "that the common elements of units" and adding the phrase "that all the common elements and units" in its place 2) Subsection (f) is amended in the 5th sentence by striking the phrase "distributed to a unit owner or lien holder as his or her interest may appear" and adding the phrase "distributed to unit owners and lien holders as their interests may appear" in its place, and in the 7th sentence by striking the phrase "for an assessment" and adding the phrase "for any assessment" in its place. Section 45-1802 Section 45-1807 Section 45-1808 Section 45-1823 Section 45-1833 Section 45-1837 Section 45-1838 |nroiled Original (3) Subsection (g) is amended by striking the phrases "Any lien" and "his or her successor" and adding the phrases "Any liens" and "his or her successors" respectively in their places 4) Subsection (h) is amended in the Ist sentence by striking the phrase "as the unit owner’s or lien/holders’ interests may appear" and adding the phrase "as their interests may appear" in its place 1) Section 230 (D.C. Code §45-1839.1) is amended as follows I) Subsection (e)(2)(B)(ili) is amended by striking the word "[any] 2) Subsection (e)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "of (this act J) Section 305(d D.C. Code §45-1845(d is amended by adding a sentence at the beginning to read as follows Notwithstanding any contrary provisions of the condominium instruments, this subsection establishes the requirements for the validity of proxies k) Section 313(a)(D.C. Code §45-1853(a is amended to read as follows a) Any assessment levied against a condominium unit in accordance with the provisions of this act and any lawful provision of the condominium instruments shall, from the time the assessment becomes due and payable, constitute a lien in favor of the unit owners’ association on the condominium unit to which the assessment pertains. If an assessment is payable in installments, the i~ull amount of the assessment shall be a llen from the time the Ist installment becomes due and payable I) The lien shall be prior to any other lien or encumbrance except A) A lien or encumbrance recorded prior to the recordatlon o£ the declaration B) A 1st mortgage for the benefit of an institutional lender or a ist deed o( trust for the benefit of an institutional lender on the unit recorded before the date on which the assessment sought to be enforced became delinquent; or C) A lien for real estate taxes or municipal assessments or charges against the u-.Air 2) The lien shall also be prior to a mortgage or deed of trust described in subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section and recorded after March 7, 1991, to the extent of the common expense assessments based on the periodic budget adopted by the unit owners’ association which would have become due in the absence of acceleration during the 6 months immediately preceding institution of an action to enforce the lien. The provislows of this subsection shall not affect the priority of mechanics’ or materlalmen’s lien I) Section 316(b D.C. Code §45-1856(b is amended to read as follows b) A declarant shall warrant against structural defects in each of the units for 2 years from the date each unit is tat conveyed to a bona fide purchaser, and all of the common elements for 2 years. The 2 years shall begin as to any portion of the common elements whenever the portion has been completed or, if later 1) If within any additional land or portion thereof that does not contain a unit, at the time the additional land is added to the condominium; Section 45-1839 Section 45-1845 Section 45-1853 Section 45-1856 Enrolled Original 2) If within any convertible land or portion thereof that does not contain a unit, at the time the convertible land may no longer be converted 3) If within any additional land or convertible land or portion of either that does contain a unit, at the time the 1st unit therein is 1st conveyed to a bona fide purchaser; or 4) If within any other portion of the condominium, at the time the 1st unit is let conveyed to a bona fide purchaser m) Section 317 (D.C. Code § 45-1857) is amended to read as follows A Judicial proceeding for breach of any warranty that arises under section 31{; shall be commenced within 5 years after the date the warranty period began n) Section 404(a-i D.C. Code §45-1864(a-i is amended by repealing the text designated as the 2nd paragraph (4) which reads as follows 4) A statement of any services not reflected in the budget which declarant provides, or expenses which he pays, and which he expects may become at any subsequent time a common expense of the unit owners’ association, and the projected common expense assessment attributable to each of those services or expenses for each time-share estate o) Section 411 (D.C. Code {}45-1871) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase "prior to" and inserting-the phrase "on or prior to the 10th business day following" in its place 2) Subsection (a)(1) is amended to read as follows I) Appropriate statements pursuant to section 313(h) and, if applicable, section 315, which need not be in recordable form ¯ 3) Subsection (a-l) is amended to read as follows a- I I) If the condominium instruments and certificate prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section are not furnished to the purchaser on or prior to the 10th business day following the date of execution of the contract of sale by the purchaser, the purchaser shall have the right to cancel the contract by giving notice in writing to the seller prior to receipt of the condominium instruments and certificate, but not after conveyance under the contract 2) Except as provided pursuant to paragraph (5) of this subsection, the purchaser shall have the right for a period of 3 business days following the purchaser’s receipt of the condominium instruments and certificate prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, whether or not such receipt occurs within the time period described in subsection (a) of this section, to cancel the contract by giving notice in writing and returning the condominium instruments and certificate to the seller, provided that the purchaser may not so cancel the contract after conveyance under the contract 3) If the purchaser cancels the contract pursuant to paragraphs (i) or (2) of this subsection, the purchaser shall receive back any earnest money or other deposit without delay or deduction 4) From and after the earlier of (i) the expiration of the 3 business-day period for review prescribed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, or an extension of the 3 buslness-day period agreed to by the parties in a signed writing, or (ii) conveyance under the contact Section 45-1857 Section 45-186a Section 45-1871 Enrolled Original if the purchaser has not exercised the right to cancel, the contract shall not be cancellable by the purchaser under this subsection 5) If the condominium instruments and certificate are furnished .to the purchaser on or prior to execution of the contract of sale by the purchaser, the 3 business-day period £or review prescribed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection shah commence when the contract is executed by the purchaser Sec. 3. This act shah take effect after a 30-day period oi~ Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columb~ta~M’unicipal Regulations. Ch Co~in~fl of the District of Columbia District oI~ Columbia APPROVED: January 28, 1992 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO: Bill Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: 9-240 AdoDted First Reading. 12-17-91 Approvg all present [] ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V.A.8. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY C~MN. WILSON JARVI S BEAZIL LIGHTFOOT CRAWFORD MASON CROPP NATHANSON K--qAN KAY A.B, COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY NV. ROT,r~RK X Indicates Vote A.B Absent N.V Present. not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Final Readinq, 01-07-92 Approved Secretary-the Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Adopted _Lightfoot VOICE VOTE: Recorde:l vote on re&amp;lt;~uest Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER JARVI S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY A,B Absent AYE NAY N.V, A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER N.V Present, not votin~ L~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V, A.8 CI WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFOR~ CROPP EVANS X indicates Vote CERTIFICATION RECORD S ¯ Council ROLARK S141TH. THOMAS, SR. AYE NAY [ NV. A.B. Item on Conse~ Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; OA7 vOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. JARVIS LIGHTFO0~ MASON NATHAN$O AY A.B Absent NV Present, not voting. CERTIFICATION RECORD [~ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER I AYE NAY N.V.A.B. CH WILSON BRAZIL CRAW-FORD ~RO~ £’VA~S X trial=cares Vote COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N V ROLARK SMITH, THOMAS. SR. Secretary to me Counc=l Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
