<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 9-93">
  <num type="law">9-93</num>
  <heading type="short">EDUCATION IN PARTNERSHIP WITH TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION ESTABLISHMENT ACT CAPITALIZATION AMENDMENT ACT OF 1991, BILL 9-239</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1992-04-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/9-93.pdf">D.C. Law 9-93</citation>
      <citation type="register">39 DCR 1371</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B9-0239"/>
    <search-text>E ROLLMENT(S) kwiktag ® 103 246 653 0 0 0 Enrotled Original AN ACT D,C, ACT 9-161 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FEBRUARY 21, 1992 To amend the Education in Partnership with Technology Corporation Establishment Act of 1986 to allow certain donations from private sources to be treated as contributions to capitalization. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Education in Partnership with Technology Corporation Establishment Act of 1986 Capitalization Amendment Act of 1992 Sec. 2. Section 9(4) of the Education in Partnership with Section Technology Corporation Establishment Act of 1986, effective February 24, 31-2508 1987 (D.C. Law 6-170; D.C. Code §31-2508(4 is amended by adding the phrase "of equipment, or in-kind services, or other cash or non-cash contributions" after the phrase "a commitment for funding Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a 30-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233(c)(1 and publication in either the District of Columbia Register, the District of Columbia Statutes-at-Large, or the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations Chairmgn Counc~{l of the District of Columbia rOt District of Columbia APPROVED February 21, 1992 COUNCIL OF HE DISTRICT OF COLU]~B[A Council Period Nine RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE DOCKET NO Item on Consent Calendar ~] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. AB. C~MN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVAN£ X Indicates Vote Secretary o~e Council Item on Consent Calendar ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: Bill 9-239 Adopted First Reading, 1-7-92 Approved Lightfoot COUNCILMEMBER JARVIS LIGHTFOOT ~[AS ON NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Adopted Final AYE NAY N.V, A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. ROLAI~II SMITH L JR amp;I{OHAS, SR. NV Present, not voting Reading, 2-4-92 VOICE VOTE: Approved Recorded vote on request Absent: Evans C_ ROLL CALL VOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. CHMIN. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANS COUNCIL MEMBER JARVI S LIGHTFOOT MASON NATHANSON RAY AYE NAY N.V. A.B COUNCILMEMBER OLARK SMITH. JR. THOMAS SR. AYE NAY N.V. X Indicates Vote Secr~j~ry to Council Item on Consent Calendar A.B Absent N.V Present, not voting CERTIFICATION RECORD ate ’~’-’~ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE: C VOICEVOTE: Recorded vote on request Absent: L~ ROLLCALLVOTE RESULT. COUNCIL MEMBER C~MIq. WILSON BRAZIL CRAWFORD CROPP EVANg AYE NAY NV. A.B. X Indicates Vote COUNCILMEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER JARVIS ROLARK LIGHTFOOT SMITH, JR, MA£0N THOMAS. SR. NATHANSON RAY A.B Absent NV Present. not voting AYE NAY CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
