<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-108" flag="true">
  <num type="law">3-108</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-09-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-108.pdf">D.C. Law 3-108</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 3781</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-108 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-191, which was referred to the Committee on Transportation and Environmental Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 15, 1980 and July 29, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 31, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-233 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLLl~ 3IA NO TICE D.C. LAW 3-1 08 Ne i g h b o r ho o d M u n i c i p a 1 0 f f S t r e e t P a r i n g F a c i li t i e s Act o f 1 980 Pu r sua nt to Sec tion 412 of the District o f Columbia Se l f Gov e rn ment and Governmental Reorganizatio n Acr, P. L. 93 198 rhe Act the Council of the Dis t rict of Co lumbia ado p ted 3ill ?fo 3 1 9 1, on first and second readings, Jul y 15, 1980 a r,d July 29 1980, respectively. Following the signature of the 1ay or on July 31, 1980, this legis l ation was assigned Act No. 3-233, pub lished in the August 29, 1980, edition cf the D.C. Regisrer Vol. 27 page 3781) and tran smitted to Congress on August 1, 19 80 for a 30-day review, in accordance ~ith Section 602 (c l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notic e that the 30 day Congressiona l Revi ew Period has expired, an t b.erefore, cit es this enactment as D.C. La-w j-108 effecti v e Se pte mb er 26, 1980. r \\ { AR R.1.'\GT 0 DI X 0 Chai ~man of the Counc i l Da res Co unted During the 3 0 day Co~gressional Review Period: Augu s t 1 ,4,5, 6 18 ,19,2 0 ,21, 22,25 25 ,27 ,23 Sept ember 3 4 5 8 '9 '1 0 '11 1 2 15' 16 1 7 18' 2. 9 2 2 '2 3 2 4, 2 5 D.C. LAW 3 10 8 I~ THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CDLU~BI~ To aut,orize tne estaol ish~ent of neiqnoornood municip31 off-Streat par~inQ facilities to encouraqe econoTiic 1evelooment and St30lization i, neiqnoornoods• BE IT ENACTED 3Y T~E CJUNCIL OF THE DIST~l:T O OLUMBIA• Th3t t,is ~ct ~ay oe cited as the ~Nai~noornood ~unicioal Jff-Street P3rkinq F3ci1 ities Act of 1980 Sec• 2. Tne Council of the Jistrict of :olumoia finds (a) A numoer of traditional neiqhoorhooa conmerci31 centers nave suffered and declined b any of tnese oecl ininq naiqhnorhooa conmerci31 :enters nave traaition3lly encoura~e1 ana oromoted minority entrepreneurship and e~ployment opportunities c) One of the District's qoals is tha revitalizati:&amp;gt;n of nei~hoornooj conmercial are3s for tne purooses of :reati,q n ew jobs• increasinq incones• and increasin~ tn O)DIFICATICN Note, D.C.Code, sec. 40-804 :ivailaoility of qoods 3nj services at the neiqnoorr'1ooa l evel uar ti cJlarly in 10~-ana TIOder3te-i,come neiqnoornooas; 2 (d) One of the n3jor proolens ninjerinq tne re11ital ization of neiqhbOrhoOd comnercial centers is t,e l3ck of 3dequate snort-ter~ oarkin~ f3:il ities for Shoopers e) If the District is to achieve its goal of re11ital ization of these co~merci3l ar~3s a~d maximize their qrowth potential. lo~-cost short-tarn oarkinq nust be orovided in or adjacent to sucn ceiters. Sec. 3. The District of Columoi3 ~otor Vehicle P3rkinq Faci I ity Act of lq42. aporovea Febru3ry 16. 1942 (56 Stat O; D Code. sec 0-801 ~t iS a~ended as follows a) By stri~inq tne wora "Comnissioner" wnere11er it aooears and insertinq the wora avor" in lieu tnereof O) S2ction 3 (D.c. Code. s ec 0-804) is 3.-nenaea as foll ows l the introductory oaraqraon is amenjed to reaa "Tne ~avor of the District of Columoia is convenient to carry out tne pJruoses of tnis ~Ct• the saij ourooses beinq hereby decl area to ~e tne nereinaftar provided• unaer oubl i: requlations. of Duo 1 i c of f- street oar lt; i n q f 3 c i 1 i t i es i n t :ie D.C.Ccde, sec. 40-801 et seq. D.C.Code, sec. 40-804 3 District of Columoia as a nac:ssary incident to ins~rino in tne public interest t,e free cir:ulation of traffic in a1d throuqh tne District of Columbia and to promotin~ the economic gro#tn and staoility of neignoornood comTiercial centers. Sue, jQ~ers include. but Sh31 l not oe l imitea to 2) subsection (a) is amended bY inserting the followinq sentences imTiediately after the ohrase ecessary gt;r expedient In the case of neignoornooa municipal off- street oarKinq ondemnation powers. under tne provisions of :hapter 13 of title 16 of the Distri:t of :olumbia Coae. shall not oe used to acquire resiaenti~l prooertY on wn i :h there are imorovements or conmercial orooertv #ith imorovements that are in use. Before acquiring any real oropertv for neiqhoorhood Tiunicioal off-street par~ing facilities or estaol isninq such fa:il ities tne ~ay:&amp;gt;r s~all 1ola at leist one juolic hearinq ana request any affectej Advisory Nei~hoorhood Co~mission(s) for its comments and reJorts #ithin tnirty jays of such reoJeSt•"i c) Section 5 co Code. sec 0-806) is anendecJ bV 3djinq tne followinq orovisions 3t e end tnereof eiqnDor~ooa municip3l off-straet ~arking fa:ilities s~all not be locate:l in districts zon ao C-4. D.C.Code, sec. 40-806 4 they be astaol is~ea on lots on w,iCh housing currently exists or on parcels withi, four blocks of a Matrorail station stop and (d) Section 10 (O.c. Coae. sec. 4C&amp;gt;-909a) is anendao by l deletinq inmediately follo~i,q tne phr3sa "fringe Jarkin~ facility" the word "ana anj (2) aaaing inmediacely after the ohrase uol ic hiqnway" tne ohrase "ana (4) any neiqnbornood off-street oarking facil icy to promote economic ~rowth and staoil ity Se 4. Tnis act shall tal(e effect after a thirty (30) jay oeriod of Conqressional review following aooroval oy tne ~avor (or in the event of veto by tna ~avor• action oy tne :ouncil of t,e District of Colum~ia co override the veto) as nrovidad in sectio 02(c 1) of tne District of Columoia aooroved Decemoer 24. 1973 (87 Stat. 813 Code• sec. 1- l47(c)(l&amp;gt;&amp;gt f r District of Columbia APPROVED: July 31~ 1980 o.c.eoae, sec. 40- 809a i I i I CCONCml CF TIIE DI S'RICT OF Cillll!llilA E'liillJ CJF CIFRQ11.1comD::U..AaUGI cocxr: NO: B 3-191 M:'tION: Adopted First Reading 7-15-80 fii VQta VQ1 U n a n i m o u~s A.Meat: Mggre D 1 :I IN KANE SHACKI. Ei'Ol\ tM M' MASON SP~ITT.DING 4 Qin MOORE WTT c;:nN t1A'l1T'\V Q'1V TA'O~C OnT A QT c l4 \ J a l l L.W c%ll u er a?CCitC scrwcarr en. Coua.c:U Aet:ON Ad o~p~t~e~d F-ina_.l R~e~a-d-in~g 7 2_9_8_0 6i votc:z: vom _Ma J,_o_r_i_tY AG.ec a_l_l p_r_e_s_e_n_t c I T'lrrnn I 1'ITT I Ar'!n F'T'n TJ N I 'fA C:f'l1'f C:1 TTT n nrr. f"r .1 '11tn \(&amp;lt;1&amp;lt;1QF r.m c: f'l1'f I l:A'QT'\V 1u,y I I ru1~c: QnT .11:nr I d \ l. c JJ a cam:o o~ o u:cc.m c1 AC?:ON 0 VOtc:Z VO A.ta8eac I a </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2634"/>
  </section>
</document>
