<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-146">
  <num type="law">3-146</num>
  <heading type="short">Alcoholic Beverage Control Board Rules of Procedure Amendments of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1981-03-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-146.pdf">D.C. Law 3-146</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 4753</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-146, the “Alcoholic Beverage Control Board Rules of Procedure Amendments of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-165, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first and second readings on July 29, 1980, September 16, 1980 and September 30, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 21, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-267 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 3-146 "Alcoholic Beverage Control Board Rules of Procedures Amendments of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Govecnmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No 3-165 on first, amended first and second readings, July 29, 1980, Septembec 16, 1980 and Septembec 30, 1980, respectively. Following the signatuce of the Mayoc on Octobec 21, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-267, published in the October 31, 1980 edition of the o.c. Register Vol. 27 page 4753 This act was ociginally transmitted to Congress on October 24, 1980, and resubmitted on January 14, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-146, effective March 5, 1981. \ ARRINGTON Chairman of the Council 8ates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January 14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 February 2,3,4,5,6,17,l8,l9,20,23,24,25,26,27, D.C. LAW 3 14 6 D.C. ACT 3 2 6 7 IN T~E CJU~CIL OF THE OIST~I::T a~ COLuMB[A OCT 2 1 1980 To revise tne orocedur3l rules of or~ctice to qovern hearinqs oefore tne District of Columbia Alcoholic Bever3qe :ontro1 ao~r1• and for otner ~urooses. CHAP TE~ I I PART 20 GENERAL P~OVISIONS GO~E~NIN EARINGS BEFORE THE ~O~RJ gt;ec 2J.1 J f F p,1£ TI JN 5 5ec. 21.2 O\IFLI:TING ORJVISIO\IS o= LAw 5ec. 2J.3 JT~E~ 0 E~5JNS AV :3 E f-4tA ~0 Sec. 2 \JOTI::E Sec. 2J.5 TI E LllvlITATIO\jS 5ec. 2 SE~VICE JF PAPERS ec. 2a.1 =AILURt ro APPEA~ FO iE&amp;lt;\R ING e 21.q :a TINJA\IC::s 5ec. 2J P 0 EAR ~NC E A \10 l&amp;lt;EP~ESE'IT~T I O'J n QJ.J 1 f I Ccdif ication D.C.M.R. Note, D.C. Code,Sec.25-107 2 Sec. 20.13 3U~OEN a~ PROOF Sec. ZJ.14 JBJECTIO~S TO EVIDENCE; Ex:EPTIO~S ·Sec. 2J.t5 )F~E~S OF PROOF Sec. 2J.l7 ~ECO~OS IN OTHER P~O:EcDINGS Sec 20.18 S TIPuLATIO~ Sec. ZJ.19 ~OTIONS PRACTICE Sec. ZJ.20 ~ECEIPT JF I~FOR~ATIJN A~TER HEARI~G Sec 20.21 EX P~RfE CJM~UNICATIJNS Sec. ZJ.22 DINGS OF FACT ANO CJN:LJSIO~S OF LA~ PART 21 TJ PRJTEST ~EARf~ GS JELI~E~TIO~ OF NEIGH80~HJOD ~AJiuS PLAT-LOCATIJNS i.1.r 0 1.1 n 0 c gt;~c 2 l P, c. 2 l Sec 21 1 Sec. 21.a Sec. 21 3 PETITI Y.h ~EAL P~ OPE~ TY ~ITHI N 600 ~EET ~AJIJS i30ARO'S ~ECOROS FI~OIN~S OF FACT ANO CJN:LJSIO~S OF LAN rt r- 1 1· 7 c 9E If ENACTED dY T~E CJU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF :OLUMB Tn~t t~is 3Ct ~av oe cited as the "Alconol ic 1everaqe Control Board Rules of Procedure ~mandments of 1980 Se 2 P3rts 20 3nd 21 of :h3pt8r II of the Alconolic 3evera~e Control Raqul~tio,s 3pD r oved 35 fo l lo s: Definitions gt;r ou r ~oses of t~ese Rule s nl es s t ne context in1icates otnerwis e i) D=finit.ions contain ed in :h~Dt?.r r. 0 c1rt I of t,es e Rules. an~ in s ection lJ2 of tn a -lOulic~tion of t:1e Act J C. C:&amp;gt;a s~c 25-lJl ec 'i~Q •l Jr or' tnes ul e5 to 3 0 1rr:i:ul:3r li cens i:&amp;gt;l~tiois of tn e Act (O.C. Coae. s 25-101 2~ Such naari1q snail oe consider ea t:&amp;gt; oe a contested C3se Tne t e r'Tl •Protest Hea rinq• neans a ~earin Jefore tne Board. under the JroviSions of gt;ectiori 14(0) of t.,e Act J.C. Co d e• sec. 25- ll5(o in O'.JPosition to tne issuance or transfer of a 1 icense under tne Act (D.C. Code• sec. 25-101 neanin~ of t1e Act (D.C. Code, sec. 25-101 et J) Tne tern •oar ties e~n s l) To a Notice to Sno~ CaJSe ~earin q A) resoond en t, licensee gt;ermittee, or Ool icant Go v e rnm~nt 2) fo a Protest h~a ri1 q A) aool icant 1) orotestant or rem:&amp;gt;nstrant Sacti:&amp;gt;n 20 .2 Confl icti nq Pro11isi:&amp;gt;n c lf L.:i w "Tnese Rule s a r e issuea in acc:&amp;gt;r1 an ce ~ith tne Jist ri::t of Columoia Aaministrativ e ~r:&amp;gt;cedu r= ACt 01e ec 1-l'&amp;gt; Cl ll .2 ana t:tl c&amp;gt;v~nr Jt ny o nf l i::t n2t"ean tnese i&amp;lt;'ules i'1d t'1e Li istrict if 1-lSOl g g.1 the District of :olumoia Aarninistrative Proceaure Act oor::iv~a Dctoo~r 21• lQ~8 2 Stat. l20 o.c. Coae. se l-l50l In 3nv confl i:t witnin these ~ules r::ivisions of soecific aool icati1n sriall sJoarseae tnosa Jf qanar3l aoolication T~e Boara in its discretion may oerTiit interestaa pe rsons. Jtner tn~n oartias 3s aefine v s~cti::in 2J.t (d)e to intervene iri a gt;roceedinq for such qenaral or 1 i mi tea ouro::ise ~s tne c3odrO l1 3 'f 5 D ~C i f v A ~erson oerTiittad t gt; inr:~rven~ consiaerad 3 party t gt; the or::icaediriqs Sacr:ion 2J Notice i) Trie ?oara snail oroviae 3t le-l st i tnir r:v 30 oays ~otice of the tine and pla::e of i b 5n-1 ll 5't:H r.ne is5u ~s i11volve :1 in t'"lf o ro: t:~dinQ ina sn:ill 1o)risa 311 0:3rties f t'"leir riqnt t J~ r eo res~nte 1 Jy counsel 3nd to presant evid2nce 3na irqument oafore tne ~oara D) Before anv license under gt;e:tion 11(1) of tne 3Ct or a ret3iler•s 1 ice11se (e~ceot r etai ler's Ii :ense, cl ass E or cl ass F) is qr:rnr:ea tne for at least four (4) weeks in a newso:ioer of qeneral :ircJlation in tne District of Col~moia the followinq information l) T ne name of tne aopl icant 2) A aescriotion by street ~nd nJmner. or otner olain jesiqnation. of tne gt;remises for wnicn tn~ li:er'lse is casired 3) T11e 3ooli:at.ion numner T11e class of li:ense ioolie:l for; ana aoDl icaole S~c~ notice snail st3t.e tnat renonstr:ints are ntitleo to gt;e neard D;:afore the li 1S ill 02 ~r3nte:l inrJ sn::ill :ont::iin tne tine 3'1C ol ace of '1e-1rin.;i t least tnirtv (3J) c3len1ar ~a vs 7 l e~ st tw:&amp;gt 21 cooies of the notice consoicuous Jl~ces on tn~ outside of tne prenises souqnt to oe icensea Tne Board sna1 l inspect tne oreni ses -3t 1 e~st ~he noti::e i~ order to ensure that t,e notica co,tinues to be orominentlv and visiJly displayed to tne ouo1 i 11 Sect i gt;n 2 O 5 Time li ·11itations 3) Unless otner~ise st3ted. in comoutinq any oeriod of tine under tnese Rules• tn e day of tne event is not included. If tne 13St 1av of tne oerioa is~ Saturaay. Sundav or le~al nolidav. tne oe riod s,~11 run until tne next ja y ~nicn is not a wnen the ti11e gt;eriod is tive l) d3VS or less. i "U:erne &amp;lt;ji-=tte e x cl u d ea gt wne11ever j o irt.v to :3 oro::ee(J i nq 1Jnaer these ~u les 1as tne riqht• or is r eaJired to oerfor n sane 3ct witnin :3 soecifiea tine p~rioa i tter tne se rvice of notice uoon nim. ana ~ne o ti e is s prv 2a uJon ni v m~i I• t, re 3 a~ vs sh~l l 1e a1a ea tJ the u r~scrioea tim~ JeriJa E~ceot as other~ise provijej Jy l~w nv cine oerioa orescriOed ov tnese ules nay. tJr ~ooo Cduse s~own e e~tenaea or snortened by the Jodrj Ni th nJtice to all parties. Ser~ice of Paoers "Ci) Any pacers reauirea to oe servea uoon a Jartv ~av oe servea uoon him or upon his jesi~ndted reoresent3tive nan a odrtv nas 3DDeared tnrouqn a reoresent3tive. service snall oe m3de uoon t~e represent3tive ~f r?Cora J) Service uoon a oarty ~av oe maoe oy Jerson3l a~l ivery. ov reqisterea or certifiea nai I Y teleqra or as otherwise 3u~~oriz oy c) Service uoon oartv is comol ete ll Jpon ndnjinq t~@ o~oer tJ tn e JersJn to oe ;erved: Jr 2) Leavinq tne oaoer ~t tne 1 ic ense a Jremises witn an Alconol ic Beverdq e :antral dODrovea manaqer; or 3 1 Le-3vin i r:n~ D-3De r i t t"1P o~ rson•s suitable aqe and discretion resi1i1q tnereini gt;r 4) upon deposit Dy reqisterea or ertifiej u.s ail• prooerlv stam:&amp;gt;ej -3nd :JO:lresse:l: or 5) upon deposit wit, a teleqraon o~p~nv. oro~erlv aadressea ana ~itn cnarqes gt;reo'!i :J or 11 (6) 6y conformity ~itn an or:ier of the ~oara in any oroceeainq; or 7) Uo:&amp;gt;n deposit DY first l~ss J ail gt;r:&amp;gt;o e rlv staTioea ana aaaressed. ov an -3ttornev of re::ora J ate of er vi ca s n -i 1 1 oe s no wn D v l ritten -iCKnowl~dq~ent oF the ~ers:&amp;gt;n serv e d o r nis re o res entativP.s; or tha servic or 3) A. return rec e iot• if s~rv~d JV re ii star a or certifiea nail gt;r 4 l A r ec e i o t i f s er v 2 a D ·1 t e 1 e i r 11n. lO gt;~cti:Jn 2).7 ~ules sh~l I ~3ive ~edrinq or itnJu~ sufficient reason tnerefore. fail to ~poear 3t the tine and ~itnout cne 03rticiDdtion of sue~ Jartv• not oe del3yea Dv notion for a conci1u3nce unless the ~otion is made prior to five (5) days oefore cne ~03rd. sets forth qood and suffi:ient cause for such continuance. Conflictinq 81qaqements of counsel #i 11 not De deemea qood anj sufficient cause for co1tinuance unless s~t f~rth in notion ti lea oromotly after notice of tne hearinQ h~s oeen qiven JI Tne qrant of a continu~nce Jursuant to reJuiremencs of )e:tion 21.s. qoverninJ tn~ tiTie in ~ni:h to file oojcctions. oetitio1s. or or.ner Jlea~inqs oursuant to thes ules s~cti Jn 2'J c nroi1 q 0 riginai l l l l 3n inai11i clUal m3y 3:JD~:H in his o"'n (2) 3 oartner of a oartners1iJ ~av reoresant tne oartnersnio if prooerlv 3uthorized; 3nd 3 a of f i c er of a c or oo r a t i on or 3ssoci3tion nay reoresent the coroor3tion or 3Ssoci3tion if aut~oriled to dO so ov the dodrd of Directors of sucn corpor~tion or 3ssociation oartner or officer aooearinq oursu3nt to estaolisn nis 3utnoritv to act in su:n c3p~city Ol ~eJresentation Dv Counsel l) A oerson 3Doearinq or n.:ivin~ tna ri~nt to r:n a ir choic e 2) If it aoo~ars to the ~o'lr::J th'lt tne f.:icts or issues in a m'ltter oefore it 3r~ so intric3te Jr i nvol 11er1 th-it in tne interest ot iust ice. of 12 1 n i '1 e ] u -i 2 r e o r d 1 o a r t v o u 'J n t t o :i r e Jr~s~nteJ nv a1 1ttornav• the o~r1 n~v Jr~e sucn p-:trtv t gt gt;ot3in counsel and 5 ,1311 3ll gt;w nim a reasonaole time ~ithin wnich t gt; do SJ• so lonq 3s tne riqnts of otner oarties 3t t1e nearinq are not suost3ntiallv and ~aversely affe::tea c) Notice of Aooe3r3nce No oers gt;n m3y aooear oefore t1e Boarct in reores2ntative C3P~Citv orior to SuDnissio~ ot a si~n~d st3tenent containinq his 13ne• aadress gt;c::uoation. te1eohone nunoer. and tne na~ure of Tiaae a o~rt gt;f tne record of t1e oro::e~dinq An 3ttorney aoo e arinq as counsel in 3f'ly orocee1inq sn3ll execute a notic e gt;f aoD e dranc a co1t3inina nis n3me• office ~Ojrass. office teleonon~ nunDer. Qistrict of :otumDi3 o ~r n umoer. I, tn ase ot la# stud~nts wno 3op e ar ~efore t1e Bo3rd unaar li re::tion of 3n accreoi tea 1 aw sch gt;ol 1 inic:il oroqran. tne suoervisinq actornev sn ~l l reaist e r i th t1e r3 gt;ard 1) Siqnature of ~aoers. Enrolled Original l 3 "il1v pa rson ~ur.t°'J r 1 zed t gt iP)t&amp;gt;-jr o Jrsu int tO su,s ctiJn 3) mdy sicn anv oaoer r e 1u i r ~d or Jer mi ttej ,v statute. re~ulati on gt;r t1ese Ru l s to be fi1e1 ~itn t~e Board. Any p3oer other than Jetiti gt;ns. protests• or consents tiled oursu~n~ to ~ection 21.5 of these quJes Tidv ae siqnea oY o~ n s e 1 gt; f rec gt; r cl. 11 Sacci gt;n 20.10 Inform-3tiori Inspection of ~ites; E~e~ot 3) Tne rec gt;r::ls of the Bo'Jr:l stHl 1 De availaole for inspection and c gt;Dvi~q dJrinq normal ousiriess h~urs at the reauest gt;f any i•terestea Jartv gt;r memoer gt;f tne ouolic D) Not~itnst~nrtinq the raauirenent of ~e:tio1 20.11 the dOdr~ shall #itn,ola fron its files th gt;Se :locunents ~n~ ot~er inform~tion #nicn -jra exemot tro~ oual ic disclosure Jn:l~r tnd =ree:lon of I•fornation Act of lq76. effective ~arcn zq. 1977 (J L3w l-9 O.C o1e e l- 1521 § Proviae nowever. tn3t dll :loc uments 3n1 gt;tner inform3tion #hie• is r a l ie:l J U gt;n t gt; 3nv Je~rae bv tne ~oar1 or ~nic n re l 3tes to anv i5s ue in~ or gt;c ee linq o e f~r it• sn i ll 0e Enro11e d Original i n to t1e r cJr'.J ot t~e oroceedin qs gt;~ct i rn 2 O. l l :onolete Aoolic3tiJn R&amp;lt auir e'.J "T,e Board snail not scnedul2 3n aopl iCation for nearinq iJntil the aoolicant n3s suomitce i. i11 1ocunents reouireo OV' the 4Ct co.c oae, sec. 25- 101 illJ·l ana tnese Rules Sect i gt;n 2 'J. l 2 Evidence and Exa~inacion of Alitn esses "In 3ny oroceeainq Defore the 3o 3rj. every J 3rtv Sh31l nave tne riqnt to or esenc in person. or Dy counsel. his c3se or def ense nv or31 and jocument3rv e vid ence. to suonit reoutt31 evi j ence. 3n j to cro s s-exanine ooposinq ~itn e sse s Any neno er of tn e ~odrj nav question dnv ~itness a t e x i min 3tio11 suoj ect to OOJection Dy 3 J d rtv• An v or 3 J or 1oc unent3ry e vidence m3y oe r e c e iv ed out t he 3o -H 1 sna i l e)(cluae irre le v dnt• iTi m:Jt ri a l. or unaulv r e Jetitious evidence. imoose s ucn ti ne 1 imit3tions on or3 l a r a ume nts as i t d eens 3oo r o ori3ce. l 5 "T'1P prOJonent. of i rule or Drjer 5nal 1 hd ve th~ Durden of oroof in 3ny proceadin efore tne Bo-Jrd Sacti:m 20el4 Jb1ections to Evidan:e; Ex:eotions 3) Any p3rt.v 001ectino to the ~nnission of aviden snail state tne qrounds of tna gt;b1ection(sl reliea uoon D) Fornal ax:eotions to tn~ rul inqs gt;f tne 1oard naae durin~ tne course of a ne3rinq ara unnecessary SactiDn 20.15 J f f e r s o f P r oo f A,v offer of or gt;of nade i, connacti gt;n witn in objection to any rulin~ of t~e Board wnich rejects Jr el(cJujes oreferrer:l gt;r-'11 testinonv S'1al1 consist of "1 state~ent f:&amp;gt;r tne recor of tne sJOstance of iOaucea ~v s~cn testimonv. If t'1e e&amp;gt;&amp;lt;cluoe o evid ence is 1o:unentarv• a copy Df SJCn ~ritcen avidan:e S'1a11 b~ Tiarked for identitic3ti0'1 jnj Shill :onstitute tne otfer of oroot. T'1e 16cu~ent snal 1 ca r eta in e d ov tn a Jo3rj 35 Di rt of t ne re:ora f:Jr tne ou rooses of 3JD~31 Section 20.16 Jo:unent~rv Ev idenc e 16 ,8~ rin J Jetore t ne Boa ro snal 1. i f r ~c3ivea ~v tne 3o~ r j 02 r ec ain~d Dv it and v ca 2x~m inea ov anv interested Person oursuant to )e:tion 20.10 of tn ese ~ules J) Tne 3oara. i~ its discra~io m3y p e rnit tne ~i th jraw3l of ~riqinal documents receive::l in evidence and tne introauction of certified cooies in lie.J tnereof wne, relevant ano material mactars offerej i n evidence 3re emor3cad in 3 ooo~ or nateri~l or relevant. tne oerson offerinq th= e v id ence snail plainly aesiqnace tne matter sn~ l 1 Je e&amp;gt;&amp;lt;c luaeci ana shal 1 oe seqre'.latea insof a r as or:t:tic'3Dle ction 20.11 ~ecoras in Otnar Pro: eaa in~s oefore :i,y 3::lministrdtiva ~qencvl is of t e r ad in ~viaance certified true copy ot SJCn oart snail De orese1t~d to tne ~o d rj as an axni ~it un l ~ss: En:r-011 0 1 Igine.l 17 t:-1 rt is n =scri o~a i 11 su :n d rn::i n ner 35 do-ir::J. or o) tnere is a stipulation on t,e recora that tri~ oart m3y be incorpor~ted by ref P. r e nce ina tne o~rd jirects such incoroor3tinn. or c) the o~rt is a esc ribed in such i manner ~s to De reddi lv identified in tne files of tne Section 2 O. 18 Stioul~tion orocee1inq. or uoon tne suostance of e t~stiTionv ~nicn ~oul::J oe qiven Dy itnass. its di5cretion Tiay require :Jdjition'll e viaenca on 3nv ~attar c:&amp;gt;ver ea ov stioulatio S ct:ion 2J.l9 "loti m Practica tvoe~ri tt:en ana Jouole-soacect• an ori q in~l ana tri re 31 l e ~iole ooies snail D tile::i ~ith the 18 fhe re gt;PJnse s n~ 11 not inclcJda :i 11oti:Jn fJr otner affirn'lc;ive reliet 3Q3inst the novinq p3rty. wnere 3 party fil1no an opoosition desires to suomit Suen notion. it snall ~e done oy seoar3te ole3dinqs. A reJ l y Tl3y oe filed ~ithin tnree (3) days 3fter s~rvice of a response in opposition to 3 ~otion ut such reoly shall ,ot re3rque propositions Prese~t~d in cne TIOtions. nor present mdtters wnich 3re not strictly in reolv to tne ooposition. \lo further ola3Jinq m3y be filed exceot by le3vd of tne 3o::3rd Sac ti on 20.20 ~eceiot of Inforn3tion After ~No ~ocunent or otner inform-itio, sn~l I De ~cce~ted for tne record ~fter tne :l~se of a inform-itio11• or (2) unless oftici&amp;lt;ll notice ot -i record is t3&amp;lt;en in 3ccord3nce ~it n s~ctian 1J9 of tne Jistrict of :olumoia Admi nistr~tive Procaaure i j S c i Jn 2 2 l x P irte C o ~nunic~ti J n5 11 1 m ere a proceedinq is a C:)ntest 2d C-1se: coTimunicdtion relev3nt to the Tierits of the JrJcaejinq; 3nd (2) no memoer of tne boara snall Tiake or cause to be TI3de to any interested person outside the 3oarJ ex parte communication relevant to tne merits of t,e oroceeainq o) Tne oronioicions orovidad i, suosaction (a) 3P)ly upJn tne issuance of notic? Jf an ao~l ication for an oriqinal. tr3nsfer or renewal icensa. or 3 notice to show c3use h~arinq T~e terTI 'ex oarte communic3tion• includes an oral or ~ritten coTimunic~tion not on ~n e re:ora witn resoect co wnicn re3son3ol2 orior notic e t'.l :Jll oarties is not. qiv~n· It aoes not. include re~uasts for status reoorts 3n matters ,otice of a ne~t.inq Jr h e arinq Sacti'.ln 20.22 ~indinqs of ~3ct ana Conclusions i) T-,e 3 J~rd s 1al 1 afford Jarti e s 3n Jpoortunitv to subnit ~rooosea ~in 1 i, q s of ct 20 3v3i l3Jle Dy written notice of tne ao~rd to each oartv. Proposed finainqs shall oe tvpawritten and double soaced. An oriqinal and three (3) leqiDle cooies snall be filea ~ith tne Board A copy shal 1 oe sar~ej on eacn oartv J) Witnin a reason3ble time 3fter tne close of a proceedinq. tne Board snail renjer its ~ritten jecision accomoanied bv findinqs of fact and conlusions of law. Findinos of fact snail consist of a concise statement of the aoar1's shall oe Dasea solely uoon eviaence :ontainea in the re:ord. Finjinqs of fact and conclusions of la~ sh3ll oe suoJortea DY ana in a:coraance ~ith rel iaole. orooative• ana suostantial evidence. fr3nscriot of 4earin~ transcrioed un~er the jirection o~ tnP Board porovea transcript shal I De supJl iej to anv Zl 1:3 1G e s i'l he ottiCi1l tr3,s::riot n:iv na i e o'lly in C:3ses ot ndteri~ l errJr. A m:&amp;gt;t. ion to orr :ct trie tr -Jnscriot snall o e file:'l ith t.ne 3oarj ~ithin ten (10) days of receipt Jf tne served o al 1 oarti e s. If no oojections to sucn notion are filed witnin five (5) days after service thereof• tne transcript shall oe correct ad DY t'le B gt;ard. Tne Boa rd snall n~va final ~uthority to disoose of 3ll motions tor correction of the recora Sac ti :rn 2 O. 2 4 PetitiJn for Reconsijeration 3) A petition for reconsid ar:3tio1 renearinq. or re:3r~u~ent may b e filej Dy 3 Pdrty ~it. ni n tan (10) jays afte r r acai~t. tilinq nJr t'le Qrantinq of sucn Jeti':i gt;n snail spacific~l ly ordered Dy tne 3oara ucn St:3Y will P&amp;lt ti ti Jns shal 1 le typ ewritten ln 1 10.JOle-sJaCed. An ori :4 i na l -rn:J three 13) l eqir gt;le :o.Jies ot c.ne CJe ti ti :rn Sh31 l oe fi lea th tne ~Jara. A COD y 2 2 st:it e ori ef ly tri e ndtt-:rs of rec gt;rj 1lleqed to ,3ve oeeri rroneouslv ~eciaed. tne qround r e l i~d uoon. 3nd tha relief souqht• If tne oatition is ~ased in wnole or in ~3rt on a new m3tter. sucn nat ter snail be set fortn in an =iffijavit 3n~ acco~panie~ oy a statement tnat the oetition~r could ,ot oy due dil i q ence ha va ~nown or j~scoverad sucn ne~ natter Prior to tne 1ate tne c~se w=is presented to tne goarj for jecision c) The Board• in its discretio may permit or require oral 3r~unent uoon 3 oetition for reconsiaar=ition s ec t i gt;n 2 a. 2 5 ~aintenance of DecorJm ~o~corum ana q ooa oraer shall oe m~intiined at 311 tines J ur i 1q n aa r i nqs. ana tie 9o=tra m=iv "Sect i on 2 t l Ora e r ot Aooear=tnc J DDl ie:'int l i cense or .Jermit no l J e r sn~ll o r s n t :i t. i ri o r v i o 0 c l n d 3 r c n n r r SectiJn 2l·2 Ddlin~ati.Jn ot 'leiqno gt;r,ooo i) U~on re:eiot of an aool iC3tio, for ne~ 1o:ation of an e~istinq li:ense, tne boara snall gt;r:&amp;gt;motly delineate tne oouno:ir·v lrnes ot tne "naiqn~ornooa" u,der Section 1~(3)(6 gt;t tne Act 3nd Bo:ir::J sn3ll in all advertise11ents 3nd notices ouol is,ea or posted concerninq s~ia :iool ication. set fort, tne oounaarv lines ot the ,P.iqnoornooa to trie nearest oubl i c roaa ay. natur'il oounodrv or thorou::infar Tne oound3ries of tne n~iohoornooa 5h3ll oe r easonanlv ecuidiStdnt from tne prenises for wnic dn 3JP1ication for license is filea Nei::inoorn gt;oj oounaary lin e s snall oa not less t 1 an si unarej (oOOI te e t fro~ tn lot or Suos e ctions l) and s:"lal l not d!JDlv to aoolicati:&amp;gt;ns for retailer•s license cl-:1ss E or l dSS S ~ctiJn 21·3 ~aji~s Plat Loc a tion ri q in"ll lic:~nse or tha tr:insfer of 1n exi:;tin c; I icens a to~ n~w lJC"ltion is protest ~o the ~o r~ Tidy lirect t11e 3oplic3nt to file witri the '3o~rd. 3 o13t or survay oreoareo ov the Offic? of tne Surveyor of tne Jistrict ot Columoi3 nicn Jldt shal 1 snow ov lot. parcel• or gt;tnerwi S tne re:d orooerty loc3tea witnin 3 raaius ot si~ nunared (6 00 feet of the oound3ry 1 ine of t,e lot or Jarcal uJOn 4hicn is situated the astaol isnment snall -ilso oot~in from tne Ass~ssment ~aninistr~tor. District of C gt;lumoia )e~art~ent of r3aius }S sno~n o, the recoras of t~e Assessor iucn lis t sndll oe orina facie e11ide1c~ of gt Suose:tion (3) sn-311 11ot aoJly to 3n 3P:&amp;gt;li c3tion for 3 retail e r's lic e nse class C or c: l 3 SS i ssuaa for a hotel or cl uo. 3 ret3i l e r's I icens 1 -tss L issuea for a clue&amp;gt or 3 ret-:li ler s 1 icense :l~ss 3 or cldss E onrasiaents of ~eignoornood "At 3n y orocaedinq Defore the dodrd on 3n ~oD1 ic~tion for issu ance or reissuin:e of license. or tr3nsfer of 3 license to a new parson or l OC::ltion, tne Boara sn3l l he3r al 1 oers gt;ns ~e sire to De ne3ra. II sect i :Jn 2 le 5 Petitions 3) Oo j ~ctions or Consents ~ilej Pursuant t o Section L~(a of tne Act (O.c 01e. se c zs- ll"&amp;gt l)(61 Petitions in suooort of or in tr1nsf~r ot 1 licens e to 3 new r so :i or l C-:tt i or-i sn-:Jl l e&amp;gt;e fil~d witn the -3oard '3t least tiv e (SI c3lend-:Jr a -ws a rior t o t e 03t t :3, ori q 1n :ll or re scne 1ul en ,earin specified in t~e p uot ish~a or gt;ost e d n:)tic an a sn3ll set f orth t""P. follo inc i nto r mition Z t.,e aaar ess for wr-iich t:ie li c~nse is Jes ir e.i 3) t'1e cl 3ss of li cens~ r eau~st81 t P. d o 1 i a n "t. n urn a e r 26 3 ori~f surn;i'3rv Ot' th r i s Jn gt or liceris proviae1 th :cH: P-irtici o atiJn i:i \o-Jr'.J orjcee'.Jinqs is nJt limited ov such sJmnary; ina tne name. ana address of aa:h Petitioner OojectiJns or Consents ~i leJ Pursuant eo ~ectiol"l t4(c) Jf trie Act (D•C. CJaa. sac. 25- lt5(C Petitions filea ov persons i, suopJrt of or in oooositiJn tJ tne issuance of I icel"lse jr tne transfer of~ I icense to a new lJcation snall oe filaa wit, the ~oara at least fiva (5) calendar Javs orior tJ the date of dn oriqinal Jr rescne'.Julea ~earinq specified in tne oubl ished or Jost nJtice, ana in addition tJ tha informdtion re iuirad ov sue&amp;gt;sectiJn (a shall co ta•n th~ r'ol 1 Jwin l) tne straet idrlress an:J lot gt;r Ddrcel of Jr~oertv o~nea nv oetitioner(s) dnj l ~inea co oe ~itnin a rdaius gt;f six hundred OJ) f et of tne ~o~naarv lines ot' tne orooertv u~on ~Mien is l. 7 2 t ne h1 n el writ t n sian:jt_ur e or i c h Eacn p~rson nust sian nis name in tne nann?.r a~d form i1 ~hicn the ownersnio of Sdid Jr gt;pertY i po e i rs· I n t ne of f i c i 3 l records gt; f th@&amp;gt; lJ i st r i ct gt; f :olumbia l gt;rTIS f gt;r tne filinq of petitions sndll e a11ai l 3ole at the Office of the jo.,ir::1 Secti gt;n 21 qeal Prooerty ~ithin 6JO Feet ~aaius 3 ere a oetition is filed DJrSu3nt to Se:tion 2l.5(bl• and tne orooertv :1.:ii nea to oe ~itnin t1e six nundreo 00) feet ra::Jius is neld I si~n3~Jr?.s of 311 joint tenants ~re reauir~a t gt here th e gt;wners of s3ia gt;f 3n owner snall ~e o ee~e~ to oin1 ~nly tn3t l) If any si ndture on 3 o=tition filea Jursua1t to Section 2l.5(b) is n gt;t 11 tn e nanner ~uJe3rs in t1e offici3l recoras gt;t t,e Dist rict Jf :olumbia ne ~o~r1 sh1ll oermit oro1 f t~dt sucn 28 5i n-:1tJr2 is i1 f3:t tne siqn iture o r:h o r ~p~ rty "SectiJn 2i.1 Solicitor of Si ~n::1tJr~s tor DetitiJn lisclose nis i:le'ltity to tne Boarcl ·aid snail file. affidavit statinq l) tnat ne h::1s volunteered to ootain or th~t ne nas oeen enploye:l for cne ~urpose of oDt~inina si~ndtures ano tne iaentity of his enplover 2) tnat the siQnatures ano aaaresses 3poe::1rin~ on tne oetition(s) are nelieved ov nim 3) wnetner t,e siqn~cures ~ere vol untarily ~iven or wnetn~r anytninq of v~lue w~s offerea o r "S ec tion 2l Boara•s ~ecoras En c, l d -4 c r1gi r.111 3) All p9 tit.ions til~a una~r t"1e s e Rul s sn:ll l Je CJnsiGered J:lrt ot tna re:oro ana snatl ne 3v3ilable for puol ic insoecti)n D) Petitions filea oursuant to Saction 21.5 snall not oe witndr3~n atter tne date Jf hearinq c) Tne Board wj11~ uoon requast. notify anv. oartv ~netner oetitions nave neen re:eivea Section 21.q =inainqs of =3ct and Conclusions of Law "Wit,in 3 reasonaole time after the close of a oroc e ejinQ• the Bo3ra sh~ll issue its #ritten je:ision as re~uired ov tne Act to.c oae. sec. 25-LOl l and Section 20.22 of tnese Rules• 3na tna 3cconpanvinq f inainqs of fact 3na onclusions of l:lw snail include gt;ut not :Je irnite1 tO• tne followinq tne oouna~ries of tne naiqn~or~oo J) tne aoproari3teness of tn~ lo:acion tor inicr tne l i :ense is aesir~a. co,siaarinq tna character of tne orenises• its s~rroJnainos. an~ t n isnas of th e oers ons owninq oroJertv or r e siai,q in tne vicinity; 30 1) 3 fi n::iiriq 3S to tne 3;)Dli ni itv ot Se 3 ioor:&amp;gt;vea Julv i• 1~64 Title 3. JC~Rf is a enaed to rea::i as fJllo~s JI 53id aist3nce shall De measured Jetween tne nearest street entrance to saio JI ace of ousiness and the nearest street nain e1tra1ce to s3ia cJl leqe. university. or recre3tion ~rea• or ch..ircn. ov tne snortest I ine bet~een sucn av or u io 1 i: Jar1&amp;lt; or oar t&amp;lt; i nq. This s..iose:tion col leqe. universitv• or recr atiJn are3. or the :onm~r:i'.31 or in iustri-il accorCJin q t gt; tl"le ott'ici'-31 gt;f Colum gt;i-1 Sacti:Jn l~to) of tne Jis~ rict ot :olurnoia A1cono1 ic Bever3qe Control t.ct. a;&amp;gt;oro11e 1 Auqust 25. 1~37 (50 Stat OZ; o.c ode• s e c. 25- ll5(n) is 3mended to read 35 follo~s: Be fore qr3ntinq a 1 icense ~naer Section 11(1 l of tnis Act co.c. Code. sec. 2 5-111(1 gt;r a ret.ail~r•s license. exceot. a ret:tiler•s license cl3ss or cl3ss F. the Bo:ird sn3ll ~i11e n gt;tice ov 3dvertisement ouolicnea once a wee~ 3nd for 3t le3st four weeKs in some newsp3per at qeneral :ircul:ltion ouolisned in tne District ot Columoid• Th e fe~ for such ouolication snall oe ~aid ov tne 30olic:lnt. 3t tne time of tne fil in Jf sucn :lODI iC:ltion. Tne ~d11ertisement so ouol isnea snall cont3in the n3me of the 30Dlic:lnt 3nJ 3 Jescriotion JV street ana numo e r. or ocr~ r plain ne 1 i en s~ is reauest~d '3nd tne cl ass of 1 i ens~ 1ec; i re::l ucn notice shdll St:lte tn:lt renonstrints are e~title1 to o~ ne3r1 Jetore tne ir-'3ntinq of such license ana sn:ill n -irn~ the t in lna ol~ c f sucn ne~rinq. fhera c;h-311 OP. oo ste l'.1 ov t"1e a~oli:an t t o (2) n gt;t.ic ~s for t our E.o.ro11ad o k l u Tnese not•c~s sn::tl l st3te tnat. renonstrants are entitled to Oe ne3rj ~efore tne ~r3ntinQ of sucn 1 icense ana snall n3me the same tine and olace f~r sucn nedrin~ as s~t out in tn e ouolic advertisenent; dnd. if renonstrance aqainst tne qr3ntinq of such license is tile :h no t'inal renonstrant snall nave ndd an oooortJnitY to oe near1. under rules and requlations orescrioed oy sa i d Boara. Any oerson ~illfully renovinq. Jbl iteratin q narrinq. or aefacinq s~ia notices snall Je aee~ea quilty of a vio13tio1 of tnis Act Jf tnis su~s ec tiJn ralatin q to noti c Y ~dwertisem~nc in some ne~soaoer of qener~J 1 i c e nse to a retailer for any olace Jt bu si nes s it sucn r =t3ile r is tne nolaer ot a lic anse ot tne sane class fJr tne same oldce 3nj if s~ia lase- itentione a li:ense is in etfect on tri a Jate tne toolic:ltion for t he li cens~ is til~a S s fhi s act snail take effe:t sixt v 0 1 011 qressional revi w tollowinq a oo ro11 a l DY tne Enro11ea o r g:i aJ .n ~avor 1or in t ne event of vero ov tn vor. action bv tne Council of tne District or Colum~i~ to overrid~ tne veto) as provide~ in section o02(c)(ll of the District of C~lumji~ Self- Govern~ent ana Govarnmental ~eorq~nization Act. Code. sec. l-li..7(c)(l) ana snall a:&amp;gt;ply to ~11 C3ses. e Jistrict1of :olumoia o 1 u :110 i a APPROVED: October 21, 1980 CClllJNClllL Of nBE DI Sili1CT ~IF COl!IDIIlimA E::r:&amp;gt;m G= GF.RG\t a:mmcLAO'U«Iml occn:i: NO: B 3-16 s a VOIC VOTt U n a n l 0 ID~O U S Moore .D ROU. CAI.I. von 4 A.A. C OUJlllCH Cit r \lllCCZI c.w DTXON I KANE SHACKLETON T.JT7'M'n MASON SP&amp;lt;1.1JLDT'iG rT .1 ~Tti MOORE TT r-.f µ11~rw RAV T ,\ 1)~7T&amp;lt RnT A~Tl' I i 1. 1 CEZ OF RICORD A S.cnarr e:&amp;gt C iuacil ~ON: Amended First Reading (9-16-BOl f;i VOICZ VC U_n_a_n_i_m_.o_,u_,s s.m a~l l p~r-e.s.e n.t l~tC f lt f t c:a.i c f l'llA1 1 T"Hvm.r 11 Ni I I c R ArvT 1 1 I I r r,.\C l1"T I I lt gt T1T T'1~ I I r.T llHC OORE I r rJTT C l~T I I I I 'R'1RT'lV I 1HV I I I I T .1 11'&amp;lt l&amp;lt;l"lT A lt I I I I 1•1 t l t VMIW ACT!CN: Adopted Final Reading (9 -3 0-80) f§ voter; vo u n_a_n_i m o_u_s \bse~t a_1_1 p_r_e_s_e_n_t c.;w t •I C I at 1 lt C::t C!'9•Clt I Ct r I f 4 w-.c:n C:ii.•c~ I I I t lnrmN I I i I lt l 'n i I I I 6H l.CXI.2T O~I I I r T'J Q I I I I \,f .\ C:"M I I I I :s 7 AGlD G I I I I !n .lt&amp;gt;Tl I i I \ .H'V'\1 I I I I TT &amp;lt l!IT I I i i itH RT'\V I i I I 11 I I I I I I I I l 1 :in lt I I i I 11 l. 1'V I I I I i I I I I I a </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
