<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-149">
  <num type="law">3-149</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1981-03-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-149.pdf">D.C. Law 3-149</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 4886</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-149, the “District of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-198, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 30, 1980 and October 14, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 29, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-274 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 3-149 0 Distcict of Columbia Public Emergency Act of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-198 on first and second readings, September 30, 1980 and October 14, 1980, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 29, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-274, published in the November 7, 1980 edition of the o.c. Register Vol. 27 page 4886 This act was originally transmitted to Congress on November 7, 1980, and resubmitted on January 14, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as o.c. Law 3-149, effective March 5, 1981. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January 14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 February 2,3,4,S,6,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27, March 2,3,4 ~N ACT D.C. ACT3 2 7 I IN T~E CJU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT o= COLu~BIA OCT 2 9 1980 ro aut,orize t~e ~3yor to take certain actions i~ connecti~n witn a ouolic e~erqen:y. ae IT ENACTED ~y T~E COU~CIL QC THE QIST~ICT OF COLU~BIA• rnat t~is act TI3y ne cited ~s tna ~District of Columoia ouol ic Ernerqency ~ct of l98Q Sec. 2. As us~a in this 3Ct t,e t?r l E11erg2ncv Ooerati ons o I :in n?.Jns th~ District of Columoia•s State Plan for Ju~lic oursud~t to section 201 of the Disaster ~eli~f Act u.s.c. sec. 5121) and section 3 istri:t of :olu11oia or nis or h~r a siqndte 3 Puol ic emer~encv" m~:ns 3ny 1 i s s t r c d ta s t r o one or em a r a enc v s i tu ct t i o ;1 CODIFICATION D.C.COde, sec. 6-1001 2 ~nera tne nealtn. safety• or welfdre of aersons in the Jistrict of :otumbia is thredtenaa by re~son of tne actu-31 or inminent consequenc2s within the District of :olumoia of 3) eneny attack• sanotaQe or other nostile action D) severe and un3nti::iaatej resource snortaqe c) fire 1) flood. e3rth~uake, or ot~er serious act of nature el seri gt;us civil disorder f ny seri gt;us q x.)losio conflaqration lt gt;o"'er failur or (nJ injuri:Jus environm~ntal contdmin3tion hicn thre:3tans or causes damaqe to life e3ltn. or orooerty Resource" means. out •snot limited to• natural ~as. nHatinq fuel. automotiv fuel, Se 3. Tne M3yor may establ isn a oroar'im of uolic e~erqencv oreoareaness tn:3t utilizes tne servicas of 3ll aooropri~~e aqencies includinq tne 1ffice of ~meraencv Preparedness) ana the roqr3n sn.:ill incluae. out nrn. be limited to 3) develoomP.nt of an ~m~rqe~cv Enrol:ea Or:ginal D.C.Code, sec. 6-1002 3 (1) s e t fortn a compr2n~nsive ana da t3i led ~istrict of Columbi3 st3te m3jor dis3sters• includinq oroviSions for 3ssistanca to indiviau3ls• ousiness as and affacted aesiqnat ed sub 1 ivisions of tne District of Columoia; and (2) include provisions tor: aooointT1ent 3nd traininq of aoorooriate staffs; fornulation of necessary req~lations and proceaures; and ·c onauct of r eouir e d e~ercises DI oost ouolic gmerqenct ~v 3 l uat ians c) oerioaic r evie~ of oro~rams; and j) coor n ination of feji:ral and stdte or~p3raaness oroarams. Tna ·4a o r s tnll ouolisn in t1o10 (21 C')nsecutive not ice and comment• anv o roqra~ or pl an for ouol ic a m a r~encv or~oareaness oreoared ourSJ3nt to tnis ict. Tn oun l ic3t ion sti il I. at. 3 Tii n i T1um sta te the suo 1ec t nattar ot tn e oroqran or p lan ana tne sp ecific m3nner in wnic~ 3 comol~te :oo v c~n oe oDt3in~d or review ed ~nd cum~entad UJO~ Drior to the tr3nsmitt3l Jf tne Dl3n or oro~r~m to tne :ouncil of t~e District of Columoi3. Sec. 4 d The ~ayor Sh3ll tr3nsrnit to the Council of t,e District of Columoi3 conolete cooies of dnv existinq Dl3n or progr3m creoared oursuant to ~ection 201 of tne Ois~ster Relief Act J c. s2c. 51211 ~ithin tnirtv (30) c3Jen~ar days of t~e eff~ctive d3te of tnis ~ct. o roqr3~ snall oe v31 ia onlv if tne cou~cil of the u istri:t of :olu~oia aoes not 3dODt• witnin (30) j3yS (ex:ludinq S3turddYS• Sun d 3VS ol i13yS ana avs on ~hie, the :ouncil of tne District ~f :olumbid is in recess 3ccorainq to its rules) afte r the receiot of the pl3n or oroor~m trom the oroqran o) Tne M3yor snall transmit to t,e Council of tne Oistrict of Columoi~ co~olece copies of any ol~n or oroqr3m orep3rea oursudnt to ~nis section ~i tnin t~irty (30) cal~nd3r d3ys ot tn~ completion oe Vil id onlv if t~e Council of the listrict of Ezlra11ect Original D.C.Code, sec. 6-1003 5 :olumbi3 does not ~aoot ithin thirty (30) d3ys (el(clu:linq S3turaavs gt;und3ys 3nd noli:lays a ;1a :iavs on Nhic, the :ouncil of tne District of :olumoia is in recess 3ccordin~ to its rules fter receipt of tne o13n or proqr~m fro~ tne th~ existence of a ouol ic emer~encv 3n:l the a etermination by tne Mayor tnat the issuance of an ~raer is necessarv tor tne immeaiate preserv~tion 3nd 3S a prerequisite to reouestinq emarqency or naj or dis3ster 3ssist3nce in accoraance nith tne l)i sastar Relief Act of l 'H aopro11e1 1.1av 22• lq74 (88 Stat. 143; 42 5.c. sec. 5121) the ~3vor rnav issue ~n Emerqencv Executive Order w,iCh s~all severity of the ouolic e~erqency 2) Tne Tie3sures necassary t~ reli ve the o uo 1 i c eTier qenc y: D.C.Code, sec. 6-1004 3) Tne SP3cific reauire~ents of tne Jrjer 3nj the oersons upon wnon the Or1er is t&amp;gt;i'"lainq; ana (4) The 1ur3tion of the Jrjer D) uoo n tne issuance of an Eme r qency Executive araer the ~3yor ~3y 1) Exoena sucn funas 3pprooriatea to tne Jist rict of Columbi3 qovernm ent sufficient to carry out ouol ic emerqencv servic e ~issions ana resoonsioilities 2) Imolement those orovisi0,s of the Jistrict of :olu~Dia e~erqency 0Je rations Dl~n as issued t&amp;gt;y tne M3yOr itnout r~qara to escaol is,ea ooer3tinq oroceduras rel3tinq to the oerfor~anc ot puol ic ~arks. ent~rin~ into contracts. inc~rrinq o~l iq~tions. emo loynent of t3rnDorarv wor~ers. rental of eauiomant• our criase of suopl ies and m iterials in:1 exoenditure of ouDl ic funds: PRJVIOF.D. fnnt this piraqraoh snail aoply o nly to enolove~s of tne District ot Columoi~ qovernnent 3) Preoare for. ora~r. an1 suoervis e th imolementation of ~e3sures d esionea to orotect oersons :ind oroo~rtv i the i str i c:t 7 of CJlurn~ia• Such me3sures v include th e evacuatiJn of oersons in the District o f Columoia to such e~erqency snelt~r5 ~ithin t~e District of ColumDi3 3S the ~3yor TI3Y desi ~ndt or such snelters Jutside th District of Columoia as the ~avor nay desi~ndte with tne 3pproval of tne Governor of the St3te to which District Jf CJl~moia citizens are to oe evacuatG.d. 3n3 orovision for the receJtion. snelterinq• maintenance. 3nj care of such evacuees. Ev3cJation of 3ny personriel or 3ctivitv of tne feaeral qo~ern~ent snail take olace only with tha consent of tne Presiaent of tha Jnited States or trie Presiaent•s desiqnee: PR1VIDEO. That upJn a q reenent oetween tne Fader~l d nd Oistrict of Columoia qovernments• any are3rr~n~en evacJation Dian sM~l l :onstitute sucn conserit 4 equire the shuttinq o f f, jisconnection. or susp e nsion of ~ervic~ trom or nv, Q'.35 m~ ins. e l ectric oow e r lin e s r ot,er ou~l ic uti I ities 5) Oest rov or cause to oe nestrOV8d a ny Columbia. found ~o be contaminated bY 3ny ~attar or subSt3nce whicn renders it deleterious to life or he31tn• 3f'ld bv reason of such ont3min"'tion is of im11e:Ji 'lt~ or im11inent aanqer to persons or JrJparty; to cause th e re110113J from the District of District of Columbi3 of anv cont~min~tea or:&amp;gt;oertv: and to prohibit pe rson s tram co,tactinq o r aooroacninq such orooerty so as to enaanqBr th~ir lives or nealtn amp;l Issue Jrjers or re~ulati:&amp;gt;ns to co,trol. restrict. allocate. or re~ulate tne use. 53Je. projuction ~nd :Jist.riJution ot fooa. fuel lotninq, and otner :onmodities re~uir ed bv t.he Eme rqencv Jp~rations Plan or 7) Jirect any p2rson or qro~p of r e1u or ot~erwise ~lter th? noJrs ~urine ~nicn tney c:&amp;gt;nnuct nusinass Jr simil ~r activity at oremises estnDl ish?.d ana n3intainad tor a business dn1 to di r c t any oers)n or qr ouD• or class of persons itnin th istrict of :olu~Dia. to remain off the ouol ic streets in the ev~nt that any puDI ic emerqencv re~uires tnat th e ~ayor institute n urfew B Es tao l i s n such p u D I i c em er qe n c 'I services units as he or she nay 1eem apiJr:&amp;gt;ori ate 9) ExJana existinq lee&amp;gt;artnent-'11 and 3Qency units witnin the Distri::t of co1u~oia ~overnnent concernea with ouol ic eTiergency services 10) Exercise operational 1i rection ov~r -31 1 Jistrict of :olumoia Gnverriment 1eJart~ents and aqencies aurinq t he Derioa ~h an an Emerqenc v Executive Jr::ler nav De in effe:.t 11 Procure suool i es ind eou i Dment. institute tr3i'1inq oroqr=.ims "lnel gt;UDlic intorm~tion oro qrarn s ana t ake ~l I otner gt;reo:ir 1torv st~os. includi11q tne u:'lrti3l or full mo oil iZ3tion of pur&amp;gt;l ic emerJencv sP.rvicas lO units in 3avance of actu3l dis~ster. tJ insure tne furnisninq of 3dequdtelv trained and eauioo~d personnel durin~ a Juol ic e'llerqency. coJr1in3tea ~itn tne emeraency s 2rvice, Jlans anj oroqr3~s of the feder31 qovernTient 3na of tna neiqnborina St3tes 3nd Politic3l suJdivisions tnereof l 2) Raauest oreaisast~r assistance or federal disaster 3ssistance anj :o~mit tne use of 3 cert3in 3Tiount of District of Columoia qovern11ent fun:1s to al 1 ev i ~t tn e aa•naqe. loss 3rdsnic• ana sufferin~ resultinq from the 1i s3st~r; or l. 3) Prevent or reduce narnful co,seauences of disaster. Se 6 In addition to dis3star prevent.ion ne~suras included in District of ColumJi3 :o ns~aue~c~s ot 3 jisast.er, 3nd consist~nt wit.n Enrolled Ori~inaJ D.C.Code, sec. 6-1005 l l aporopri3te• issue r?qulations or re:oTimena le~isl~tio, t o t~e Council of the 0i~trict o f ColumDi 3 rel 3ti nq to flood Pl3in man3oernent• nodifi:3tion. fire prevention dna co~trol• 31r o l a nni~q. ana construction st3nodras. Sec. 7.(a) 4nv fmerqencv Executive Oraer issued nv the ~avor sn3ll oe effective for a oeriod of no mor e t~an fifteen (15 31enaar aays from t~e aav it is siqnea by tne M3vor. Out ~dy oe rP.scin de a in wno1e or in o3rt ov the M3yor witni n tn3t p ~rioJ snould tne M~yor det?.rnine tnat th~ ou ol ic enerq~ncv no lonqer eKiStS• or no lon~er ~xr.ena~d f o r uo to nn ~a1itional fifteen (15) aav r.n e adoption of. an emerqencv 3ct ov tne Counci 1 of tne District of Columoi3 cl SnoulJ e xte~uatina Circumst1nces• Suen 35 je~tn. a~struction or otner oerilous con~itiJnS r ~n iDit tne conveninq of ~t l 2 3st t~o-tniras (2/3) of tne memoers of t:he :ounci 1 Jf tne Enrolled D.C.COde, sec. 6-1006 Origina L 12 Jistri:t of :olumbia for consiaeratiJn of em e r qency le~isl3tion. tne Mayor sn3Jl make a re~son3o1e attern~t to consult with t•ose mP.mDers of tne CJuncil of the Oistrict of :ol u~Di3 not affe:tad by jeatn. destruction. or ot h~r perilous conditio;s. after ~nicn the ~ayor nav a x tena the Emerqency Exec~tive Jrder for up to fifteen (15) aavs al uoon the issuance of anv ~ma rJency x~cutiva Qrjer• as soon as or~cti:aJl iven tne condit ion of the e~erqencv• tn e Jrjer snall oe JuDl isnej in tne Qi2tri£L.Qf..f rn~l gi?!i in twJ C21 jaily ne~sonoers of qeneral circulation in tn ist rict of :olumoia. and sn~ll Je Postea in sucn Dubl ic o13ces in tne Oistrict of :olumbia as tn e ~3vor jeter~inas hy requl3tiJn. Ce) Tne MdyDr m~y aaoot and inple~ent such rules ~n1 re~ulations 35 tne M3yJr finas necessary to c~rrv out tne purooses ot t~is ~Ct• pursuant to the uistrict of Colu~bia Aaministrltive ~rocaaure ~ct. aocroveJ Octooe r 21· 1968 CR2 St~t. 1 ~0 4; J Coae. s~c. l-15 01 iRg•l fl T~e ~3y~r m~y join or ente r into. on oenalf of tne District of Columoi~ g3v e rnm2nt. Enrolled Original l3 s uodivisions tnereof. for the coorai13tion of jisastar preoareaness oroqrans. Sec. 8. An Em2 r~encv ExecJtive Jrder issuea nv tne M3yor m3v oroviJe for a fine of not mor e fha :orporation :ounsel of t~e District of Columoi3 or anv Assist3nt Coroordtion Counsel mav ~rina ~n action in the n3m e of the District of C:1IUm ia "lQ'iinst anvone wno h3S viol3teJ the orovisio1s of 3n Em erqency Exacutive Jraer issued OJr5u3nt co tnis 3C t Sec• 9 o action taKen oursu3nt t o ~n Ema r qen cv Ex ec utiv e Jrjer issued n~ cna ~aver oursu:=nt. to this 3ct sn3ll o e r;uoj ect t o s eci:ion l09 (t1e c ontested c 3Se orovisions) of tne Oistric t of :ol u ~bi3 A1ministr a tiv roc e aur~ Act. j dte ot th Emerqencv ~xecutive J r1e Se l'.J. An act to a uc~oriz ol ~c outs in tna District of :olu moia. 3n 1 for ot1e r ouroos~s· o.c.Code, sec. 6-1007 D.C.Code, sec. 6-1008 O.C.Code sec. 6-1001 et se&amp;lt; 14 )ec. ll. D.C.Code, sec. 6-2301 et This i3Ct snal l t3k2 2f feet dfter a thirty (30) jay oerioo ot Conqressioial review followinq 3Dorov31 ov the ~avor (or in the event of veto oy tne Mayor. action o th9 :o 1ncil of tne Distri:t of :olu~oia to averrije tne veto&amp;gt; as orovid~d in section 602(c)(ll of tne District ot Colu~oia Self overnTient ano Governmancal ~e~rqanization ACt• aporoveo Decemoer 24• 1Q73 (97 )t .H 813: o.c oje. sec. l-l47(cl(ll I• yor District of Coluni:&amp;gt;ia APPROVED: October 29, 1980 ClH!l~C llll If T'~[ IU 57'.i~cr !lf COt ruJ=SlA G a:rumlCU.Aenm CCCX O B 3-1 98 ACnoN: Adopt ed First Reading (9 30 80) tf1 votezl/On u~n~a~n~i rn~o~u~s Abs.at: Moore L I ROU. OU OT A I I U CI C C I t amp C.w•c~ I .ar c 1 r f I T'ln'ON I I i K.\ iE I SF.AC:&amp;lt;L ETO i I TH 'l'T' F~ I I I MASON I S P Alrt D I:TG I r rT .l R!{F I I I ~fOOR E I nqw I I ~a 1mv I i I I R4 V I I I T l&amp;gt;~TTC I I I Q lT l q I I I I lt;a s9ft&amp;amp 1. I ll:i OCCt VOT u=n a n i rn=o u s sent H a_r_d_y U ROU. C.\U. l/C'n c.o.t•GC 4 4M.A I c I t t c.:i c c a I f a I t a I re i I 1 nrvnM I I I I 1 \ r I I I I ~H ·1 r'Z C"'T \j I I I r.TT~'O I I I I VdC l llT I I I I o .H-:1' n vr. I I I rr l qr I I I I ~OO RE I I I t I .7TT C: l'\ )\T I I I µ4on v I I I I q lV I I I I i I I I r 1 OU1"C I I I I OnT lO!&amp;lt I I I I I I I I I \. i r ° AC7.CN U VC[ OT I I RCU. CU 107 S EACKLETO~n ·f :7 ;v 6 </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2301"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2302"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2303"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2304.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2305"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2306"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2307"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2308"/>
  </section>
</document>
