<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-158">
  <num type="law">3-158</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Civilian Complaint Review Board Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1981-03-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-158.pdf">D.C. Law 3-158</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 5127</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-158, the “District of Columbia Civilian Complaint Review Board Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-247, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 14, 1980, and October 28, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 10, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-285 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 3-158 "District of Columbia Civilian Complaint Review Board Act of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Govecnment and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198, ftthe Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-247 on first and second readings, October 14, 1980 and October 28, 1980, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 10, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-285, published in the November 21, 1980 edition of the D.C. Reoistec Vol. 27 page 5127 This act was originally transmitted to Congress on November 19, 1980, and resubmitted on January 14, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 6-02 (e)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-158, effective Ma r ch 5 19 81. ARRINGTON IXON Chairman of the Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February 14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 2,3,4,S,6,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27, \ D.C. L4 W 3 15 8 UFtCTTvr; ff DAT( MMR 0 5 i381 AN ACT D.C. ACT 3 2 8 5 IN T~E CJU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT a oLu~BIA NOV 10 ml fo est3blish tne District of Colum~i3 Civili3n Conplaint ~evi:w e~ard f~r t~e p;r~osa of resolvinq citizen alleq3tions Jf misco~duCt JY officers of the ~etrooolitan Pol ice DeJ3rtnent anj 5oacia1 Pol ice enployed oy tne District of :olum0i3 qJv~r~ment. 6E IT ENACfED BY T~E CJU~CIL OF fHE DIST~ICT OF :OLU~BIA• fhat tnis act ~av ~e cited as tha •District of :o1umbia Civilian CoTiplaint ~e~i BJaro Act of Sec. 2. Creation ana Puroose a) Ther~ is est3ol isnaa A District of :olumoia Civilian Conplaint ~e~iew 8Jara (hereaftar referred to as the •Board findin~s and recomnendations witn respect to citizen co~plaints concerninq nisconjuct Dy officers of the ~etropol itan Pol ice Jeoartnent and the Sp~cial ?olice enployej oy tne District of CODIFIC TION D.C.Ccde, sec. 2-2701 2 :olumoia qovernment• wnen such misco1ouct is jirect2d toward any oerson wno is iot 3 ne~ber of the ~etropol itan Pol ice Oeoartnent or Special Police enoloyed oy the District of CJlumoia (c) The Boaro snall have ~utnority to act •ith resoect to 3 citizen complaint 3lleoi~g one (l) or more of tne follo•inq l, Poli =e harassment 2) Excessive use of for:e; or innerent diqnit.y of 3ny oerson to •hOm it •as airectea and to trigger disres~ect for l3w e~force~ent officers. Sec. 3. Board Recom~enoations. 3o3ril shall find ~nether eacn alle~ation in a co~plaint filej aqainst an officer s1oulo ~e sustainej. disTiisseo. or found to evidence Tiisconjuct not directly relatej t.o t~e immediate conplaint out •ithin tne autnority of the Boarj. The Bo3rj shall oe e~pow2red to re:o~mend D.C.Ccde, sec. 2-2702 3 oersonnel ~ctions aqainst officers i1volve1 in Tiisconjuct. Each findinq snal 1 De in writi~g. taKen oy tne Cni2f of the ~etropolitan Police OeoartTlent C) Except as hereafter pro~ijej. the Chief of tne MetroJol itan ~olice Department snall oe tie final autnoritY in reqarj to fin1i,gs aoout and aiscipl ine of officers of the ~etroPJl itan Pol ice Deoartnent and Soe:ial Police offi:ers eTiploved Dy the District of :olumbia governm~nt: PR JV I OED. fhat ll riqhts provi1ed DY tne District Jf :olumoia Government Co~prenensive ~erit Personnel ~ct of l :na. effective March 3. 1979 J.c. Law 2 13 o.c. Co1e. sec• l-331.l l·l 3S anendeo ov tnis act• including tne riq,t to apoeal oefore tne Office of Emoloyee Aopeafs and t,e rignt to a trial ooard ,earinq orior to aisnissal are 11a i n ta in ea. It is further provioea that if tne Chief of tne MetroJolitan Pol ice Department jetermines to taKe any action ot,er than tnat recoTimendej Jy ·tne Boara. ne s11a1l i 11aicate in therefor. Tie finji~qs and reconmen1ations of tne 3o3rd, toqat~er •ith tne recomnendation oy tne of the District of Columoi3 who sh311 ~ave t~irtY (30) d3ys from tne d3te of tne tr3~snitta1 by the :hief of the Metro~olitan Police Oep3rtment to either uoholj the recommendation of the Chief of the ~etropolitan Police Deoartnent, im~ose tne recommended 3Ctions of tne Board, or order a If the ~avor fails to act witnin the orescrioed t~irty (30) aays, t,e recomnenaed 3Ction of tne Cnief of the ~etropol it3n Pol ice Qeoartnent s,all oe ~eemea final. Se 4. Comolaint Procedure a Except 3s provided in subse:tion (d all :itize, co~p1aints of 3lleqed niscondu:t Oy offi:ers snall be adjudicated ·by tne 803rd O) fhe 3oard shall be res~onsio1e for oromul~3tinq r~las and procedures in 3ccord3nce #ith tne District of Columoi3 adninistrative ~roced~re ~ct, aoproved Octooer 21, 19~8 (B2 Stat• at a minimum: D.C.Code, sec. 2-2703 5 {l) Ganaral public access t:&amp;gt; required forms 3nj inform3tion concerning t,e su:&amp;gt;mission. re~iaw• and jisoosition of conplaints 2) Tne a~judication of complaints ana forwardinq of findinqs to the :hief of tne ~etropolitan Police DeoartTient i1 an axJejitious nanner 3) Tnat :oTiplainants and a:cused officers h3ve 3c:ess to all 3oarj :lroc:ejings anj receiv~ cooies of the 3oarj•s investiqative reoorts. findi~gs, and reco~menjations si~ultaneously witn tneir transmittal of any sucn naterials to tne Chief of i'ne ~atrooolitan Poli:e Deoartm:nt or tne United States Attorney for tne District of Colurnbi.a, as tne case rna.y -oe Tnat all aoara Tieetin;s w,ere testimony is Presented or findin~s and re:o~menjations are announced as ooen to tne ou:&amp;gt;l ic 5) Tnat ~deouate records f:&amp;gt;r tne conduct of h:ari~QS• Present3tion of evijence anj 6 witnesses. ana oelioeration of finjings are de&amp;lt;ielooea o) Tnat adequate rec gt;rds 3re maintained on t,e receiot, review• anj re:onmendations concerninq alleqed misconduct cases to allow re~ular nonitoring of the n3ture and disp:&amp;gt;sition of sucn cases; and (7) That t,e grounas and procedures for ~o:&amp;gt;d cause r em gt;val from ;ne11oersnip o, the Soard are soecifie:l c) Wit~i~ thirty (30) calendar days gt;f tne re::eipt gt;f rec gt;m11endations oy tne Soara. tne Chief of tne MetrO gt;olitan Pol ice Department snall (1) imoleme~t or other~ise issue a final order witn resoect to s-Jch re::o11m e ndat i gt;ns gt;r 2) refer tne 11atter t gt; 3 oolice trial b gt;ard ailure to a::t ~ithin tnirty (30) days shall ne deenea final action ov the Chief gt;f tne Metroool itan Poli::e OeoartTient ratifying tne findi,qs anj recommen:lations gt;f the Soard. after #nicn an aqqrieved gt;fficer TI3Y exercise any riq~t of review orovided by la The decision of the Cnief of ~etr gt;pol itan P gt;lice Deoart~ent t:&amp;gt; refer the natter to a pol ice trial ooard is final ana n gt;n- 1 re~iewable. notwitnstandinq the Jrovisions of Title VI ana Title XWI of the Jistri:t of Columoia Go~ern~ent Comoreh2nsive Merit Perso,nel A:t of 1978. effective ~arcn 3. 1979 (O.C. La• 2-13 o Coae. sec. l-33b.l l-33 sec. 1-3~6.l l-346.1 d) wne in the aetermin3tio, of the Board• the re:ord i,diC3tes any proo3oility tnat the alleqed nisconduct w3s cri11in3l in nature. tne 3oard sn3l l refer the complaint to t.,e Uni tej States Attornev for the District of :olumoi3 ecords of s.Jcn tr3nsfer snall be Tiaintained and the disposition of 3Ction determined and recorded. In cas e s wnere referral for oossible cri~ina1 orosec.Jtion 3s occurred but t:ie uni tea States ~ttorney for tne District of Columji as el~cted ,ot to orose:ute. the 6odrd ~av continue its adjuji:3tion of the non-criminal 3spects of tne :o~plaint. If the Jnited States •ttornev for tne Jistri:t of :oluITTbia elects to prose:ute• the aoard n3y resu~e its adjudic3tion of tne non rimin31 3spects of t~e co11pl3int following resolution of the criminal prose:ution. 8 (e) Tne Boara snall maintain an official record of 311 co'Ttp1aint orocae linqs .nicn ~hall gt;e availa~la to tne D~blic. All gt;r a~y oart gt;f Board records Tiay oe saalej to pre~e~t pJ01ic disclosure only for qooj :ausa shown oy order of tha yor or a court of comoete~t jurisdiction. such oraar shal 1 oe a p~bl i: re:ord and state r~asons for tne seal i n::i. Sec. s. 3oara :o'Ttposition. D.C.c:xie, sec Z-2704 (O) Tha nenoars snall De representativa of ~ne oo:&amp;gt;ulation of the District of :01u~bia and eacn shall oe a resiaant of tne District of Columoia C he ~avor shall apooint tha :hairparson of the Soar l ~ho shall oe a res~dant of tne District District of :olu~bia Bar O) The recoqnizaa oarqaininq agant for tne najority of uniforne l ~etropol itan P:&amp;gt;l ice DeoartTient enployeas snall aopoint a reorasentative. and the Chief of tne Matroool itan ?ol ice Departmant shall apooint a 'Ttenoer of the etropol itan Police DeoartTient. 9 (e) fhe 3oar:j snall na e f:lur (4 itizen ~enoers, t"o (2) of "horn sn3ll b e 3pJointej JY tne ~avor anj tw:l (2) 3p~ointej oy t:ie C:luncil of the Distri:t of Colu~bia. No citizen nenoer aoDo i ntea ov tne Mayor of the District of Co1umoi3 or the :ouncil of t,e District of Columoi3 nay oe or oeco~e a memoer of tne Metroool itan &amp;gt;o1 ice Deoartnent dJrinq such memoer•s te,ure on the (f)(l le three (3) years, exceot tnat t h e first terms of 30Dointment shall oe as follows l) The chairperson. one (l) citizen ~en~er aopointed by the ~avor. a,d one (l) citi~en -11e11oer aopointed by the :ouncil gt;f tne District of Colu~bia snall De apJointea for three (3) years o) The me 0noer of tne etr:&amp;gt;p:&amp;gt;l itan Police Department and one (l itizen nenoer two (2) years; ana (C) The reoresentati e of tne recognizea ~arqaininQ aqent for tne majority of uniformed ~etropol itan Pol ice Oeoartnent enployees ana 10 one (1 itizen 11e~oer aopJinted Oy tne Co mcil shall Je 3DDointed for o.,e (1) year 2) Any mem~er 3poointe::l to fill 3n unexoired term snall oe 3Poointed only for tne unexpirea Jortion of tnat term. tn3n t~o (2) consecutive terTis. F:&amp;gt;r purooses of this SJbse:tion. any memoer 3pJointej to any tern o1nicil exceeds twelve 12) nont'ls s,al 1 be (Q) A m3jority of tne seven (7) memoers of the ao3rj sh3ll constitute a quorun h nv 303rd Tienoer m3y oe reno11ed for ;ooa cause snow'l oy tne Mayor witn the concurrence of a ~ajoritv~vota of tne Board or oy a m3jority vote of tne B~~rd-witn the concurrence of t'le Mayor. In sucn event. a new Board memoer sn3l 1 oe 3DJointed oromotly in the saTie man,er as tne oredecessor to fill the unexpired term. Se o ivi1 ian Complaint Revie~ 3oard Functions 3nd ;earinqs lt;a• The Board shall convene and recei11e fron officer involved in instances of alleqea Tiiscondu:t o:c~rri'lg witnin the Jistrict of D.C.Code, sec. 2-2705 11 :olumoia. Every a:cused offic2r s,all Oe given sufficient oooortunity to responj to alleq3tions in any comol3int. witnin thirty (30) days of the filinq of 3 :onplaint the ao3rj sh3ll fix 3 ti~e 3nd ol3ce for a nearinq on tne comol3int unless tne 303ra jetermines on the oasis of tne face of a :onpl3int tnat t~e comolaint is frivolous. Tne Executiv: Director of the Boarj shall. at the of any comol3int. includinq the intervie~i,g of ~itnesses 3nj ooJ ice personnel. T,e results of 3ny in~estiQ3tion oy tne Executive Director sn3ll oe written in an investi~ative report. filed witn the ~o3r and served on every party before the Boarj•s ne3rin~ on tne comol3int. {b) Tne Board snall decide ov a preoonderance of tne evidence ~het,er to sustain or ~ismiss the (c) Any testimony anj otner evidence. to~etner •ith all p3pers anj reouests filed ii the oroceejinqs. and all material facts iot apoearinq in tne evideice out •ith resoe:t to ~hicn official ioti:e is ta~en. snall constitute the exclusive record for decision taoe recorjinq of all lZ testimony 3nj exnioits snall be naje 3v3il30le to 3ny oarty to tne oroceedinqs uoon re~uast d) Jpon tie raasonaole request jf any p3rty to its oro:eeainqs or on its O•n motion the 3oarj ~av direct by suoooena tne attanjanca of any oerson before the Board to giva testimony unoer oath or 3ffirm3tion ana to proauce a l l relav3nt oooks. racorjs• or other documants b=fjre the ao 3r cle (e) In case of contumacy oy. or refusal to jQay a sJoooana issued to any Jerson. th e 3oard nay oy resal~tion refer the natter to the Suoerijr :ourt of tne District of Columoia #hicn nay oy orjer requira such oarson to aooear 3na qive or or o du c a ~es t- i mo n v or boo I&amp;lt; s o a o er s or other eviden:e bearinq uoon the matter und a r in estiqation. 4ny failure t~ ooey such order may oe punisned oy tne Superior Court of tne District of ColJmoia as a contenpt thereof as i, the case of failure to obey a suoooena issuad• or to testify~ in a case pendinq before su:h court fl Jnce 3 haaring has been scnejulea. ever~ oartv• includinq tne complainant or :oJnsel. shall na~e t,e riqnt t~ testify. call. 3,d e•3~ine 13 :r~ss-?xamine adYerse •itnasses. chairperson of tne B~ard snall e~cluje irrelevant. issue in tne takin~ Jf tastinony or suomittinq of evidence snall be ~i1dinq. but exc?ptiJns to rulinqs Jf t1e c1airJers~n s1all be Jl 3Cad i nt re:ord onoensat i Jn fJr wit1ess2s wno are s~booenaej to testifv Jefore tne Board. ax:eot tiose in the emoloy of the District of Columoia gJvernment or the United States ~oYernTient Q Any-willful false s"'earin~ Jn tne oart Jf any •itness Defore tne Board as to any material fa=t snall be deemed perjury and snall be Junishad in tne manner ores=ribed by la~ for sucn offense. Se 7. Liaoility of aoarj ~enbars a) No ne'Tloer of ~ne Boar:l sh=.tl l oe 1 i a gt;l e to any oerson fJr damaqes or eauitaole relief bY oy tne mamoer Jr by the Boar1. if the acti~n taken D.C.Code, sec. 2-2706 l4 'elief tnat sucn memoer•s 3ction w3s w3rra,ted CY effort to obtain tne f3cts of the natter. Sec. a. Staff and Suoport Services a) The 3o3r::l shall emol oy an Ex:cutive Director 3nd sue, orof?ssional and i,vestigative The Exec:.Jt i ve )i re::tor and staff s,al l be onsidered eno l ovees of the Distri::t of Colu~oia ~overnnent ired in accordance ~ith t,e orovisions of the Oistrict of Colunbia Government :onpre,ellsive ~erit Personnel let of l978. ri~hts enjoyed by District of :olunbia e~ployees O) The Executive Director sn31l oe a resiaent of the District of Columoia C) The Exec tive Dire::tor srtall nave full responsi,ility for tne supervision 3,d airection of enplovees of th ivil ian Compl3int Revie# 3o3rd an::l Sh3l 1 ensure tnat al 1 rules. requlations. recoros. and orders of the Soard are naintained and orooerly executed. D.C.Ccde, sec. 2-2707 15 (a) The Executive JirectJr sn3ll receive and aaTiinistrati~ely process all cJmolaints authJrized to be resolved under tnis act aqai1st an accused jfficer e) The Executive DirectJr snall file with tne ~avor anj the :oun:il Jf tne District jf Cjlumoia. Jnce every six months. a report Jf all activities e~como3ssed witnin the :onplaint ~itn s~cn re:o~menjatiJns 3S tne BJard aeeTis aoJrJpriate ~itn resoe:t ta ool ice pra:tices• of tne police complaint system e:essary to supoort tne Board. its staff. 3na suooort services. emalavea oy tne ~istrict of :olumoia qavernment snall ae camoensated pursuant to section 1108 of tne Oistri:t of :olumbia Gover~ment :onprenensive 1979 (J L3w 2-139; o.c. Code. sec. 1-331.8 Se 10. Miscell3neous Provisions. D.C.Code, sec. 2-2708 D.C.Code, sec. 2-2709 16 (a) If any saction or orovisio, of tnis 3Ct •s ,eJd to oe u,constitution31 or i~v31 id. su, n unconstituti:&amp;gt;nality or inval iaitv sn3ll not affect th~ renainin~ sections or orovisions of this act 0) Th~ 303r~ shall orep3re an infor~ational oa11onl :t on. and requl arl y Dubl i ci ze tne pol ice :011plaint ~r:&amp;gt;cedure estaol isnej oy t,is act c) Anvo,e wno wisnes to file a conolaint aq3inst a ooJ ice officer must oe pro'li dea Ni th 3 oTiplaint form eoartnent and tne ~3yor are proniJite~ frJm TI3intainin~ any system otner tnan tn3t set forth in tnis act for the orocessing of section 2 i'li1ian comolaints aqainst offi:ers of the ~etropoPitan- Pol ice Deoartnent and Soe:ial P:&amp;gt;l ice amoloved ov the uistrict of ColuITTbia wnere tne alleqea Tiisconjuct is aire::ted tow3rjs any parson :iot an offic:r of the 'illetr:&amp;gt;pol itan P:&amp;gt;l ice De~artnent or Special Police enployej gt;Y tne ~istri:t of :olumbia Qovernment. The IO!etroP:&amp;gt;l i tan Pol ice Department snall estaolis~ an i1tensive nunan rel3ti:&amp;gt;ns traininq pro~ram for pol ice officers at every le'lel of comnand• 17 (d o como13i,t may be filej nore tn3n six (6) nontns after a complainant usi,q reaso~aole jil iqence. bacdme or should nave become awara of the ~atter qivin~ rise to the :oTiplaint e) The renejies created by tnis act are cunul3tive of any Jtners orovijej Jy statute or at o ·Timon 1 aw f Tne Reg il3tion Enacti,q t'1e P:&amp;gt;l ic anual for the Jistri::t of :olumoia. effe:~iYe Ja,u~ry 14. iq12 e No. 72-2) is amenaej as follo.-s 1) Oy stri~inq sectijn tJ.t:3 anj insertin~ tne follJwin~ section o~plaints alleqin~ JOlice har3ssment• excessive use of for:e. or use of lan~J3q; likely to demea~ tne in,erent dig~ity of any oerson to wnom it was directed anj to triq:;er jisre$JeCt for law e~for:enent offi:ers initidted bY any gt;erson otner tnan the ~ayor or a memoer of t,e for:e. shall oe resolvea pursuant to tne District of Columoia Civilian Comoldint Review 3oarj Act of 1~80 in 1 ieu thereof; and (2) by striKinq tne last se,tence of sectio, 10.1:19 D.C R. l8 q) Reorq3niz3tion Jroer ~o a. effective D. C 1. R. June 2 1953 (e~capt 35 it relates to a the :ivil i3n Como13int Review 303rj :reatea under this act) sh311 continue to 3poly to officers of the ~etroool it3n Pol ice Jeo3rtnent a,a tne Soecial Pol ice enolovea JV tne Government of tne District of Col~moia nire~ 3fter Janu3ry l• 1~80. for tne JrJvisions of section 3203(b) of tne District of :olumoia Govar1mant :o~orenensive ~erit Personnel (h { .n :my :ase 1o.mere a comol 3i it is D.C.Code, adjuji:ated ~v tne Boara and referrej JY tne Chief sec. 2-2709 (f of Pol ice to a ool ice tri3l ooar raview oy tne ool ice tri31 board as orovided in ~eorqanization J r j e r 'Io 4- 8 2 f f e t i v e Ju n e 2 l 5 3 s n 3 1 1 o e the ex:lusiva ~dninistrative procedure avail3ble to an officer of tne ~etroool it3n ~ol i:e Jeoartnent ana Soe:i 31 Pol ic2 em~loyaa by the Oistri:t of :olumbi3 qovernment. not~ithst3ndinq the orovisions of Titles XVI and XVII of tie Jistrict of :olumoia Comorehensive Govarnmant 19 347.16 i Section 1~05 of the District of Columoi3 Governnent Comorehensive Merit Perso,nal Act of 1978. affe:~ive Janu3ry l. 1980 co.c. La~ 2-139; f ollowin~ s e itan:e at tne end thereof rne f i ~a i n~s a~ a recomnend3tions of tne Jistrict of :olumoi3 Civi li an :ornola i nt ~eview Board may be ~sad i n ev~ l ~ac i nq tne oerform3n:e of 3n officer Jf the MatrOJol itan ~olice Deo3rtment 3na Spec i al Pol ice enployed ~Y tne District of Columoia Se 11• Stat~torv Construction. The ourooses of this act f3vor rasolution of amoiquitv Dy an aaninistrator~ heari,q officer. or court to~ard tne qoal of promotinq PuClic Jarticioatio1 anj ~penness in the resolution of citize~ conplaints of ~isconduct by oolice officers. T,is act shall De deeTiej to super:eae and reoeal a~y ana all provisions of law or aaninistrative orders enacted or pronulqatea prior D.C.Code, sec. 1-344 D.C.Ccde, sec. 2-2710 20 to O:tJbar l• 1981 hicn are in:o~sistent or conflict wit~ 3ny Drovision of tnis 3Ct• Sac. 12. Effacti ve 03te. This act snall t3ke affect aftar a tnirtY (30} jay oeriJd of :o~qressional reviaw fJllo~ing dO~rJv3l by tna ~avor (or in tne eve~t of veto by tha "lavor action by tne Council of tne District of Columbia to ovarrije tne vato as orovioed in section 602(2)(11 of tne District of Columoi ct. aupro~ej OeceTib e r 2 1~73 (87 St3t. 813; D C gt;d a• sac. l-14 7 c l P~OVIJED· Tnat tnis 3Ct sh31l not ta~e effect orior to October 1 of Columbia APPROVED: November 10, 1980 D.C.Ccde, sec. 2-2711 T 416 cc:i c 3 3 2_47 r \c o~c t ec s t e:;a cin cr;.i..c 1 0 l 1 8~0 Una.nim:lus ~l:seci Hardy D i\O t C..\t 1/C 7 a c:i A I I I itrot•&amp;lt 4 lt;A, I I 1 rc rcz ·rc:z u_naru..rro us all present lt I C t t f I I r I c 4 f ·1 lt lt;&amp;amp 4C I 1 j </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1131"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1132"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1133"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1134"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1135"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1136"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1137"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1138"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <para>
      <num>r</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1139"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§5-1140"/>
  </section>
</document>
