<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-156">
  <num type="law">3-156</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Cooperative Association Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1981-03-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-156.pdf">D.C. Law 3-156</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 5113</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-156, the “District of Columbia Cooperative Association Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-225. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 30, 1980 and October 14, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 10, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-283 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 3-156 woistrict of Columbia Cooperative Association Act of 1980. Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198, wthe Actw, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-225 on first, amended first, and second readings, September 30, 1980, October 14, 1980 and October 28, 1980, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 10, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-283, published in the November 21, 1980 edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 5113 This act was originally transmitted to Congress on November 19, 1980, and resubmitted on January 14, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-156, effective March 5, 1981. Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: January February March 14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 2,3,4,S,6,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27, 2,3,4 4 D.C. LAW 3 I 5 6 lfftcnvEMAR O S ~n 1981 4N ACT D.C. ACT 3 2 8 IN T~E CJU~CIL OF THE DISTRI:T OF :oLuMBIA llov 1 0 1980 To anend the District of Columoi3 :ooperative Asso:iation Act to provide for directors of housinq coopar3tive associations aopointed bV no1profit sponsors and to allow 3deQuate coTipensation for the orqaniZ3tio1 of tne association includinq promotional. advertisinq, and legal fees. Enroll ed c 18. J. BE IT EN4CTEJ ~y THE CJU~CIL OF THE ~ISTRI:T OF COLU~BIA That tnis act ~av oe cited as tne •District of :olumbia coooerative Association A~end~ent Act of Sec. 2. The Jistrict of :olu~oia Coooerative Associat i on Act. aoproved June l 1~40 (5~ Stat. 48 D.C. Code, sec. 29-801 is amended as follows a) Sac ti on 16 (D.c. Code. sec. 29-8lB) is amended oy inserting iumediate1y follo#inq tne first sentence tne follo.ing sentences The oy-laws of an associa~ion that orov i das multi-family cooperative nous i nq for low (l)DIFICA T'J:CN D.C.COde, sec. 29-818 z and TIOderate incoma oersons who are receivinq assistance tnrouqh one or ~ore of tha feaeral oroqrams described in section l(t) of An Act To define tne real oroperty exempt from taxation in tha District of :olumoia. effective Jctooer 1978 (J Law 2-lloi o.c. Code, sec 7-80la(t Tiav orJvide that one or ~ore of the jirectors out not a ~ajority of the directors ~av oe appointed ov a nonorofit soonsorinq orqanization wnich nelped create the association so as to ~aintain a continuinq and staoilizinq interest in its well oe i ncp PROVIDED, That tne soonsorin~ orqanization snall not apooint ~my direct.ors after tne Associ3t.ion ~as oeen established fo~ tan years. Such airector or directors aopointaa by the soonsorinq orqanization need not be ~enbers of the association b) Section 38 (O.c. Code. sec. 29-838) is amenaed ov aadinQ the followinq oroviso at tne end of the first. sentence PROVIOEO, However. any association wnicn pro~iaes nulti-fanily cooperatiwe housinq for low and moderate inco~e persons wno are recai~ing assistance Enr I 1 l i~L O.C.Code, sec. 29-838 3 tnrJu~n one or nore of the 3vailaole federal proqrams descrioed in section l(t of 4n Act To define tne real prooertv exempt fro~ taKatiJn in the District of Columbia. effective October 4, 1978 (O.c. L3w z-110; o Coae. sec. 47-80la(t may p3y compens3tion for the orQanization of the association• inc1udinq necessary laqal fees. and for pro~otional e~penses in tne a~ount aoproved oy tne federal aqeicy administering the proqram of assistance to the rne~bers of the association witnout the limitations imposed ov :this sect i Jn Se 3. Tni s act shal 1 take effect after a tnirtv (30) jay oeriod of Congressional review followin~ 3pJrov3l by the ~ayor (or in tne event of veto ov tne Mayor, action by the :o~ncil of tne District of :olurnbia to overrije tne veto) as orovidad in section o02(c)(l) of t~e District of Enrolled Or ig i nal l r J d 0 r1g1na1 :olumbia Self-Governnent and Govarnmantal ~eJrqanizatiJn Act, aporoved Oecemoer 24• 1973 (87 Stat. Bl3i o.c. Code, sec. l-lr.7(c}(l olumbia APPROVED: November 10, 1980 cc-r o B 3-225 tU V'OICZ 'ICT M a 1.i ~o,.r i t..iY ­ ~bsectt: all present c c amp 11 I l a c f I I I iw-.c C 4 I r 111 I 1 I nrmN I I i :z I I I I I 5 l_ c o 1 i I I r l'1 l I I I L;l.SON I I I I 5 i I \l ~rr. I I I I f"T .l T I I I OO!lE: I I I I t7 n'T I I I t:.l lnV I I I I ~iv I I I I I I I I T~OtTTC: I I I ~f"T l 01( I I I I I I I 1 i•t I C~C..\ O ~f Ct C l #24':c CN A~d~o~p~t~e~d Am:M.M:eliOi.l..n~d~e~di IF i.i•r•s~ti R~e~a~a~i~ni..l ig 1 ~0~,1-1 4~,1-s~o CtCZ V'C":Z M a J o=r i t i;Y sent H a_r_d~y C:1 4 4A I •rC f r l I C• I C 1 1AP I C lt;C A I I f' I I \;•rl"'M j I I I I l I I I I le I I I l I I I I 4 lt l~T I I I I .jc r T I I I I I r"'T lP'{ I I I I l \,(Q01E I I I I :\-.7T r" I I I I I :l .l ~T'\V I I I I 1 V I I I I !f I I I l I r l 1 lt I I I f'l'T'l~T I I I 11 I I I I I r ° M:.z• I ~N A~d~o~p~t~e~d F~i~n..wa_1 s e~a~d i.n~g 1.a 1~2-s 1.s~a Ji •1c tc vc M a 1 0 r.i t y M_o_o r_e C 1-AC I c 4 j 1 4 I c c t </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
