<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-15">
  <num type="law">3-15</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-09-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-15.pdf">D.C. Law 3-15</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 11003</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-15 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-26, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 8, 1979 and May 22, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-55 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>cou~rCIL OF IE DIST:ncT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. c LAT.1 3- 15 "Advisory Neighborhood Commissioners Term of' Office Act of 1979 ursuant to Section 4 2 of the District of Columbia Self Government and Governmental qeorganization Act L. 93 198 the Act the Counci l of the Dis tri ct of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3- 26, on first and second readings, May 8 1979 and ~ay 22 1979 respectively Following the signatu re of the Mayor on June 18, 1979 this legislation was assigned Act ~o 3-55, published in the June 29, 1979, edition of the :J C e g i ste r Vol. 25 page 1100 3) and tr'ansmitted to Congress on June 21 1979 for a 30 day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c l) of the Act T 'cl e Co 1.1n c il of the Di strict of Co l 'lffi bi a he re by gives :1 o t ice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites the following legi3lation as Q. C. Law 3- 15, ef:~ecti?e September 8, 1979 AR~ erG'I'IJ I XO i&amp;lt; Chairman or the Council Jates ~aunted Du ring 30-day Cong r essional Review ?eriod: June 21, 22, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29 July 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 16, 17, 13, 19, 2 0 23, 24, 25 1 2 3 J D C j ~I Z l I Enrolled O zinal I~ THE :ouN:IL JF T~E O[STRICJ JF CJLJM3IA To anena t .1e Ajvis:Hy 'Je ig n bo r1 ood CJu,1cils ~c t of 197 5 )y el i rnin:it i n'.J the twJ- term li11itati o 1 of s e r vi:e fJ r Ad v i so r y 'le i :j h) or n 0 d o nm i s s i gt; n er s onmi ssi Jn 2 r s' T~ r n CJ f Offic 2 \ct f 1':17 ounci ls ~ct of 1975, effect iv e Jcto:&amp;gt;er l O o 197 5 (J L3w 1-21 J Coce. sec l-17le(c) l i s -Jnen:.Jej 35 follo..is a gt;y str i kin:J out "t"'o (2 ifter tne o r d "t han" i n i 'l e t o :in.j i 1s2r ti 'l &amp;lt t n r ee (3 i1 l i eu t1ereof ind b J y s t r i k. i n q o u t t o 2 11 a f t e r t h e o r a t h e i 1 i 1e s ix an:1 i1s~ rt i'lc t h ree (3 il lieu tiere gt;f z Sec 3 Thi s a:t s1a l l t3ke e ff t as r J vid ed fJ r a: t s Jf t1 e CJunci l of t he J i stri:t of :olurnb i a i1 sect i o1 ~JZ{c) Jf the Di strict Jf CJl~mbi3 Se lf- GJva ri man t Jnd ~overn nenta l e J r :1 a n i z. a i Jn A c t 1 \ \ Jv \ v c n a i r nan •j (Ju"lci1 of th e Jistr i ctt of olu .noia I J ld Or J i str i: t of olu~b i a APPROVED: June 18 1979 :CtlllU~C ll !l Of T.f.lE D U S"J'i~t"'J DfF C O IL1ll 3U ,rl cir .Of:R~:i&amp;amp; rom.n:n AW1r!L7.l ccc:i r :10: Bill 3- 26 AC::ON: To Adon t (5-8-79) g VOICE 07 B V X a~i O r 1 t V Abs en Kane lj ~Ct CALI 07 Cl A I U C I I l'-f C::U C C re t I I C.:l1.,1Mc::a c c I •no I t "4 I OFON I I I i K \ E I I I SP.AC:&amp;lt;:Lc'.TO~ j I I I T,:T~'i'J:'1 I I I I \S O:.i I I I S?Al'ElI lG I I I I rr .1. Q l{ I I I I 1001:\ E: I I I I ~WP n'J I I I I I µ .1.onv I i I I lt \. y I I I I I I I I \ gt;llTC: I I i I gt;nr lt; I I l i I I I I lt 10 1Q i i q sent: Clarke U Ct CALL 'IC 7 c H I l \.ll't C UI' J T I c:i C ol•&amp;lt llt C r I" I i\T Y n \J i I I I j \. \ j ] I I I Sµ .\. \ KT T' r\\l I i I r:T j I I I I 4 'A 1.c: n I I I I ·1c: P .1. T'T n r,-r. I I I I T q l I I I I \[('0 lt I I I i \ TT t::n'\T I I I I 1 gt;nv I I I I i Q !V I I I I I I I I T .\ gt; T'T C: I I I I f gt T .\ gt; l( I I I I I I I I I I UM 1 T r i u r-1{ c o ii amp L I J gt;t Sec:-ec~r e S ounc l u ·1orc IC Z \ sec </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
