<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-157" flag="true">
  <num type="law">3-157</num>
  <heading type="short">Alcoholic Beverage Control Act Amendments of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1981-03-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-157.pdf">D.C. Law 3-157</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 5117</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-157, the “Alcoholic Beverage Control Act Amendments of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-256, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 14, 1980 and October 28, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 10, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-284 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 3-157 "Alcoholic Beverage Control Amendments of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Distric t of Co l umbia adopted Bill No. 3-256 on first and second readings, October 14, 1980 and October 28, 1 980, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 10, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No 3-284, published in the November 21, 1980 edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 511 7 This act was originally transmitted to Congress on November 19, 1980, and resubmitted on January 14, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the Distr ict of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this e nac tment as D.C. Law 3-157, e ffective March 5, 1981. ARRINGTON D ·XON Chairman of the Counc il Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Re view Period: January 14,15,16,19,20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 Febcua ry 2,3,4,5,6,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27, March 2,3,4 D.C. LAW 3 1 5 7 EFri~~1iVE MAR 0 5 1981 AN ACT D.C. ACT3 2 8 h IN T~E C)U~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT o~ CO Lu~BIA IDV 1 0 1980 To reoeal that portion of the Oistri:t of Columbia Alconol i: Beveraqe Control Act wniCh pronioits the sale of alcoholic oeveraqes on tne day of the oresidential election in the District of Columbia durinq the hours the oolls are open• and for other ourposes. Enrolled Original BE IT ENACTED BY THE C OU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF COLUMBIA• That tnat this act may be citej 3s tne "Alconol ic 1everaqe Con trol Act Amendments of l~RO Sec. 2. Tne Alcoholic Bever3qe Coritrol Act• 3poroved J3nuarv 2 193 48 Stat. 31q; o.c. Coje se c 25-lOl 2P-O is a11enaed as fol I ows a) Paraqr3ph 2 of section 7 (D·C· Code• sec. 25-107(2 is amenjed Dy scrikinq th e followinq sentence otwitnsc a ndinq anv otne r orovision of this Act. the Council shall not authorize the sale DY ~ny licensee otner than tne holder of a retail:H'S license. class E• of any gt;e11erages on CODIFICATION D.C.Code, sec 25-107 2 the day of tne p residential election in the Ji strict of Columbia aurinq the nours hen tne oolls 3re open. and 3n y such sales are hereby gt;r gt;hi b i ted b 5 e c t i on 11 D C ode• s ec 2 5 111 i s amende-:t is fol lo s: D.C.Code, sec. 25-111 (1) subsection (c O.c oje. sec. 25- lll(c is a11ended by striKinq tne fiqure 2.475" 3nd insertinq the fiqure "s3.713" in 1 i eu cnereof; {2) subsection (d O.c oje. sec. 25- lll(d is anended by strikinq tne fiqJr e "il.250" 3nd insertinq the fiqure "sl.875" in lieu thereof 3) subsection (e O.c ode. sec. 25- lll(e is anended by striKinq the fiqJte 11 s1.25 0" 3n:1 insertinq the fiqure 1. 8 75 in lieu thereof i subsection (f D.c oje sec. 25- lll(f is anended by strikinq the fiqJre 165 3nd insertinq the fiqure "S248" in lieJ thereof 5) sutsectio q O. c Coje. sec. 25- lll(q is anended by A) stri~inq the fiqure 825" e3cn ol 3Ce it aooears and insertinq tne fiqure "51.238" in liei.J thereof; 3 (8) striKinq the fi qura 25 eacn ol:Ke it aopears and insertinq the fiqure 63 13 in li eu r.h ereof insertinq the fiqure 2.475" in lieu thereof 0) stri1&amp;lt;inq the fiqur 10D and insertinq the fiqure uil50" in lieu thereof E) strikinq the fi qure 3" ana insertinq t h e fiqure 4.5 0" in lieu t~ere gt;f; 3nd (F) strikinq the figure 20" ana insertinq the fiqure 30" in lieu the reof 6) subsection (h O.c. Co:le sec 25- 111 h i s a Tie nd e d by A) strikinq the fiqure "1&amp;gt;330" e:icn ~l3ce it aopears and insertinq tne fiqur e Q5" in l i eJ thereof 8) strikinq the fiqure 3 0 and insertinq the fiqure 45" in li eu t iereof Cl strikinq r.he fi gu re 1.50" ana insertinq the fiqure 2 Z in lieu triere gt;f 0) strikinq the fiqur e "515" 3nd insertinq the fiqure "£22.50" in lieu tnereof; and (E) strikinq the f i qure 50" and ins ert inq the fiqur e "1i75 in li eu t,1 e r eof 7) subse c tion (j D.c oje. sec. 25- lll(j is a11ended bv striking the fiqJre 7.50" 3nd insertinq the fiqure "s50" i lieu tnereaf 8) Si.Jbsection (k O.c oje. sec. 25- lll(k is aTiended by stri1&amp;lt;inq the fiqJr e 1 00 ° and insertinq the fiqure "Sl50" in li e J thereof 9) su bse ction (l O.c o::ie sec. 25- 111(1 is aTiended by striKinq tne fiqJre "SlOD" 3nj insertinq the fiqure "sl50" in lieu thereof; and 10) insert a new suosection (m) to read as fallows m) Insoection Fee Tne f ee snail ba SZ5 for an aTiend11ent to an AlCahalic B~ver3qe Contro l L icense ~hich results in an inspectian of t.ha 1 i :ensed pre11ises oy the Alcohal ic Bever3ge Control 3oard or staff c) Section 13 (D Code. sec. 25-114) is 3mended DY addinq the followinq se,t ances at the a nd thereof to read as fallows The ~avor is autnorized to est ablish a late wrie tpol ications for 1 icense rane al snal l De f i 1 ad The fee far an appl icatio'l filed aft.er D.C .Code, sec. 25-114 5 the date estab l i shad Dy the ayor Sh3 1 l be 1 5 oer centum of the apol ication fee d) Section 16 (D.c. Code. sec. 25- 117) is 3mende j JY striking the fiqure "Sl JO and i n s er t i n q the f i qu re l 5 O" i n l i e tJ the r eo f. Sec 3. The Alcoholic Beveraqe ontrol ~e~ulations. effective July l. 196 Title 3• DCRR is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended by 3dding a new subsection (c) to read as follows {c) The fee for processing an 3PJ 1 ication hi ch nas been deniej or witndra~n shall Je SlOO.DO for a proorieto rsniJ 165.0Q for (D) Section 3.5 is amended as follows 1) suosection (a) is anended by aooing the followinq sentance at the end ther~of to read 35 f gt;l lO\olS The f ee for change of Jfficer shall oe $75.0:J 2) subsection (b) is amended to re ad as fol lows b) Wnere al ic ensee 1as aesi~nated 3 gt;erson to nanaqe the business l i:ensed• each such manaqer shall be the nolder of 3 val i a D.C.Code, sec. 25-117 D.C.M.R. 6 n3n3qer•s Permit which shall be rene.,aole 3S orescriDed by the ~avor. The fee fo r said pernit shall e&amp;gt;e HOO.DO. S3i::l permit snall rem3in valid until surrendere j sus oended. o r r e v:Jked. An apolicant for a 11anaqer 's permit (i• 2 one iho ~as not gt;e e n aopro11ed o y the B:Jard) s~3l l oe in11estiqated and snall be suoject to tne aopro11 a l of the Boa rd. Prior to issu3nce of the permit an 3pol ic:int shall obtain a copy of tne Act D· C· Code sec 25-101 et and tnese Rul e s and Requ l ations 11 manage rs who hOl::l gt;ermits at the ti11e of the effective da te of this subsection sh3ll oe r e quired to ootain a reissued per11it c c ord i n~ to tne terns of this s ubsection itnin LBJ davs of the e ffective date o f this s u gt; sect i Jn 3) A n ew subsection (c) is a'.l d ed to re30 a s fol lo.,s c) Manaqers holainq 3 val id gt; e rmit 3cco rdin~ to tne terns of suos ecti'.Jn o may o e 2mo l:Jy ed by one or more 1 i censees it h:Jut furtner in11estiq3tion s u oject to compliance gt;y the lice nsee witri s uosect i on (d Eorolled Original 7 (4) A new subsection (a) is added t gt; read 3S fol 10-NS d) In the event a licensee des i qn3t e s a person to m3naqe the gt;usiness licensed. s:iid licensee shall notify tne Board in ~ritinq ithin 7 days of tne e~ploym nt• s e ttinq forth the nane and p e rmit nu~Der of said ;nanaqer 5) A new subsection (e) is 30ded to read as fol lo s e) In the event a licensee has jesiqnated a person to manaqe the ousi,ess 1 i:ensea and the enplovment of sucn nana qe r shall termi n3t e tne 1 icensee shall notify t:ie Bo 21rd thereof• and Shall d es iqnate a new manager witnin 7 davs afte r the ter~ination of the )revious nanaqer (unless such time De e~tenje1 av tne doa r a The licensee shal 1 set fortn the .name and e rmit numoer of tne aesiqnate1 nana~er. In the event that a 1 ic ensee desiqnates a Person no dOes not nold a v3l id man3qer•s permit. s3id aerson snal l apaly for a aermit according to the a rovisions of suosection (D If no manaqer is emoloyed witnin 7 jays or no aaPl icant acc e ptaal e B to the Boa r d is desiqnated witni, 7 j3yS• the license nay, in the discretion of th e Bo 3rd, oe re1101&amp;lt;.ej 6) A new subsection (f) is 3dded to re:3d 35 follo s f) A holaer of a m3n3qer•s per~it stBl 1 notity the Board witnin 7 d3ys of nis or ner arrests and convictions otner th3n t,ose for minor tr3ffi c 11i ol 3tions. 11 7) A new subsection (q) is 3dded to re ad a s fol lo"'s q) A holder of a m3naqer•s permit shall notify the Boa rd within 7 days of any chanqe of home 3dcJress 8) A new subsection (hl 1s ajded to read :3S f gt;llows: oermit snall surrenaer said oermit t gt; the Boa r d ~itnin 7 days, wnenever the use gt;f said Permit is discontinued for any r eason whatsoev er Tne Board shall nold saij oermit until tne pernit nolae r resumes emoloyTient as a manaqer. Should the oermit holder not resume employment as a manaqer for lZ consecut.i ve months sai d pe rson snal 1 oe 9 reJuired to file a new aop l ication e investiQ3ted. Dav the re quired aopl ication tee dfld De aoproved DY tne 8:)a r d c) Sect i on B.l is ane nded by 3dji 1q tne followinq se1tence at the end thereof tO r ea3 3S fo l lows Tne annua l fe e fo r such oerni t sha l 1 oe £25 oo d) Sec tion 7 of Apoendix A i s a Tie n de a b v s trikinq tne followinq sentence otwi tnstand in q any otner )ro visio n of this Act. the Council shall not auth:&amp;gt; riz e the sale by any 1 icensee otne r than the holder ot a retail er•s 1 icense. c l ass E. of any gt;e veraqes on tne 1ay of the presidentia l eli ction in the Jis trict of :olumoia auring the ,ours ~nen tne oo lls are ope n. an3 any such sales are hereby orohibit ed Sec. 4. Tni s lCt shall take effect after a tt'lirty (30) day oe ri oa of Conqressio1al review fo llowinq 3p)roval by tne ~ayor (or i n the event gt;f v e to oy tne Mayor action bv the :ounc i I of tne J istrict of :olumbia to over ri je tne v eto) as orovid ed in section 602(c l) of the Di strict of :otumb i a 5elf- Go11€1n~ent and Governmental lO Re3rqanizatiJn ACt• 3poroved Oecamoer 24, 1973 87 5t-3t. 813; o.c. Code. sec. l-14-7(c)(l C CnairTian \ Council of the District df Co lumbia of APPROV ED: November 10, 1980 B 3-256 cc a s VO!CE l/C via j_o_r_i_t_y Absent: I I ROU. CAU. l/QT ca C c..11 re I j I A 11 u lt 1 « C.11' l •Y'C I I l 1 l,J c c I r'C r I '1. 1 j J nr&amp;lt;ON I I I i K lE I I I I C C T 0'1 I I I I r nrr R 1 I I I L-\SON I I I 5 1_ L'T p;r, I I I I I rr _1.qt I I I I QORE I I I JTT r;.\! I I I I l U fW I i I I iv l I I I I I I 1 I T.10\7T&amp;lt I I I I RnT J:I~ I I I I 1 I I I I I fOt e t J 10 l..J c::c T: Adopted Final Read i n a 10/28 /80 /Yl 11orcz ·10-r u n a n 1 m o u=s Aosent M_o_o_r_e lj C!.I. CALL C c A t'C. I I f u lt c c" I Cf "l•l" l f t amp 1 C c I r"C I l" I 1 -A £ l iVnN I I I I ;I lt I I I I kµ :r n,i I I I r,77'1T I I I I c: n1&amp;gt;r I I I I k i •T ;\ T \"r I I I i rT Rl(7 I I I f l OORS I I I I r.;rr c:n,r I I I I t \RnV I I I l 1 1&amp;lt;.lV I I I I I I I I I Tl l TT&amp;lt I I I I j RnT IRK I I I I :j I I I I I I f AC7:CN lj 'lotCZ ?QT l.bsec I I RCt c;,r i073 }I 1 I i fJ c lt;C Jll I 1: I I i 1.1 c::1 lt lt;f!C I I L'°'C 1 l </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
