<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-33">
  <num type="law">3-33</num>
  <heading type="short">Newborn Health Insurance Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-10-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-33.pdf">D.C. Law 3-33</citation>
      <citation type="register">26 DCR 1116</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-33, the “Newborn Health Insurance Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-12, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 17, 1979, and July 31, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 31, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-99 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OP THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-33 "Newborn Health Insurance Act of 1979~ Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Colw:ibia adopted No. 3-12 on st and second read ngs, July 17, 1979 and Ju:y 31, 1979 respectively. Following the signature or the 1ayor on August 31, 1979, th s legislat on was ass!g."led Act Ne. 3-99, published in the S~ptember 7, 1979, edition cf the D.C. Reg!ster iTol. 26 page lll6 and t:-ansmittcd to Congress en September 7, 1979 foe- a. 30-&amp;lt;iay r-eview, in accor"dance with Section 602 c l) of the Act. The Council of the Distr"ict of Colt xbia hereb7 gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review ?et"icd has expired, and, therefore, cites th s enac~~ent as D.Cw Law 3-33 e~recti ve Oc to~er 20 979. Dates Counted Dur1n~ the 30-day Congressional ~eview Pe~iod: September October 7, 10, 11, 12, l.3, 14, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21 24, 25, 26, 27, 28 2, 3, 4, 5, 9 O l, 12, 15, 16, 17 1.8 9 r-1 Ill JI U1 ·d 0 11 f 0 r!l tr\ n 3 5 c&amp;gt; c::i Ol CJ) C&amp;gt lt;01 r_J 0 gt w u 7 -1 0 0 I u c:J ci rn J u U. r u fY v&amp;gt; 0 HJ 11. n z gt; 0 t I HI 1 rn I m C gt; g q 0 n 1• c L ti rtt u n L r 11 L' 0 L IU 0 c n l J c r E 0 r: l; u 11 !TI I GI r I: u n rt! l r fL t1I ll L r 1 L t;J c L 0 I J J n t' II l I I I r J ll 1 _J u J n u UI gt n lll v UI v r L :J c r I c 0 n c: IJ t7 u v '11 n ti r v II r IJ u 111 r r- t It 0 tJ v v c 11) L :J c r c: 0 1 0 L tr u c 111 l t n c flt 1 u c 1 r \1 \ \ 1 c 11 r 1)1 n K r c 0 (I I u gt; n v v r 0 L n V1 0 n v m l c n I n &amp;gt; IJ c c L 0 ti \ u :1 0 L lJ' t7 f J n ti c n• L 0 &amp;gt; n L n c r n ti II L L IJI r 0 L u c: 0 r 0 t J 1.1 u n ]• L r 11 0 gt Cl Q• n r 1'1 c: o• n m c L r t: ll r di r E n L L '1• n L v 1n 0 L n '1 Cl: \ j c t IL 0 0 c L 0 n t O• r r L n c QI 0 r 'ti r c c r. L n 0 &amp;gt J c: L 0 QI 111 L GI 0 ti (II J I v '11 r t u 1 \I r 111 c: v v L n L :J r n Ill v m L n u &amp;lt;L 0 0 ti 0 r J" II O l c II• r p n• L u I' L rt \ Ill \I IJ II• r r~e Ca 11a e i l o f, t ho l r tr t a oltHtb i gt L 1 r L I r I tJ r: L 0 r 0 r: p L n Vl LI v n m t c o• u r 0 II r I I r { r f n f c n n L n J L 0 E -j r di L I v u 0 0 c di f gt n J 1' V&amp;gt u n (\ o• r t• r L Cl t&amp;gt L n gt; n u di r 0 L 0 0 t1 II.I \ 1 u !II L n 0 c \ n c 0 u n c rn r: 0 L J 11• L &amp;gt r v L u c 0 v L 0 I I f\I L 0 E r- 0: L u t1 L :J f1 d' L !II r: u 0 u c Ill r 0. u c 'Tl u r. v c: L 0 n QI r L n v &amp;gt; L Ill t.J 0 L 0 c 0 r L 0 L n1 \ll r: QI r 0 L t1 QI r r: L :i m 0 J r c tJ L Ill gt u n• c n I J L r: tJ c: r tJ r 0 m \ n 0 \ 0 u t1 c r u c 11 c n &amp;gt n fl r: L' r 0 lt \ n u 0' r LI QI &amp;gt; OU r n \ 0 L 0 c r: fJ L n 0 di rtl rt ti 0 \ ftl n u II c 0 I u \ r c II :J 0 t.J gt; f] n t' r 1: u \L 0 VI u c f L ;J {I :IJ \ 111 c In 11 L n fl \ Ill &amp;gt II u ll 'II L tJ r. 0 L p \ u VI IJ 1 VI u r 1J VI 0 n v c 'I' L :i r 01 \ ti r J r c n r r tJ L 0 r v \ tJ VI 0 r c \ Ill tJ \ n IL i VI fl 11 v c L. 0 '1J rtl 11 !IP &amp;gt; 1J v nr IL c LI \ QI t.J gt tJ p N &amp;gt 1) c Ill :t LI 1J II L 11 r: 0 L 1• n u u 0 r 0 or v c Ill L :i Ill c r: v 0 LI gt c 11 11 L I! c ;l c 0' r 0 \ u J o• \ \ 0 tl u c n 11 Qt r 11 L n l.J c '11 u r tJ n «II t.J 0 Cl gt; IJ v Ill Ill r u tr c 0 n Ill 11 gt n n aJ o u n c 1 r: QI c 0 c r. aJ 0 r: c \ 0 n c QI L tJ u c n 11 c 0 aJ '11 II nr gt n• IL L i: a.J L nr LI 'L '11 Couae:tl or- t h~ Ji tcr\ c c of :o lu•bJ l Couac-!l o f n'lo :l tr cr i.ct of I I 'fl I u r u I J n n I I ll c 1 L 0 n r J 0 c l- ti t1 u E ll r L L l 111 gt 6 n r: f} L 11 fJJ c: Ill L II 0 r j 0 II c (\I 0 t I n r E L u r. 0 I 3 n IJ n y u u v u m I L 0 c u 0 a.J 11 u r. 0 VI \ f 1• u tJ r: Ill c Fl ti u 11 0 u I o I \. I Ill 0 QI 0 I I r 1:1 J c 1J O I v c n n J 1.1 "\ l.d n r gt; \J 11 0 t: O' 11 di c I D. u r \ i r1 QI N &amp;gt gt 0 Q n n n l cu 9 l~C r~1 1~1 c a Ct e \ c r oore ca 9•4A I I' I g i c::z ·re 3;.v f 3 o cc c k~a f I 1 r Osei c n a 7 c </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3801"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3802"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3802.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3803"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3804"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§31-3805"/>
  </section>
</document>
