<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-41">
  <num type="law">3-41</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Consumer Transmission of Money Act of 1978 Amendments of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-12-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-41.pdf">D.C. Law 3-41</citation>
      <citation type="register">26 DCR 2078</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-41, the “District of Columbia Consumer Transmission of Money Act of 1978 Amendments of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-143, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 25, 1979 and October 9, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 30, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-113 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRIC~ OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-4 District of Columbia Consumer Tra.r:sz::ission of i-toney Act of 1978 Amendments of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorgan!zation Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Distr ct of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-143 on first and second readir.gs, September 25, 1979 and October 9, 1979 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 30, 1979, this leg!slation was assigned Act No. 3-113, published in the November 9, 1979, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 26 page 2078) and transmitted to Congress on November 5, 1979 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites this enactment .as D.C. Law 3-41 effective December 21, 1979 L MT DIXON I Chair~an of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Conzressional Review Period: November December l, 2, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 13, 14, 15, 16, 19, 20, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10, 11 2, 13, 14, 17, 18, 19, 20 D.C. LAW 3 4 1 ~EDEC 2 11979 AN ACT D.C. ACT 3 11 3 I~ THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCT 3 a 1979 Enrolled Original To amend the District of Columoia Consumer Transmission of ~oney Act of lq7 and to provide administrative flexioilitv• ae IT ENACTED 3Y THE COU~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA. That tn·iS act may oe cited ·as the "District of Columoia Consumer Transmission of Money Act of 1q79 Amendments of Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Consumer Transmission of ~oney Act of 1978. effective Jctooer 4• 1978 (O.C. Law 2- 114; o.c. Code. sec. 47-3201 9 is amended as follows a) Section 7(a 4) co.c. Code. sec. 47-3206(a is amended to read as follows 4) a surety oond issued ov a oonding comcanv or insurance company. authorized to do ousiness in tha District of Columbia. or other security as provide~ in suoseccion (O in tne principal sum of fifty thousand doll~ri (S50.000 Each aoplicant shall submit proof of security to the Mayor prior to tne issuance of t~e 4 rJ 2 renewal license for any cal~ndar year in tne amounts provided herein or a licensee with average total outstandinq and unpaid checks for the previous year of not over fifty thousand dollars (SS0.000 the oona shall oe fifty tnousand doll3rs (SSO.OOO For a 1 icensae witn average total outstanoinq and unoaio checks for the previous year in excess of fifty thousand do113rS (SS0.000) out less than seventy-five thousand dollars (S75.000)w tne bond snall oe seventy-five thousand dollars (S75.000 Ford 1 icensee #ith average total outstandinq and unpaid cnecks for tne previous license vear in excess of seventy-five tnousdnd dollars (S75.000 tne bond shall oe one nundred thousand dollars (Sl00.000 The bond shall oe in a form satisfactory to the Mayor and shall run to the· Di strict of Columbia for the benefit of any claim~nts aqainst t he applicant or his agents to secure the faithful oerformance ~f the ooliqations _of the apolicant ano nis aqents witn respect to the recaiot• nandl ing. transmission and pay~ent of ~oney in connection with tne sale of checks in the District of Colu~oia. Such cl3imants. aqainst tne aopl icant or his agents ay cnemselves oring suit directly on the oond or the Corporation Counsel ~ay orinq suit tnereon in oenalf of 3 sucn claimdnts either in one action or successive actions. The agqreqata liaoility of the surety in no event shall exceed the principal sum of the bond: I EXCEPT, That the surety shall have the rignt to cancel such bond. uoon givinq ~ot less than tnirty (30) days written notice to tne ~ayor. out sucn cancellation shall not rele~se the surety from any 1iaoilitv tnat may arise with resoect to ooliqations of tne aoplicant ou~Stdndinq on or orior to the day tnat such oond is.cancelea b) Section 7(o O.C. Code. sec 7-3206(0 is a~endea b) In 1 ieu of a corporate surety Oona or oonas or of any portion of the princi~al :ne~eof as required ~Y suosection (a tne applicant may deposit witn the ~aver or with such oanKs or trust companies or national ~anks in tne District of Columoia as sucn apol icant may cesiqnate and the ~ayer may approve a deposit in tne nature of a cash oond. stocks. interest oearing DondS• notes. debentures. or other forms Jf security as mav oe determined by the ~ayor in an aqqregate amount. oased upon principal amount or market value. whichever is lower. of not less tnan the amount of the required corpor~te surety oond or portion tnereof. Tne security shall oe deposited as ~entionea ~Dove ana neld to secure 4 tha same ooliqations as would th~ surety bona but the deoositor shall oe entitled to raceive all interest and dividends thereon ~nd shall have tne rignt. with tne approval of the Mayor, to suostitute other security for those deoosited C) Section 10 co.c. Code• sec. 47-3209) is amendea to read as follows ANNUAL LICENSE FEE "Sec. LO. The ~ayor shall estaolisn an annual 1 i cense fe111 Sec. 3. This act shall take effect at the ena of tne thirty (30) day oeriod provided for th~ Congressional review of acts of the Council of tne District of Columcia in section ~02(c)(l) of the District of Columoia Self- Govern~ent and Governmental Reorqanization Act Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: October 30, 1979 CCUIClll CF mE DI m~a GIF COl!llltlSUA EB CF GnCW.1CDm:la.Atn«Ilm cocm No: Bill 3-143 ACTION: To Adopt (9-25-79) ti VOIC?vtltt U~n~an~i~m;l,ll:O oUS AO•eczt: All P?'esen t au.en c:~w111ci c.w e.;i t nr~nN' KANE SlLl\CKl ETm \I MASON sp~mnrnG rT &amp;lt;l.O llT MOORE WT T SON U &amp;lt;l.OT'IV RAV TA 1'~C om Aorr lt I 1 tte1 cc AC::ON: Io Adopt (10- 9- 79) ti VOCC! VO Bo.i,y-.iM;1o1a j1o1oo.i.ir..ii..ot.x tJ ROLL CU. VO c t ¢.:tv c;a i I n rrn"M 11 rr .nti I .euii.f"TI nm Vd.C::ti"1 I I I C l) d. TTT T"l T".\Tr. n.:1.ou ~CORE rJTT C::1'1'.T l:f &amp;lt;l.l)T'IV l'.l.V I T &amp;lt OtTT C QnT ;I.OT( I 1 l r t lt;MMl"I I I \C'r:ON 0 VOtc:t VO ca~c:t P •t C I amp;1 :ite&amp;amp c~•CJJ f c J r I f cn j j t n-rmN f t I I 'l?'l;\fi I I I 16HACKLETON1 I I I I I I V AC::fillf I I I ioP AULD LNG I I I I rT .I gt I I I llvn!"t&amp;gt I I I I 1 rr lf\J I I i I ~A~T'\V I I I I v I I I I I I I I I T .\ 1'11'T' C' I I I QtiT \ t" I I I I i I I 41cn w 4 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
