<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-46">
  <num type="law">3-46</num>
  <heading type="short">Youth Employment Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1980-01-05</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-46.pdf">D.C. Law 3-46</citation>
      <citation type="register">26 DCR 2310</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-46, the “Youth Employment Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-138, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 25, 1979, and October 23, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 9, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-124 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE 1 D. C. LAW 3-4 6 "Youth Employment Act of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bi l l No. 3-138, on first and second readings, September 25, 1979 and October 23, 1979 respective l y. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 9, 1979, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-124, published in the November 23, 1979, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 26 page 2310) and transmitted to Congress on November 19, 1979 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-46 effective January 5, 1980 ARRINGTON IXON~r Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: November December January 19, 20, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 3, 4, s, 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 24, 26, 27, 28, 31, 2, 3, 4, AN ACT D.C. ACT3 12 I~ THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~BIA llJV 0 9 1979 To autnor~ze proqrams to provide e~ployment for District of Colu~Oia youth• to authorize a program for on-the-job traininq of adults with one or more dependents and to direct the Mayor to issue requ1ations to implement this act. SE IT ENACTE~ SY THE COUNCIL O~ THE DISTRICT OF COLU~BIA• That this act may be citeo as the "Vouth e~ployment Act of Sec. 2 a) The Mayor shall establish and implement orograms. suoject to the annual aporopriation of funds. for the emoloyment and training of young persons who are domiciliaries of the District of Columoia. as follows: Program to provide for the employment each summer of youth oetween the aqes of fourteen (14} and twenty-one (21) on the date of enrollment in the pro9ram. at a rate eaual to the federal mini~um ~aqe as established ~Y section b of the Fair Laoor Standards Act of 1938. approve1 June 25. lq38 (52 Stat. 10&amp;amp;2; 2q u.s.c. 20&amp;amp The weekly number of hours of i c 7 z such enployment shall be established according to the age of the youth to be empl~yed and the nature and requirements of the joo. but snall not be less tnan twenty (20) nor more tnan forty (40) hours per week. Employment under this oroqram may include an aopropriate number of supervisory oositions at a waqe not to exceed the federal minimum wage oy more than twelve percent (12 2) In~£ Q.2l l£bs. An In School Joos Proqram to orovide for the employment throuqhout the school year ~f students aqed fourteen (14) throuqh twenty-one (21) years on a oart-time oasis at the federal minimum wage. Priority Shdll oe qiven to students who may droo out of school to seek work oecause they are economically disadvantaged. of School Year-Round Employment Program to provide for the employ~ent of youth aqed sixteen (16) through twenty-four (2 years at the prevailing entry-level wage for the joo beinq oerformed. not to exceed S3e25 per hour during fiscal years 1979 and 19eo. and thereafter not to exceed a waqe tw~lve percent (12 greater than tne federal minimum wage. Priority for employment under this proqram shall be given to economically disadvantaged youth; ho•ever. the program Shall ~ave soecial safequards to assure that the prospect of such employment does not induce students to drop out of school. 3 t) On 1 2Q-1~i i ng_Fot U.J!il.11_DeQ lll ~2.9 g A oroqram of on-the-job training for five hundred (500) adults at least twenty-two (22) years old with one (l) or more deoendents. for a period of twelve (12) months at the orevailinq entry-level wage for the job Oeing performed. not to exceed five dollars (SS.00) per hour. under ~hicn the emoloyer shall pay an average of one-half (1/Z) of the emoloyee•s total wage cost for such oeriod. in accordanc2 with a schedule to be adopted by the Mayor. The Mayor snall immediately appoint a Task Force. consisting of. but not limited to. the ~ayor•s Special Assistant on Youth. the Director of the Department of Laoor, the Director of Emoloyment Services. the Minority Business Opportunity Commission, the Office of Business and Econo~ic Develooment. and a reoresentative of the Council of the District of Colu~bia. The Task Force shall identify and contact emoloyers within the private sector, with emphasis on minority businesses. in order to i~ple•ent tne program. The ~avor shall encourage participating employers to retain emoloyees hired under the program after the one (l) year oeriod b) Employment under the proqrams established pursuant to subsection (a) may oe provided directly ~ith the Qovernment of the District of Columbia or witn the private 4 sector on a fully funded. partially or match-funded basis throuqn qrants to or by contract with nonprofit or profit makinq orqanizations. associations. institutions or ousiness~s C) The proqrams established pursuant to subsection (a ay include. but shall not be 1 imited to. the following supportive services and activities: transportation; orientation; counseling and training; supplies and eouioment: and program promotion d) For the purpose of this act. the term Meconomica11y disadvantaqed" me~ns economically disadvantaged as defined from t i me to time by the Secretary of the United States Deoartment of Labor oursuant to the Comprehensive Emoloyment and Train i nq Act of 1973. aporoved December 28• 1973 (87 Stat. 839; 29 u.s.c. ao1 ~s ~g·&amp;gt e) An employer required by law to pay a minimu~ wage niqher than that specified in this act snall pay sucn higher wage to persons employed pursuant to this act f} The Mayor of the District of Columbia shall issue requlations to implement tnis act. The rules and requlations issued by the ~ayor for the ourpose of implementinq tne provisions of the act sna11 be submitted by the ~ayor to the Council of the District of Columbia for a forty-five (45) calendar day review oeriod. excluding days 5 I of Council recess. No sucn rules or regulations shall take effect until tne ~nd of the forty-five 5) calendar day per i od beqinninq on the day such rules or regulations are transmitted by the Mayor to the Chairman of the Council. and then only if during such period. the Council aoes not adopt a resolution disapproving such rules and regulations in whole or in part. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect as provided for acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section ~02(C)(l) of the District of Colu moia Self-Government and Governmental Reorqanization Act District of Columbia ~1 I 1 I amp r ayor F District of Columbi&amp;amp F APPROVED: November 9, 1979 I COUICSL OF TIBE DI S112CT CF COUJ41132A E:rB CF •IIIF.MmrolmDC3.ACnGil ocar. NO: Bill 3-138 § voter VOT U~n~a~n im~O~U S All "Present iJ RCtt CALL VOT c u I f c:1uaaci c I 1 a ca C \ I S T)T'(m~ I I I KAi.\fE I SBACK!.ETO~ fJ'T:IM I I I MASON' I SP .1 rrr I TG I M .1~Tn' I I I ~OORE I CJTT c:n:&amp;lt;l I t1i10T'IV I I I l.V I I TA ttTC: I I I I Ql"IT H!Tl' I I c J a-u ;l V'O!Ct O':Z 1Ii.o,iTDJ.i8ilolD im.ii.a~11 iS f I I AC CN D l/Otct OT U m c.a cn 4••U uc 1 I l c C f C I f' I 6 4~1S I C l f' I j IT'IT'rn~ I I I I l I I I •6H..J..CKI.ETOm I I I f I i I I V\&amp;lt 111 I I I Al:i ;i r r: I I I I l QT I I I I I I I I Ir.IT c:n'1 I I I I I 'C1.l0T'IV I I I I I v I I I I I I 1. l I TIO lt I f i I ° T l QV I I I I I I I </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-242"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-243"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-244"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2c</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-245"/>
  </section>
</document>
