<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-52">
  <num type="law">3-52</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Insurance Act Amendment of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-02-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-52.pdf">D.C. Law 3-52</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 26</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-52, the “District of Columbia Insurance Act Amendment of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-53, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 20, 1979, and December 4, 1979, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 21, 1979, it was assigned Act No. 3-142 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-52 "D1stt"1ct of Columbia Insurance Act Amendments of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Sel£- Government and Goverrtmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Dis tr1ct of Colu=ibia adopted Bill 'No. 3-53, on f'1t'St and second readings, Novembet' 20, 1979 and December 4, 1979 t"espect1vely. Following the signature of the Mayor" on December 21, 1979, this legislation was assigned Act ·No. 3-142, published in the January 4, 1980, edition of the O.C. Register Vol 27 page 26) and trans~itted to Congress on January 8, 1980 for" a 3·0-day r-eview, in accor-dance with Section 602 (c)(l) o£ the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressiona~ ReV1ew Period has expired, and, therefot"e, cites this enactment as O.C. Law 3-52 effective Febr-uary. 23, 1980 Dates Counted Durin5 the 30-dai Con5ressional Review Period: January 8, 0 10, 11, 14, 15, 16, 17, 22, 23, 2 4' 25, 28, 29 30, 31 Feb rua t'Y' l, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8' 11, 12, 13, 14' 19, 20, 21, 22 i I I D.C. LAW 3~ 5 2 u FE9 2 3 1980 AN ~CT O.C ACT3 14 2 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OEC 2 1 1979 To revise qrouc term life insurance am~unt limitations. to revise certain· insurance fees and· charges. and f gt;r other ourposes. BE rr ENACTEJ BY THE COUNCIL OF fHE OIST~ICT OF COLUMBIA. That tnis act may oe cited as the "0istrict of Columbia Insura~ca Act Amendments of 1979 Sec. z. Section 2 of Cnaoter II of the Life Insurance ~ct. aooroved June ·19. 1934 (48 Stat. 1130; o.c. Code• sec. 35-402) is amended to r-e3d as fo 11 ows All charqes and fees orovided f gt;r in this section snall oe collected by the superintendent and m3de payaole co tne District of Columbia For filinq charter or articles gt;f incorporation or association. or deed of settlement or copy tnereof. r-equired by 13w• Sl50; for each company certificate of authority SlOO; for 1 i cense of _each general 3gent. sso; for 1 i cense of each aqent or solicitor. s10; for license of e3Ch o~'Jker. S50. Al l Ji::enseS for br"Ol&amp;lt;ers. insur-ance Comp3nies. tne i r 2 aqancs or solicitors. who may apoly for permission to do ousiness in the District of Columoia. shall date from the first of the month in whicn applica~ion is mada and expira on the 30tn day of April following. rnere shall be no proration of 3ny cnarqe or fee providea for in this section. 11 Sec. 3. Section 10 of Chapter v of the Life Insur3nce Act. aoproved June I9• 1934 (48 Stat. 1·lb4; o.c. Coae. s~c. 35-710) is amended as follows 3) by striking out the 13st sentence in subsection (l}(d b) by strik i nq out "Sl0.000" in subsection 2)(d) ana insertinQ in lieu thereof "S25.000 c) oy aadinq in subsection (2)(a) immediately after ~whichever is less a comma and tne following or s75.000 for ~ortqaqe transactions hicnever is l ess d) oy striking out the l~st sentence in subsect i on (3)(d e) by amendinq suosection (4)(b) to read 3S follows b) The premium for the Pol icy snall be paid by the trustees wholly from funas contr i buted by the emoloye~ or emoloyers of tne insured persons. or by the union or unions. or by botn. or oartly from sucn f unds 3nd partly f rom f unds contriouted oy tne in sured 3 cersons oolicy on which cart of the premium is to oe derived from funds contributed by the insured persons specifically for their insurance may be placed in force only if at least 75 per centum of the tnen el igiola persons. e~cludinq 3ny as to wno~ evidence of insuraoility is not satisf3ctory to tne insurer, elect to make the required contributions. A policy on wnicn no part of tne premium is to be derived from funds contributed oy the insured person~ specifically for their insurance must insure all eligible persons. or all exceot any as to whom evidence of individual insuraoility is not satisfactory to tne insurer ft Oy a~endinq subsection { c) to read as follo~s C The ool icy must cover at date of issue at; least: one hundred oersons; and it must cover an averaqe of not less than tnree persons per employer unit unless the· ool icy is issued to the trustees of fund esiaolished by employers who have assumed obligations throuqh a colle&amp;lt;:tive barqaininq aqreement and ara oarticioatinq in the fund either pursuant to those ooli~ations •ith reqard to one or more classes of their emol~yees ~ho are encompassed in the co l lective oarqain i ~q aqree~ent or as a m~tnod of providing insurance benefits for otner classes of tneir amo l ~yaes or unless the policy is issued t~ the trustees of a fund escaolisned Oy one or more labor unions q) oy strikinq out the last sentence in subsection (4&amp;gt;} (d h) oy amending subsection (6)(d) co read as follows d) The 3mounts of insur3nce on employees insured under the policy shall be based upon some clan orecludinQ individual selection ~ither by the employees or by the association i) oy a Tlendinq the first oaraqr::1on of suosection (7) to read as follows 7 ny pol !cy issued pursuant to this section. exceot a policy issued to a credit~r pu~suant to suosection (Z or a pol icy issued to a credit union oursuant to suosection (8 av oe extended to insure the deoendents of insured oersons. or 3ny class or cl-3sses thereof, suoject to the following reQuiremenes j) by striking out "spouses and children" and "family ~e~oers" in suosection (7)(3) and inserting in lieu thereof "dependents• in each such olace k) oy striking out •soousa or cni l d" in suosection (7)(0) and insertinq in l i eu there~f "aependent r A.ZJro111!&amp;gt a i g nal 5 (1) ov addinq at the end of suosection (7) the follo~ing ne~ paraQraph Ce) For the purposes of this subsection. the ter dependents• means the spous&amp;amp; and unmarried children of the insured oerson. The ter children' includes anv child ~no is unde~ 21 ye3rs of age and any chi la wno is 21 years of aqe or older 3nd ~ho is a student within the ~eaninq of section 151(e)(4 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (26 u.s.c. 151 (e)(4 and receives_nis or her orim3ry suooort from t~e insurad person or insured oerson•s soouse. The term ~cniJdren• includes natural children. stepcnildren• adoptej children. foster children. anj any otner children under tne custody and care of the insured oerson and (mt Dy stri~ing out the last sentence in subsection (9)(d Sec~ 4. Section l~ of Chaoter II of tne Fire and Code. sec. 35-1317 is 3mended Oy stril&amp;lt;ing out subsection" each place it occurs tnerein and inserting in 1 ieu tnereof section at each such p13ce. See. 5. Section 33 of cnaoter II of tne Fire and Casualty Act. aporove~ Oetooer 9. 19~0 (54 Stat. 1079; o.c. Code. sec. 35-1337) is amended as follows 3) Oy strik i ng I 6 out 3nd paymen~ of the fees for sucn licenses snall be or~r3ted accordinqly and (b) by 3ddinq the follo~ing new sentence at the end thereof There snall be no proration of any fees for such licenses Sec. 6. Section 41 of Chaoter II of tne Fire and Ca s ual t y Act. 3poro ved October q. lq4o (54 Stat. 1081; o.c. Code. sec. 35-1345) is amended to re3d as follows Annual fees to be paid throuqn the superintendent to the District of Columoia for 1 icenses issued under tnis chapt.er shal 1 be as follows a) For pol icy-writing agent or for firms. C3rtnershios. or corporation~ licensee as sucn. sso. witnou~ reqard to the number of companies repr~sente PROVIDED· That in the case of firms. partnerships. and corporations. and addit!~nal fee of SlO shall oe c~arqed for each cerson in excess of two wno is named in sucn license ~s reouired under section 32 of this Act (O.c. Code. sec. 35-1336 O) For solicitinq aqent. s10 for each company reoresentea oy such soliciting aqent. or for eacn company reoresented oy any pol icy-writrnq a9ent througn ~nich sucn sol icitinq aqent sol icrts: PROVIDED. That no ~fol icit i ng aqent shall oe reouired to pay for soliciting agents• 1 icenses a sum in excess of s20 for anv one licensing year 1rc Original 7 c) For salaried company employee autnorizea to sign colicies and to solicit insurance• sso. without regard to the nu~ber of comp3nies represented Oy sucn salaried company emoloyee d) For salaried company emoloyee authorized to solicit out not authorized to siqn policies 10 for eac h company reo~esented oy said emoloyee: PROVIDED. That the aqqr~qation of sucn fees snall not exceed szo·far any one 1 i cense year e) For nonresident or resident orokers. sso, except that tne fee snall oe SlO in case the applicant for a resident broker•s licens~ is sub ject also to the fee orescribed under·paraqraphs (a) or (c) hereof fl For licenses to procure lines in unauthorized comp3nies. 130 q) Under Che license issued to any oolicy-wricinq 3qent or S313ried co~p3ny employee. or in the name of any firm. oartnershio. or corporation as pro¥ided under section 32 of chis ~c O.c. Code. sec. 35-1336 and for ~nicn license 3 fee has been P3id in accordance ~icn par3graohs (a) or (c) heraof~ there may be added names of persons wno 3re emoloyed in or who acti¥ely function tnrouqh tne District office of the· pol ic:y rit.i nq agent sal_aried co~o3ny emo l oyee. or firm. p3rtnership. or c:oroorat i ~n. 3nd 8 •ho nave company authority to sign bu~ not to solicit colicies. For such persons therg shall be cnarged a fee of s2 per year for aach comoany whose policies such person is authorized to siqn n) Broker•s 1 icenses may oe issued in the names of individuals. fir~s. oartnershiOS• or corporations. In the case of firms, partners~ips. or corporations. the 3Uthority to solict sh~ll axtend only to the i~d(vidua1s wno are desiqnatad in the license and in the aoplication th~refor as h3vinq autnority to solicit. and there snall be charged for aach sucn indivi~ual in excess of two 3n additional fee of s10 i) Licensas to procure lines in unauthorized coMoanies shall be issued in the names of individuals only Sec~ 1. Section 1 of title II of tne Qi strict of Columoia Rev~nue Act of 1937, aporov~d August 17• 1937 (50 Stat. 675; o.c. Code. sec 7-1801 is amended to read as follows on and after the first day of September 1937. every do~estic. foreiqn. or a1 ien company organized as a stock u~ual. reciorocal, Lloyd's fraternal, or any other cvoe of insurance co~pany or association. oefore issuing contr3cts of insur3nce aqainst loss of l ifa or healtn. or Oy fire q marine. accident. casualty fidelity and sure-ty title quarantv~ or other hazard not contr3ry to puolic policy, shall obtain fro~ the suoerintendent an annual license or certificate of authority~ upon payment of a fee of SLOO per year or fr3ction tnereof to the District of Columbia and collected by the superintendent. Al 1 1 i censes for i nsur3nce co~panies who ~av 3pply for permission to do business in tne District of Columbia shall date from tne first of the ~onth in w~ich aoplic:ation is made. and exoi.re on the 30th d~v of Aoril followinq Sec. a. Se~tion 4 of title II of the Oistric:t of ColumOia Revenue Act of 1937. 3poroved August l 1937 (50 St3t. 075; o.c. Code~ sec. 47-1804 is 3mended to read 3s follows Each of sucn companies sh311 file an annual state~ent. in ~he for~ orescribed by the superi,tendent, oefore M3rcn l of e3ch ye3r. of its ooerations for the year ending Oece~ber 31 immediately preceding. Such statement shall oe verified ~Y oatn of the president and secretary or in their aosence ov t~o other principal officers. The fee for filing said statement shall oe S50 and pay~ent t~erefor sh311 oe collected ov t~e superintendent and nad~ payable to the District of Columbia 10 Sec. 9. The folding Company System Regu13tory Act• aporoved Auqust Z4• 1974 (88 Stat. 75Z; o.c. Code, s~c. 35- 1901) is amended as follows a) section Z(c) of such Act co.c. Code. sec. 35- 190l(c is amended oy addinq a comma immediately 3fter reoresentinq b) section 3(a) of such Act (O.c. Code. sec. 35- l902(e is amended by strikinq out sec. 35-1521 and insertinq in 1 ieu thereof "sec. 35-1321 c) section JO(a) of sucn Act (O.c. Code• sec. 35- 1909(a is 3mended (l) oy ,striking out sucn insurer of such director and inserting in lieu tnereof "such insurer or such direct~r and (2) by striking out "failure" and inser~inq in lieu tMere6f nature and (d) section 10(b) of such Act (Q.C. Code. sec. 35- 1909(0 is amended oy strtkinq out "section 4 oF any rule" and insertinq in lieu thereof secti~n 4 or any rule ll Sec. 10~ Tnis act shall take effect 3S provided for acts of the C~uncil of the District of Col~mbia in section b02 1 of tne District of Columoia Self-Government and ~overn~ent31 Reorqanization Act. Columbia J{l Distr i ct of Columoia APPROVED: December Zl, 1979 J r I I I Cllan~can. Cf me ~u S1':i~CT :Qf COt!ll=StA E':JillD CF mr:;rn {CClm'Jt:tACnm COC?r! NO: Bill 3-53 N ICN: To Adoot (1st Reading) 11-20-70 e IJelC m r In.-i 1 i-m_,0 1 s Ate H~a.r idY CA j•tC j f J IW:I c.at•c• I I t l ci I •t• l r f t nr"&amp;lt;"nN I I I I K \i.'f I I I SF.ACT ETm-i I I I r..rr~ I I I I M..il..SOM I I I I s 1.Ui ornc 1 t I I f l 1:1 I I I I M'.IJO~.E I I I I [TT c:rw I I I I i:rii. 1:mv I j I I lV I t I t I I I I 1'&amp;lt t!~C I I I I qm .l I I I I I I I I c 'O 1 ill""I&amp;amp l \.Ci:ON: To il.dovt d i:i cni i J._7c l!i VO!C 110 IJngpi-mg115 Aasac sw:i111a Ind CJ I •IC I I c I re I t l r f 6. l nrrnM t I I I .1 lm I I I I .k~ l r-r f"l 1 I I I T I I I I ·4 "il. C 11\f f l I I H!1' n Tr. I I t I 1' i Rv I I I f ~OORE I t I I l r:TI C 11'.T I I I I 'Cll:i'n"7 I I I I I q.i.v I I I I I I I I T \ 'QrTTC I I I I i ~nT .lR~ I I I I I I I I I 1111::111 l t r ACT!CN D votc:z ·ro c a ~u. c.u ro I if </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
