<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-59">
  <num type="law">3-59</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-04-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-59.pdf">D.C. Law 3-59</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 983</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-59 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-193, which was referred to the Committee on Human Resources. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 22, 1980, and February 5, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 26, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-155 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>Self- 198. d llUl and r th• Ace No red ct1ve 1 ,1 iu lt I J a V U D.C. LAW 3-59 DISTRICT OF a&amp;gt;LOMBIA CBILO-PIACING Atn'BORITY AC? al 1979 IN- THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 23, 1980 To authorize the Mayor to approve rules and regulations promulgated by the Ccmmittee on Regulations relating to private child-placing agencies. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRIT OF COLUMBIA. That this act may be cited as the •oistrict of Columbia Child- Placing Authority Act of 1979 Sec. 2. An Act to regulate the placing of children in family homes, and for other purposes, approved April 22, 1944 (58 Stat. 193; o.c. Code, Sec. 32-782 _il is amended as follows a) by striking the word "Commissioners" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Mayor" it its place; and (b) by amending section 3 (D.C. Code sec. 32-783) to read as follows a) The Mayor shall appoint a committee to formulate and adope rules and regulations, prescribing standards of place, care, and services to be required of child-placing agencies, pursuant to the intent and purposes of this Act. TheCommittee shall be composed of three(3) representatives of the Department of Human Resources, of who two (2) shall be fran the Social Rehabilitation Administration, one of who shall act as chairperson, and one from the Community Health and Hospitals Administration; two (2} representatives from each of the charitable organizations of the District of Columbia licensed to place children in family homes, a member of the legal profession, and a member of the medical profession. The terms of off ice of each member of the committee shall be three (3) years, staggered so that one-third of the appointments expire each year. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occuring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. Upon expiration of his trem of off ice a aember shall continue to serve until his successor is appointed and has qualified b) Rules and regulations promulgated by the committee shall be l) issued according to the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-1501 _il } 2) reviewed by th committee annually and amended when deemed necessary; and 3) subject to the approval of the Mayor c) Section 13 (D.C. Code, sec. 32-791) is repealed. Sec. 3. This act shall take effect after a thirty (30) day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602 (c 1) of the Dis tr ict of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. l-147(c l}}. 227 !2!W! Pur11.1ant to Seot1on ~12 or the Otatrt=t or ~01 wn111a S11r- Jovernmer.t and JOVe~nm• nt al Reo~i•n!.zat!.on ~ct P 93-198 th• Act the Counc1l or the 011tr1ct ot Columc!.a adopted SU.l No. 3-l93, on t11"1t and aecond readincs, J1nuar1 22, 1980 and Pebr1.1&amp;amp;rJ 5, l980 re1pect1ve17. Pollowtnc the •1cnature or the ~a1or on Peoruar1 26, l980 th11 legislation was ass!.if!ed Act No. 3- 155, publUhed i n the amp ch T, 1980, ed!t!.on ot the O.C Reciater Vol. 27 ll&amp;amp;C• 983 and trar~m1tted to Congl'ess on amp Ch 3, 1980 tor a 30- day view, tn accordance w!th Sectlor: 602 c l) ot the Act. Tiie Council or the Otstrict or Columb ia h•l'eby gives notice that the 30-day Cong!'esstor:al Review Period has exp1!'ed, and, tneretore, cites this enactment as D.C aw 3-59 ettective Aprtl 23, 1980. 228 i</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
