<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-60">
  <num type="law">3-60</num>
  <heading type="short">Property Tax Relief Application Deadline Extension Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-04-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-60.pdf">D.C. Law 3-60</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 987</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-60, the “Property Tax Relief Application Deadline Extension Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-210, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on January 22, 1980 and February 5, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 26, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-156 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-60 "Property Tax Relief Application Deadline Extension Act of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reor-ganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-210, on first and second r-eadings, January 22, 1980 and Febr-uary 5, 1980 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on February 26, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-156, published in the March 7, 1980, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 987) and transmitted to Congress on March 3, 1980 for- a 30- day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-60 effective April 23, 1980. ARRINGTON IXON Chairman o the Council Jates Counted During the 30-day Cong~essional Review ?eriod: April 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 17, 18, 19, 20 21, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 3l 1, 2, 3, 15, 16, 17, 18, 21, 22 AN ACT D.C. ACT 3 1 5 6 IN T~E CJUNCIL OF THE OIST~ICT OF :OLUM8IA To ext.an:l tna aeadl ine for fil inq tn: 3001 ic3t.ion for tne no~estead exemot.ion 3nd :13ss Jne Property t3x r3t.a for Tax Ye3r 1~80. ana for ot er ourposas. 4 ae IT ENAC7E0 3V THE CJU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF COLU~BIA. Thdt tnis act nav oe cit.ea as tne "Prooerty Tax ~elief Aopli:ation Deadline Extension let of l 9 79 Sec. 2. Section 3(c 2) of tne Rasiaenti 3J D. C. Cede, e&amp;gt;rooen:y T3x Relief Act. of 1977. eff:c::i ve sec. 47-659.l (c 2 Feoruary 28. 1978 (O.C. Law 2-45; J Code. s~c. 47 -659. LlcJ(2)l as 3menaea oy t~e Raa t ~rooarty Tax Cl3ssifi:ations Act for Tax Ye3r lqao. effec'tive "lo11enoer 20. lq?q (Q .C la 3-37: 26 DC~ 2515 is 3menaea to reaa as follows 2 In or aer to oot3i r1 ne rieauci io n oroviae~ for un1er tnis s~Dse:cion. o ners Jf e li qi ·ole re-31 orooer~v snc.11 1 2 comolat~ 3n~ file wit1 tha Jistri:t of Co1umoia Oeo~rt~ent of Fina~c; ana Rev;nue (nerein~fter. referre~ to as t~e ~oeoart~ent on or oefor; June l pre:edinq tne tax year, a~ apol ication forn aevisea Oy the Oao3rtment 8) For the tax year beqinninq July 1. lq79. and endinq June 30, 1~8J, tie 3opl icstion form required oy se~tion 3{c){2)(A) sh-311 oe comolet~a and fi lad witn the Oeoartment o~ or c:fore ~ov.e~oer 30, l97q. Prior to Novemoer 30. l979. tne Oep3rtment: sn3l l :nail sue 3001ic:3tion to all resiJenti3l real orooertv owners for wnose resicentidl raal orooerty no such 3uo l i:ation w-iS received ov tne Oaoartment as of Jul y l• Fn If suc:i a ool i c3tion is f ilec wit.n tne Oepartmanc in oerson. t~e real prooeri:v o..oner so f i linq sn311 oe g iv en a racei it for t.r\e aopl i at i on If sucn aooli::ation is nailac t::i tha )e oart ~ent• tne re3l Jr::io~rty o ner so F il i nq: 3 PROVIDEO, f n3t tne rea l orooerty ow~er so filinQ ancloses a stanpea sal f-3darassed enval~pe ~itn his 3opl ic:tiJn Cl In tne case of raal orJp:rtv o n~rs wno take ~avant3qe of tne extenoaJ f i l inq period or~viaea for in tnis saction for tne tax year oeqinninq July l· 1979 nd enainq June 30, 1980. tne 3oproor i ate ad justments to real prooertv tax li3oilities shall t&amp;gt;e reflecte:l in tne secona-nalf t3x Oills wnich are due and 03y3ble on ~arcn 31, 1930. No 3d j ustment snal l oe ~ade co first-nalf t3x oills wni:n are alrea1y issued ~n:l ~nic n ere aue 3nd oavaole Oy Seot~moer 17. 1979 Sec. 3. Tnis act snal I taKe ef f :ct 3fter 3 thirty (30J ~ay oerioa of Congr~ssio~a l reviaw fo11Jwin~ 3porov3 l Oy the ~ayor (or in tne event of veto cy t~e Mayor. action ov the :oJnci l of t he t Ois~rict of :olumoia to overrije tne vato) a s or~vidaa in section o02(c)(l) of tne District of :olumoia Sel f-~owern~ent ana Govar~mantal ~e~r~anization Act. aoorovea Oecamoer 24• L973 (97 St-3t. 9l3; o.c. Co~e. sec. l-l4-7(c)(l \e l 1 E council o f t e Jistrict o~olumoia a yo r Jistrict of :olumo· APPROVED: February 26, 1980 \ } I tnl!liaCill OF T 5£ IH ST~~C'T Of C~lm~aa a ogo 'tti 71 lt Oll~:l.kC!la l CCCXZ O: Bill 3-210 Wilson c c.a I r r I f ca C CA f C I r f i ~4 CD C t I 11ar t t nrrn~ I I I I KA fE I I I I !SEACKLE O:J I I I TJ"T I I I I M lt;\SON I I I I •sPAUlDT Tr, I t I I ·MARV I I I I ~OORE: I I I I Tr &amp;lt rw I I I I 11:1' i l)TIY I j j I 'QiV I t I I j I I I I r~l 1 I I I 'Q('lT i R~ I I I I I I I I a C::ON: To Adout (2-5-80) Final E,e-'1 di pc a Ota 'IO'tZ 1,rr a Siii uia.m Al_l_P_r_e_s_e_n_t c t J f' t C»9C• I Cr t t I I I t J I nrrn111 I I I I l 'n I I I I ii A r lt;T r'(i 1 I I I t I I I I ~VA &amp;lt 11\T I I I t -le rrr T'\ T'Ir. I t I I I r"'T .l Q'!I I I I I ~OORE I I I I 1b lt 1'\• I I I I IA 'QT'\V I I I I I ~AV I I I I ii I I I I l)tM I I t I l)f"T!l)I I I I I ii I I I I I 11ia~1111 'I i s I N iJ 'IOICZ'I0-0 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
