<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-67">
  <num type="law">3-67</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-05-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-67.pdf">D.C. Law 3-67</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 1266</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-67 was introduced in the Council and assigned Bill No. 3-145. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on February 5, 1980, and February 19, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on March 17, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-166 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>17 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 3-67 "District of Columbia Bus Shelter Act of 1979" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 3-145, on first, amended first and second readings, January 22, 1980, February 5, 1980 and February 19, 1980, respectively. Following the signature of th Mayor on March 17, 1980, this legislatior. was assigned Act No 3-166, published in the March 28, 1980, ed i tion of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 1266) and tramitted to Congress on March 20, 1980 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 3-67 effective May 10, 1980. Dates Counted During the March 20, 21, 24, April 1, 2, 3, 15, 29, 30 May 1, 2, 5, 6 I&amp;gt;J~ 30-day 25, 26, 16, 17, 7, 8' 9 ARRINGTON DIXON Chairman of the Council Congressional Review Period: 27, 28, 31 18, 21 J 2 2' 23, 24 J 25, 28, I \ E.r:r·c D.C. LAW 3 6 7 envr: CATE_ MAY l 0 1980 A/14 !\CT D.C. ACT 3 1 6 6 IN THE COUNCI L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBI~ MAR 1 8 1980 To authorize the M3yor of the Distri:t of Columbi3 to enter into a francnise aqreement for t,e inst3llation 3nj Tiaintenance of bus shelters. and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF COLUMBIA, That tnis act Tiay be cited as th e "District of Colum~i3 3us If Shelter ~ct of 1979 C'ODIFICATION D.C.M.R. Sec. 2 f. i n Qi 119 L Q!l fl [Q o s g. Note, D.C. Ccx:1e a) The Council of the District of Columbia finds t:iat: sec. 1-231 (1) there is a s hortaqe of bus shelters in t ne District of ColuITTbia 2) there are over three tnousancl five hunared (3.500) bus stops in the District of Columoia 3) the District of Columbia Oeparcment of Transportation estimates that it would be appropriat e to olace ous shelters at at least one t,OJsand five hundred (1,500) of the three thousand five hundred (3,500) bus Stoos •ith ajv ertise~ents on seven hunclrea fifty (750) of the ous shelters; 2 the Washinqton MatroJol itan ~raa Transit Authority currently proposes to inst3l1 only three hun3red sixty six (366) ous shelters in the )istrict of Columbia 5) additional bus shelters #ill enhance tne safety and convenience of bus tr3nsportation throuqhout the District of :olumbia 6) it currently costs 3pproximately two thOjSand eiqht nundred dollars (s2.BOO) to purc,ase and install a bus shelter in t~e District of Columoia. The Jnited St3tes DeoartTient of Tr3nsportation has bee, oaying eig~ty ~er cent (80 of this amount. while the washinqton Metropolit3n ~re3 Tr3nsit 4uthority is rasoonsible for t"enty per cent (20 7) the 3istrict of Columoia government does not nave the funds to purchase and install the numoer of bus shelters which are necessary to Tieet tne needs of tne ou s ridinq public in the District of Columoia; ana (8) the awardinq of a franchise agreement, qrantinq tne riqnt to erect anj Tiaintain bus snelters containinq advertise~ent disolay panels along ouol ic streats. can provide the needed ous shelters at no cost to the District of Columbia and will further 3fford the District of Columbia additional re~e~u2s b) The purooses of this act ar; to: 3 (1) orovid2 the District of Columbia with ous shelters 3lonq its bus transoortation routes 2) inst3ll and maintain bus shelters in tne District of :olumbia throuqh tne a ardinq of a francnise aqreement 3} oermit advertisement to oe displayed on soTie of tne bus snelters; 3nd (4) qenerate revenues for tha District of :olumbia C) Notninq in this act snall ba construed as conprisinq the francnise aqreenent. Sec. 3. Th!Ll=ranchi s§t_~re~m a) Tne M3yor is directed ithin one (l) year of tne effective date of this act and b3sed u~on 3n evaluation of th e orop~sals received following 3n open request for oropos3ls. to enter into 3 francnise 3~reenent for the installation and m3intenance of ous shelters on oublic s~ace of the District of Columbia b) Tne Mayor shall permit t h e franchisee to plac e 3dvertisements on no more than ninety ~er cent (90 of the ous shelters installed pursuant to t,e francnise aqree Tient c) The franchise aqreement shall. for its term. be tne exclusive aqreement in tne District of Columoi3 for priv3t e l 4 installation and maintenance of bus shalters in ouolic sp3ces wnich dis~lay commercial ad~ertisements d) The franchise agree~ent snall be for a oeriod of ten (13) years. One (l) year prior to tne termination of the franchise aqreament each party snall notify the otner. in writinq, as to ~hether or not he ~ants to renegotiate the franchise aqreement for an additional ~eriod of tine bsent satisfactory reneqotiation for a rene~al period. the ~ayor is directed. based uoon an evaluation of the prooosals received followi~q an open request f3r proposals. to entar into a n e w francnise agreement for tne installation anj maintenance of bus shelters on ouolic space of the District of Columoia. The terms of the new franchise agreenent s~all not oe i~consistent ~ith the provisions of this act e) Undar the ter~s of the franchise agreement the franchisee s~atl be responsible for l) all of the costs and expenses for tne ous shelter desi~n aoproved oy the Mayor 2) the construction. Tiaintenance, and ligntinq of the ous shelters and repair of all structures including sidewalks. curt&amp;gt;s. streets or utilities which shall in any way be disturbed by the installation of the ous shelters 3) the costs associated with movinq bus shelters ~aintained by the ~ashinqton Metrooolitan 4rea Transit 5 ~uth~rity~ wnich are locatea on sites ~hicn have been 3poroved for bus snelters with advertisement disol3yed on them; 3nd (4) the costs associated witn changing. Nithin three (3 ontns. the location of 3ny ous shelters wnich are no l~nqer needed where oriqinally placed due to changes in ous routes or otner factors f) The franchise aqreement shall establish l) the ~inimum number of ous shelters. ooth witn and ~ith~ut advertisement. which are t~ oe installed in the District of :olumbia pursuant to tne fr3ncnise agree~ent 2) the specific locatio, of the first one hunjreo (100 f the bus shelters referred t~ in paragr3ph (1) and apor~ximate locations for the second one hunored (100) bus sn2lters 3) the order for installinq the first tNO hun~red (200) ous shelters 4) that subsequent to signing tne francnise aqreement the Mayor and the franchisee shall enter into 3n aqreement specifying tne locations and the order for installinq the remaining bus snelters to oe installed ~r Tioved oursuant to the franchise agreement. This agreeTient TI3y be aTiended as necess3ry to incluje additional ous shelter locations; 6 (5) the desiqn of the bus shelters; and (6) standards whicn the franchisee is to follow for the ~ini~um ~aintenance 3nd replacement of the bus shelters inst3lled pursuant to the fr3nchise aqree~ent q) The Mayor shall include in the franchise agreement those orovisions which are so specified in this 3Ct and 3ny otner orovisions wnich the Mayor deeTis 3ppropriate to carry out the ourpJses of this act h) Uoon the expiration of the franchise agreement. or upon tne expir3tion of the renewal terTI provided for herein. or if the franchise is terminated according to tne orovisions of section 8 whichever shall occur first. tne bus shelters installed pursuant to tne franchise agreeTient snall oecome tne prooerty of the District of Columbia without cost to tne District of Columoia. Sec. 4 b.~ati.QQ_of hell.er 3) Prior to the issuance _of a Request for Prooo sals for the franchise agreement• a,d oased on consultation witn the Council Qf the District of Columoia, the Mayor shall estat&amp;gt;l i sn 1) locations for the installation of ninety 0) ous shelters witn advertisements. te1 (10) b~s snelters ~ithout 3dvertisements. 3nd for the Dus shelters owned by the Washinqt~n Metro~olitan Area Tra1sit Autnority wnich 7 TIUSt be noved to perTiit the franchisee to install the ninety (90) new bus shelters •ith advertiseTients; and (2) the sequence in ~hicn the bus shelters are to oe install ed. The selection of locations and tne sequence for installation of bus shelters shall take into acco~nt, first, the various needs of the different areas of the District of Columbia for bus shelters, and second, the advertising ~arket potential in these areas b) In estaolisninq the locations for tne bus Shelters the ~ayor shall consult ~ith tne District of Columoia Deoartnent of Transportation, the Puol ic Space Committee. the Commission of Fine Arts, tne Pen~sylvania Avenue Develooment Corporation, and tne affected ~dvisory ~eiqhborhood Com~issions, and any otner groups which tne ~ayor oelieves aopropriate c) The Mayor shall consult witn the Commission of F ine Arts on the ~esiqn and location of all bus snelters located •ithin tne monuments area as defined in section l of A ct To requlate, the height, exterior design. and construction of private and semi-ouolic buildinqs in certain areas of tne ~ational Capital, aporoved May lb, 1930 (46 Stat. 36&amp;amp o.c. Cooe. sec. 5-410 Sec. s. Ad~r!_ising 8 (a) Tne franchisee is authorized to sell commerci31 advertisement space on no more tn3n tw 2) sides of a sinqle end of the ous shelters wnich have Deen designated oy the Mavor to contain advertise~ent. The end of the ous shelter •ith advertisement shall be opposite the end nearest the aporoachinq buses. Ten per cent (10 of the total av3ilanle 3dvertisement space shall be m3de av3ilable for ouolic service announcements and 3dvertisenents regarding =onmunity. art ultural. educatio~al and similar events. This snall include public service notices #hicn the District of Columoia qovernment may want to post. The amount of such ouolic servi=e a~nouncements and advertiseTients sh311 oe jetermined by the total nunber of no~rs the advertisement is displayed in a calendar year b) The Mayor shall estaDlisn orocedures for the review of oroposed advertisements c) The ~ayor shall approve or dis3pprove any proposed advertisement suomitted within ten (10) working days of its receipt. settinq forth in writinq the reason or reasons for any disaoproval. Any oroposed advertisement not disaporovea by tne M3yor witnin ten (10) worKing d3ys of its recei~t shall ~e deeTied to have oeen aoporoved d) The franchisee shall remove 3ny advertisement ~hich the Mayor determines to be deceptive, Tiisleading, q untrutnful. obscen2 or in violation of the District of Columbia Consumer Protection Procedures Act, effective July 22. 1976 (D L3w 1-76; o.c. Code. title za, 3pOendiX ithin fifteen (15) days from receipt of a request from the '4ayor e) No Tiore tnan fifty per cent (50 of the 3dvertisements posted sh311 relate t3 tobacco or alcoholic oroducts. Tnis amount sh311 be determined by the total number of hours the 3dvertisement is displ3yed in 3 calendar (f) At least ten per cent (lOt) of the ous shelters to oe installed by the franchisee snail n3t h3ve 3dvertisements gt;n tnen q) No ous shelters witn advertisements sha11 be oermitted in public spaces wnich are inmediately adj3cent to residential districts of the City zo,ed R-1, R-2, R-3, or K oy tne Zoninq Commission a) The francnise a~reement snall est3blish the compens3tion wnich tne District of ColumOi3 government snall receive under the fr3nchise 3greement. The franchisee snall 03Y to the District of Columoia, o~ 3 Quarterly basis: 10 1 a fee of ten per cent (10 of its gross 3dvertisement receipts for the first five 5 ye3r per i o and 2 a fee of fifteen per cent (15 of its gross advertisement receipts for the sec:&amp;gt;nj five 5) ye3r period. Gross advertisement receipts sna11 be defi~ed as paynents received by the franchisee, its agents or designees. less co~mission paid to the advertise~ent brokerage age~cies involved, in connection with the disolay of advertising ~aterial on the ous shelters. Tne Mayor may require tne franchisee to TI3intain specific records and accounts wni=h the Mayor shall nave the riqnt to inspect to ascertain tne correctness of aTiounts paid to the District of Columoi b) Notwithstandinq the aoove provisions. the fr3nchisee will qu3rantee to the District of Colum~i3 ~overnTient a minimum payment of three nundreo dollars 300) oer ye3r per bus snelter for tne first five (5) years of tne franchise aqreement and four hunored fifty dollars (S450) oer year per bus snelter for the sec:&amp;gt;nj five (5) years of the fr3n=hise aqreement. The ~ayor nay estaolish the aporopri3te TiiniTiun oayment levels t:&amp;gt; oe inclujea in a,y franchise effective after the ten (lJ) ye3r ~eriad c) As furtner security for perform3nce oy the franchisee of its ~bliqations. t~e franchisee sh3ll aeoosit 11 into an escrow a:count• every three (3} montns, oeqinninq si 6) Tiont~s after the effective date of tne fr3ncnise. a SUTI eqJal to one tenth of one ~er ce1t {•1 of its gross revenues until S3ij fund reaches a tot31 of one hundrej thous3~d do113rs 100.000 This fJnd shall oe maintained 3t sue~ deoositories designated oy tne Mayor pursu3nt to tne Distri:t of Columbi3 Depository Act of 1977, effective Qctooer 269 1977 (D.C. L3w 2-32; o.c ode, sec. 47-271 et anJ sh3ll oe3r interest to tne franc~isee. The funa sh311 oe usej to reiTtburse the District of Colum~ia for any financi31 loss incurrej by reaso~ of a default nv the fr3nchisee. or for the cost of movinq ous shelters if the franchisee does not TIOve tnem ~hen reqJired to do so. Uoon the exoiration of the term or the re1e~ea term, the unob1 i~ 3ted su~ on deposit snall be returned to the fr3nchisee Se 7. Insurancg_~g_Bond a) Witnin thirty (30) days of the effective date of the franchise 3qreement. tne franc1isee sh311 file witn th e Distri:t of :olumbia and shall maint3in throughout tne l ifa ~f tne franc~ise agreeTient• li3bility insurance policies and perforTiance ~onds acceotable to the ~ayor in tne minimum 3m~unts as follo~s: 12 (1) for ~odily injury. including death (A) t#O hundrej fifty thousand doll3rs (S250.0JO) for any one Jerson 3nd (B) one nillion ioll3rs (Sl.000.000) for any o:ie 3ccident; { 2 for property damage. o,e hundred thousand doll3rs 10~,000) per accident; and (3) for performance of mai,tenance and repairs. and ot,er or)visions of the franchise aqreament• two hunjr-ed fifty dollars (S250) per bus snelter. up to a maxiTiun of one nundred thousand dollars (Sl00.000) for all ous shelters b) Tne francnisee shall 3ssu11e any legal responsioility for and shall hold the District of :olumoia and/or tne washinqton ~etropolitan Area Tr3nsit Authority narmless fron. any liaoility tnat arises because of injury to persons or oroperty. includinq side~alks. curDs. streets anj structures by reason of the construction. operation. or naintenance of the bus shelters installed or moved pursuant to the francnise aqreernent. Sec. 8. Te[ i n i oQ_of _fU se li~~Q a) Tne Mayor shall notify the franchisee in writinq of any violations of tne franchise agreement and estaol isn a coTipliance schedule for correcti~q t~e ~io1ations. In tne event that tne c~mplia~ce schedule is not Tiet, the M3yor m3y termin3te tha fr3nchise aqreement after sixty (60) days i!lal 1 13 ~ritten noti:e to the franchisee of his intent to termin3te the franchise 3qreement. settinq forth tne re3sons for t,e termin3tion b) In the ev~nt of b3nkruptcy jf the francnisee the ~ayor sh311 termin3te the fr3nchise 3qreement. providing tn~ franchisee witn Nritten notice of his 3ction c) In addition to default on tie franchise agreenent ~r b3n~ruptcy Dy tne franchisee. tne M3yor m3y incluje in the franchise aqreement. for t~e best interest of the ~istri:t of :olumbia. 3ny other onditions and terTIS w~i:h shall constitute the basis for cancell~tion a) In 3w3rjinq the francnise a~reement. the ~ayor shall ~ive priority to proposals s~bTiitted by entities w,ich orJvide #ritten evidence tn3t thay meet the fo11owin~ criteria 1) that no less than fifty ~er cent (50 of th e equity interest holders of the entity nave resided in the ~istrict of Co1umbia for at least three (3) years 2) t~at 3t least fifty per cent (50 of t,e votinq snares or equity interest of the entity is ~eld by indi~iju3ls NhO 3re members of 3 minority qroup or orq3nization ooerated for the ourpose of aiding such persons as defined in the ~inority Contr3cti,q Act of 1976. l 't effectiv2 ~arcn 29. 1977 (D.c. Law 1-95; o.c. Code. sec. l- 852 et and (3) that the entity is cap3ble of satisfying tne ~eneral stanj3rds for respons i~le prJspective contractors as set fort~ in the Federal ProcureTient Ragulations (41 C.F.R. l-1.12 gt;3-l b) The prooosals sub~itted pursuant to an open reqJest for proposals shall oe e~aluated by the ~ayor on a scale of one hundred (100 oints. An additional tan (10) points shall ~e qiven prooosals which meet the criteria in oaraqrap 1) above and an additional ten (10) points shall oe qiven prooosals wnich meet the criteria in oaraqrap 2) The ~rovisions of section 2 of A, Act To r egu late the e r ection na~qinq. placing. oaintinq. jisplay. a~d nainte,ance of oJtjoor siqns and other forTis of exterior ad~ertisinq #ithin the District of Columbia. approved ~arcn 3. 1931 (46 Stat. 1486; D.c. Code• sac. 1-232) and Title 5A- l• Article 14 of tne Building Code of the District of :olumbia. oertaininq to outdoor signs in tne District of :olumbia. shall not oertai~ to tne ajvertisenent resulti,g 15 The ~ayor is a~tnorized to pronulq3te regulations to carrv out th2 Purposes of this act. If a provision of this act or its 3pD1ic3tion to a ~3rtic~l3r parson or circumst3nce is held invalij. sucn invalidity d~es not ~ffect oth2r provisions or app li :ations. This act snall become effective oursua,t to the orovisions of Se:tion 602 (c)(l) of th2 District of Co 1umbi3 Self-Government ~nj Government3l Reorqnization Act. or istrict of Columbia APPROVED: March 17, 1980 District of Columbia 1 l i i I COUNClll OF TIB!E DI STlillCT OF COU!l=St:l E?M m: ClfiACIL a:t1Jm:taM:nm occxrr NO: Bill 3-145 AC'ttON: To Adopt (1- 22-80) First Reading j$ VOIC% VOT By Maj prj ty Abuat: Rav, Wi l son and Spauldina D ROU CAll I/On cawac:n C c.a C:~VJlll,C.lt amp;.llteCll r C:~\ilf'ICI&amp;amp it nn:nN I KA IS F_i\ C1&amp;lt;L ET m: w"i~R MASON SPAITT :nrN&amp;lt f"T 4 lH MOORE wTT &amp;lt N lH~T'IV' R .AV TA tHTTC R T A'Rfl c ·111•ia ° l 1 1 riM AC"t'!ON: Ta Adopt J 5 80 Amended P jrst Reading /12 l/OICtvon u_n_a_n~i_m_o_u_s ­ .\l gt;aem All Present 0 ROLL C.uI. VO'!t « t"C 1 a clilf nrvrm ~AN"F I SH A rTCT FT('n. fu lJ '\( A C l?&amp;lt;J I C P A TTi n n.rr: r.T ARl('l MOORE rJTT c::nM ~Al:mV 'RAY I I 1'A'IHTTC RnT A 'Rfl" I 1 1ri. i r ° ACTION: To Adop t 19-80) Fiw1J Readjnli VOIC! I/OT Unanimous Aesact: Moore w llAT' f J a I I I I I I</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1151"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1152"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1153"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1154"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1155"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1156"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1157"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1158"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1159"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1160"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§9-1161"/>
  </section>
</document>
