<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-70">
  <num type="law">3-70</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-06-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-70.pdf">D.C. Law 3-70</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 1776</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-70 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-197, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 18, 1980 and April 1, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 25, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-176 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>D.C. LAW 3-70 DISTRICT OP COLUMBIA FUND ACCOUNTI11G ACT OF 1980 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JUNE 14 1980 To establish the fund accounting framework and financial policy for the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACI'ED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act be cited as the "District of Columbia Fund Accounting Act of 1980 Sec. 2. The Council of the District of Columbia finds that a) the diversity of governmental functions, activities, and programs requires that they be accounted for in several different funds and that the funds represent separate accounting enti ties b) the number of funds should be kept to the minimum necessary for sound financial administration c) the financial information and reporting needs can vary depending on the specif ic requirements of agency management, the Mayor, the Counc il granters, and the public d) change is increas i ngly a major factor in governmental accounting and reporting and the District must be capable of re sponding t o these changes e) cont rol and accountability over District resources is a primary function of all public section 448 (2) of the Dist ict of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Code, sec. 47- 226(2) J has the authority and responsibility for monitoring syst ems of accounting fl the financial accounting of the Di strict and the systems supporting this accounting must provide for t imely, accura te, and full and complete financial disclosure g) the fund structure and the financial systems and related accounting policies, practices, and procedures must provide info rmat ion to demonstrate compliance wit h applicable laws and administrative regulations and enable the District to refX)rt i ts fi nancial activities in accordance with generally accepted acco unting principles h) section 4(a) of an Act to provide for an independent audit of the financial conditon of the government of the District of Columbia, approved September 4, 1976 (90 Stat. 1208; D.C. Code, sec. 47-120- 2(a requires that fo r the f isc al year beginning October l, 1979, that financial statements should be prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles i as an outgrowth of the study and activ iti es of the Temporary Commission on Financ ial Oversight of the District of Columbia, a proposed fund structure for t he District has been recommended that will provide a modern financial systems base for sound financial management of the District, and preparation of fin anci al statements in accordance with generally accepted account ing principles j) the said system requires certain changes in the current fund structure of the District of Columbia; and (k) the Council intends to adopt said fund structure ad policies in order to resfX)nd to change and meet the informtion 255 Law 3-70 DISTRICT OF COL UMB I A STATUTES AT L ARGE Law 3-70 needs of the various users of financial informtion t o assit the Mayor to design, implement and operate the financial systems and policies, procedures, practi ces and controls necessary for the sound financial managment and administration of the District in a manner consistent with generally accepted accounti ng pr i nciples. Sec. 3 a) the Col um bi a b) the Columbia; For purposes of th i s act: term •Mayor means the Mayor of the District of term •counci l means the Council of the District of (c) ther term •Fund• means a fiscal and accounting entity with a self-balancing set of accounts recording c ash and othe financial resources, together with all related liabilites and residual equities or balances, and changes therein, which are segregated for the purpose of carrying on specific activit i es or attained certain projectives in accordance wit h special regulations, restrictfons, or limitation d) the term •Fund Type• means grouping or classification of funds of similar character or purposes e) the term •Fund Category• means groupin gs or classifications of fund types of s i milar character of purpqses f) the term •Account Group• means a grouping of accounts as provided in section 4 (c g) the term •Fixed Asset• means capatil i zed, tangible, l ong lived assets which are of significant value. Ge ner al fixed assets are District fixed assets not recorded in a spef if ic fund; and (h) the term •Generally Accepted Acco unti ng Pr inci ples GAAP) menas uniform minimum standards of or guidelines to f inancial accounting and reporting wh i ch are pr omul gated by recogn i zed a ut horitat i ve accounting organizations or ent i tites, such as, but not l i mited to, the financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB) and to predecessor organizations, the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA the National Council on Government Accounting (NCGA the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Comptroller General of the United States. Sec. 4. Effect i ve October 1, 1979, for purposes of accounting and financial reporting the District of Col umb i a shall utilize a fund structure organized into the following Fund Categories Fund Types, and Account Groups a) Fund Categories All Funds of the District of Columbia shall be classified and maintained by th e Mayor into one (1) of the following three (3) categor i es 1) Governmental Funds These f unds shall be composed of accounts for the Acquisition, use and balance of the District's expendable financial resources and the related current l i abilities except those funds accounted for in Pr oprietary Funds. The Governmental Fund category shall include the following fund types A) General B) Capital Projects; and (C) Debt Service 2) Proprietary Funds These funds s hal l be composed of activities which are intended to be monitored in a manner s i milar to those found in the private sectorl The assets, Law 3-70 LAWS OF THE DIST RICT OF CO LUMBIA 1979 and 1980 Law J. 70 liabil i tes equities, revenues, expens e s, an d transfers shall be s epara tely accounted for in such fund and be maintained separately for the general fu nd of the District of COlLlll\bia in accordance with the l egal requirements appl ica ble to such f und or in accordance with generally accepted acco unting pr in ci ples applicable to s uch f unds. The following fund types sha ll be considered proprietary funds A) Enterprise Funds B) Munc i pal University Fund C) Internal Serv i ces Funds; and (0) Rosptial Fund 3) Fuduciary Funds These funds shall consist of assets held by the District of columbi in a trustee capacity or as an agent for individuals, private organizations, other governmental units or for similar types of purposes. This category shall include the following fund types A Trust Funds; and (B) Agency Funds b) Fund Types. The Mayor maintain nine (9) fun d types within the fund categories established in s e ction 4 (a as follows 1 The General Fund to account for all f i nancial reso urces except those required to be ac co unted for in anot he r fund 2 Capital Projects Fund to acco unt f or financ i a l resources used for the acqui sition or construct ion of ma jor capital fa cil iteis ot her tha n those financed by proprietary or f iduciary funds 3) Debt Service Funds to accout for the accumulation of resources for, and the payament of, interest and principal on genera l long-term debt 4) Enterprise Funds to account for oper ations that are financed and operated in a manner similar to private business enterprises; or where it has been determined that per i od i c determination of revenues e arned, expenses incurred, and/or net i ncome is appropriate for capital maintenance public poli cy manageme nt control, accountability, or other purposes 5) Internal Service Funds to account for the financi ng of goods or services provided by the f und t o other departments, agencies or funds of the District, or to other governmental units, on a cost-r eimbursement or fee for service basis 6) Muni ci pal University Fund to account for the f unc tions and activities of the University of the Di strict of ColLlll\bia and its constituent funds 7) Hospital Fund to account for the f unct ion and acti vities of the D.C. General Hospital 8) Trust Funds to account for assets held by the District in a trustee capacity or as an agent for individuals, private organizations, other govenement units, and/or other f unds or similar nature 9 Agency Funds to account for assets held by the District of a custodial capaci ty as an agent for individuals, private organizations, other government units and/ or funds of a s imil ar nature c) Account Groups The Mayor shall maintain two (2) account groups A) the General Fixed Asset Group of Accounts and (Bl the General Lon Term Debt Grou of Accounts, to establi sh account control an accou ntab1ity or the District's general fixed assets not accounted for in a specific fund and the 257 Law 3-70 DISTR ICT OF CO LU MB IA STATUTES AT LARGE Law 3·70 unmatured p rincipal of its general obligation long-term debt and a ny other non-current liabil it ies of the District not accounted for in a specif i c fund 1) The General Fixed Asset Group of Accounts shall be used to record the District's capitalized general fixed assets which are not recorded in proprietary or fiduciary funds. Fixed assets related to specified proprietary funds or fiduciary funds will be accounted for through those funds 2) The General Long Term Debt Group of Accounts shall be used to record the unmatured principal of general obligations long-term debt and any other non-current general long-term liabilites which are not recorded in another proprietary or fiduciary fund. Non-current liabilities or proprietary funds, and fiduciary funds will be accounted for through those funds. Sec. 5 a) Beginning October 1, 1979, the Distirct will account for an report on, unless specifically noted in financial transactions in accordance wi th general l y accepted accounting principles b) The systems, procedures and controls established by the Mayor shall permit the Ditrict to demonstrate and report on compliance iwht legal requirements and contractual agreements as well as generally accepted accounting principles. Sec. 6 a) The Mayor sha ll be responsible for the future classification of any funds and accounts within the appropr i ate f und types and fund categories as set f or t h i n t hi s act b) Classifi c ation by the Mayor sh all be consistent wit h generally accepted accounting principles c) The ~ayor shall furnish the Council notice of hi s or her c l assif i cation at the time of the submission of the annual budget for the District of Columbia goverrunent as provided in sect i on 442(a) of the District of Columbia Self-Governemnt and Governmental Reorganizat ion Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 798; D.C. Code, sec. 47-22l(a d) The Mayor, pursuant to sections 447, 448, and 449 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganiza i ton Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Code, secs. 47-225 47-227 shall be respons i ble for developing and implementing appropr i ate accounting pol icies and procedures to carry out the purposes of this act, i ncluding all steps necessary to establ ish the systems and internal procedures and controls necessary to assure prope r application of the policies and procedures and appropriate proceedings for monitoring such system e) The financial statement submitted by the Mayor to the Council pursuant to section 448(4) of the District of Columbia Self-Governemnt and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 802; D.C. Code, sec. 47-226(4 shall i dentify any c hanges i n accounting principals and policies followed by the Distirct, the reasons therefore, and the practical effect of the chances f) to the maximim extent possible, common terminology and classifications will be used in th.e budgeting, accounting and reporting process. 258 Law 3-70 LAWS OF THE DISTR ICT OF COLUMBIA 1979 and 1980 Law 3-70 Sec 7 a) Section 16(b of t he Dis tri ct of Col um bia Securities Act approved August 30, 1964 (7&amp;amp; Stat. 632; D.C. Code, sec. 2-24 15(b is repeal ed b Subsection (i 1 o f t he first section of an Act to grant additonal owners to t he Commissioners of t he Di str ict of Columbi a, and fo r ot her pu rposes, appr ove d Decem ber 20, 1944 (58 Stat. 819; D.C Code, sec. 1-244 (i 1) i s a le nde d by striking the second and t hir d sentences and inserting the following serntence Al l recei pts from the sale of such material shall be deposited i n the General Fund in l ie u thereof c) Section 4 of Article II of an Act entitled to Cr eate a Recreation Board fo r t he District of Columbia, to define its duties and for other purposes, approved April 29, 1942 (5 6 Stat. 263; D.C Code, sec. 8-211 is repea led d) Moneys ma i ntained in mi scel laneous t rust funds pursuant to section 4 of the District of Columbia Appropr iati on Act, 1945, approved June 28, 1944 (58 Stat. 531; D.C. Code, sec. 7-1238 s hall transfer hereafter be deposited in the General Fund e) The District of Columbia Boxing and Wrestling Commission Act, effective October 8, 1975 (D.C Law 1-20 D.C. Code, sec. 2-1231 n is ame nded as follows 1) Section 8 (a} (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1237(a is am ended to read as follows a All re ceipts of the Commiss ion shall be depos ited to the General Fund 2 section 8 (e D.C. Code, sec. 2-1237(e is amended by st ri king the phrase •and the f i nanc ial conditon of t he trust fund and (3) sectin 3(b D.C Code, sec. 2-1237(n i s repealed f) Ther e is t ransfe rr ed to the Motor Vehicle maintenance Fund an unexpended bal ance in the Ma i ntenace and Repair of Ve hicles Fund, established by secti on 18 of the Dis trict of Columbi a Appropriation Act, 1955, appr oved Ju l y 1 1954 (68 Stat 396: D.C Code, sec. 47-136 g) Ther e is tranferred t o the Depart~ent of General Serv i ce s Internal Service Fund, or successor f und establis hed by t he Mayor, any unexpended balances in t he working capital fund fo r print ing, duplicating and photographing established by the Distr i ct of Col umb ia Appropriation Act, 1956, approved July 5, 1955 (69 Stat. 263; D.C. Code sec. 47-13 7) and the educational surpl us property fund, established by an Act to establ ish an educat ional agency for surplus pr operty wit hin t he goernmetn of t he Dist rict of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved August 16 1950 (64 Sta t. 450; D. C. Code, sec. 31- 13 01 n h The Mayor is authori zed t o esta bl ish for accoun ting and fin an cial reporting purposes a Water and Sewer Enterpris e Fund in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles i) The enumeration contained in th is section s hall not be constured so as t o limit the Mayor's authority with respect to classification and establishment of appropr iate accounting procedures for other funds or accounts not specifically referenced j} Noth i ng contained in the Revenue Funds Ava i labi l i ty Acts of 1975, effective January 22, 1976 (D.C. Law l-42; D.C. Code, sec. 4·7-130) shall prevent the Mayo r from accounting for revenues and expenditues in accordance with generally accepted accounting pri ncipl es k) The District of Columbia Public Shcoo l Food Services Act, approved October 8, 1951 (65 Stat. 367; o.c. Code, sec 31- 1401 et is amended as follows 1 section 2(e) of title I (D.C. COcTe, sec. 31-1402(e) is amended by striking the phrase •which shall be deposited in the fund created by sect i on 4 of 258 Law 3-70 D ISTRICT OF COLUMB IA STATUTES AT LARGE Law 3-70 th i s Act 2) section 5 of Title I (D.C. Code, sec. 31-1404) i s amended to read as follows All revenues and receipts of any nature whatever derived form teh operation of food services or as othe_rwise provided by this Act shall, under regulations established by the Mayor, be paid to the o.c. Treasurer and deposited in the General Fund, and accounted for within the General Fund as a separate revenue source allocable to provide authorization for such school author ity as the Board of Education may approve. Any unexpected balance at the end of the year shall be reserved as a restricted fund balance and used to provide authorization to expend for subsequent years subject to the direction of the Board of Education 3) section 7 of title I (D.C. Code, sec. 31-1406) is repealed; and (4) sect ion 8 of title I (D.C. Code, sec. 31-1407) is amended by striking t he phrase "fund created by section 5 hereof" and inserting t he phrase "the General Fund as provided in section 5• in lieu thereof 1) Section 2 of the Rome Purchase Assistance Fund Act of 1978 effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-103; D.C. Code, sec. 45-1801) is amended by striking all that follows the numeral 1 000 ,000) and inserting the following and accounted for i n the General Fund as a separate revenue source allocable to provide financial assistance to the residents of the District of Columbia of lower incomes for the purposes of enabling them to purchase decent, safe, and sanitary homes in the District of Columbia. Any unexpended balance at the end of the year shall be r.eserved as a restricted fund balance and used to provide authorization to expend for subsequent years subject ot the direction of the Mayor in lieu t herof m) Section 1 (b 1) of The Act to provide fo r the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of the said Distirct, and for other purposes, ef f ective January 5, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-45: o.c. Code, sec. 5-313(b 1) is amended to read as follows b 1) There is established in the District of Co lumbia and accounted for within the General Fund as a separate reven ue source allocable to provide authorization for the purpose of paying the costs of correction of an y condition, and all expenses incident thereto, that the May or mayorder or cause pursuant to subsection (a Any une xpended balance at t he end of the year shall be reserved as a restricted fund balance and. used to provide authorization to expend for subsequent years sub)ect to the direction of he Mayor n) Section 1 of An Act To .fix the respons ibili tes of teh Disbursing Officer and of the Auditor of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved J uly 30, 1950 (65 Stat. 124: D.C. Code, sec. 47-112a relating to the examination and certification of records, is repealed o) An Act to establish a District of Columbia purposes approved June 4, 1948 (62 Stat. 339: D.C. Code, sec. 2-170 il is amended as follows l) by striking the phrase "Armory Board working Capital Fund• in section 6(i D.C. Code, sec. 2- 1706(i and i nsert ing the phrase •starplex Fund" in lieu thereof 2) by striking section 7 {D.C. Code, sec. 2-1707) in its enti rety 3) by striking the first three sentences of section 8 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1708) and inserting the follow ing sentences which read as follows There is established a Starplex Fund into which shall be deposited all receipts derived from the exercise by teh Armory Board of the powers granted by this Act and the District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1957, approved September 7, 1957 (7) Stat. 621: D.C. Code, sec. 2-1720 260 l aw 3-70 LAWS OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMB IA 1979 and 1980 law 3-70 il J The star pl ex fund shall be an entepr i se fund as defined in section 4 (b 4 of the District of Columbia Fund Accounting Act of 1980 and shall be used for all expenses incurred by the Armory Board in the exercise of the powers granted by this Act and the District ·of Columbia StaidUni Act of 1957 4) by striking the phrase •Armory Board working capital fund• each place it appears in the fourth and sixth sentences of section 8 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1708) and inserting the phrase •starplax fund" in lieu thereof 5) by strking the phrase •general revenues• inthe fourth sentence of section 8 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1708) and inserting th phrase •General Fund• in lieu thereof 6) by striking the last sentence of section 8 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1708 and (7) by adding immediately following section 8 (D.C. Code, sec. 1708) the fol l owing new section to read as follows sec. Ba. All assets held in the Armory Board working capaital fund, the canteen fund of the District of Columbia National Guard, and the Stadium operating fund shall be transferred to the Starplex fund established in section 8: PROVIDED, That the asssets in the canteen fund and any funds derived form the operation of the canteen fund and any funds derived form the operation of a canteen in the Armory for the use and benefit of the District of Columbia National Guard shall inure to t he benefit of the Di strict of Columbia National Guard p Section 6(a) of the District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1967, approved November 7, 1957 (71 Stat. 621; D.C. Code, sec. 2- 1724) is amended as follows 1) by striking the phrase •an operarting fund" in the first sentence and insertring the phrase "the Starplex Fund established by section 8 of An Act to establish a District of Columbia Armory Board, and for other purposes• in lieu thereof 2) by striking the third, fourth, fifth sentences thereof; and (3) by striking the phrase "operating fund• in the sixth sentence and inserting the phrase "Starplex fund" in lieu thereof. Sec. 8 a) Nothing in this act shall be construed as impinging upon or otherwise superseding the authority otherwise vested by law in independent agencies or instrumentalities of the District of Columbia b) Nothing in this act shall be construed to prohibit the Mayor fran establishing accoutns within funds, to the same extent that he or she was authorized prior to the passage of this act c) The Mayor shall promptly advise the Council of any changes in teh financial management system required pursuant to section 2 of an Act to provide for an independent audit of the financial condition of the government of the District of Columbia, approved September 4, 1976 (90 Stat. 1205; D.C. Code, sec. 47-101 note Sec. 9. The Mayor is authorized to establish such systems as may be required for the accounting and certification of financial obligations of the District of Columbia government and may, thr~u~h delegations and designtins of District government off1c1als and agencies (identified by name in the District of Columbia Register prior to such delegation or designatin provide for the decentralized audit and approval before payment of bills, invoices, payrolls, and other evidence of claims, demands, or charges against the District of Columbia government. Law 3·70 DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA STATUTES AT LARGE Law 3·70 Sec. 10. This act shall take effect after a thirty (30) day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayro, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto as· provided in_ section 602(c 1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganizaition Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813: D.C. Code, sec 1-147 (c 1 it•c 7QJ a liH l c:i amp s e US \;t l JO 7aa I. JC--a7 S'l t amp Q 9 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
