<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-71">
  <num type="law">3-71</num>
  <heading type="short">Rental Housing Locator Consumer Protection Act of 1979</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-06-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-71.pdf">D.C. Law 3-71</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 1891</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-71, the “Rental Housing Locator Consumer Protection Act of 1979,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-124, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 18, 1980 and April 1, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 1, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-179 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D C LAW 3- 71 "Rental Housing Locator Consumer Protection Act of 1979 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia Adopted Bill No. 3-124, on first and Second readings, March 18, 1980 and April 1, 1980 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 1, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No. 3-179, published in the May 9, 1980, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 27 page 1891) and transmitted to Congress on May 7, 1980 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 3-71, effective June 21, 1980 DIXON \ Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May 7,8,9,12,13,14,15,16,19,20,21,22,28,29 30 June 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,ll,12,13,16,17,18,19,20 D.C. LAW J~ 71 EF~~WVE JUN 2 11980 A 'l A( T D.C. ACT 3 1 7 9 I~ THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CJ LUMdlA MY 1 1980 To est3b1ish stand3rds and eliminate unf3ir Dusiness ~r3ctices Dy rental housinq locator firms. BE IT EN~CTED 3Y THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, Th3t this 3Ct may oe cited as the "Rental ~ousina Locator :onsume r Protection Act Jf 1~79 S~c. 2. Chaoter 38 of Title 28 of tne District of :olumbia Code is anended by 3ddinq tne follo~ino new section ~t the end thereof to read 3s follows Sec. 2 8-3819. Rental HouSi'lq Loca tors As use d in tnis sec tion th e term or t e r ms CODIFICATION D.C.Code, sec. 28- 3819 l Fee 1le an s an v fee c gt; m n i s s i on c ha r g e de ~osit. down oavment o r other valuaole consid e r ation inclJdin~ any fee or cna rq e for a cred it che ck or consultat i on {2 Re ntal housinq loca tor or 'loc ato r ne -1nS ~nv oe rson wno for a f2e i jent ifi e s or pur~o rts t o 2 identify or ~ho orovides or ouroJrts to provide 3nv ot1er information about anv rent31 unit av3il3Dle for rent, other th~n a r~ntal unit ONn2d or m3na ged Dy such 3 R ental housinq locator contract' neans a contract bet#e e n a r e nt31 housin~ locator and a notner Jerson tnat obliq3tes the locator for a fe e to i de,tify any nu~ber of rental units as avai 1aol e for rent or to o rovid e any otner information about them 4 Rental unit' means anv room. suit e ao3rt,ne nt or sinqle f an ily house rented or offered for r ent as a residenc e includinq any app~rten ant s e rvices• facilities. i mo rov em~ nts or land Cl) Within thirty (30) days of t he eff ect ive date of t n is section• e3ch rental hou s in g l oc a t o r tnat orovi de s listinqs for rental uni ts loc a t ea in th e 8 istri c t of :olumbia shall fil e Nith t he Di r e c to r of t ne Qffic e of :o~sumer Protection reqistration sta tenent on a forn aooroved Dy th e J irector. T ~e r eq is tration stat e me nt shall in clu d e the nu si1 ess aa ar ess of the rent a l h:Jusinq loc -3 tor aqency. tne n -3me gt;fall ONne r s is Ne ll as any information th e ~i r ec tor may r?.auire. The 3 Director snall r eq uire a r eq istr3tion f ee s ufficient to re cover the costs of a dm inisterinq thiS section 2) Each r ental nousinq loc a tor Sh :3 ll Keep a duol icate of tne reqistration St3tement posted iri 3 consoicuous olace in tne busines s office of th e rental nousinq locator l very rental housinq l gt;C3tor snall r evis e -jnd co r r ec t a 1 l i n farm 3 t i on to be Jr J v i de d p u r s u ant to 3 rent:31 nousinq locator contract or otherHise made -3V:3i l 301 e to 3ny custorner, ootenti al c usto1T1er or tne qeneral gt;Uol ic. every 24 hours fJr r ental units it advertises and every 48 nours for r enta l u n its it j Oes not advertise. or else remov e s uch units frorn its 1 ists 3nj jiscontinue the 3dvertisinq Jf suc n units 2) A r e ntal housinq l :K3t::ir sn:31l identify -35 a vail ao l for r ent or orovide otne r infor mJ tion about a r e~ t a l uni t only if the locator ~3S been q iv o. n oe rmission to do so by t ne o~ner/ ma n aqe r of th e un it. or t he rent a l unit n3S oeen adverti s ed• pos te n o r otne rwis e Juolicly off e r ed or ne l d o ut a s ava il ao l e for r e nt. Dy t ne o~n e r/ rna naq e r of th rental un i t 3) Re '1t a l housinq loc 3tor a-:ien ci e s Sh3 l I De r ea ui r ed t:l 11a ke avail3ble uoon r e au e st• r ec ~r~ s o f f z 4 unadvertised 3nd 3dvertisea l iStin~s proviae::1 to custJmers and ootenti3J customers to tne Office Jf Cons11mer Protection and th2 letr gt;ool itan Pol ice De J a r t ifle n t l) Contract.s netween the rent3l hous i nq l oc3t:&amp;gt;r aqency 3nd the customer shall De written. and a copy of the contract snal l be supplied to tile customer 2) The contract sn3ll clearly state tne dur a tion of tne locator service contract 3 l Every rental housing locator shall refund. upon request. 3ny fee to any custoner within thirty (3J) ct ays of said request if 3ny of tne rental ~ousinq inform3tion orovided to that custoifler o y tne locator fails to comolv ~ith tne r equirements of a:curacy as d e fin e d bv su osection (Cl or if the locator fails. upon de mand. to orovide th e correct street address or t e leohon e nunber of any rental nousinq unit it 3dvertises or oth e r~ise oes cr i oe s t o a custoTier: or if the locator fails to provi de a cust ome r ith r ental "lousinq listinqs as c a ll ed for i th e co ntr a ct ti 4) The c ontr :Kt sh a ll incl J d e i n a o ro 0nine 1 t o l 3c e anj in bOlj face tyo e th e f o llJwin q c l aus e s The first cl a use 5h3ll re ad as foll ows: 5 SAV E THIS D0CUMENT A N~ ANY ~E~TAL H~USI~G LISTI~G S P~OV IDE D TO YJU• WE ARE AN I ~FOR~AT I ON SERV I ~E O~LY E MAKE ~O ATTEMPT TJ SECURE YJU H OUSI~G CONC ER NIN5 AVAILABLE RE\JTAL HJUSI ~G u~rrs NJ G JA~A'HEE IS A :J E Tf-i AT YOU ri I LL FI NL E~T~ L PROPERTY By USI\JG nn s 5E{.V ICt VOu IAA V 3E E'lTITLEfJ TO A RE FUND Ii: A~Y 0 i: THE REN TAL HJUSI~G INFORMATION PR OVI DED TO YJU IS NO T :u~R~NT ACCURAT E JR OTHERW IS E NOT I~ COM PLil\NCE WI Tl-f TH c LAW; 3nd 3 Tne second c l 3use snail state tnat 311 inquiries should be made to th e J istr i ct of Columbia Offic e of Consumer Protection follo~e d nv t ne current 3ddress teleohone nu11ber 3nd nours of tn a t office I D.C.Code, title 28, appendix (al Section 5 of tne Distr ict of Co lum n i3 onsume r Protect iJn Proc e du r es Act, ef f e ctiv e Ju ly 22 La i 1-76 J de title Zf3 aooenj i &amp;gt;&amp;lt is :im~nded D Y s u~ stitut inq a s emi colon f o r t~e p e ri o d 3t tne en d of suo s ection IY and ny 3dd in q a ne~ s u os ect i on (Z t o re a 3 5 fo ll o s zl Vi:&amp;gt;l3tP 3ny p r ovision of t:-ie Re nt a l 1ous in ~1 Lo a tor :onsume r Pr o tecti on lC t J f 1 9 79 O. C o~e s e c 6 28-3819) or if a rental housinq locator. to re f us e or fail to ,onor any obli qation u1der a r e ntal nousinq loc3tor contr3ct b) \Jothinq in this act shall De construed to d i11inisn the authority of tne District of Col~ m oia under any existinq law to brinq or oursue any action the cause of which arose oefore t,e effective date of tnis act Se c 4. Tne Mayor is authorized to issue requlations to D.C. Code, title 28, e ffectuate t:ie provisions of tnis ac t append.ix Sec. 5 This act shall take eff ect after a thirty (30) jay oeriod of Co,qressional review followinq ao p roval o y tne ~ayor {or in tne event of veto bv the ~ayor, action Dy t ne :ouncil of tne District of Columoia to override th e ve to s orovid e d in section 602(c)(l) of tne District of Co l um n ia Self-Gov e rnment and Governmental Reorqanization Act, aporov e d December 24• 1973 (87 Stat s 13; a Cod e s ec. 1- l47(c)(l District of Columbia yor District of Columbia APPROVED: May 1, 1980 CCllDIC llll Of TIHIE DB STilma OIF cnun4tliU~ m::mm «lF m!RaM ACin«Iml oo cn:T NO: BHL 3-12 4 ACnON: To Adopt (3-18- 80) First Reading i votcz vom u~nJ&amp;amp;laJ;.jniolii..11m~o iouil.lis;i Shackleton D ROLI. CALI. VOTE Aft v coui.cs CJll•C Hd rtcu c.ec nrxrm KANE SHACKLETO~ l l.i'TN1'1 MASON SP&amp;lt;\ULDING ll"T APTl'i MOORE ~TT C:ilN U AlnW PAV T AP~TTC: PflT ARK l Ol l a &amp;amp;1&amp;amp;4 AC'T!ON: Tq Adopt (4-1-SQ) Final ReadiPB lJ vorct von u_n_a_n_i_m_o_u_s U C 4T Absent J~a~r.v i~s ia~n~d~WMi~n~t~e~r D ROLI. CALI. von 4• 0:0\1..C Cl C.Jll 41 C I t A 1' nTvnM I T \ 1'J"F 'C::H ArT&amp;lt;'T .i T'nl\ I w v VAC:nl\T i C P TTT TH 'l.T I rr APK"R MOORE rJTT c: n l\T I H Alm V lBV I I T AlHTT C: P nT AR V I icaE lote J i 81 ~r r oi cumc ACT!ON 0 VOIC von Absent D ROI.I. CAI.I. I/On::</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
