<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-95">
  <num type="law">3-95</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Financial Institutions Tax Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1980-09-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-95.pdf">D.C. Law 3-95</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 3509</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-95, the “District of Columbia Financial Institutions Tax Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-190, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 3, 1980 and June 17, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 9, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-217 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 3-95 "District of Columbia Finan cial I ns titutions Tax Act of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93 198 the Act the Council of the Distric t of Columbia adopted Bill No 3- 190 on first and second readings, June 3, 1980 and June 17, 1980, respe ctively Following the signature of the Mayor on July 9, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No 3- 217, published in the August 15, 1980, edition of the D. C. Register Vol 27 page 3509) and transmitted to Congress on July 15, 19 80 for a 30- day review, in ac cordance with Section 602 (c l) of the Act The Counci l of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that th e 30- day Congr es sional Review Period has expired, and, therefore cites this enactment as D. C. Law 3- 95 effective September 13, 1980 P~ ARRI NG TON IXON Chairman of th~ Council Dates Counted During the 30- day Congressional Review Period: July Augus t 21,22 23,24,25 28 29,30,31 1,4 ,5,6,18,19,2 0 ,21 22,25,26,27,28 4 l0.1 1 .12 D.C. LAW 3- 9 5 EF~~CT~VE SEP 1 3 1980 t.N ACT D.C. ACT 3 2 l 7 r T~ E c Ju~CIL o TH E 0rsr~r:r c oLuM e £A JUL 9 1980 To r ao~a l th JrJS5 ea rnin s t 3x 01 ri1anci l in 5titJtions a id r ~p lace it ~itr a p ~r5 o n a l Jr Jp~ rtv t 3x a1d a fra'lc1ise tJx h3s 2 d o n nP. t inc o ne 3n1 for gt;tn e r uur o gt;s s. Thi t t 1 is 1ct nay Je cited as th o istrict gt;f :o 1u "1b i ,J Fin~nci :il I'1Stituti rns fa ct Jf l :ttiJ Se lJl. Section gt;f Titl e I ot th e J i5tri c t ti n 3nCi 3 1 ins t it LJ ti o 'l i ft e r t'l e gt;r :1 c gt;r oo r3ti gt;n h2 r v 2 r i t lP De-:i rs; 31 &amp;lt;1 Enro11 ea o i g1na1 CODIFICATION D.C.Code, sec. 47-155lc 2 fb) A n2w subsection (Y) 1s a::lOea attn en d t n~ r eof to r 3 1 1s fJllo.;s y nedn s nv J31k or trust como3ny incorpJr ~t~a or r e~u ir ~d tJ oe i ncor oor3ted 3nd 1o in Jusiness Jnle r tha l 3 "s of tile Jnit2a St3tes, of whic ,1 th i stri:t of :olumbia r an y State su~stant.ial e x~ r isina f i d Jci a ry p:J we rs s i il a r to tnose onptr:&amp;gt;l 1 e~ r Jf tne (Jr r e ncy. and h is 5uL) j c t Jy l w t:J ~uJerv isi on 3na e x arn in~tiO'"l ~Y tne i ns tituti ons SJC'l te r m i nc lu j e {l l ny sa 11i nos n l 1 o 3 n 3 s s gt; c i a t i gt; n s a n d 2 a n y c J rn o a n y o f 1isc:&amp;gt;unts o r Jf e x e rci s in fi~u:i~r~ JO ers 3Uth Jritv Jf t'1e (Jrnotr o ll e r of the :u rr en :v• 3 Jftice or r 1nc11 in th2 Jistrict Se l 2. Sect i on l of Ti tl~ II of th 2 u -3 r l n t e t h f i 'J e l i t y o t :rn v i n 1 i v i 1 lH l o r :onp1n i es nic1 furnisn 3hstract5 Jf title o r hicn i nsu r e tit l es to re-31 e St3te 111 f wni c h ~3Y t3xes ~n t~eir qross ei rnin as oreniums or 1r~ss r e:eiots under existinq la ~s ot tne }i 5t ri :t l e l J3 Title III of th istri:t of sec 47-15573 {4 relatinq tJ ta fr ee 0 4) f3 f r e e int e r est Inte r es t uoori (a wli::iatiJns Jf a St ite Territ::J rY Jt t'le D.C.Code, sec. 47-1554 D.C.Code, sec. 47-1557a J n i t e S t a t e s o r =i n v o o l i t. i c a l s u J a i v i s i o the reof. o r the 1istrict of :o lu TIDia inn (o) instrunent=il iti es EXCE ~T. Th=it t ni s e xcl~siO:l Jn ited States o r =inv Clo litic a l suJdivisiOr"I th?.r?.of except tl e Jistrict at :o l umDi &amp;lt;h -rn :J (2) i n st run e nt l l it i es t'&amp;gt Su:&amp;gt;s e ctiJn 1)(2)(j)(i) Jt s ct i'Jn 3 J C interest dedJcti:&amp;gt;ns is =im e nc1e1 ly i, s rtir"I O tin an ci a l institJtioriu after t:ie w:Jr j "c:&amp;gt;roorati Jn c) SuDsecti :rn 5} of Sc&amp;gt;ctiJn 3 J C gt;d2 se 47-l5"i71(:1)(5l relatinq t gt; Ja .1 :Jents) i s 5 l 'l. 3 j 1 e o ts e gt; ts 1 s cert =i i '1 e :1 to De D.C.Code, sec. 47-1557b D.C.Code, sec. 47-1557b Q c Q u Q Q n tne C-iS gt;f a fin3nci1l instituc:.i:&amp;gt;n anv Jr2vio ,1s cH(1·JCti gt;ns ere ill gt;w~d. w, e ri satisfiej thJt 3 debt is rec gt;v e r3ble onlv in D3rt tne M3yor c1e1ucti o'l o deht hicn ~xisteJ Jri o r to J~nu3 rv a u 1 c; 2c t i Jn 3 l r of s e t i o 'l 3 I D C f i n -Jn i i 1 i ri s t i t u t i gt; n 5 3 f t 2 r t e w gt; r n c Jr oo r d t i :l n s S e lJ4 Se tion 2 of Title V of th J i:;t.ri t JPDf:)ved Jul v lo• 194-7 6 1 St.at• 34-1; J c. C:&amp;gt;a e 5 e c. 47-l5~4=i) is 3men:iert 35 t gt;llo"'s 3 ue&amp;gt;secti :rn 2 l l (O.C oJe• sec t.+7- l'5b4::l lJ r e lar.inq t corp gt;rJtlo,s) is a nend 2d JV l) a a in j "a'ld Fin=.inci3 l l'l5titutiJnS ft r tn~ rie ,1ciinJ C gt;roor3ti gt;ns 2) ins ert in r. r o r ,1s o r fi,a ricial institJtio:i" dft"'f t'1e wJr 1 S D.C.Code, sec. 47-1557b D.C.Code, sec. 47-1564a "Every cJrooratiJn and (3 1ns 2r t11q tne wJrJS "or fina1cial instit~tions" Jfter th2 ~ord b Su D sec t i gt; n e 2 o. C co ~1 e. 5 e c 4 7- l5 gt;4a( e 2 1s 3m2nc1ed to r~ a::l JS fJllows 0 (2) Affiliatej coro:&amp;gt;r1tio1s (inCJjainq 3ffili:3te::1 incoro o r cite tj fin,nci1l i nsti tuti rns I sn::il 1 fi l seJ3 r3t P. r ~t. ur1s c gt;nsol iaat e:J r etu rn s 1po r a v ed Jdl l6• l q 4-7 Jl Stat 3~5 C gt;d gt; e c 47-1.571) is a ne no ed as foll gt;w s I r--J s T I T J T I 0 s II DI Sectio1 2 O.C. Co1e. s ec 47-15711 r e1 3tin~ to inpasition ind rat e ot- t c:i l&amp;lt is th~ r ~of The t3x es irnJosed b Y t'1iS sect io1 sn i ll. D.C.Code, sec. 47-1571 D.C.Code, sec. 47-157la 7 Q 1 =ind;-\Cidl Insti t Jtio1s T'lx Act of l q;1Q e 3. Effec tiv e for t:3l(3Jl ve :1r5 s n 11 I i n c 1 cJ d e f i n a 1 c i a 1 i n s t i t ;j t i o 1 i rri n 1 e 1 v l i 1 s r t i n q t n e w r 1 s t' i n a n c i a l ent2n:e 2 t 1nse r 1 n~ the ior ds tin"-ln i-J l in st itJtion" bet e e n tne w gt;r js 0 co r pJ r 1t io n o r u n i n o r P gt; r J t e d b 1J s i n es s 11 i n t he I '3 s t p r o 11 i s o 3) 3drli'1q 3t the enct ther'!of th follJwin q J 0 t w i t n 5 t 3 n d i n 1 t h n "r J v1s10 ·1s ot tlliS ivi den1s e x ce0 t d ivi d~nJs of cJroor "i tiJns su~ j ect to t~e n istrict o f D.C.COde, sec. 47-157la.l D.C.COde, sec. 47-1580 n f inrn::i'll institutiJns sh:=ill CJe de~ne 1 t: o 1 s a n e fld~ d by insert i nq th or ds f i n 3n c i :d o r ,Jn i n or p r 1 t 2 d t) J s i n 2 s s w 'le r e I/ P r t n e y 3 µ o e '3 r 1n tn :H sec ti on Sec 1 17. Se: ti o n 14 of Ti t l 2' XII f tn 1ist ri t of :olumbi a Incom e ~n1 r~n i se Ta x net Jf 1~ 47 a~pro~e1 July l 1 ~4 7 (6 1 St~t 352; l 1d2 S2'C lt 7-l"i 8 f:&amp;gt;l-l r 3 J =Jt in J to e tirn1t c~d l 5 q 6 l -1 t o r e ~d s fol l w s J N I l\J 0 P J R A T c 0 8 J S I N t S S E S D) ATiend subsection (a O.C oae• sec• 47 a l E e ry c~r oo r at i~n· fi'l anci a l in stit~tion ann uni'lcorJoratea nu s i ness r eau ir eJ to make anj fil e 3 franc'li se t~x r t J rn D.C.Ccde, sec. 47-1580a D.C.Code, sec. 47- 15861-1 u 1 c r t n i s ~r t i c l e sh :1 l I ,11a &amp;lt; e an &amp;lt;1 t i 1 1 o r t i 11es rn1 Jn de r su cn conJit i ons l1C1 tne Distric t i f C gt; lu11o i1 sn-Jl l 1 y 1 th e c~s o f o~ fo r t h~ l 3st a~ y on ~n i c i J r e ~u r n t or u1d e r s ct i :J n 3(a l :Jf Ti t l e v o f th i s est i m~t?d t x f r s~cn ve~ r i n x:e 5 s of one h-Jl f Jf sue s t i nateJ r.:i l fi n.:inc i :il i nst i t u t i gt;ns t ie o r o v is i gt;ns af tn is se t i o sha ll De JO ·e t t~ c o s I C t1 11 3J l( a 3 of th D i st ri ct of cl u rnb i a r e l atina t gt; Ddvm~n t f e sti rn tt a t~x 2 s du r inq th a sha r t ~e r i~d n 1 t o 5 }Ct i on 3 0 l(D 2 C f SUC.I Act (r gt; l3t i n to 10 p-:iynent or 2Stin:iteJ taxes luri na tne t ra nsitio1 aeriod c) Anend subse::tio11 (D 0 C J o ae. sec. 47- 15 ·l 61-l 1)1 to r ~a ~1 1s f gt;lloi&amp;gt;Js J iilure of~ corpor3tio1. fin3nci~l institJtion, or un incoroor~t 2d busin2ss to o~y sti nated t~1e { l) AO .HfIQN TJ TH fA rn c a s e ot ~nJ Jn de rp~vnent of e stinat e J r~x JY c o r o gt;rJtio1 financi::Jl institutiJn• Jr n Jnincorp:&amp;gt;rJt e d bJSin~ss tnere snail De 3d1ej Lo t_ h t 3 &amp;gt;&amp;lt; for t. n e t 3 I( 3 gt; 1 e ye :1 r 3 n i rn Ju 1 t ci et r n i n e '1 ci2 t e rnine1 Jnder e&amp;gt;3ra~rripn (3 Z) A"I OJ N T ]~ U\I OER PAV'M El';f or JurpJS c S o f sh-=il l JP. tne excess gt;f A) the =Jm:&amp;gt;unt of th e inst:Jl lment 1hic1 e r e e Ju~l t:&amp;gt; 10 p~r c entun gt;f tne t3x sno"'n on tn e r e turn f:&amp;gt; r tne t3xable v e 3r gt;r. it n gt; r etu r n a s f i I e 8 J Der cent J m of th e t 31( f o r such y e a r 11 i n st:i l l rn~nt J :Jid on or be fJr th 1 'l s t d::it? Jr~scribed fJ r p3ynent { 3 pt: R r o) J F u \!DER~ Av Mc f\J r Th Je r i d of inst'l l lrn~ nt 35 re~uir ~d t:l Je P'lij ro ~nicnev 2 r "{A) th 15th dJy of th~ fo1 r th mJntn tol 1Jwin::i th l Js2 Jf the t:=ix -1b l e v 21 r; or 8 1 itn resoect t inv Jo rti on of tn e rl J 3 J f estiin1t.Jr1 t:ix 01 any inst-'ll nent alt:&amp;gt; c;h3l l Je 1nl v t gt; the a xtent Si.Jen 3ym~ n t 2 x ds tn 2 2 l f gt;r Si.Jen i nsta ll rn2nt 1at e Se 1D8 Se:tio'l 15 of Tj tl? XI r gt;f t1e )istr i t of :olu nb i a Income :3nj =r:ln:h i se fax t\c t )f 1~47 1Jo r ove1 Ju l y 16. 1~47 6 l c· t 35 t :3 gt J e s?c 47-1 586m i s anenoea h y in sertin 1 th e ior ds r find rJCi:ll in c;titLJtio1 i mne1i:3telv 1ft e r the "Or d "c orp r :3tion D.C.Code, sec. 47-1586m l2 Se 211 Jara~r~pn i Jf s 2c tiJn 6 o tA1 ~ct tn~ fi5c1l v a r ~n i 1 q Jun P. ttli r i 2t1 nin2t e n ~P DrJv d July l 1~02 (32 St 1t l o.c oae SP C• 47-l7 J[ r e1:3tinQ tO t~e q r o55 e 3rninQ5 t d K fo l l:&amp;gt;w s 11 ias e l ect r ic li inti1 q in'i off ic e rs, 5'13 11 m a k ffi 13vi t to t:i e b~a rd of J e rson3l-t3x aoo r~i s~ rs Jn o r t~ t~ e amou nt of i ts Jr t~eir q ro ss 30t'l :J:3y of J une 3rid e::1c1 i :i s conp-1nv. tixa s of the J istri :t of :ot u nb i a c~r r c 2 i o ts fro'Tl th 53 l p of JuJl i c utilitv D.C.Code, sec. 47-1701 lt; l3 District Jf C~l~mDiJ \nj in 31ditiori t112ret1 th 2 r e -1 1 P5tlte o.wn~d bv e:3Ch q1s el ec t ric li qhtin nd t e l e o~one cJmoany in th~ Ji~trict of e st-3t~ in s-:ii j Ji strict 7-17 0 r e l a tinq tJ ~r~ss ea rni nls tix o t21 0 J CJd2• s~c 7-170&amp;lt reta t ina t gt; insolv~nt c:&amp;gt;uiljinq or :ionesteaa .]Sso:i1ti o ns) i s Ti f LE III T ~A~S[TI O ~Al ~ULES FQ{ I~A~CIAL I N STITJT IO S ~o v e rnne nt o f th 2 Jistrict of olu~Oi3 t~r t:i e fiscal v ar 2n1inq J~n 2 thirti et nin 2 t 2e D.C.Code, sec. 47-1703 D.C.Code, sec. 47-1704 D.C.Code, sec. 47-1705 14 1u1drej 1nn tn r e2 3na for otn~ r J o r Jo ses 3DJ r Jv2n JJly l 1~ 02 (3) St 3t l o.c oJe ec 47-1 7J4 r2J3tin1 to t~ x on fi1a1c i al institJtionsJ 5 l 1 Jmen ed ov aJd i n t tne e 1 a thar~of th e fo l lJw in nE 3 03 r qr :ip1 P"Jr. 20 Tra1sitional D.C.Code, c; 1:3nci -3 1 Inst itJti o'1S sec. 47-1709.l l) S'l o rt Perio rl { l l c:or fina'1cial i nst itJti 0'1 s wit'l 'l c:e1 e r3I t3X3Jl e ve~r ena in q an 3 da t Jtne r tnan 7 ·H1 l J :Jt s gt;ct i Jn 6 D CJd e s 2c c £+7 -l 7J1 7 17 03 a'l~ 47-l7J4) for the ~e ri Jd f r on Ju l y l 11 2) Jue j'3 te Tne s'lo r t oe r iO-:l r e turn r ea u ir ed i1 su r:&amp;gt;sect i gt;n 3 1) 30 gt;ve sh3 ll Je fil ed 3 C stinated Tax r:&amp;gt iyrn ent F iri a ci a l inst it uti ons reaJirej to fi l e~ r e tur n 35 n:i &amp;lt e est i rn3ted tax p c~ynen t s 35 fJl lo s 15 \) s~ote1102r 1 l~lil 1 1 th~ snJrt JeriJd d ivi ded ov 12 J f11 U 1t t t j t 5 t l( 1 j 'lb j 1 j t Y 'IS nult i o li d hv th 3rn:&amp;gt;Un ° sti n3t 1 t31&amp;lt; J3vm?nt is due If th~ taxo~v?r's s~o r t o~ ri o 1) Tra1sitio1 oeriJd II l } )E: f j f'I j t j n e T~e fir st tra1sitio1 ve1r is i tiri v1ci3l in5titJtio:-i•s first full t1X:l D I P v 2'3 r 1 ftc~r July l• 191-ll \)A t3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;·1Dle ye a r for u r p 5 .2s of tn is s~Dsec~ion is a c~elv2 Cl2) m~nth p2rio1 2) fa Li3Dilitv Duri-iq Tr l 1 s i tiori Jotn t1 e q r o ss e ~rni-i cs t3x ann tn2 frJncni s2 ~3x 16 oeri gt;a E~c1 financial instituti o 1 s~~I (i or t'1P first t r 3ns it• o1 yeir tha fr3ncnise t~x o l ~s 6~ 2;3% o f th i i i o r t n 2 t h i r 1 t r i n s i t i on ye r. th~ fr3nchis a t3x o l us 33 l/3 of th e l7 ~r ~d t e r tnln t1e t)t31 of tne fr1n:nis e ta~ Jlus i In n gt v ent sri.:il 1 tn 2 t o td l o3 i d o r ccruea un je r tha or gt; visi o~s of this i.:i n ility 3 A urinq tne t"1 r e (1) y r n d &amp;lt; e a 1d f il e 3 jecl3r1tion of e s tim 3 t d t~x a t c; h i ll 113K e p:iynents )f sucn t 3~ iuri1 q i t s t:ix cJ bi v 3 r in sucn 3nounts 3nd under SJC1 :01a it ions 35 r s:r i bad i1 se:t i on 14 ot ti tl Kii J f t~e J c~a e s c 7-15 8 61- 1 in1 r e~ ula t i o n s r e l a t i nq t1e re t o 7 0 18 9 Aft2r t:i e t:ir 3 ye 3r Jy p3 r 1cr3on 5 of section O .c oje sec 47- 17 )1 sh:J ll nor 3 PJ ly to fin=rn::i:tl iistitu':i m&amp;lt;&amp;gt tnj e3:n fin~n::i~l i~stitutiJn S13ll o~ su~J2ct to tna Frinchis~ t3K iS p r o vi dej ~Y tne Cistrict t :olumbia I~com nJ ~ranchis? Tdx c~ Jf 1 ~47 TITLE IV rsC f LLA ~EJU~ D~JvlSI O ~S f l=.iw ti'l a 1cial instituti ons is 1 ef i1 RCl i n tit l e lt r s gt; n 3 l o r o J e r t v t a x J r :l i s i o s o t l n A c t J lt; i n J 'lU'ldre1 ~n j three a nd for othe r p Jr JOSeS io gt;r gt;v a Julv l• 1 02 (32 St:it 17: o. c o::Je. sec 47-14- J l e.] l df1Cl sh.:ll I e D.C.Code, sec. 47- 1712 J r :J o~ r ty 3DJ1 ic1tion tn~r ~of, t:&amp;gt 3ny Jers Jn or e;n-:i ll 1ot iffect oth2r oro11isi :rn s )r 'jJPli 3ti::ins Jf t i s ~ct hic 1 :31 ne o iv en tf c t ~ithJut th e 11 er3J 1 Se 4 J3 a x i St i riq R i q 'lt S 3n1 L i 3D i l iti e S c o nrn n: e d in an y civil c i us e b e fJr~ su ch r gt;p il a r i rn 2 n l rn e n t b c1 t 3 l l r i q h t s ,3 n d l i b i 1 i i e s u n J e r (Dl r i11~s C:Hld P2 n -3 lti 2s lll o tf ~nses co nmitt e i 3nj Je 'l alt i e s i ncurrad n ie r '3ny Jv c Q D.C.COde, sec. 47-1713 D.C.Code, sec. 47- 1714 20 JrJvis i o1 of l i w n~ r eDy r eoe~l2d or im n dej ay ~ith t1e s 1m2 2tfe:t as if t1is iCt 131 not Jeen f n 2 a yo r J f t r1e D i s tr i c t J f C J l .J m J 1 1 1 s 3 r rv Jut th~ o rJvisi ons of this a:t Se 405 ot wi t1stana in q ~nv Jt1e r PrJvi s i on f l3w fina1c ial inst.i'tJ t ions as 1ef i1 e:1 i n titl e r e =il p rooe rty ta l gt;rJvisions of tt"i~ foJlowi n -J 1 3 is l n A:t TD dist inc tiv2lv 1es i q n=it 2 .Ja rc~ls gt;f l =ind in tne D i s tric t gt;f C:&amp;gt;lJmo i -J t or a t1er Jurpos~s 3DJ r gt;v e a M3 r ch 3 1 8~ 9 30 St~ t. to dne n n A1 Act 3nt i tlea "An Ac t m=tkin l PJroori=itions tJ p r o vi ae for the ~x:&amp;gt; e 1ses of t h 0 11ern11ent t:&amp;gt; r t,e D istrict gt;f C:&amp;gt;l-Jm gt;i :1 for tn e :rn a:&amp;gt;o r o v e 1 arc1 31• Lg~z Z7 St a r 13 o c Original D.C.Code, sec. 47-1715 D.C.Code, sec. 47-1716 Q z l C 0 1 E 5 e 4 7 gt; 0 l l C cip J rJPri nioris f r t1 e qo v er ri m~nt Jf t1e Distric t ~nJl a Jr 11 Jart a~ainst t ne rev~nJes Jf s~cn i s t r i t f o r t n e f i s ci l v e 3 r e •1 d i n i Ju n e 3 D l =I 2 3 StH 6 D.c 01e, 5£,~C 47-C,Ql o.l 1 q .J a l i l -3 t i :rn o f r e 3 1 e s t 3 t 2 v :j 1 u 2 s i 1 t: h 8 J i s t r i t s t .Jte i1 s3i&amp;lt;1 Cistricr. in t'le y ea r i~hte :ln 1u1 a re j 1 n ·1 1 i :i et v s i x 3 n d every t 1 i r a y ,d r B] l a I sdles in tn P District Jf C~lJmJiJ. a ~o rove J 7 l 0 l t Q f An ~ct ~elatinq tJ th e l vvin~ 3nj collect inq of taKes Jn1 lSsessnentS t CJ t 1 l 8 j c d 2 s 2 c 7 l 1 0 l 5. gg } q taxat iJn i~ the Jistri c t of :oluTioia. 3pa r Jvaa 22 7-8 Jl ~t. sg:,i a 1 d sna l 1 b 2 l i ml E f:&amp;gt;r t~e TITL E V E FECT IV c )ATE~ Se 5Jl Tn2 Jr:&amp;gt;visioris of tit l rT o t t hi s 10Jl ic::iol e t gt; fi1a1cial in s tit ut i o 1 s 1 ill D8 2f f e ctive f r financial inc;tituti cns p~a in1i-i q J r:&amp;gt;vi d2 f o r th e 2xJ e 1ses of th 2 qo~ernnent of tn~ J i5tri :t of :olu'Tloia f'.l r tri e f i sca l ve =ir e1d i nq June t•irt i etn ni1ete2n hu n d r ea 3 1 a tnr e p JnJ f o r J t 1 e r :Ju r p gt; s 2 s l p or gt; v e d J .J l v 1 1 10 2 3 sect i o1 30 1 of this a: t. Jf t-i i s ict sn=i l l taKe ef f e c t ift e r 1 thi r t v 3 0 ia v gt;eri:&amp;gt;d of :01qressional r e vi w fJllo fin q sect i o 1 "10Z l) Jf tn e Dis t r ict Jf C:Jl um i'l D.C.Code, sec. 47-1717 2 3 ~ct a~o rov eJ l e :enn 2 r z 1~73 8 7 ~t~ t 13 J C1 a s c. l-l47(c ll n3 irn 3n En.ro11 ed O r1g1na1 C~u~cil ot th e J istri t of :olumoia } l )f 14 ·J v o r i st r i t 0 f 0 l u rno i a r APPROVED July 9, 1980 C I COllDIClllL OIF BE ilU ST!lna ~IF COIL!!Il=imA fEllJm Cf «miRCK mimm:3l AClllm oocn:T NO: B 3-190 ON Adopted First Reading 6/3/80 tff VOICE VOTt Jl.1.J!Du.iB~Du.1.1..1· m~ou.1u.1 S Absent: All Present 1J ROU. C4'U. von C:OM•Clo C.OOe&amp;amp;a lt 11o110Cll. IOC••CJ! UC t:~\ll'tc:i CJ•eC:\ I nT'ff&amp;gt;N KANE SHACKLETO~ WTN1'F~ I MASON SP.:\TTT.nT~G rr AR'!{F MOORE tJTT .C::fiN A"QTW PAY I T .1 Q~TTC QnT ARK 101 i iiot ctar nc.u:oN CF :U:CCRD ACT:ON: Adopted Final Reading 6/ 17 /80 &amp;amp; l/O!CC: I/CT i,IIu.nw;au.n1..1i..iim~a..i.1 i JS:i D ~ou. C.\U. van cow•C&amp;amp amp a&amp;amp;A fC t 1•r 9Y.j u.a c 1 w I I: f ca c I A "t"C 1 I T'\T'Vli~T I I I( HIT: I lt µ Ar 1 1\ij I I UT\~'D l \f AC f'IN PA TTTT'\ T\T~ I I I ri &amp;lt;iRTC-i t ~OORE r.TT'T C::f'l\T I I I I l-f &amp;lt;i OT'\V I RAY I I I I I T O~TT C l RnT AQV I I I :\ lot J u ~r f o.c c cz:~n::c~o i o u:cc;m ACT!ON D VOICZ VOT Atisen RCt.l C.\U 10 c amp;JI c 1 I l•J:'l'.C:t « { l t if c c~•c ll •TC i I I a. i-nT'(r'IM I '1 I I V l \T'l l l f3H CKLETONI I I 1 l I i \.O~ r&amp;lt; u 1 r I PAFL rJI ~TG I I I l T.r I.I f I. Ir'\' l QV'l I t I fl"'l f'l l I I I I i lJTT C Xl I I I i QAPTW I i I I l i I i j I I \~U i T nT 1l7V l I I i i i r C ] i O </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
