<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 3-98">
  <num type="law">3-98</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Certificate of Need Act of 1980</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1980-09-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/3-98.pdf">D.C. Law 3-98</citation>
      <citation type="register">27 DCR 3528</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 3-98, the “District of Columbia Certificate of Need Act of 1980,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 3-129, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 17, 1980, and July 1, 1980, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 16, 1980, it was assigned Act No. 3-220 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NO.TICE D C LAW 3 9 8 "Dis tl ict of Columbia Pharmacist and Pharmacy Regulation Act of 1980 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self Government and Governmental Reo r ganization Act, P. L 93 198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No 3- 129, on first and second readings, June 17 1980 and Jul y 1, 1980, respectively Following the signature of the Mayor on July 16, 1980, this legislation was assigned Act No 3- 220, published in the Augus t 15, 1980, edition of the D. C. Register Vol 27 page 3528 and transmitted to Congress-on July 22, 1980 fo r a 30- day r eview, in accordance with Section 602 (c l) of the Act The Council of the Di strict of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30- day Congressional Review Period has expir ed and, the refore, cites this enactment as D.C Law 3- 98 effective September 16 1980 w~w k DIXON Chairman of the Counc il Dates Counted During the 30- day Congressional Review Period July 22 ,23,24, 25,28,29,30,31 Aug ust l,4,5,6,18,l9,20,21,22,25,26,27,28 September 3, 4 ,5, 8 ,9,10,l l ,12,15 v n 7 n D.C. LAW 3- 98 AN ACT D.C. ACT 3 2 2. 0 I~ T;E CJ U ~C I L OF THE OI STRICT OF OLUMBIA To est3DI i sh a oh3 r 11ac i es J i str i ct of JUL 1 6 1980 8oa r d of Ph ar ma cy and to r equ l ate t h e J r actic e o f Jha r nacv i 1 tna ColunDia and for ot 1er ou r p~s~ s. 2 Duroose and Scope 3 J e f i n i t i n s e~e r al Dr on i bitions 5 03 r d of PnarmaCV LiCe1sinq of Pnarm3c i s ts 7 eqis t ration of ~nar ma c v I nt9 r ns ii rou11as to r Je11 i a l, Suspension o r Revoc3tio11 of a Dha r nac i st s L i c e n se LiCensinq of Pna r mac i es 10 Jp~ r a t io11 of a Pha rm acy 11 rounds for Jen i a l. Su spens i on, o r Revo c atio11 of a Dharnacy L i cense I Z. 0 harnacy De r so~nel I 3 ju) k Sal as or Transfers P3q~ 2 3 3 0 11 13 l L+ l6 17 1 8 zo 21 2 Je t e riJr atin q Dr uqs. Samo l e r Jqs a1 a R~ tur~e j Oruqs 22 l 5. La gt;el i~o of Pr s e cr1ot1ons 23 16 Pr~script on Reco s r "1 2 3 l 7. I nsp ectiJns 24 l 8 eddl i~q of Jruqs on Str eet s; p ro h1b1ti gt;n 25 ~e~ula t ions 26 zo ee s 28 21 e,a l t i es zq 22 dn in istra tive Review zq 23 Se v e r a~ il ft V 30 La ~s Repe ale j 30 25 ffective Date 31 3E IT f ACTE) 3Y THE COU~CIL OF TH E o r s r~r:r oc U LU~3IA Tn 3t tn i s 3Ct Tid Y oe ci ted as the ~District f o lumoi a Pn~rmaci st 3nrJ Ph :H 11 acv Re q Jl ~t i on ~ct f l q10 a l The ourp gt;ses of this act a re 1) to l i ense oh3 r TI 3ci es 3na pha r maciscs 2) to r eq i ste r onarmacy inte rn s 3) t gt; r e lul3te tne o r3cti ce o f gt;h3 r'Tlacy; 3nd (4} to est=in l i sh a o gt;ar d gt;f Pr,3rm·'iC in tne Distr ict of C gt;lumoi i i n ord e r to orot e ct t'le puo l i c :ie31 tn a nd we lf a r e CODIFICATION D.C.Code, sec. 2-601 3 (D) This act snal l n ot :1Dp l v t:&amp;gt ll -1 duly lic nsed 11enic3l )rc.1ctiti:&amp;gt;ner hJ persJn1l l y di s:&amp;gt;e nses or 3drni ni sters ;Jrugs Jr ~oisons 35 t1e pr3ctitioner jeems prJp~r in tne (2) the 3dTiinisterinq Jf aruqs Dy reqist2r2d or licensed nurse under t1e airectiJn J f 3 medical practitioner to tne pra:titioner•s (3) or Jtnerwise interfer2 ~i th tie 5312 Jf over-tne-counter druqs; { any p2rson ~ho iS a ~nolesaler Jr nanuf 3cturer, Jr 31'1Y e'Tiplovee of suc1 DersJn wnen enqaqe~ in t1e a ischar qe of ~is Jr ne r official \Jotnin1 in t11is :let sh.:ill Je constru"!c1 as =ilterinq or 3ff2ctinq iri :iny 3y 13 is of the Jistrict o f Co lumoi a or 3ny ~ede r~l ~ct r eq uirin 1 ritt en orescriotiJn for contr~11 ea s o u s~31c s or o t~e r 'J 3 n q e r o u s i r u q s Sec 3 Def initi ons FJr ou r ooses of t11is :let 3) T11 e tern Bo3rd" means th e J i st rict of Cotu~b i a Bo a r d of Ph3r11acy. D.C.Code, sec. 2-602 4 ID) Tne tern »aisoense" means t J sell. j i str iJute l eav2 ith qive a~av. disJose o f Dr ep:i r e r d2 l iver a aru q c) The t er11 "druq mea1s 1 I 3ny sub stance r ecoqn i zed as :3 druq ne:1i c i ne or ne :Ji i1al chem ic :il 1n t/12 ffiCiJl Jnit2d St~tes Pha rnacoooaia offici31 ~3ti3n3l o r mul 3ry, off icial Homeop3tnic Dh3rna cooo e i3 o r o fti: i l l veterina ry ~ed icine Comoe na iun o r otn r offic i 31 d r u~ conpenaium or 3ny suople nent to i ny of tneTI 2 any substance inten dej for use •n the 1 i3qnosis c ure rn i tiq3t ion. tre3t ne nt. o r o r e v e ntion of j i sease in ma n or otner ~nim a l 3) any c,enical substanc e (Oth e r t nan food) i nte nded to affe ct tn e struc ture or a nv functio n of the nody of nan or oth e r ani 11a l ina (4 inv suostance int ended fo r us e as 3 co nponent of 3'1Y i ten s soecified i 1'3u ses (1 2 or (3 b ut does not inclua 2 ne 1ical j e v ices o r tneir c omoone1ts• pa r t s. or 3cc2sso ri 2s d) The tern "l 3D e l in q" m a ns t,e p r o e ss of 3 ffixinq a l 3De l to any j r uq c ont::iin 2r ut does 'lot incl Jd2 the la oe li nq by 3 113nufa: t.J r 8 r J 5 J 3 ck~r. or aistributJr of an over th o unter 1ru q 03:1&amp;lt;3q~d 1eqend aruQ gt;r rn~dic'j1 aev iC e} T~ e ter M ayor" mean s tha ~avor gt;f tne Jistr i:t of Columbia or the ~avor•s jesiqnited 3qent f) rrie ten1 "medic31 a2vice" ne::ins in instrunent• apoaratus, implement, TI3:nine ontri~ance. implant, invitro re3qent• or Jt~er simila r Jr r~ l3te d article, inC LJd in i i ny co~ pon~nt. part or access3ry nic1 is 1) rec:&amp;gt;q1ized in tne offici al 'tati'.ln:il ~ormu l~ry, or t he Jfficial Unite1 St1t~s Dh3 r 11ac oooeia, or 3ny supplement t1ereto uo 2 intended for us e in tie di3:nJsis of dis23se or any otner condition, or in t~e cur e nitiqatiJn. treatment, or ureventiJn of dis~~s~ in na n or otn~r ani 11al; o r (3) intended to 3ffect th 2 st ru:tu r e or nv func ti on of the noay of ~a n or other 3nin31. 3nj ~hie~ does not acnie~e an y of its Jrin:iJal i ntended purJoses thr o uqn hem ic~l 3:tion wi tn in or on the ~od y of 113 n or otn er 3ni113l, 3nd wnich j oe s n ot deoend upon beinq met3D01 iz ~a for th e 6 jc1iev2rn2nt Jf any of it5 orinciJ31 uuroos2 s q) T1e tarn ~medicinal cneni:als" ]€d05 chem ic3ls us?d in th e treatm?.nt :Jf i Jl1ess or 1 i seaS hi Tne tern "over-the-counter j ruq" Tie 3ns jruqs ~hie, nay De solj ~ithout 3 Jr2scriotion a nd Nhicn 3re are-D3Ckaqed for use by th 2 consum2r 3na laoe led in accoraanc2 with t1e r2auirenents ~f tne l3w s 3nd r eau l 3tions of the District of Columbi3 and the feder3l qovern11ent i) Tne ter11 "person" means a ny i1aiviaual. 03 rtnersniJt 3ssoci3tion, coroor3tion. como3ny, 1o int stoc1&amp;lt; 3ssoc i "It.ion. or rnv or::ia11i zed i ro uo of oersons ~n e t1er incorpor3t.ea or not: o r anv tr ustee. r 2ceiver. o r assiqnee tnereof I) Trie tern pna rmacist" m~3 lS 3ny person Nho is icP-nsed in tne Distric t of Columoia to enq3qe in tne ~ractice of onarna:v K) The t e rn pnar m::tcv" means a 1v e s tao l i S'1rnen t or i .1sti tuti on. or any pa rt ther~of n~re (ll the p r actice of oha r ~acv i s :onauctea 2) jruq s a r e conpounaea. dispense3. ofter d for lt a 7 53 1e iven 3w :3 Y• or displayed fJr S:jl 2 at ratail: or (3) ores:riptions 3re conpound2d or a isp ensea 1) Tne t e rn "pharmacy intern~ neans any Jerson wno is reqistered in the )istrict of :olumbia tJ enqaqe in the or3Ctice of Dhjrnacy unae r tne 1 irect SJpervision of 3 oh~r]3Cist ml T1e tern "oractic2 of pnarm;cv" means tne interpret3tion 3nd ev3luation of orescriPtion Jf'le rs; th2 comooundinq. diS;Jensin 3na libelinq Jf dru~s and devices. 3nd the mainte1a~ce Jf orooer r~corjs tnereforei th e resoonsioil itv for idvisinq her~ requl3ted or Other~ise nec2ssarv. Jf tner3oeutic values and content. h3 Z~rds 3na use Jf d ru~s and devic es; ana the oft e ri1q or Jerforn inq of those :3Cts. services. op2ration5. in d trjns3ctions nec e ss3ry in t he 01a uct 02 r a ti o rna n aqe me nt. dnd control ot a ah3rnacy n) The term "Jr 3ctitioner ne3n s oe rson l i ens2d arir1 oe rTI i tt ed riv sucn 1 i c 2nse ot11e r tn')n Jh~ rn ist} to prescrioe. to disoe1s e or tJ 01d uct re se3rch witn resp ect to. Jr to adTiinist e r 1ruqs ~ithin tne course of s~c, Jerson•s o ro fession~ l p r3ctic e or r ese3rc E.nrolled Origina o) T1e t~ri "prescriotion" means ~ny order f o r :3 J r u q ne j i c i 1 3 l ch em i c a 1 o r co n b n at i o q or ~ixtur~ s tnereof, or for 3 rneaic:3lly orescr i)ed ne::1ic3 J devi:e, in writinq, dated :3nj siqnea by :3 J r actitiJner, or qiven or~lly to 3 p 1 3rm~cist or Jh~r~acy int2rn JY 3 pr3ctitioner Jr sJcn oe rson•s ~ritin~ DY tie pharmacist or pnarmacv intern. 5p2c ify inq tie address of the Jers3n fo r wnoTI tne jruq is orjerea ana directions for use to oe al aced on the laoel. {al The term o r op ri eto r of 3 Jnar~acv~ 11eans 3 oerson desiqnated as proorietor in an 'lODl icatio 1 for 3 oharnacy li c ense und r s 2cti:)n Th~ oroorietor mav be an individJal. a co1 trollin q int e r e st in the CJh:'lr11acy S I Tne t e rn Radioaha r 11aceJtic J ls" ma ans rajioactive drJqs 1nd cnemica l s itnin tne cl=Jssificati:rn of le qend dr u qs 35 :Jef i ne':l un de r June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. lO~o: 21 u c. sec 301 g o r requ13tions issu ed by tna var Jursuan t tJ this a t Se lt General ProniDitiJns al It sh3l l oe unl 3wful for 3ny DerSJn t:l anqaqe in the pr3cti ce of Dh3rTiacv ii the oistri ct ot C:&amp;gt;l umoi 'J un l ess tne person is current 1 Y 1 icens2d 35 a ~h~ rnacist or reqisterea as j Dh3r~acy intern in accordance ~ith t1e provisions Jf tnis act• i\ny oerson holdinq 3 v-:il io l ic~nse to pra:tice 35 a pnarm3cist un der th2 orovisions gt;f the District of CJlumnia Pnarnacy A t• aooroved ~ay 1, 1906 (3~ 5t3t 175; o.c oje• sec. 2-602 snal l continue tJ le recoqni zed 3S i 1 icensed Jh3rTI3:ist SJ lonq 35 ne or sn 2 :onpl i ~s witn th Jrovisio'ls of this :3Ct includin q re-ie il of tne 1 icens e 35 orovideJ in s ecti on 6(dl D) It shal 1 gt;e unl '3wful for -3 re;:ii ste r ed ~v o rescriotion in tne District Jf (Jl~moi~ exceot ~nile in tne presence ot and under t~e i mmea idte 5uoe rvision of a pnarm3cist cl N~ oharn3cist sn3ll suo~r~ise mara th3n D.C.Code, sec. 2-603 10 (di r( ShJ) I Je unlawful for 3ny De rs :rn t:J 02r~t2 rn ii1t:lin. open or est3Dl ish a oha rmKv ~ithin tne 1istrict Jf CJlumDi-l ~it hJut first (e) rn tne C3Se of scheaule II CJnt rolle j suJst3ncas only 3 oharnacist m:1Y rec aive an or31 e&amp;gt;r~scriotion fl It s:"l::ill be un1:3"ful for :3ny establ i sh11ent or institution or :3ny oart tnereof t1:3t aoes not Jrovia e ser vic es of the oractice of Jh:3r~:3c y :35 3r disal3y e d witnin it• o r affixea to or us e j in ioras P'1a rm:3cy aootnec3 rv d ru store druJoist 3r a riy word Jr Orjs of si11ila r or JrJCti:e of Jhar113cy is oe inq :onauct e1 i n t~e esta o lishment or instituti'.Jn. Se s rner c is established a 13oa r d of in:3 r macv for tn~ 8 istri ct of :olumoia D.C.Code, sec. 2-604 11 3 1 The o .3 r j s n cl l I dd 11 i s &amp;gt gt; t ne M '1 v :H w i t n respect t o t1e reqJ 13tion of pnar mjcies. t1 e J r 3ctice o f Jh3rnacy. 3nd re1atej natt2 rs bl 1 l) The i3 oar'.1 sh:ill consi St Jf s ven Pl nenoers 3poointed Dy tne M3yor. Tio10 (2) snail b I 3y oersons anj the rern3inder shal I Je Jh :i r .naci sts• l ic2nsed to pr3ctice Jh3r113cy in tne J istri:t of :olumoia. Ul T1e lay parsons snall b~ resijents Jt tne Oi5trict of Co1umoia, De at le3st 2iqhte2n (13) y23rs of aqe 3nd not ever 1ave neen a Jh3rnacist or the spouse of 3 oh3rna:i st• Jr h3ve 13 j my TI3t eri31 i1terest in t1e orovidi:iq of oh3 r n3c y se rv ice or oeen enqaqed i1 ~nv ~ctivitv 1irectly r ~l 3ted to tn e Dr'.3ctice of Jh:'lr11acv 3) Tne p13 rm acist nenbers Jf tne BJ3 rd sh .31 1 it t ne ti me of tneir aopo intnent and t h rouq~out t1eir ter n A) be resi dents of ti e District of ColurnDia 8) be licef"ls e a i, th e J istri c t of ColumDia of"ld in qood stdnd in to n q3qe in the J r ~c ti ce o f J h~rn3cy i n t ne D istrict 3f C~l~moi 3 nd l2 (Cl hav~ naJ six (61 vears Jf exJeri~nce in the Jr3ctice of Jhdr~acy in the Jistri:t of :olurnoia after 1 icensure. { Th~ nenbers of t~e 8Jard of PhJ r ma cy shJl I 1e aopJint~d ov the ~avor for 3 term of hJ 3ra 3poointea to fill vacancies ~hicn occur arior to tne e~piration of a Forner nenb8r's f ul l term sn3ll serve tne unexpired Porti)n of such term 5) Jf tne memDers first aooointed under tnis act three (3) Cone (ll of ihic, sn3ll ae a l a v oe rson) sn:ill serve 3 term of nr e e 3 Ye:3rs. two 2) ne11ber s sh all serve 3 term of two 2) ve3rs. and t..io (2) meml)ers snail serve a t e rn f one (l) ve3r b) \lo mernDe r of tne Boa rd s:ial l s e rve 'Tlore trian two (2) consecut ive full terns. Tne onpletion of th e unexoired portion of a fu ll ~e rm sh':ll l not constitute a f..il 1 ter m for tne pur;:ioses of tnis sec~ion 7) Any vacancy ~nic~ occurs •n tne nenoersn io of the ~oa ra for anv re a s on incluainq 13 1 is ao ilitY• Jr disJu:Jlific3tan. sn3ll De fill e d Dy d Jers)n 3DOJinted bY th2 ~3yor 35 orovidej in ae rson to fill a v3c3ncy after tne v3C3ncy o:curs c) Trie Board sriall elect fron its rneno~rs a cn3irmin and suc1 other officers as it aeens apJrooriate and necessa ry to con juc t its nusiness. The n~i r m3 n of the doard shall Jresi ae 1t al l neatin~s of tna Boar d and shall be r eSJOnSible for the oe rfor~anca of all of the duties 3nd functions gt;f tne Boara d e~oe rs of the Boa rd snail ba :onpensated d S orovidej in s ac tion 11 03 of tne Distr ic t Jf :o l umDia Government :om prehenSiv e ~erit PersJnneJ ~ct of 1~7q effecti ve ~3rch 3. lq79 co. c. l w 2 lJ:j; o. c Coje se ction 2 of th e 0istrict ot :olumoia Act 4me n d ments Of 1980 Counci I di 11 3-236 e) Th e "13yor shall assiqn t the 3oa r :1 thos e r e soonsiDilities w11ich the Maya r :Je li e ves i r e i o o r oor i 3t 2 Se 6 D.C.Code, sec. 2-605 1 4 (al Tn e 3 vo r sn3ll i ssue 3 l ic~ nse t J J r 3ct i= e as 3 pha r Tiaci st i n th~ Jist ri =t o f Co l urnDi3 to 3 ny p a rs o n ~no nea t s th 2 fo ll owi nq :Ju el l i fie:n i o ns l is a t leas t e i qh tee n t 8 l ye a rs o f -7 q e 2 1 no l a s 3 deq r ee i n ona r nac y q r a nt e d DY 3 c ol leqe o r scnool of oh a rn a cy a ccred it ed ov t he Amer i c ~n Cou ncil of P h~ r naceut ic l Ed u ca ti on 3 na s se rv ed a s a oh 3r Tia cv i n t e r n i n a Jh3 rnacy for the arnoun t o f tim e r e:J u ired b y tn 1 a yo r 4l nas satisfacto rily c~s s eJ su c n th eor et i ca l and orac tica l e xamin 3ti o 1 o r 2x 3rni nat i ons 35 the a v or n3 v o r e scri o 2 a nd (S) nas Ja i a al l r equ ir e d t ee s h Exc e r ienc e n i c n i n t ha oo inion ot tne a yo r is e ~u iv 3le n t t o p ha r macy interns nip d nd ~n ic n is ootdined J ri o r to su c n ti ne o r t i nes s t h e ~a v o r na y ov r equla tio n o r e s c ri o e o r obtain ed i n t ne se rv ice of t h e Jn it ed Sta t es o ve rnn e nt n a y o e acceoted 'JY tne Ma yo r i n 1 i gt; u o t c; e rvic as i re q is t e r a d o na r rnacv inte rn as re a u i r ~a unc e r s e ctiori gt 3 15 (Cl Tn ly gt;r may 3lso lic e ns e :is 3 Jn ,nnacis t any 02 rson who 3t tne ti m2 of f"ilinq 3n Jrec~dinq nas ne2n, l icensea as 3 )n 3rnacist Dy -rnv st=it2, PJSsession, or coTimon e~ltn of r:n 2 Jnit2a States o l ic nse snall be issu e a una c- r this SJDse:tion unl es s tne l icanse is suej ov the (l) w3s issue 1 3fter ex3min~tion 2) h3s not Deen suspendej, r e v ok ed or jenied aurin~ such one year oeri gt;d is 1ot sunject to 31y 3:tion or Jroceeiino wnicn miant result in its susoension or re11oca ti Jn; 3n 1 was issued DY a state. Joss e ssion gt;r :onmo n~e3 lth wnich und e r lik conaiti o ns qrants icens ea by 2xamin3tion in tne District of Columbia. NJ oers gt;n snail be licens ~a und e r tnis suosecti gt;n unless th e r e auirem e nts ot Jar3qrdons (l Z 3 and (5) of SUDSectiJn (3) are rnet 3n 1 in tne ooinion of the ~avor, tne c ircunst ances so warrant. Enro11 ed Ori· g inai 16 (01 Every license issue d Dy tne i v:Jr •1 cc o rdince witn the DrJvisions of th 1· s 1 1 s 2cti Jn, 5hal I Je suo ject tJ rene ·l'/31 s J d~tern;ned Dy tne Yor. A l i:ense ~hich has not Jeen r enew ed ~ithin tne time 3na in tne manner sp 2cifiea oy tne th~r~of shall not Jr3ctice 3S a Jharnacist i1 tn e Ji strict of :o l umDia wni Je tne l icense is not in :10 gt;d st.:3ndinq al r, e M3yor shall reqiSter for a oe rioa of l l iho nas filed an aopl i 3t:.i on suo scriDed unaer o3 t~ or affi r na ti on CJntainin a 111 re auired f e es 2 ho is curr ently r ~q is te r ed in and atte nai n q 1u ly accredited coll~a e or school o f scnool of onar nacy b l T~ e Mayor ma y. DY requlatio prov i je for the r eq istr a tion of o h a r~acv int~rns w,o ontain their o r3cti ca l exoeri e nce outs i1 e of the J i strict D.C.Cc:x:ie, sec. 2-606 17 {c e qistr~tion ~s 3 pn3rm~cv intPrn may De re1e~e1 fo r successive periods of Jn 1) ye~r if the 1A 3yo r is s'3tisfied tn3t the 3pJlicant iS i:i ~ood f~ith 3nd wit1 reason3ble dil iqence wJrKinq to..iard his or ner phar11aceutical deq re2 gt;r, if he Jcc u11ul3te tne numoer of hours of service required (a otwitnstandinq tne orovisiois of section tne vor is authorized 3nd enpower2d t gt; refuse to i ss~e re e..i or restore. or m3y SJSDend or r ev oke rny license gt;r reqistr.:it1· an to pr ictict= as 3 gt;n~rnacist or Dharnacy t i n ern. if th~ dDD l ic i nt l) P roc u re:J ni s or her l ic~nse or r e i s tr a tian tr gt; hf n u q rau d nisr~or~se nt3tion. o r 1eceit 2) is 3 chronic alcoholic :3 s tn t term i s de fined in se c tion 3(:3) of th stri c t ot 0 l u inb i 3 A I c gt; h gt; 1 i c R h a D i 1 i t at i 0 n Ac t f l 6 7 196 8 8Z St:3t. bl D.C. Co1e D.C.Code, sec. 2-607 18 se 2~-52 2 or 3 Jruq user 3S tnat term is 1ef inej in sectiJn 3 of tne Act To pr o ~i de fJr t 1e tr?3tm~nt Jf us ers of na rcot ics in t 1e District of :o l umD ia. apJroved June 24• 1953 7 St ar 77; J C. C gt;d2. s~c. Z4-60lli (3) 15 unfit Jr unaDle to pra:tic2 Jhd rna:v bv re3son of a Jhysicil or ne nt 3l aisease Jr diS::1b ility h3s e iter ed a ple3 of nJlo co1tanaere or h as oeen :onvicteJ of 3 viol 3cion at th~ feje ral Conp r enensive Oruq Aous e Pr e ve1tion 1nn Co ntrol ~ct of lq7 J aoproved J ctooe r 20• 19 70 34 St3 t• 1 2 ~2; 21 u.s.c. sec 801 ] ·l• tne te::Jeral r=ooa 0 r uo 3nJ Cosm e tic A t ioo rov 2d June 2 5 t q3q (52 Stat 10 40; 2 1 u. s c. se 3Jl Q ·l• or tie p~a r m 3cy l a~ or n3r:otic l a o f :iny Stita o ossess i o n. or c onmon~e 3 J tn ot th2 Jn it ed S tates 5) h:is h3d his or ne r I i: e1s2 or r e~ is tration to pr actice 3S a Dh~rn3 ist o r oh3rrn3cy int ern suso ended or r evoked o y an v o rJp e rly c onstitut ed licensinq a ut'lor it y; or J h3S willfultv viol:H eJ :H willf ul l y :Je r mitte:J t h e vi l :Jt ion of a ny pro vi si n of cn i s oursuant t) this act b nv jeni 31, suspension, or r:iv:)cation of 3 oh :H11 3cist license sh3ll be :TI3de onlv upon sp ecific cn3ro2s i1 writinq an1 Jnly 3fter oouortJn itv for d ,earin q n3s oean providej a) Tne aopl i cation for a pnarm3CV licens e 5h:lll )e m-1de an 3 f'Jrn to be orescrioeo bv th t 3vo r anj sha ll oe 3CcJmo3niea bY the re quir ed f e 2 The 1 i ens e sh al l De val i a for 3 per i o d of Fe~ Sh3ll oe require d for the OP2r~tio1 of 3 :Jn1rTiacv ov th e Jnitad St3tes iovernnent or Jy th~ J i st rict of :olumbia qov e rnm e n t bl .ippl ic=ition for rene al of a p'1arm3c y lic e ns e sha ll oe made not later th:3n t'lirtv 3 J javs be for~ the ~x:Ji ration dat e f t'1 e l i c en e to :ivoi1 1 3ose n 3'1dition3l fee for 1-=it e f i lina not exceedin~ the amount of the r ene al fee sn1l 1 De es t 3bl i sned by the lavor Cl C:a cn pharmacy license issued s,all aJ p lv Jnlv to the JDer3tion of tne pnarmacy ~t tne 1oc3 tiJn f?r 11ich it is issue :J D.C .COde sec. 2-608 20 (d) u Dh3 r nacy lic e n se is not tr-3nst'er:iD l e e wnether o r not the o r oo ri 2t. Jr of 3 Dh:l r macv is 3 Jh:i r11a ci st t he Ph3r na:y l ic nse sh-3 1 l ~e i ssuej in tne n:ime of t.ne o r o l r i etor f) wnen 3 oh3rrnacv cnanqes or o J ri e tors n i o th~ li:ense sh3l l Jecone voi d 3n J sh3 ll De o r omptlv surrende r ed to th e lll3yor. 31a 3 l ic 2nse sh:il l ne oot3 ined oy t,e n e oroor i e to r wh e tner o r oh:i rrnacy. l i:ensed ona rm aciSt Ou ri nq a l l times wnen tne e on juty The oha r mac i st Dn Outv sn;.il l .Jost ni s J r her l icense in 3 consoicuous :Jl"!ce :iur in q the Tne nou r s thdt tne consoicuouslv j i solayej on tne outs i j e of tna (D) The Jh ir113ci st on 1ut y sn31 l cont r gt;l cil l orofess i on~ l asoacts of tn e oractice o f ona rn acv nv us~ro3tion in ref e rence or irn o3i r nent of the dxe r c i se of orofessiona l juaqm e nt of tne D.C.Code, sec. 2-609 21 Jn1rna:ist 0 1 juty DY a non-oharTI3cist proorieto r Jr p e rsorin 2 l snal l 02 aeemed tne o r a:tice Jf JharTiacy 3nj constitute 3 violati'.Jn ot this act C)(l) If only P'Ht of an 2st:iolis"'lrne n t gt;r institution is usej 3S tne pnarm3Cy ~n1 if tne Jh:=Jr113 y is not gt;pen t gt; the ouol ic 3t the ti 11es when t"'le r E~st Jf t'le establ i Sh'11ent. is JPen tJ cne JU'Jl ic• the ciharn3cy snal l be secure! y enclosea so 3 5 tJ Prevent unauth'.Jr iz ed access to ona r m3cy J r eas an1 to prevent tne diversi'.Jn of j r uqs st gt;r2d in onarmacv areas 2) Tne p"'larmacy 3nd 3nY stJriQ~ 3r eas for Dr~ s crioti gt;n a ru ~s outsije of th2 Jh3rn3cy sh1 l l gt;e suDst rnti 3l I y constructed 3 Al l d JO rs s n al l be c 3 o 3 J 1 2 of D 2 i n q se curely loc&amp;lt;ea and access shall Je restrictea to Jn~rnac i sts tne oroorietor Jf t'1e p,3r m dcy o r Je rsons 3Utn'.JriZ2d Dy 3 on'lrTiacist witn th onsent Jf t"'le p r oJrietor Tne Kev or Keys t'.J 3r eas 3r e to De unje r the cont r ol or in the ooss ess i Jn of tne Jn~ r n3cist on duty or th o r ~or i et gt;r of tn 22 (d) 3 ur~l :iries 3nd damaae tJ th e Jndrnacv or its :ontents by fire, fl ood or Jt1er :ausas sna il ~e r2oortej imneji3tely to tne M3Yor. Ne itner jruqs 1or other .nercn3ndise shdll De disoe1s ea, so ld, 1eld fJr sal or q1ven away i1 3nY Jh~rmacy janaoed DY fire. flood• or oth~r C3uses unti 1 tne ~avor 1a s 1etermined tnat the nerc,a0dise is not Jd ulter3te1 Jr ocher~ise unfit f~r s~le, use or con sumotion. Danaqed or2mises s,all b2 inspected suit3bil itv for oh3rnacv ooerati gt;ns al The ~avor ma v refus e the issuance r rene ~31. or nay revoKe gt; r may susoe1a for not ;iore tnan ninety 0 Jays 3 li cens~ issu ed gt;u rsu3nt te&amp;gt; this 3ct for 3ny one 1) or 3 conoin3tion of t ne follo~inq r easo ns: re~ulation of th e 0ist ri ct of :olu~Dia or of D.C.Cc&amp;lt;le, sec. 2- 610 viJl 3t2a by any Jerson n~m e a i1 tn2 3P J1 ic3tion for ohar11acy l ic'=nsurei (Z) furnishinq f31se or misleacinq intor m3tion to tne M3yor, or f:ii ling to furnisn inform3tion requ~stej JY t1e M~yor, or refusinq to 3llo~ 3n insoection in accor~a n ce itn secti gt;ns 11, 12, 3nd 18; Jr (3) sell inq, or offerinq for s3le, 3dJ lteratea or misor3nded druqs or devic2s b) The '1:iyor shall fortnwitn suspend l i:ense issued Pursuant to tnis :lCt ihenever the ~avor finds that tne fdilure of a Dh3rTiacy to co~ply wit~ any orovision of tnis 3ct or witn anv J istrict of :olumoia or federal la Jr regulation aoolicable to such onarmacy is of such 3 s2r1ous nature anc maqnituje tn t a an inminent aanqer to the e a lth or safety of 'th e ouol ic is Jresentea. r n s uc i case f a h ea rina is reiu ested. S uC 11 re que st Jr hearinq shall not serve tJ stay the issuance of an order susoenainq the Ii cense. Sec. 12. 0 11arTiac P U ersonnel lt; a l &amp;lt; l l 1'l J oe rs on ne 1 t~e 3Ctivities of ~hich nerc~a~dise Jr druqs in h o arnacy or the care of D.C.Code, sec. 2-611 24 1isoens;nq nanufactJrin q, or StJr:3q2 f aci liti es no is aff?.ctea DY• or bel ievej Jy tie M'J yJr• uP:&amp;gt; n r easona bl e oroun ds tJ Je affectea JY co~mu nic~ble dise3se 3nd no persJn w~o 15 J r 15 )e l iav ed by the ~avor, uoon reasJn3D le qro unds t o 3Ctively enQiqe in any wor~ in a p 1a r m3cy 2) No orJorietor of anv Jha rn acy or nanaqe r of an y onarm3cy sn3l l inte 1ti ona llv oe rmit upon reasonaole qr ounds to De a c3 rri e r of :3 onmu nic 3ble dise3s e, to enqaqe or continu e too o lo perso'"l shall iork i1 3n y a gt;acitY in a (l is af fli cted i th bo il s infectious oun1S• sores o r an a cute r soir tory inf&amp;lt ti on 2) 1s earin~ uncl?an ~a rm ~n ts 3 l is 3 ch ro 1 i al c onol i 1s tnat term is aef in eo in sec tion 8 3 2 o r (4) CJoe s n ot f o l Jo n y i en ic wor&amp;lt; o r actices incluainq tne w;isninq of n:inas 25 JS 1 s ne:ess a rv there3ft2r tJ renove sJi l -md corit Hn i n-:it ion. {a 1 ul k sales or transfers of jruqs or is notif iea orior to tne prooosej tr-:ins3ction and the ~3Vor finds that the druqs or nej i~3J jevices ~r e fit for the use for which they were Jriqinally intendad Jr tie purposes Jf tiis section, the term "oulk s3les or tr3nsfers" s1all mean tha sale J r transfer of the entire inventory, or any suostantial Jart triereof in :inv gt;n 1) trans~:tion or in 3nv nercn3ndisinq ~ffo rt referr ed t) 35 an "auction sale t ucmKrUp Cy ale ctistress s3Je 11 or "l a c os1n~-out sal8 t e rm gt; lk l u 53 es or tr=insfers" sna1 l nat inclu a~ tr nsf e rs 2 5in q l e c ustom e r h=ivin~ 3 al f ue a fiv e- 1uriarej c1011 =irs (£ gt;00 or nore in :iny one eek P~ rio :1 sha ll oe co nsider=a t1e l f S .3 o a SUbSt:3nti:3l P:3rt gt;f tn e inventory inct :35 one tr3ns~cr n J uril c~ Ss th e s::ile co1stitutes th e fillin q f 3 v p rescr1.)t1on. or D.C.Code, sec. 2-612 26 results f r om a coooerative Duvin or~ e r. If d ru i s 1 r 2 ~cauiren by such trans3ctiJns in oth Pr jur isdicti:rns. tne Mayor sn:ill De notifi ed nd the druqs sn3ll ne officially insoectej and r ele~sea Dy the ~avor orior to sale Jr other jiscositio1 in tne District• Bulk 0Jd1titi e s of jruqs Tiay De trans f e rr ed only to p2rso1s l 2q3l ly antitlea to sell or dispense the aru~s bl fhis p rovisi on supo l e ments a~d aoes 1ot r eo l ac e the Act ro provide for tne r 2qu lation of closin~-out and fire sales in th e Jistrict of :olumo ia. 1oorov e d S e pte~ber lo 1959 (73 Stat 4 o.c o je. sec 47-30 0 1 2~1 ·l al )r.Jqs hic1 Tiav jet.e rior1t 2 shall it 3ll tiTies oe st o r e d under conditions soe c i fi e a on th e l a~e 1 contai'ler 1cc:Jr J1nce ~ith aDp l icaole Ji s trict of ColuTib ii3 or feaera l l a"'s or re1ulations. ana snall not b e so ld or dispensed ft.er the e xpiration date des i qnat aa on th e laDel of t ·1e oriqinal contai 1e r. ana i'.1 3Ccord3nc e wit :1 apolicaole Distri c t. of ColumDi3 :Jr fe :Je r1l l aws or re i ul :P:.i gt;ns. D.C.Code, sec. 2-613 27 o I r •J q c; 1 e s i q n a t 2 d s :3 TI o I e sh i 1 1 not o e so l a C 1 rc.1q wnich has bee n return ad aft 2 r 1e :3 vin~ ch a Jh3rnacy sn3ll not be ol:3cea in stJCK f or re use Jr res3le. exc e pt n3nufactJrer pac~a qed unit d3S2 or unit Jf use druqs w,i:h have oeen ~nopenad 3na un31t ered 411 j ruq s sh3ll De aisoens e a in i suit.:ibl e container :3Doropri3telv l3Deled for su Dseouen t Any druq aisoensea. ex:eot tJ in- J a ti~nts of 3 li ensed hospital. s,all incluje on tn e laJel ~f tne CJnt3in e r tne n~me Jf tne a ruq =Jnd th e stren Qth of the a ruq wheri 3pJl iC 1b le. Jnless otner ~i se airecte Dy tne orescri oinq o r~ctit iJ n e r. 3n d the n1 Tie 3d1r e ss ~n~ tel ea nJn e nu nbe r o f the J ha rn3cy till inq tne pr e scriotion. the n311e of the Jr e scrib e r• di r e:tiois for use. th e n 3ne of th e i n:li vi dual fJr whon the J r e s:riotiJn is ~ritten a n d otner inf or matio, 3n d l aoeli,q wri i :h m:3V be r eciuirea ov inv istri t o t :o l umoi a or fe aeral l3ws or re aul3tiJns D.C.COde, sec. 2-614 28 Sec. 11. I L Qt~on Records a) Tn ere s1all De Tiaintaine~ 1 1 \j v 2rv Jh~rn~cy or in tie establishnent or institution ~here a Jharnacy is located. 3 suita1l oook, file or otner e~sily retrievaol e record, in which snail ae preserve~ fJr a pe riod of nJt less than two (2) ve~rs 2ve ry Jr~s:riptiJn comooun jej Jr aisaens2a (b)(l) Tnere sn3ll be m3int3in2c :3 Dound volume r~coruinq t,e infornation reoJirea JY ldw r r eq Jl3t ion concerninq the over-the-counter sa l es of tnose oruqs wnich a re liste1 in Schedule v estaol i sne::1 o r 3nended ou rsu3nt to t:-ie feder-31 :onprenensiv ruq Aouse Preventi o n dnj Control I Z T n e r e s n a I l a 1 s o e m 3 i 1 t 3 i n e 1 d o u n r1 11 o l u rne i n i h i c ri sh i l l oe ente r d s i mi l -l r i nfo rm dtion concerninq e3ct"l sale o f ot 'l e r ne::1ical je vic es hich nay De useJ in tne 3d~ inistr ation of controll~d suostances 3 e latin caosul e s and qlassine e nvelooes in auantities suffici en t t o in j i Ca te an D.C.Code, sec. 2-615 intention to use sucn items in tne aistriout ion of controll2d subst3nces; 3nd (C) diluents or adulte r ants such as 13:tos2 or quinine in quintities sufti:ient to inJicate a~ intention to use suc1 SU)Stances fJr tna ille13l jistriDutian or dispansi10 of any controlled substance Cl T1e recorjs required to oe naintain~d DY oe 3V3ilable for insoection DY the ~3vor duri nq r equ lar business hours. Sec. 11 a) Pe r sons desiqnated Dv t1e M3yJr• Shall oe aermittej, after oresentinq Jrooer iJentificition Jutlet f3r t i e Puroose of m3Kinq insoections tJ 1e ermine conpliance witn tnis act or .vith otn 2 r l aws or re~ul3ti3ns apJl icao l e tJ the Jractice ot Dna rnacy. Persons de siq na t e d Dy tne M~vor sn~l l Je onarmacists fJr tne ouroose of naKinq nscec tiJns to daterTiine comol iance ~ith tnose sections of this act and Oth e r aopl icaol e 1 3 5 and requlatiJns reqarainq the Dractice or oharnacv 3 s D.C.Code, sec. 2-616 30 (D) Tnis inso2c t i :rn may incJuje, out Sh a l l 1 1 ot oe i m 1t ~d to, tie e xa~inatiJn of tne 0n~ rTI3cy•s r2cor ds. includinq orescriptions 3nc th~ oDt3inin~ of infor nation 3nd s~mJJ 2 s oerta ininq to jrJqs on hand or aisJens ea Sec 19. It s lal l be unlawful for any oe r son to s e l 1 or Jffe r for s3le bY ae w l i nq. or t o Jf fe r f o r s.31 e f rJm h ouse to house. or to off e r for sa l Y J uD l ic outc ry. or "JY v en d inq in the street t nY Co'Tlb in:ttion thereof or inv iffl o l em nt aop li mce Co'npou .1d o r conbin'lt i on tne r eof. uJori 3n v Juol ic ni~h a v Jr pl3ce o r ithout th e co 1s ent of the w ner ~r occupant thereof uoon 3ny Jr em is ~s i n t he 0 i str i ct of :olumbia D.C.Code, sec. 2-617 D.C.Code, sec. 2-618 31 (3) Th2 "l3 yo r snal l l) 31rninister in1 ~nforc gt; th JrJvisions ot thiS a:t 2 b2 resoonsiole for th re iul :ttion ot th2 or3ctice of Dh3rlla:y i n the i 5 tr i :t of :o l u mo i 3 rn j (3) 3 loat 3nd Publish sucn re iulatiJns as nay oe n~cessary fJr tne inolenent3tio1 of t~is act, i1clu (1inq, out not limited to, requlations :oncerninq t1e follo~inq: r eci gt; rocitv Jf aoplicants ~ho ;ire qu3lifiej to enqaqe in the gt;ractice of oharnacv u1d3r tne orJvisions of this act 1) Tne r~newal of licerises t) enqaqe 1n (C) T'1e e st':lbl ish rnent of nini nun o ra::ti ce of l icens~a 0 rm3c1sts P r3 Cticin q in tne District of Columoia and tne susaension~ r voc:ition deii 1 J C) r re stri::tion of licenses to enqaq 2 in tile or 3 ctice of Ph:3rm:3cy D) T11e est:iblish:nent of 11 ari:&amp;gt;us l:iss ific3ti gt;ns Jf Pnarmacies in::luain 32 limite 1 to ret-'il inst1tut1Jn~l. r3 J iJ or nucle~r Jh-3 rna s E) Tr 3 in in q. o u 3 l i f i c 3 t; Jn s ind amo loynent of Jh3rnacy interns i Administrativ e Jr.Jc edu r ~s for Public 1e1rin~s can:erned with the deni3l. suspensi.Jn Jr r e voc3tiJn of any license or r eq istr1tion orovided fo r in tnis act l Est3blishrnent of reJuirem2nts f~r a c ontinuinq ejucati:&amp;gt;n proqram f gt;r l ic:!nsed gt;n-:1 r nac i sts in t~e District of C gt;lumoi :i gt;-q Est"lbl i shnent of .ni ni nun c;t-1n r13rds 11 i ni11un re ·1uirem ents f or t ecnni c:tl eJuipnent 3nd J) T~e r~auirenents to assure that h:tr11ac i es sriall be clean, in qo gt;n r ep 3ir. wel faciliti~ s f gt;r t e pur gt;oses of cl e::inc;inq h in.Js. e auiament cinj utensi IS a n d the urem is e s tnerein: su cn f ic ilitie s nay oe l :K i t ed i n 1r 2 as ddja cent 33 to tne pn~rm~ cv ~n 2 r 2 Jn1y part Jf 31 ~r nst 1" tut1 n s usad as t st 3 ol is1rn~ nt l\) Tne est .1blisnment of r e~u lati :ms co veri1q the storaqe and di soe1si n~ Jt ra1iop1arm3ceut ic a ls D) Tn 13vor shall puo lis1 t h~ requl:3ti::ins re::iuired i ·1 suoparaqraohs (A)t Bl C t G)t 3nJ (Hl• wit1in thirty (30) davs fJ ll o~inq tne effective date of this act. Tne M3yJr snall 3nd (K ithin nin ety (90) a3ys, t1ose r eauirea in suop 3r3qraon (I) witnin on e 1una rej ei~hty (1 80 1a vs nd th~se requirea in suDp3r 3qr~Jh Nithin t~o hund red s e venty (270) d3V5 of the e ffect ive Jate of this act a T:i e initi3l f ees sh3 ll e ac; t o ll ·Y-'s l Ph =ff11a::i st 1 ic ense S65 2) Pnarm 3 cy J icen 52 liP.5 3) Every p e rson .m o sel 1 s lv e r-t,e-c unt e r gt;reo::u·3ti o ns snal 1 P3Y a annual 1 i ens e f ee of tSZ fhe fe e s r e ferred to in this suosection Sh 31 l Ge es t3Dlish gt;d in such a11ounts is will. in tne 1u~qnent of th gt avor aoproxiTiate tne casts D.C.Code, sec. 2-619; Note, D.C.Code, sec. 47-2308 34 to tne District Jf CJlumoi1 qovernnent fJr ~d~inistarinq this act. Tn e yJ r i s 3UthJrizea to cn3nqe tn~ fees from tiTie tJ ti ne for a1 y services r 2ndered under tn1· s act P~ O VIDE J Tna t. th2 ~avor 1 ives thirty (30) jays not ic prior to cnanqinq sucn fees bJ The MayJr is authJrizea aft =r thirtv (30) ja ys nJtic~ to est3bl ish and to :h3n~ e as n~y oe riecess1 ry. tne e xoir3tion d3tes :Jf 1 icenses lnd r e1 istrations orovi ded for in th is act. uoon the cha nqe of in e~piration d3te. tn e re,e a l fee for on the oas is of the tiTie c ov e r ea. Sec Z l E l l ~i s. {al Any pe rson ~n o viol3t es an y p rovision ot this ac t snail be quilty of a nisd ~m~a rior 3n~ s n a l 1 oe ounisnej oy a fin e of not mJ r e thin fiv undrej jO Jl a r s 5 00 o r Dy inPrisonm~nt for not nore t:ian si&amp;gt;&amp;lt 6 nont hs or bOth for e acn (bl Prosecutions f or violations of any o rovision of t,is 3Ct shall oe c'.ln'.lu::t ea in tne Suoe rior Court of the Distr i ct o f :olu~cia o y tne It sn a t l be surf ic i ent tQ D.C.Code, sec. 2-620 35 orJv e in 3ny or osecutiJn or nea rin J Jn~e r th is act 1o ld inq Jut or anv atte~pt thereof, witno~t o rovin~ 3 Qe neral :ourse of cond uct in ord 2r to constitute a violati gt;n c) In aaaiti :rn t gt; the re nedy s2t fort h i n tnis saction 3pol ic 3tion ~ay oe rn~d e to a c Jurt na11i nq cJmoetent j.Jrisdiction over t1e Parties 3nd su!Jj?.ct 11 att e r f gt;r a writ Jf injunction or Other civi I re11e1y to rastrain vial~tion s of tne or gt;vis io ns of this act Suen aoJl ic 3tion nay oe na1e bv tha :orpor~tion coun sel Sec. 2 2 Aoministr at ive ~evi 2 w Anv oA rsJn aqqriav~d Dv an a j ver se act ion of ja t e n Auqust ls 1~5 C o. 55-l~OJ; o.c ti tl 2 r. aooe n Ji&amp;gt;&amp;lt T ne 8 :Jar a of ~p~e3 l s e v i 2 w sn a l l. in a::c:Jrdance NI.th s~ c1 J r qan il atiJn and its rules of r ~c t·rce ~1d proceau re J r der Jr:Jvid e th e aqqrieve1 ~erson wit1 n o opo rtunity fo r a 1ea rin q anJ shal 1 susta i n m:)a ity o r v3cat~ su c h aj v e r se act ion o y tne v~ r J as is a oo r o or i at e in t ne c is e D.C.Code, sec. 2-621 n 0 36 ~nd ~evi=w sna11 oe the final dninistrative renedy Any pe rson nJ is 3d ver se ly 3ffecte d hy 3 Jec i s i Jn of th e doi r d Jf Aooeals and Revie~ nay se=k judici al revi ew t e reof i n tne )i 5 t ri ct of :o l umb i a Cou rt of ~ooeals, Pu rsu~nt to tne Jistri:t of :o lu ~Di3 Administritiv rJc?du r 2 4Ct iOD rov ed OctJber 21• l96 A (82 Stat l2J4; J If a~ y o ro11ision of thi s ac t i s for 3nY r e~ son ju r isdicti n, the :n ovision Shdll )e dee ·ned d its i n 11a l ijity snall not atf ect tne va l iaitv of tn e renaininq o rovisio~s a An ~ct To r equl Jte the gt;rJct i ce of gt;narnacy and t ,e sale of D) i sons i n tne Di st ri ct of C gt; l ~m gt;ia 3nd fo r Othe r D ~r gt;oses. 3 gt;Dro11eJ ~3V 7 iqo 3~ St3t 17 5 o. c coae. se 2-601 b i:&amp;gt;ara~r3p i3 of secti n 7 of ~n A:t ~a&amp;lt;inq aac ro gt;riations to pro11i1e for tne e xpens es D.C.Code, sec. 2-622 D.C.Code sec. 2-601 et seq. D.C.Code, sec. 47-2308 37 n i net2en 1undrej 3nj thr e e. and f~r other oJrJOSES sec 47-2308) 1s repealed c} The Jrovisions of thiS a:t SJPJlernant 311 Jt1e r re:iul3ti:&amp;gt;ns :ind l:iws 3pplic:iol e in tne Jist ri :t of :olumoia. Requlations ner 2tofJre in affec t i1 the Jis trict of Colu~bi~ wnich 3re inconsistent witn th~ DrJv isions of this 3ct 3re 1ereDy superseded ~ith rcsoect tJ n3tt ers coverej 'J y t n i 5 IC r This act Shall become effective sixty (6J) jays afte r a tnirtv (30) d3y oerioj Jf oy tne ·1a vor (or i n t:ne e vent o• veto ov th ave r ict i on Dv t:.h~ Cou n il of tne District f Columni i02 1) Jf tne D istrict of Coluin o i :i 5e tf- D.C.Ccxle, sec. 2-623 Co:1e se l-147(c)(l)l• J is t ri::t of Columbi a APPROVED: July 16, 1980 38 Cn3ir n3n Cauncil Of th ~Olled Original Co lumoi a CCQllaGClllL Cf NIE ilUSllina GIF COUlllll~UA mmm m:~mmuca.Aenm oocttr NO: B 3-129 AC'nON: Adopted First Reading 6-17-80 { VCIC! l/OTt u n a n i m o u s Moore, Spaulding and Ray D ROU. CALI. 1/0TE c 4tC I lt Ul'tCU UC e4!\I C)eeC:t nnnN I Kfu'tE SHACKLETO~ TJTN'ri;"Q MASON SP.\Ul DTNG rT RTl'F MOORE WTT &amp;lt;:n!&amp;gt;l il.PTW f lHV TA tHTTC i:im A"RT&amp;lt i o J i t tioc w tt AC ON: Adopted Final Reading 7-1-80 ,r; VC!CE lfOTt: Unanimous A:Csant: Wilson u i\OU. c.u.r. von lt;:ow..ci C••CA f 4rC e:s\l,.c:i I f''C t F i c:a c T'ITVf'\T\J I Z Ti I Ari-'i i T'm T.TT'\T"'i:'1' I i \.f,\.C \1\T I 1 &amp;lt HIT n nrr. rT ARK I ~OORE fJTi C::f'\l\T PAl:mY I 1 1BV I I B1'UTC I ~f'\T 1nr 141 J s..u :t f iol 4S.:C 0 1/0!C! VOT I .1 RO AL 1107 UC re I t 1 I I I I I I I I Z z </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
