<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 4-111">
  <num type="law">4-111</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1982-06-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/4-111.pdf">D.C. Law 4-111</citation>
      <citation type="register">29 DCR 1684</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 4-111 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-374, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 9, 1982 and March 23, 1982, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 12, 1982, it was assigned Act No. 4-174 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 4-111 "Anti-Sex-Discriminatory Language Act and Unform Disposition of Unclaimed Property Act of 1980 Amendments Act of 1982 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Se1f- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 4-374 on first and second readings, March 9, 1982 and March 23, 1982, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 12, 1982, this legislation was assigned Act No. 4-174, published in the April 23, 198'2 edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 29 page 1684) and transmitted to Congress on Ari1 20, 1982 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 4-111, effective June 4, 1982. ARRINGTON IXON J:J+ Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: April 20,21,22,23,26,27,28,29,30 May 3,4,5,6,7,10,11,12,13,14,17,18,19,20,21,24,25,26,27 June 2,3 D.C. LAW 4 111 £F~"WVE JUN 0 4 1982 AN ACT D.C, ACT 4 1 7 4 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APR 1 2 1982 To ameDd the ADti-Sex-DiscrimiDatory LaDguage Act to revise the geDder rule of cODstructioD; to make techDical DumberiDg ameDdmeDts to the UDiform DispositioD of UDclaimed Property Act of 1980; aDd for other purposes lInrolled Orig1U8L I BE IT ENACTED B~ THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "ADti-Sex- DiscrimiDatory LaDguage Act aDd UDiform DispositioD of UDclaimed Property Act of 1980 AmeDdmeDts Act of 1982 Sec. 2. The ADti-Sex-DiscrimiDatory LaDguage Act, effective October 1, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-87; [1976] D.C. stat. 194) is ameDded by addiDg the followiDg sectioD 44 thereto Sec. 44 a) The sec oDd paragraph of sectioD 2 of the Act of March 3, 1901 (D.C. Code, sec. 49-203) is ameDded to read as follows UDless the CouDcil of the bisti{ct of Columbia specifically provides that this sectioD shall be iDapplicable to a particular act or sectioD,all the words thereof importiDg ODe geDder iDclude aDd apply to the other geDder as well b) SectioD 2(3) of the GeDeral Legislative CODIFICATION D.C.Code, sec. 49-203 (1981 ed \ PAGE 2 Procedures Act of 1975 (D.C. Code, sec. 1-230) is amended by inserting after the phrase 3 the phrase 'with regard to resolutions c) D.C. Code, sec. 18-101 is amended by striking the phrase 'words importing the masculine gender include all genders Sec. 3. The Uniform Disposition of Unclaimed Property Act of 1980, effective March 5, 1981 (D.C. Law 3-160; D.C. Code, sec. 42-201 et seg is amended as follows a) Section 104 (D.C. Code, sec. 42-204) is amended by striking the phrase "sections 102 and 105 through 114" and inserting the phrase "sections 103 and 105 through 116" in lieu thereof b) Section 130 (D.C. Code, sec. 42-230) is amended by striking the phrase "section 131" and inserting the phrase "section 132" in lieu thereof. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect after a thirty (30)-day period of Congressional review following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto) as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved D.C.Code, sec. 1-230 (1981 ed D.C.Code, sec. 18-101 D.C.Code, sec. 42-204 (1981 ed D.C.Code, sec. 42-230 (1981 ed PAGE 3 nroll Or1gi:nal \' December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code, sec. 1-233(c)(l f Columbia Mayor District of Co APPROVED: April 12, 1982 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Council Period Four First Session DXKET 00: B 4-374 1=1 Ite.'I\ on Consent calendar ACTION: Adopted First Reading, 3-9-82 IXI mICE U n a n=i m~o u s s~t: all present 1=1 roll. CALL Ixl Item on Consent calendar ACTION: Adopte6 Final Reading, 3-23-82 I.-XI mICE u n a::n l m o=u s t: all present 1=1 ROLL CALL lUrE: 1=1 Item on Consent calendar ACTION 1=1 mICE ebs~t 81-P-6755 Secretary to the counc~l CBte </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
