<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 4-70">
  <num type="law">4-70</num>
  <heading type="short">Consumer Credit Interest Rate Amendment Act of 1981</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1982-03-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/4-70.pdf">D.C. Law 4-70</citation>
      <citation type="register">28 DCR 5236</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 4-70, the “Consumer Credit Interest Rate Amendment Act of 1981,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 4-138, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 27, 1981, and November 10, 1981, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 2, 1981, it was assigned Act No. 4-117 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA NO'l'ICE D.C tAW 4-70 ·C'onSUr:1er C:-edit Interest: Rate- Amendments Act of 1981 ursuant to Section 412 of the Dist:i of Columbia 5elf- Gove"rmnent and Governlllental l&amp;lt;eorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill NO. 4-138 on first and second readings, October 27, 1981 and November 10, 1981, l:'especti'lely. Follow-ing the signattU'@ of t:te Mayor on Oecember 2, 1981, this legislation was assigned Act No. 4-117, pUblished in tbe December 11, 1981 edition of the Re&amp;lt ister 101. 28 page 5236) and transmitted to Congress en Dec~~ber 11, 1981 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (e 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia he~eby g!yes ~otice t~at the 30-day Cong~essiona1 Reyiew ?e~iod has expi~ed, and thece!oce, c:tes this enac~ent as C.C Law 4-iO, effeetiye I'!a~ch 10, 1982 ARRINGTON DIXON Chai~n of the Council Dates Counted Curino the 30-day Cono~essiona1 Review Pe~iod, Decembe~ 11,14,15,16 January 25,26,27,28,29 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,22, 2J, 24,25,26 Mal'eh 1,2,3 S,8,9 o lJ,W 4 0 W 1 0 19a. AN AC~ O~ACH-117 IN T~ COUNCIL OF TF!:E: OISTRICT OF COLUMSU DEC 2 EEl 1''0 amenc allcvacle in~.r.s a~.s en ce~aln e~nsu=er c edit' and 1'04:1:1. and for ot'her purposes. BE !T l:TAC1 B Is CO(]NCZL OF 'ffl! O!STRICT OF COLOMBIA. Sec. 2. D.C. Code, sec. 2S-3J02 is amerAed o sad as ~l!O'IO's C:ac=~9S aqa!:ls 'I' to e Oi.s'l c'l Of Columbia, 1. J,t 1 111 l t'e 'Of CIDInO t:N o .c sec. 251- 3302 o PAGE 2 A o amend t he Tariff Sehedules of the United States to permit the importation of upholstery regulators, upholst erer's r egulating needles, and upholsterer's pins free of duty, approved January 1, 1915 (88 Stat. 2114; 26 U.S.C. sec. 6621) for underpayment s and overpayments of tax to the Int e~nal Revenue Service, PROVIDED, That a court of competent jurisdiction may lower the rate of interest under this subsection for good cause shown or upon a showing that the j udgment debtor in good faith is unable to pay the judgment. In the case of the judgments entered prior to the ef~ective date of the Consumer Credit Interest Rate ~enCment Act of 1981 that are not satisfied until after the effective date of the Consumer Creeit Interest ~a Amendmen~ Ac~ of 1981 he ra~e of in~eres~ thereon shall be the rate of interest ~rescri~ed in this sUbsection fr~ the effee~ive date of the Consumer C~edit In~eres~ Rate Amen~~ent Ac~ of 1981 ~ntil the date of s~tis~ac~ion Sec. 3. D.C. Code, sec. 2S-33QS(a) is amended to read fol1cws a) On a loan (other than a lo~n directly secured on real estate or a direct motor vehicle install~ent loan covered by Chapter 36 of this subtitl e) to be repaid in equal or substantially equal monthly, or other ~eriodic install~ents, including a loan obtained by using a eheck edit card, o~ other device to access a line of credit, any federally L~sured bank or savings and loan association doing business in the District of Col~ia may contract for and o.C.C::de, sec. 28-3308 PAGE 3 ~eceive i!lterest at the r ate pernlitted under t~is chapt e r r, in lieu ot such interest a finance charge, whi ch i~ lxpressed as an annual percent a oatil does not exceed a ;a of 21 percent per n or he unpa.id b.1a.~ces o f rillcipit.l. 1"!l.is section d o es net li.:t1t or 1 s ict' th e= o nt actio:g for the fillanc. char"e whether by y ~hat per::d t'ed "oy his sect'ion Sec. 4 C. C. Code, sec. 28-3602 is amended to ead as !ollows, O.C.CCCe, 5e 25- 3602 ~Such a eank 01 savings anQ loan association may tra~ tor and cei V'1I! int'e:est at the rate ;1I:'ovi4ed ~or i:l chapter 33 C1 lieu o~ such ir.te es a ~i:'1ance charqe Sec. 5. C.C. Cod sec. 28-3701 is &amp;amp;mended liS ~ollQWs 1 Para&amp;lt raph (1) is ameD.d 1 to rlllll.d 11.3 !0110&amp;lt;0f be~een a selle r or financial i nstitut'icn and a tuy.r III to t~e either ectly f th e seller or ~ssued "oy the se1:.r or a f~ancia1 ~stituticn 3 the o.c 22-370l o o PAGE 4 and credi~ service and o~her appropria~e charges are debited to an account C) a credit service charge if made is not precomputed but is computed on an outstanding unpaid balance of the buyer's account Erom time to time, and (oj the buyer has the privil~ge of paying the balances in full or in installments. The term 'revolving credit account' shall not include loans obtained by a person from a financial institution where a check. credit card, or other device is used to access a line of credit b) Paragraph (2) is amended 1:'0 read as follows 2 credit service charge' means the sum ot (A) all charges iyab1e directly or indirec'l:ly by the buyer and imposed directly or indirectly by the seller or !inancial institution as inci~ent to the extension of c~e~it i~cludi~g any of the followi~g type~ of charges which are applicable: time-price di!fe~ential, service, carryi~g, or o~her cha~ge, hcwever denominated, premium or other charge for any guarantee or insurance protecti~g the seller or financial ins~itu~ion against the buye~'s default or o~her credit loss charges incurred for i~vestigating the collateral or credit- worthiness of the buyer or for commissions or brokerage for obtaining the credit irrespective of the person to whom the charges are paid or payable, unless the seller or financial i~stitution had no otica of the charges when the credit was granted c aragraph (6) is 4mendec to read as follows 6 Ei."lancia! i!lst i tut ion eans a person who ent rs PAGE 5 i:lfO an aqreement ith a buyer h.r. by t~e fo:r-ter agrees to t.~c c~.cit to the buyer and to apply it directed by t~e buyer pursuant to a credit card i ssued t o the ~uyer by the :ir:ancial inllfitut"ion: il ld this e= inellldl!ll:!l any i::su=ee. bank UI clefi ec. in sect'io n 3 of ~h. Peder 873 12 U.S.C sec lSI or any 'insured i~st'itut'ion' as d.~ined i sect i on ~Ol of the National ?ousing Act approved .June 27, 1934 l2 0 5 lt se 1724 4S Stat. 1255 and any Sec. 6. C.C CoCe, sec. 28 702 0 is ~er~ed to r ead u follow c l illi q cycl e ~ears to thirTy For the rurposes of this seet'icn, a variation of not ~r. th.&amp;amp;J:l our d.Y5 ~CID n :mth to :IlOnt"h is ohe ,aate day of the billi!!g cycle 2 ot-.ti thstandi g the te~ 0: a..c.y ol"i 1 ~adit ac:ount or any other provis1cn cf la a sellar or (5) C.C.c:ca sec. 28-)702 o mini~um periodic paymen PROVIDED, That the seller or =inancial institution mails a written notice of the change to each af!ected buyer at least thirTy (30) days before the effected date of the change ROVIDED. FURTHER, That the seller or financial institution shall permit each affected buyer to repay, under the existing terms, any debt incurred prior to the effe~ive date of the change, unless the buyer ir.curs additional debt on or after that date or otherwise assents in ~itinq to the changes. This paragraph does not authorize a seller or financial institution to Lmpcse a credit service charge in e~cess of that pe~itted under r ragraph (1 3) The notice J:'equired by [:'aragraph (2) shall clearly set for~h the new ~e~ er terms he corresponding existing ter.n or terms, and the effec~ive date of ~he change: shall appear on a single doc~ent ~hat contains ~o o~her info~tion except the changed revolving credit account agreement or other material directly related to the ange: and shall be in plain language. The notice shall clearly explain the t~ options available ~o the buyer. The options shall be presented more conspieuously than the rest of the notice by. tor example, bold-faced type, larger type size or eontrasting eolor See. 1. II any prevision of ~his act or the pplica~ion thereof to any person or circumstances is held to be &amp;lt;.1ncons tit'Cltional or beyond the "tatutory authority of the Council of ~he Oistriet ot Col~bia, or otherwise tarolle4 Or1g PAGE 7 the inv~l id prevision or application, and to this e nd the Sec. 8. This act shall take effe:ct' a!t"er a thitty JO day per'icd of CCr'l.gTessional review followinq appro'll l by the Mayor {or the event at veto by the ~ayQr action ~y the Council of the District of Colu=bia to over=id the approved Oece 24, 1913 97 Stat. a13; D. C. Code, sec. 1-233 0 1 I!.aycr c c.an Council of Oistri~ ot C~l~ia ~0VUl, O.emb~ 2 981 \ I Oillt'rio~ o f o o CO!J:'lOL Of ntt OIS'T1JCf Of CO LlM!tA. C oIP F s 0, B 4-138 1= 1 to e:.r-n J.ordc Adocted fir st Reading, 10-27-81 III \ot'l Bv Majo:d&amp;lt;:y, Members Mason and Rola..rJc voted no 11- 20-Bl 1= 1 a c=r-n \CI:CII: l,dopt ed D l S i d lg 11 0-81 1= 1 11:lta 1::0 :a 11-20- U 1= 1 a </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
