<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-109">
  <num type="law">1-109</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-109.pdf">D.C. Law 1-109</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8739</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-109 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-339, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 22, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 4, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 1-194 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>tistrict of Columbia Register 6 MAY 1977 COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 1 3 1977 D. C LAW 1-109 "Naming of Public Places Act of 1976 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Se l f Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 t he Act, the Council of the Distr ict of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-339 on first and second readings November 22, 1976, and December 7, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 4, 1977, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-194, published in the January 21, 1977, edition of the £ £' and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, i~ accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives not ice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, c i tes the following legislation as D. C. Law 1-109, effective April 7, 19 77. S!l'ERLING KER Chairman o the Council (Ref. 23, D.C. Reg 4951, January 21, 1977) 87.39 District of Columbia Register 2 1 JAM 1gf AN ACT 1-1 94 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA January 4 1977 To require that no highway, circle, bridge building, park, other public place or property in the District of Columbia under the jurisdi ction of the Distr ict of Columbia shall be named in honor of any living person BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That t his act may be cited as the "Naming of Public Places Act of 1976 Sec. 2. Subsection (f) of section 1 of the Act of December 20, 1944 (D.C. Code, sec. 1-244 (f is amended to read as follows f) Name and rename highways buildings, public places and p roper ty, etc The Council of t h e District of Columbia is authorized and empowered within its discretion to name or change the name of a highway circle bridge, building, park or other public place or property in the District of Columbia under the jurisdicti on of the District of Columbia, except l) No highway, circle, bridge, building, park or other public place or property under the jurisdiction of the District of Columbia shall hereafter be named in honor of any living pe rson, and consideration shall not be given to 4951 bistrict of Columbia Recister_ 2 1 JAN 1 7 naming any such public place in honor of any deceased person, until two years after his or her death 2) The name of any person shall embrace the given name or names as well as the surname of such person and shall be so noted on the records of the Council of t he District of Columbia and official records filed with the Surveyor of the District of Columbia Sec 3. The provision concerning changing the names of highways having the same name in the provisions relating to "Streets in chapter 540 o f the Ac t of June 30, 189 D C. Code, sec. 7-1 06, 30 STAT. 532) and section 5 of the Act of March 2, 1893 (D .C. Code, sec 7 112, 27 STAT 534) are amended by deleting the period at the end thereof and adding the following as provided by subsection (f) of section l of the Act of December 29, 19 44 (D.C. Code, sec l-244(f and (2) section 1 of chapter 159 of the Act of February 16, 1904 (D.C Code, sec. 7-107 is hereby repealed Sec. 4. The provis i ons of this act shall not be deemed to limit any authority of the Board of Education to n ame public school buildings and grounds under its control Sec. 5. If any section or p rovision of this act is held to be unconstitut i onal or invalid such unconstitutional ity or invalidity shal l not affect the remaining sections or provisions of this act. 4952 Dis trict of Columbia Register 11 JAM 1W7 Sec. 6 This act shal l take e ffect at the end of the period provided for Congressional revi ew of acts o f the council of the Distric t of Columbia in subsection (c 1) o f Section 602 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (D C. Code 1975 Supp sec. 1-147 (c 1 4953</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
