<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-102">
  <num type="law">1-102</num>
  <heading type="short">Standing Up Service Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-04-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-102.pdf">D.C. Law 1-102</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8732</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-102, the “Standing Up Service Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-329, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 15, 1976 and October 12, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 8, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-171 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>cotnCI OF THE C!S TRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 13, 1977 D. C LAW 1-10 2 "Standing Up Service Act Pursuant to Section 412 of the District o f Colwr~ia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-1 98 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-329 on first and second readi ngs September 15, 1976, and October 12, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on November 8, 1976, this legislation was assigned Act No 1-171, published in the November 26, 1976, edition of the o .c Register, and transmitted .to both Houses of Congress f or a 30-day review, in accordance wi•h Section 602(c 1 of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30- day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislat i o n as D. c. Law 1-102 effective April 6, 1977 J-s RLING T CKER Chairman o the council {Ref 23, D. C Reg 3501 November 26, 1976 D.C LAW 1-10 2 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA April 6, 1977 To permi t patr ons of restau rants a nd h o t e l s to b e served alcohol i c ·beverages while standing up. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this a c t may be cited as the S tanding Up Service Act Sec. 2 a) The fourth fifth, and sixth sentences of section ll(g) of the District of Columbia Alcoholic Beverage Contro l Act (D.C. Cod e, sec. 25-lll (g are repealed b The f o urth, fifth, and sixth sentences of section ll (h o f t he District of Col umbia Alcohol i c Beverage Control Act (O.C. Code sec. 25-lll(h are repealed c Sectio n 4.5 of the Alcoholic Bev erage Co ntro l Regula t i o n s 3 DCRR 4 5 is repealed. Sec. 3 Thi s act shall take effect immediately f o llowing the period provided for Congressional review in section 602(c 1) o f the District of Co lumbia Self-Go vernment and Governmental Re o r g anization Act Docket for the Bill l 3_z_s Considered in Council Se otem ber l S, 19 7 6 First Vote September 15, l976 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE C OU lt;:JI c ac A'l'C HA'f I N V A COUNCii lt Cit I ATC AY N V a. cou c 11 lt lt 4YC NAY H. Y TUCKER x DIXON x SPAUIDINC x DORE D. x HA WY x I I tnLSON x BARRY x HOBSON x l.l!N!ER x CL\.Q.KE x I MOORE, J. x COATES x SHACKL.ETOH x X-ladic&amp;amp;I" Vol• A. B s..buru N. V-?iol Volinq a.LJ)~Q~.u:r Secretary of the Council) Final Vote in Ccuncil October 12 197 6 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCii CM81l" A YE NAY N.v A COUNC:IL. Mll a lllt A"r l: NA"t Jllt V COUl'CCll. Ml:MaC TtiC~R x DL"&amp;lt;ON x SPAIJtDING x oRE D. I x llo\P..DY y lITLSON ARRY I x HOBSON x WINIER x CLl \Z x ~OORE, J. Tx COATES x SRAC~ON x X-huikal" Vo A. B.-Abs•nt N. V Nol Volin11 Secretary of the Council} Presented to the Nlayor OCT l? tr EZG d1J)1 Secretary of the Council) Mayor's Action Approved UOV i976 Disapproved ut~NOVW (Mayor's Signature) tfl Enacted without Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Councill l -329 Bill Docket Page Two Reconsidered by Council RECORD OF COU N CIL VOTE ou r:n c u1 I •TC v lt;:ou e11 wc c11 AT IC TUC.K R I H OBSON I HARDY I H MOORE. D. B A R.RY I I I I MOORE L I Cl..AR.KE I I R OLJ_llK DIXON I s--r;cBl..E 'ION X-1'.Ac!.k&amp;amp;JH Vote A. B-Al&amp;gt;s•n.1 Present2d to the President Sustain Mayo r's V~to Not ~stain Mayor's- Veto JAN Z 1 i97]1 Submitted t o the Congt'eS 5.?nata Action Resolutio n Number Secretary of t he Senat a Enacted wlt."lout Congr1!$sional ac ion Secret:i ry o f the Council) K.V c ou c a C C It T l w.v j I SP AUL U'i G I I WILSON I I WL'i'T ER I N. V-Not V oti::g Se retary of the Councill (Secretaiy of the Councill (Pmident of the U. S.} (Secretaiy of the Council) House Action Resolution Number Clerk ot the House)</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
