<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-115">
  <num type="law">1-115</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-115.pdf">D.C. Law 1-115</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8744</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COVNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 1:3, 1977 D.C. Law 1-115 "District of Coh.unbia Codification Amendment Act of 1976 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District 0£ Col~~bia Self- Government and Govern.~ental Reorganization Act PL 93-198) the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted 3 le. 1-358 on fi=st a d second readings ~lovember 23, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Following expiration of the ten-day period provided t e Mayor, in which no action was taken, pursuant to Section 404 (e) of e Act, this legislation was assigned Act No. l-207 mblis ed in the January 29, 1977, edition of the o.C. Recrister and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section €02 (c l) of the Act he Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-cay Congressional review period has expi!:ed and, therefore cites the following legislation as o.c. Law 1-115, e:fective April 7, 1977 j STERLING TU KER Chairman of the Council :Ref. 23, D. C. Reg 5 0 5 2 Jan:.iary 28, 1977) D. C. LA\-1 1 11 5 r :oi THE COL"NCI L OF THE DIST!UCT OF COLCM.BIA April 7, 1-977 To amenc the District of Columbia Codi ication act of 1975 to author i ze t he conti nuec effectiveness of any rule act or resolution not pu~lishe~ in the Dist:ict of Columbia Municipal Cece until eigh t een mont~s after the o r iginal publ i cation of s uch Code BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCI~ OF T HE orSTRICT OF COL~M9IA That this act may be c ited as the "Dis t r ict o! Co l uobia Codificati o n Amendment act o f 1976 Se c 2. Paragraph (2) of subsection (f) of section 20 4 o f o.c. Law No l-1 9 is amended by striking everything after the wor d adoption" and inserting in l ieu t hereof t he following or within eight een (1- 8) rr.onths of the original publicat ion of the Dist: ict o f Col umbia ~unicipal Code, whichever occurs lat er, stall not t ereaf ter be in ef feet Sec l This act shall take effect upor. beco.~1ng la~ pcrsua nt to the ~rovisions of s e c t ion &amp;amp;02 of the District of Columbia Sel f- Goverm:1ent anc Go•Jer::ment al eorga niza t i o n Ac </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
