<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-112">
  <num type="law">1-112</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-04-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-112.pdf">D.C. Law 1-112</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 8741</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-112 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-368, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 22, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 11, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 1-201 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OP THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 13, 1977 D.C IJ\W 1- 112 otor Vehicle Reqist~ation Date Act Purauant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 th8 Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill llo. 1- 368 on first and second readings. November 22, 1976, a nd Declll\ber 7, 1976, respectively. Followi nq the s ignature of the Jllyor on January ll, 1977 this legislation was as signed Act IO. 1-201, published in the January 28 1977, edition of the D.C Reqiste and tran smitted to both Houses of Congress for revi ew, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Collll!lbia hereby notice t .hat the 30-day Congressional Review Period has therefore, cite s the following legislation as D. c. Law 1-112, effective April 7, 1977. 23, o.c. Reg. 5037, January 28, 1977 O.C. LAW l-112 IN THE COONCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COL~MBIA April 7, 1977 To allow the· Mayor to distribute motor vehicle registration dates throughout the year IE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA hat this act may be cited as the "Motor Vehicle Registration See. 2. The second, third, and fourth sentences of 11ction 2(c) of title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue let of 1937 (o.c. Code, see. 40-l02(c are amended by 1ubstitution to read For the purposes of this act, a 119istration year shall begin and end on dates established by the Mayor of the I&amp;gt;istrict of Columbia. During the thirty immediately preceding the date, as specified by on which a regis•tration expires, it shall be motor vehicle or trailer registered for 1111uin9 registration year Sec. J. This act shall take effect immediately the period provided for Congressional review in tion 602 (c} (l} of the District of Columbia Self- eminent and Governme.ntal Reorganization Act </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
