<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-120">
  <num type="law">1-120</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-04-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-120.pdf">D.C. Law 1-120</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 9924</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-120 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-340, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 23, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Enacted without signature by the Mayor on January 1, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 1-206 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 2 6 I 1977 D .C. Law 1-120 "D C. Register Publication Act of 1976" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act PL 93-19 8) the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-340 on first and second readings November 23, 1976 and December 7, 1976, respectively. Following expiration of the ten-day period provided the Mayor, in which no action was taken, pursuant to Section 404 (e) of the Act, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-206, published in the January 2 8, 1977, edition of the D. C. Register and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in acc-ordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. Th~ Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law 1-12 effective April 19, 1977 Ref. 23, D.C. Register, 5050, January28, 1977 i gt t D. C. LAW 1-120 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA April 19, 1977 To amend the Administrative Procedure Act regarding publication of the District of Columbia Register. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "D.C. Register Publication Act of 1976 Sec. 2. Subsection (a) of section 5 of the Administrative Procedure Act (82 Stat. 1206; D.C. Code, sec~ l-1504(a is amended to read as follows r "{a) The Mayor shall publish on at least each Friday, or if Friday is a holiday on the next working day, a bulletin to be known as the 'District of Columbia Register' in which shall be set forth the full text of all rules filed in the office of the Mayor during the period covered by such issue of such bulletin, except that the Mayor may exercise the discretion of omitting from the District of Columbia Register rules the publication of which would be unduly cumbersome or expensive, if, in lieu of such publication there is included in the District of Columbia Register a notice stating the general subject matter of any rule so omitted and stating the manner in which a copy of such rule may be obtained. The Mayor shall also publish quarterly an annual index .of all matters published in the District of Co lumbia Register r t i r r 1 c f }1 r t [ 2 Each entry in the District of Columbia Register shall contain the date upon" whfch such entry was submitted to the Mayor for circulation in the District of Columbia Reyister. 11 Eac.11 District of Columbia Register shall contain on its cover the actual date such issue was generally circulated to the public fo review and comment, provided that, s..1.ould t.P-ie Register be circulated a:fter the cover date shovm, a notice stating the correct date shall be attached thereto. All time computations based on the DiS:rict of Columbia Register shall commence f om the cover date, or ii a:nended, t.11.e date of notice thereof The provisions cf t..1.is subsection shall also apply to any and all supplemental additions to the District of Columbia Register. 11 Sec. 3. District of Colum.biE. Law 1-58, the 'Duties and Respon- sibilities of the Adviso:-y Neighborhood Corrir-,issions .Act of 1975" is amended by deleting from section 13(b) t.1.ereof the p!lrase in the last sentence and shall, as of the e~ective date of t..1.is act, be published on Friday of each week. 11 Sec. 4. The provision c:fth:S act shall become 'effective as provided by section 602(c) of the District of Columbn Self-Govern- ment and Governmental Reorganuation .Act I I Docket for the Bill i-_3_4_o Considered in .Council November 23 197 6 First Vote November 23, 1976 RECO R D OF C 0 U N·c l-L V OTE c:ou c:n. MEMBER I AYE NAY N v .1 A.8 C:OUNC:l l. M EM B ER I AYE N A Y N.'11. A .a II COUNCii. MEM8UI AYE NAY N .V I A.8 TUCKER I x I I DIXON I x II SPAULDING Ix. I }!DOR D. I x I I II HARDY I I x II WILSON x I I B.A:i\RY I I I x HOBSON I x II WTh"TER I x I I I CURKE I x I l MOORE, J. I x II I I I I I co z.s I Ix I SHACKLETON I x II I I I I X lndic:a.ies Vote A B A.hse:d N. V-Nct VotinS L Ctl d 1 1 December 7, 197"6 Final Vote tn Counctl Secretary of the Counci l) RE CO RD O F COUN C IL VOTE I COUNCii. M£1'18E.R A T£ I NAT I N.V. A.a. I couNc11. ME1'4BER I AYE i N A Y I N.v. I e c:ouNc::i £ 11 £.R 1 AYE I NAY i N v. I .a a j Ix I I l II DIXON ·I x r I I SPAUI.DING I I UCK R I DORE, D. I x I I I jj F-'L~Y Ix I I I l WILSON I I EARRY I x I I II ROBSON I x I l I II WINTER Ix I C IB!a: Ix I J I M OR.E' J. Txl I !I I I COATES I j I x SH.ACKI rON I x I I I i I f sen: N. V Nc: Voting Q J) 1lh.M?y.1 (Secretary of the Council) DEC 2 3 1576 Presented to the Mayor Secretary of the Council) I hereby certify that Council Bill 1-340 was presented to the Mayor· of the District of Co l um bi a on December 23, 1976 and that the Mayor neither approved nor disapproved the bill Within the ten day period specified in Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Govern- ment and Governmental Reorga!lization Ac t Publ ic Law 93-198 of DecembeT 24 1973 £!Jb Max'l:in K. 1challer, Exe cu'tive Secretary, D.C. January ll, 1977 I I x I I jx I i I I I I I I I I I Bill Docket B_il_l_N_o l-_3_4_o Page Two Reconsidered by Council Vote RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE C:CUNC:ll E BEl'I AYll: I NAT I N V I A-L C:CUNC:l l M&amp;amp;JlolaE" AYE I NAT I A.a. I CCUNC i C £1' I ATE NAY H.'I. TUCKER I I I I HOBSON I I I I I SPAULDil\;G I I HARDY I I I I II MOORE, D. I I I I ll WI.LSON I I BARRY I I I I I MOORE I I I I I II WINTER I I C L:J R l{E I I I I ROLA-itK I I I I I DIXON I I I ~KI.E'ION I I I X-tnci.aiea Vote a u-m N. V-Nct Vo::i:q Presented to the President Sustain Mayor's Veto Not SusMain Mayor's Veto JAN 2 6 197? Submir..ed to ne Congress Senace Action Resolutic~ Number Secretary of the Senatei Enacted without Congressional action Se etary cf the Counci l Secretary cf the Counc:I Secretary of the Council President cf the U. S J~&amp;amp f d LC&amp;lt L1 0 (Secretary of the Council) House Action Resolution Number Clerk of the House A.a. I I I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
