<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-131" flag="true">
  <num type="law">1-131</num>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-131.pdf">D.C. Law 1-131</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE May 11, 1977 D.C LAW l-131 •Day Care Policy Act• Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 he i t, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-240 on first and aecond readings November 23, 1976, and December 7, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on February 3, 1977, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-227, published in the February 18, 1977, edition of the D.C. Register, and tranamitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 1-131, effective April 26, 1977. 0 1 j_"J TUC~R STERLTNG Chairman of the Council (Vol. 23, D.C. R~qister, 6388, February 18, 1977) District of Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 AN ACT 1-227 IN THE COTTNCIL OF THE DIST1HCT OF COLUMBIA February 3, 1977 To provide policies relatinq to the provisions of day care services hy the Depar tment of numan Fesources. BE rr ENACTED BY 'I'HE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA That this act may be cited as the "Day Care Policy Act Sec. 2. As used in this act the term a Child" means an individual between the ages of birth and fifteen years b Chi ld Development Home means a child develop~ent facility as defined in section 103(5) of Regulation No 74- 34 (Child Development Facilities Regu l ation except that for purposes of this act a child development home s hall also include care qiven to a child by a caregiver related to that child pursuant to section 20l(a) of Regulation No. 74- 34 c) 11 Department" means the District of col um bi a Departm~nt of Human Resources. 6388 ~istrict of Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 s e c 3. The Oeoartme nt is hc r ehy auth~rized t o provid broad proqram of day c a re servi ces for children of parents ref err~j or approve0 by the Departm~nt for variou3 traininq and work inc e ntive proqrams, for children of other parents known to the De partment wh~re 1ay care a pp0 ars t o be in the child's hest i nt e rest, and for chi l dren of low- i n come families, othe rwise unknown to the Department whe re the parents are employed outside the home. Sec. 4. The Department is hereby authorized to pay the full cost of day care for children identified through the fo llowi nq circumstances a) Children of AFDC mothers referred to, enroll0 d in, and participa t inq in the Wor k Incentive Program (WIN b Children of AFDC mothers in other goal oriente 1 traininq proqrams such programs be inq i dentif i ed as those which include services of a job placement officer social worker, counselor, or other s pec ial staff member who offers support and help in ioh finding and employment adjust~ent {c) Chil dr en of AFOC mothers who have comple t ed training for the first three months followinq placement i n full time employment d) Ch ildren of AFDC fathers or AFDC c hildr e n who are livinq with caretaker relatives whose requi rements are 6 389 Dis trict ot Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 inclurl~d in the publi c assistance qr lnt and who 'lrP. i n train i n q for ~mployment e Childr en of AFDC mothers who are m~nta l ly retarded or who have a history of mental i l ln ess when day care is deemed to he in the child s best interest {f) Children of AFDC parents who are receivinq extended trea tment because of physica l or mental probl ems and day care is r ecommended by the treat i ng f acil i ty q Chi ldren of AFbC mothers who are attending hiqh scr.oo l, until the mother receives a hiqh school diploma or drops out of school I n the case of hiqh school qraduates day care shall he con~inued for three months after qra duatio n occurs h) Children of unwe d mothers who liv e with one or both parents or another caretake r relative if the parPnt or parents or other caretaker relative either refuses to qive care to the child or is unable to do so until the mother receives a hiqh school diploma, or reaches the aqe of 18 or drops out of school i) Childre n who arP approved for AFDC and live with caretaker rel ati ves (not parents and children approved for General Public Assistance and live with unrelated caretakers when day care is requirE&amp;gt;d due to employment of the caretaker. C3~0 District ot Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 (il Children of un~rnploy~d pa r e nts who are recaivinq vocational r ehabil i tation services when day c~re is nePded to allow them to e nqaqe i n an established vocational rehabi l itation proqram. Sec 5. The Departm0nt is hereby authoriz~d to supplemen t the paym~nt for day care services by parents (paid dir ect ly to a child development center, child development home or to an in-home careqiver accord inq to a daily f~e scale whose gross annual income does no~ exc eed the limi ts specifie~ in the f ee scale fo r the desiqnated family size in section 6 of this act, under the fol l owing circumstances a Chi l dren of AFDC parent s placed in employmP.nt throuqh the Work Incentive Proqram (WIN or othe r qoal oriented training prog rams after completion of three months of such employment b) Children of other sinql e parents (in single parent households) when day care is needed due to the parent s employment c) Children of workinq parents whose income is limited and the provision of day care services will enable the family ~o remain together 6391 District of Columbia Regis t er 1 8 FEB 1977 (d) Children r8c~ivina chi l d socia l services, if the childr~n are not in foste r c~re placement and day care seems to be in thP child's best interest {e) Childre n of parents who are receiving extended tr~atment due to physical or mental problems and day care is r ecommend ed by the treatinq faci l ity £) Children of employed parents who are receivinq vocational rehahilitation services, when day care is needed to allow them to engage in an established vocational r ehahilitation program Sec. fi. The scale for day care fees to be paid by parents shall be based on the following criteria a) The daily rat e of pay by parents, for chi l dren in day care, shall be based on family size the family s gross income as compared to median income specified by federal determination for services under Title XX of the Social Security Act, and a graduated percentage of costs of c a re as specified thr ouqh payment rates shown in section 13 b) Day care shal l he provided fr~e for otherwise eliqible children whose family's qross income is less than 50 percent of the median income, adiusted to fa mily size, for the District of Columbia c) Eliqihility for suhsidized care throuqh the Department shall ceasP. when the family's qross income, 6392 District of Columb i a Reg ister 1 8FEB1977 a~iustea to family size is qr~ater than 85 porcent of the specified med i an income d) Pare nts shall pay a percentage of costs for each child i n day care, on a q r aduated sca l e as the ir qross income increases from 50 to BS percent of the specified median income The percentaqes for the five g r aduated increments shall be 4, 8, 12, 16 and 20 percent of the appropriate payment rates specified in Section 1 3 as shcrwn in chart be low. Parent Pay ment Free 4% of cost 8% 123 16% of cost of cost of cost 7 8f, of 203 of cost 85 of When fami ly income i s 503 of median income 573 of me rli an in come 643 of media n inco me 71 of median ir.come median median income incom e sec 7. The Department shall not be liable for p a yment of that part of the day ca re fee wh ich the paren t agrees to pay the child dev e lopment center child dev e lopme nt home, or in-home car egiv er e v e n thouqh the paren t fa ils to pay the facili t y or in-home careqiver according to ag r eement. Sec 8. The De partme n t shall be r esponsible for its par t of the payment of day care fees to a child development center or a c h ild deve l opment home after admission of a particular child for up to 15 consecutive days for that child wh en abs ence is cau s ed by il l ness of the child or a G39J District of Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 chanqe in the par~nt s traininq status provi~ed the chil~ is in r~qular att~ndancn and the parent remains eliqible or a space is beinq reserved. sec q. The Department shall be respon s ible for its part of the oayment of ~ay care ~ees to an in-home careqiver only for those days when the in-home careqiver is presPnt in the mother's home and rendering services as agreed. Sec 10. An ove rpayment by the Departm~nt to a child development center, child development home or to an in-horn~ careqiver who is conti nuina to provide day care services shall be coll ectible in any amount s~c. 11. The collection of an overpaym~nt of not more than $25.00 may be waive d for child developMent cPnters, child Jevelopment homes, or in-home caregivers who a re no lonqer providinq day care services for the De~artment. Sec. 12. For those child development centers where special programs are developed to meet the community needs and with which contracts are neqotiat~d to cover full fundinq or seventy-five (75) percent of funding the Department 's contri hution shall not l~e rerluced by the amount of planned paym~nts by parents. These payments shall be use d to enhance center proqrams. such payment by p arents shall be basei on the da ily rates for slot-fun~ed proqrams District of Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1971 and the day care fee scale set forth in section G of this act In the event the tota1'6f the plannccl parental payucnts which are actually received in any fiscal year by any center plus the Depar t ment 's reinburscncnt to thi1t c e nter for costs for that f i scal year exceed the total budget of that center as negotiated with and approved by the Departnent for that fisca l year t hat center shal l pay the m~ount of the excess to the Department and, should it fail to c:.o so, the Department is expressly authorizecl in addition to any other remedies it nay have to hold back the ar;count of t hat excess from any reir:illursement to be made to t hat center in the next fiscal year. Sec 13. Payments to child development centers (s lot- funded where contracts call for payment per child placed, to child developnent homes, or to in-home caregivers shall be made according to the following rates effective October 1, 1976 a) Ful l Day Care (1) Child Development llor.1es 4. 50 per day per child. 6395 Di strict of Col umbia Register 1 8 F'EB 1977 2 Child DeveloprnPnt Centers 8 0 per l ay per chil with $1.00 added when transportation is providAd 3) In-Home Care A) For care during the day 2.75 pe r child p9r day B) For care durinq night hours 3.50 p8r child pP.r niqht b) Part-time Care (1) Child DevelopmPnt Homes 3.00 per day 9~r child for before and after school care. {2) Child Development centers 4.00 per day per child for before and after school care 3) In-Home care A) Before and after school care 1.75 per child per day B) For night care of less than six hours 2.00 per child per night. Sec. 14. Only licensed child development faciliti es shall he used by the Department when day care is arranged in other than the child's own home or in homes of relatives within t he deqree sp~cified by licensinq requirements. Sec. 15. Guidelines and standards for in-home care ar~ set forth as follows: 6396 District of Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 l) I n-home care within the chi l &amp;lt;l s own home t&amp;gt;y 'ln in- home careqiver shall be u sed only when other da y ca re:&amp;gt; plan s are not fea s ihle and in-home ~are offers greater he nefits to the mo t.her or o~her r esponsible rel a tive and the child b In-home car e ma y be providPd as appropriat e and ~vail ab le, for children of eligibl e persons in traininq and during their subsequent mployment and for AFDC chi l dren livin1 with ~aretaker relatives (not pa r ents) when day o r night care is r e quired due to employment of the caretaker relative c) In-home ca r e shal l be ar r anged by mutual agreement betwee n the ch i ld s own mo t her or caretaker r elative, the in- home careqiver and th0 Department d s e l ection of t he in- home careaiver sh a ll be made by the parent, s ubject to f ina l approva l by the Department e The Depa rtmen t shall make dire ct payments to the in home careqiver for services rendered f) The in-home careqiver shal l be of an a ge between 21 an d 7 0 years q) The in- h ome careg ive r shal l furni s h the Department with the same me dica l cert i ficat i on of qood health as that required fo r licen se~ c a reqiv~r s pursuant to section 4 03 (h) of Requlation No 74- 34 (Chi l d Development Faci lities Requlation Further, the in-home careqiv e r s h a ll furnish G'l9 District of CollL~~ia Regi ster 1 8 FEB 1977 the Deoartrn~nt wi th rnPdica l certification of aood health for any child of her own whom she brings to the home of thP mother or caretaker relative h) Duti e s of the in-home careqiver shall be limited to supervision of the chi l d or ch i ldren in her car e preparation and serving of appropriate meals or snacks, and washinq of dishes and utensils used in the preparation of food i) The in-home ca r eqiver shal l have no more than t wo preschool children of her own {i) ThP in-home careqiver shall not care for children other than her own and t he child or chi l dren of the AFDC mother or caretake r r e lative k) If the in- home car ea iver brinqs h e r own children to the home of the AFDC mother or caretaker relative an aqreement shal l be reached between them as to the amount of food she brinqs for the i r needs 1) The in- home careqiver shall have prior experience in child care, either with h0r own children or siblinqs Sec. 16 a Any child development center or child development home that contracts or aqrees with the Department to provide day ca r e shall comply with all applicable provisions of Regulation No. 74-34 (Child Development Faciliti~s Requlation 6398 District of Columbia Register 1 8 FEB 1977 (h) Child dovPlopmPnt facilities contracti nq or aqreeinq with the DPpartment to provide day car which a r e include~ in the proqrams for Feder a l r~i mbursement shall comply with all applicable Fe1era l requlations an~ requir e m0 nts. Sec. 17. Th e D~partment shal l ~e responsi ble for monitoring the provision of day car e services to assure that a0equate services are provided to the children and t hat contractual and other agreements are met. Sec. 18 RPgulations No 69-9 No. 71-1 and No. 74-23, approved February 7, 1969 January 5, 1971, and August 29, 1974 respectively, are herehy repealed. sec. 19. This act shall be effective at t he end of the period provid ~d for Congressiona l r e vi ew of acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in subsection (c) of sect i on 602 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governm~ntal Reorganization Act. 6 J9~</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
