<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-22">
  <num type="law">1-22</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-10-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-22.pdf">D.C. Law 1-22</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 2083</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-22 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-25, which was referred to the Committee on Human Resources and Aging. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 13, 1975, and May 27, 1975, respectively. Enacted without signature by the Mayor on June 24, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-27 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>D.C. LAW 1-22 In the Council of the District of Columbia October 21, 1975 To establish for the District of Columbia a Commission on the Arts and Humanities, and for other purposes. Be it enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia, That this act may be cited as the •commission on the Arts and Humanities Act Authority to the Council to Act Sec. 2. The enactment of this act by the Co~ncil is done pursuant to the authority vested in the Council under Sec. 404(b) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. Definitions Sec. 3. As used in this act 1) The term •Mayor" means the Mayor of the District of Columbia established under section 421 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act 2) The term •council" means the Council of the District of Columbia established under section 401 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act 3) The term "Commission• means the Conunission on the Arts and Humanities established by section 4 of this act 4) The term "arts• includes but is not limited to music (instrwnental and vocal dance, drar.ta, folk art, creative writing, architecture and allied fields, painting, sculpture, D.C. LAW 1-22 In the Council of the District of Columbia October 21, 1975 To establish for the District of Columbia a Commission on the Arts and Humanities, and for other purposes. Be it enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia, That this act may be cited as the •commission on the Arts and Humanities Act Authority to the Council to Act Sec. 2. The enactment of this act by the Co':1llcil is done pursuant to the authority vested in the Council under Sec. 404(b) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. Definitions Sec. 3. As used in this act 1) The term "Mayor• means the Mayor of the District of Columbia established under section 421 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act 2) The term •council" means the Council of the District of Columbia established under section 401 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act 3) The term •commission• means the Commission on the Arts and Humanities established by section 4 of this act 4) The term •arts• includes but is not limited to music (instrumental and vocal dance, drana, folk art, creative writing, architecture and allied fields, painting, sculpture photn9raphy,_graphic Rnd craft arts, indnr;trial ne!l;iqn, costume and fR~hion riesign, moti.on pictures, teleiTision, radin, tapP. and sound recordinq, and the arts rclatP.d ~o the oresentation, per.formAnce, exec11tion exhibi ti.on of tho!ie major art form and the study and application of the arts to the human environment 5) The ·term "humanities" inclunes, but is not limiten to, the study nf the foUowing: language, bo+:h modern and classical: linguistics: literatur histor.y1 jurispruoence1 nhilosophv1 archeoloqy: comparative religionr ethics: the history, criticic;m, theory nd practice of the arts: those aspects of the ~ncial sci.Pncas which have humanistic cnntent and employ hnrnanistic methndsr and the study and apnlicatirm of the humanities to the li.uMan P.nv:l.ron ent with partir:ular attentj.on to he relevancP. of the 'hU!'\anii:j.ec; to the current cnndif::i.ons of national life. P.stablishment of thP. roll'IJ'l'lissinn Sec. 4(a) In order to evaluate and initiate ac+:ion on matters relat;.n~ to the arts, to encournge proqrarn.s ann the cievelcprn.ent of programs which promote pro9reRs in the arts, there is established, in the Office of the Mayor, in the nistrict of r.olumbia, a com:m5.ssion to be known as the Commission on the Arts and nnmanitiPs. The ~ofl'!rT\ission shall Cl")nsist ot: eiqhteen rnembers appointed hy the Mayor, with the advice and consent of the ~ouncil. F.aeh mP.rnber appointed to the Commission shall be a persnn who has nisplaved an interest or an abilitv in nne o~ the variou!l; field~ of the arts or hurn.~nities and/or has beP.n a~tivP in the .feurt.herance nf the art~ or li.nmanities in thP. nistrict of rolUl'\b;f'l. Memb~r shall be appointen to P.n~ure that tltjl!illy arP. http:attent;.on 3 reprP.sentative of all the various qeoqr.aphic areas and neiqhborhnrH~s within the nist:r.i~t nf roJ nMbia b) MemhP.rs o.f thP. romJTtiss~ o hall s~rve terms nf tliT"ee ye~r~1 exr.P.pt, o~ the Members fir.qt nopain~P.d ix Member~ qhall he appoint for one year iy JnbeTq ~hall be ~ppninted ¥or two year and c;ix shAll be aooointP.d for three ye""ri 1'S dP.b~rmined by the Mayor. MeMbt=-r.s of the rommissinT'I 1"1&amp;lt;tY be r~anpoint'°'dr but cannot ~ervt More than two consecut.i VP. ter.Jl'\c l"e~s shnll re9ularly begin on l July and end on Jn June of the resp~ctive calendar yeari inc1 udinq the members fi.rst app_ointed c) Should a vacancy occ:ur, a successor sha.J.1. be appoint~d by the Mayor wi thirt 30 (lays, with the advice and ~onsent of thP. f"ouneil tr"l erve until the end of the tPrl l'&amp;gt;f the Me~ber. whom that RUCc~ssor ~ueceeds. Failing to receive thP nomination within t~e Jn days, the Council shall aopnint a person to ~ill th~ vacancy. Members o the roMJ'Ttiss inn on the /\.rts and Purnanities established under or~ani?.ation Order number 7A-4 of Jcmuary 7, lt'\7A, issued by the rnl"U'!\issioner. nf the "istriet nf rolul"'hia, shAll eo"t:i.nue to serv411! un-t:i, the Mel'"hers of the oJ'l"II'\issinn eic;tablished under this act are appointed and q.u21.lifv he ~ayor shall noMinate memberc; to the new co'J"lm:i.ssion within thirtv rtavs of enactment of this act d) The Mayor shall nominnte the chairper~on ~or th ommission e) Members of the ro1"'1 issiDn shall ~erve without compen!!ation, but hall be entftleii to recei in accord&amp;lt;\nC~ with appl.ic~ble l"istrict of Colurrbia ogulatirms, reimburse1"1ent http:eXr.p.pt 4 for expP.nsei 5.ncurr~d w'i.ile l'lctually r.&amp;gt;erforMing duti~s vec::tP.d in th f Co Mi s s ion Power~ of th~ Cornrnissinn Sec. 5 he ComMis~ion shall a take action concP.rriing the neeas of the re!!ildent!!i of the District of Colurbia for activities in the art~ and hUT"!ani ties, anc1 concf.!rning the develonrnr.int C\nd improvP.m~nt of activities in the art~ and hul anities in thP. f'listr.ict of Columbia b) preparP. al"\ annual plan of artistic nrojP.ct~ a,,d proci.uctions in the District of Colu?T1bia mP.~ting the requirement~ of sections S(c) and S(CJ) of the ~lational Foundation on t 1.e Arts and lh..tManiti~s Act of l073, n.nd act: a.s the designated ~tate a~ency for the nistrict of Colu~nia s ref~rred to in ~ection S(g 2 A) of the Foundation on Arts and Humanities Act of 1965, as.arnen~ed7 (c) Make grants to individuals and groups of individual~ for projects and proructions in the arts and huma!'litiAs d) cooperate with govP.rnmental d~partments and a9encies, priv~tP. organization and resident!!i of the District of Colurrtbi~ to develop·~nd undertak~ pro~ra~s which will encourage ma!&amp;lt;:i~um r;.iarticip~ti in act;.vitie~ in the arts and hnmanitie!ll anfl oromotP. qrP.ater appreciaf:j.nn and enjoyr.tP.nt of e arts and humanitiP.S1 (e) ace~~t gifts, contributions and bP.que~t~ nf mon~y and property tn can out thP purpnses of this act, which http:humanitip.s1 http:appreciatj.nn 5 g-ifts shall be depos.ited in any dPpoRitnrv in compliance with the laws of thP. nistrict of rolu~bia f) be Pmpowered to appoint advisory panelR in the various fields of th~ arts and humanitie.s, as the ~ommission may d~P.m necP.ssary, the members of which shall serve without compensation g) adopt and modify by-laws and be empowered to adopt reCNlations as authori?.ed bv lcn Administration of the _commission Sec a) There shall be an executive director for the Cornrnission who shall be appointed by the romJnisRion he executive director shall be the chief adMinistrative officer of the CommisRion and shall be respnn~iblP. for supervising the remainder of the staff of the Commission e shall report regularly to the ColTII!\issinn on his a.cti vi ties. The execut ve director shall receive annual coMpensatio~ fixP.d in accordance with chapter 51 of ~itle 5, u Code b he Commission shall·me~t rnonthlv, except·when a Meeting is cancelled by the chairp~rson and a majority of the CoMrTli~Aion. Special meetings of the Commission may be called by the Mavor, Council, chairperson of the Co1"'1!!1ission, or up~n thP. request of five members of the Commission c) The Col!U'!tission shall prepare and subMit to the Mayor an annual budget to he included in the re9ular budg~t prncess of the District of ColuMbia neveloped in accornanc~ with subpart 1 of Part D of Title IV of the Di~trict o &amp;lt;F Columbia ~el f-&amp;lt;;overnl""ent and r.overnm~ntal Reorqani?.ation Act. http:authori7.ed Ii n he Chairp~rc:;on shall submit tn the Mayor and the council the annual reports of the ComrrtiRsion's Rctivities, ancl its plar:is, r~col"'UnP.ndations, and nroi ~ctions for the followjn" year. These reports shall accompa~y the budqet requP.st in sub- section c Miscellaneous ~ec. 7(a he Mayor shall instruct the Office of Manag~rn~nt and llndaet Systems to.coordinate with the rommission the establlshment of a booY.reP.pin9 and ac countinq !l;yster.i to allt')w for swift transference of crrRnts MoniP.s from the nistrlct GovernneT1t to a r~c;.piP.nt, and shall instruc that Office, in concert with thP. CoIT'misslon, to establish a voucher sy tP.M whir:h would also ·allow for the swi .ct tr.ans ference of funds from the District Govern~nt to arant recipients b) Nomine~s for the CoJ'F'!I!'tission.shall he resid~nts of thP District ~f Columbia c) The Cotnnission c:;ha.11 establish procer!ures in its bv-laws to 'handle conflicts of interest in the awardinq of grants, when any commissioner has either a structural or ~iduci~ry relati.onship with a qrantee. Repealers ~ec. s he ord.P.r o~ the Commission of the nistrict of Columbia, numbered 74-4, issued January 7, 1974, is hereby repealed and th~ r.ommission on the ~rts and numani~iP.s establishPd by that ordP.r is abolished. All property, records, and un~xp~nden halances of apnropriations ann other money http:s i.ct http:r~c;.pip.nt I 7 availablP. to th&amp;lt lt rol'IQ'l'lissinn on the 1\rtc: and th1J'l'\anitir-os i~ transferren to the rornmission establishP.n bv this act. Docket for the Dill 1-25 Conold~rcd in Council 5/13/75 l"irst vote 5/13/7 5 Final vote in Council 5/27/75 Coun.cil RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE Co I c I YE I f. J 1 r u I II 11 11 A !l1NO r.ri.;1&amp;lt;.D.J!.A cr..v1:c11 11o11;i.111r::n ,Yt:S;UO if&amp;gt;.A.!A.0.:H.A.l°C:C:l.l Cll t:Ml•CH ·Yt;s O .r•.A.jA.S.·H ruCK::tR _Ix L. 1-iron&amp;lt;oN ~x 1 r ifS"fiur.OIN.G_txi i i 1 I MOOREL D. I _J x I! HARDY I nr 1iwu.soN ixCI. i I i~ tll\T?T?v I x I l~SON x lw.m.rER LK.J_ I Tl ClARY~ 1 v 1 11 Mno..RE. r. Ix i l 1 1 r =1_ t 1 J -C.Ot l:ES I x l iLSEACKLUO.Nlx.L I I 1 i J I I L.J x_r_na_1_cD_1_cs~V-c_1c P R._P_r_cs_·c_n1 A n A~l~,s~cn~1 n A n t p~!r J Q.,Lt J.i!U.,u A lSecretary of he- Council 1 0 JUN ms Presented t6 the Uayor Meyer's action approve disapprov.e·s k?:ii J1r1 1975 Enacted without Mayor's signature secretary of the Council oUHCll ir Mllf'll Final vote in Council~S 2_7 7_S Presented to the rt:ayor June 10, 1975 Q.;LV csecretary of the Council) Meyor's action approve disapprove a Mayor's Sign~ture) Enacted without Mayor's signature Tune 24, 1975 0.:W secretary of the Council </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-201"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-202"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-203"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-204"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-205"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-205.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§39-206"/>
  </section>
</document>
