<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-27">
  <num type="law">1-27</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-10-30</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-27.pdf">D.C. Law 1-27</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 2470</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-27 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-90, which was referred to the Committee on Advisory Neighborhood Councils. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 17, 1975 and July 1, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 4, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-39 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COU NC!L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self Government and Governmental Re~rganizat!on Act, PL 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-90 on first and second readings June 17, 1975, and July l, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August 4, 19751 this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-39, published in the August 15, 1975, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c){l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby q!ves notice that the 30-day Congressional reView period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law No. 1-27, effective October 30, 1975 1 CKER o. c. Law ~o. 1~27 In t&amp;amp;e Council of the District of Columbia To amend the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to change the name of the Advisory Neighborhood Councils. Se it enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia That this act may be cited as the "Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act Sec 2(a) Section 738 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorqanization Act is amended as follows 1) The section heading of such section 738 is amended by striking out "COUNCILS" and inserting in lieu thereof "COMMISSIONS 2) Such section 73&amp;amp; is a~ended by striking out •neighborhood council" each place it appears in that section, and insertin9 in lieu thereof in each such place •neighborhood commission 3) Such section 738 is amended by striking out •neighborhood councils" each place it occurs in that section, and inserting in lieu thereof in each such place •neighborhood commissions t \ 2 b) Tr..e table of contents of such Act 1s a er..d&amp;amp;d. by str!.k:t out "Sec. 738. Ad.visor/ neigbl:ornccd ccm:i ssicr.s ot Inter.!st Act (D.C. Code, see. l 2! et seq is ed. as t'ollcws a) Section 40l(a 5) 0£ s-.ic!l Act (D.c. ecc:e, sec. l-ll5l(a)(o is amerxied by s ild g eut "Ad:vtsor.l Ne g:lbor ocd C cil n a ld 1 l:!erti g (b) Seeticn 401(0) or such Act (D.C. ecc.e see. l-ll6l(b is ed a:r:d insert:ir..g l 1 eu t.b.e eef e r sor.1 Ne!g bori ecd Ccaa%.ss1cn a:-1.'i 2 e) Secticn 402(a}(l) 0£. such Ac D.C. Cede, see. l-llo2(a}(l} d) Section 502(1} of such Act (D.C. Code, sec, 1~1182(1)} as add.eel http:Sectj.cn r 3- Sec. 4. NJ;y re!erer.ee 1."l a:trJ law of or rel.a.ting solely to tt.e Di st i.ct of Columbia or i l any rule eg lation, pa;e report or otbe: doc~.e"lt ot the D strict of Colt:ttbi.a gove_~nt (ir.eludi S any agency the eO to the Advi.soI"J Ne bcr ccd Cour~ils sr..all be ed. to be, a ter tl e e!fecti ve by. secticn o02(c of the Dist Lc:t of Colcmb a Sel C-ove ent a d. C-cve \ http:re!erer.ee</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
