<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-29">
  <num type="law">1-29</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-29.pdf">D.C. Law 1-29</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-1.98 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-123 on first and second readings July 1, 1975, and July 15, 19 75, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August 8, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-40, published in the August 25, 1975, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, \ cites the following legislation as D. C. Law No. 1-29, effective November 1, 1975. Chairman of the Council D. C. Law No. 1-29 In the Council of the District of Columbia November 1, 1975 To expand the District of Columbia Law Revision Commission. Be it enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Law Revision·Commission Expansion act Sec. 2. Subsection (a) of section 2 of the "District of Columbia Law Revision Commission Act" is amended as follows: {a) The superlanguage of said subsection is amended by deleting therefrom the word "fifteen" and inserting in lieu thereof the word "nineteen read b) Item (7) of said subsection 1s amended to \ 7) Three members shall be appointed by the Council of the District of Columbia, one of whom shall be a nonlawyer, and one of whom shall be a member of the law faculty of a law school in the -2- District of Columbia PROVIDED That, any appointment made by the Chairman of the District of Columbia Council which fits the foregoing criteria shall remain in effect and shall count as one of the three appointments provided for by this item c) Said subsection is amended by adding thereto a new item 11 which shall read: read 11) One member shall be appointed by the Director of the District of Columbia Public Defender Se~vice d) Item (8) of said subsection is amended to 8) Three members shall be appointed by the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia PROVIDED That, any appointment or appointments made by said Joint Committee before July 15, 1975 shall remain in effect and shall count as one .or more of the appointments provided for by this item 3- Sec. 3. This act shall take effect upon becoming law by operation of section 602 of the District of Columbia Self- Goverment and Governmental Reorganization Act.</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
