<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-36" flag="true">
  <num type="law">1-36</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1975-11-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-36.pdf">D.C. Law 1-36</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 2292</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-36 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-115, which was referred to the Committee on Higher Education/University of the District of Columbia. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 15, 1975 and July 29, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 25, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-50 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> J c COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE ?ursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia {~lf Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 he Act the Council of the District of Columbia adooted Bill No. 1-115 on first and second readings July 15, 1975, and July 29, 1975, respectively. Following the signature of the C l·layor on August 25, 1975, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-SO, published in the D. c. Register on October 6, 2975, and tran.:mi tted to both Houses of Congress fer a 30-day review, I n accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period nas expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law No. 1-36, effective November l, 1975. J_j_ Chairman Council £ \ 1 l \ D.C. LAW No. l-3fi In the Council of t.~e District of Columbia November 1, 1975 To amend the District of Columbia ~ublic Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act. Be it enacted by the Council of the District of Columbia, That this act may be citen as "The District of Columbia Public Postseconnary Education Reorganization Act Amendments PTTRPOSE Sec. 2. It is the intent of the Council of the District of Cclu ia to approve the Congressional intent expressed in section 102 o! the District of. Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Re~rganization Act (D.C. Code, secs. 31-1701 et seq hereinafter =e!erred to as the •Act to authorize a public land-grant University through the reorganization of the existing local institutions of puhlic post secondary educ&amp;amp;tion in the District of Columbia, and that the land-grant ftmds shall be utilized by the University in accordance with the provisions of t.;e Act of July 2, 1862 (7 o.s.c. 3nl-305,3n7,308 known as the First Morrill Act Additional.ly it is the clear and specific intent of the Council of the District of Columbia that the University provide a range of programs, studies r l I 2 and degrees designed to reach the widest possible number of citizens and residents of the District of Columbia including career and technological education, libera"l arts, sciences, teacher education; and associate, graduate, post graduate and professional degrees and studies. Central to this is a governing board with the authortty to provide a policy framework and such administration as are necessary to carry out such policies under the law. The function of the board is to build a University to serve the residents of the District of Columbi~ consisting of, but not limited to, strong. programs of liberal arts studies and vocational-technical education in accordance with the provisions of this Act. Sec. 3. Section 103 of the Act (D.C. Code, sec. 31-1702) i s amended to read as follows Definitions "Sec. 103. For the purpose of this Act a) The term 'Trustees' means the Board of Trustees established under title II of this Act b) The term 'chief executive officer• means the chief executive and administrative officer of the University \ t 3 c) The term 'University' means the University of the Distrtct of Columbia authorized and directed to be established under title Il of this Act. I J d) The term 'academic and administrative head' means the academic and administrative head of each of the components of the University e) The term 'Mayor' means the Office of th~ Mayor of the District of Columbia established by section 421 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganizatibn Act. 11 (f) The term Council' means the Council of the District of Columbia established by section 401 of the District of-Columbia Self-Government and Governmental f\eorganization Act. 11 (g) The term 'Board of Higher Education' means the Board of Higher Education established under section 102 of the District of Columbia Public Education Act {D.C. Code, sec. 31-1602 11 {h) The term 'Vocational Board' means the Board of Vocational Education established under section 202 of the District of Columbia Public Education Act (D. C. Code, sec. 31-1622 1) The term 'Board' means the District of Columbia Board of Education established under section 3 03 of the Elected-Board of Education Act (D.C. Code, sec. 31-101 4 j) The term 'financial institution' means an insured bank as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, or a savings and loan association as defined in section 401 of the National Housing Act. I k) The term 'component' means that segment of the whole I University such as a school, college branch or campus, which, because of its nature, the Board of Trustees specifies as constituting an identifiable entity for the purpo~e of but not limited to, being administered by an academic and ad mini strati ve head Sec. 4. Sections 208. and 209 of the .Act are renumbered 2 09 and 210 respectively. Sections 201, 202, 203, 204, 205, 206, and 207 of the Act {D. C. Code, secs. 31-1711 31-1718) are amended to read as follows Title II Board of Trustees "Sec. 2 01 a) There is hereby established a body corporate by name of the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia and by that name and style shall have perpetual succession. It shall be charged with the responsibility of governing the University of the District of Columbia and shall possess all the powers necessary or convenient to accomplish the objects and 5 perform the duties prescribed by this section. Pursuant to this section and sections 206 and 403 of this Act, it shall have the power to adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal which shall be I i judicially noticed; and to make contracts; to sue and be sued, to J complain and defend in its own name in any court of competent jurisdiction; to make, deliver, and receive deeds, leases and other instruments and to take title to real and other property in its own name: and to adopt, prescribe, a.mend, repeal, and· enforce s uch by-laws, rules and regulations as it may deem necessary for the governance and administration of the University b) There is hereby authorized to be established an independent agency of the goverrunent of the Dist:Iict of Columbia known as the University of the District of Colum- bia which shall be governed by the Board of Trustees as established in subsection (a) of this section c) Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, such Board of Trustees shall consist of fifteen votinq members selected in the follcwinq manner l) eleven members shall be appointed by the Mayor by and with the advice and consent of the Council; i, i 6 2) one member shall be appointed by the student cOI:'lmunity of the University and shall be a full time student at the University: and 3) three members shall be appointed by the alumni associations in the following manners A) one member of the Trustees appointed by the Alumni Association of the District of Columbia Teachers College, wit!l. notice t iereof to the !1ayor within forty-five days after the effective date of this section B) one member of t.~e Trustees appointed by the Alumni Association of Federal City College, with notice thereof to the 1ayor within forty-five days after the effective date of this section: and "{C) one member of the Trustees appointed by the A!um i Associatio~ of the Nashington Technical Institute~ with notice thereof to the tayor wit."1in £orty-five days after the effective date of this section 7 {d) Prior to consolidation as authorized in section 205 of this Act, the Board of Trustees shall consist of seventeen voting members selected in the followinq manner: R(l) eleven menberS Shall be Selected in I the same manner as in paraqraph (1 subsection (c) of this section 2) three members shall be selected in the same manner as in paragraph 3 subsection c) of this section: and 3) three members shall be app?inted by the Mayor PROVIDED that one of such members shall be a full time student at Washington Technical Institute, one of such members shall be a full time student at Federal City College and O.'le of such members shall be a full time student at the District of Colu.T'Zlbia Teachers Colleqe e) In the event that the appointments referred to in paraqraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (c) of this section are not made within the ti~ s~cified, the Mayor shall make the appoint.~ents. w(f) As the initial terms of the alumni members expire, the three alumni trustees shall ~e appointed by t.~e Alumni Association of the University or the Mayor if no alumni association of such University exists. \ 8 g) The Trustees shall hold the first meeting no later than thirty days after the confirmation and or appoint- ment of eleven of its members The first meeting. of the I I Trustees shall be convened by a member of the Trustees J designated by the Mayor h) The student member of the Trustees shall serve a one-year term of office; all Trustees may be selected to serve one successive term i) The terms of non-student Trustees shall be for 5 years; except that the terms of office of the non-student members first taking office shall be determined by lots to provide l) Three shall serve terms of two years 2) Three shall serve terms of three years 3) Three shall serve terms of four years {4) Five shall serve terms of five years. 11 (j) Any Trustee selected to fill a vacancy shall be selected only for the remainder of the term for which bis or her predecessor was selected and in the same manner as the 9 original selection. A Trustee may serve after the expiration of his term until his successor has qualified to take office k) A Chairperson and Vice Chairperson i(l) shall be selected by the Trustees from among the District of I Columbia resident members (2 shall serve a one-year term as Chairperson or Vice Chairperson (3) may be reselecte"d, and (4) cannot serve in such capacity beyond their term as member. II (1) Members of the Trustees may be employees of the United Sta~es or of the District of Columbia Government, unless they hold positions in clear conflict of interest. 11 (m) The chief executive officer of the University shall be a non-voting ex-officio member of the Trustees n) All appointments under this sectic.,n shall be made not later than forty-five days after the effective date of this section Nominating Committee "Sec. 202 a} There is established within the Government of the District of Columbia a committee to be known as the University of the District of Columbia Board of Trustees Nominating Committee \ 10 hereinafter in this Act referred to as the 'Committee b) The Committee shall consist of five members to be appointed as follows: j l) Two members shall be appoint~d by the Mayor within thirty days after the effective date of this section 2) Three members shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia with the approval of the Council, within thirty days I after the effective date of this section c) No individual may be appointed as a member of the Committee unless he or she 1) is a citizen of the United States 2) is a resident of the District of Columbia and has maintained his or her domicile within the District of Columbia for the twelve months immediately preceding the effective date of this section: and 3) is not a member of the Council of the District of Columbia or an officer or an employee of the Government of the District of Columbia (including the judicial branch 11 d) Members of the Comnittee shall serve for terms of f1 ve years, except that of the IneI?bers first appointed pursuant to paragraph (b)(l) of this section, one shall serve for one year and one for five years, as designated at the time of appointment; and of the meneers appointed pursuant to paragraph (b)(2) of this secticn, one shall serve for two yea.-s 1 one for three yea.-s and one :for four yea.-s, as designated at the t:i..m! of appointment e) Whenever a vacancy on the Comnittee occurs, such vacancy shall be filled in the same mnner in which the or appointmen was a.de. Arzy ir..di vidua1 appointed to fill a vacancy, occurring other thaE upon the expiration of a term shall serve only for the remaincier of tbe term of such individual's p:-edecessor f) Within ten days following the date en which a tt.ajcrity of the re bers a.re f:L.-st c:.ppoir.ted pursua."lt to this section, such me.lllbers so appointed sr.all hc1.d their first ~ting as rnenbers of the Comnittee g) Except as other ise provided !n t lis section, the Con?II ttee shall act ol"IJ.y at r.leet lgs called by the Chairperson of the Comr.ittee or a majority of the meni:lers thereof and only after notice has beo..n g ve.'1. of such meeting to all merrbers of the Ccmn1 ttee 12 h) The Committee shall choose annually from among its members a Chairperson and such other officers as it deems necessary. The Commi~ee may adopt such rules of procedure as may be necessary to govern the business of the Committee. II i) Each agency of the Govern.men~ of the District of Columbia shall furnish to the Committee, upon request, such records, information, services and such ot~er assistance and facilities as may be necessary to enable the Committee to per-lorm its function properly. Any information furnished to the Committee designated 'confidential' by the person furnishing it to the Committee shall be ~ated by the Committee as privileged and confiden:!tial 13 i lhe Ccmili.ttee shall have the function of nominating individuals to the Mayor for a:;pointmmt as ~ers of tr Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Coluzmia other than the IIeI!i:&amp;gt;ers or the J Trustees appointed by the altm'li associatiOrJ:S and the student con:munity and the three student n!Stees appointed prior to consolidation. Additior.ally, tne Conmi ttee shall fill any and all vacC-"lcies other t the ali.mni and student members occurring on such,,Boa.rd after the date on which a majority of the embers firs appointed I pu suant to this section hold their rst meeting as members of the Board of Trustees k Ihe Comn:1.ttee shall develop a list of namas of not less than twenty-five persons, who must be esi- dents of the District of Columbia and have ma.inta ned the C don:icile within the District of Colu:Dia for one yes imr.ediately preceding the effective date of ~s section and who, in the opinion of the Co:mittee are qi.:alif1ed and available to be appc!r.:ed to the Eccrd of 'I'r.;stees he Comnittee is to trar.s it the list .C'I na"l'es to the Mayor with1n thirty days !ran the date of the last appointment to the Cc:mnittee ll I \ l In the event of a:rry vacancy en the Board of Trustees of the University of the Distrtct of Coll.mD:ta&amp;gt; the Camnittee shall, within thirty days a:rter such I vacancy occurs, submit a list of three persons as I ncrn:1nees for appointment by the Mayor to fill the vacancy. If' roore than one such vacancy exists at t le sarre time, the Camnittee shall stibmit a separate list of nominees for appointnent to fill eac 1 suc 1 vaca"lcy, and no indi v:i.dual' s name shall CiH'ear on more than one ~uc.11. list. In filllng such vacancy, the rtiayor appo:.nt\ mre than one 1nd1 vidU2.l from a:rry list cUITe."ltly before the Mayor m) Whenever a vacancy on the Board of Trustees is to occur as a result of the exp:iration o'£ a term o:f a member, the Comnittee shall transmit a llst of names to the Mayor of tl":ee nc:ni."lees for appointment to fill such vacancy, at lea.st thirty days prior to the expi.ra- tion of such meI:Jber' s term n) All Meycral appoi ltmmts which are subject to the provisior..s c h!.s section shtll be Cram iron aro:'l.g the r.a=Es cf t~e persc s t:-ar..sd. tted to the Mayor by the Col?m1.ttee Suspe sion Remov-c.l a."ld Te1 na-:ion "Sec. 203 a) A.'Tf ~tee shall be ai tc::i::ati.cal.ly suspended frc::i serv-1 ng as suc 1 I:ell'ber after he has been found guilty 15 of a felony by a court of cOI.petent jUrisdiction. Upcn a i'inal detert!Ulation of his guilt or mnocence, the term or such meIIber shall autanatically terminate or be reinstated. ff&amp;lt he Board or 'Irustees shall have the power to rem::ive er, after fair notice and an oppor tunity to be heard, at arq time for adequate cause ·which relates to such members' character or efficiency as a Trustee c) 1Ihe tenure of the student IIS'.ber shall auto- matica.l.J.y term1nate if the status of such ~er ceases \ to be that of a full t:L l: student at the Uni ver-si t;y CO gt;Snsation "Sec. 204. Trustees shall se?"Ve without cc::c;&amp;gt;ensation, but may be reilitlursed for their exper.ses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rr:a.:d.mJm rate equal to the daily equ1 va- lent pro-r-:ied for by grade 18 of the General Schedule established under section 5332 of title 5 of the United States Code, with a limit of $4,000 per annum, while actually engaged 1n service for the istees Cor.solidation "Sec. 205 he Trustees shall by Septer.her 1, 1976, con- solid.ate the existing public 1 1St tutians of postseconOary education :1n the District of Colurrbia under a single management system to be called the University of the District of Coluzmia, with several c c c c cc \ 16 prog:-a:ns, schools, colleges, ir.sti tutes, CaI1 uses a ld otho_r cc::n- pone::ts that offer a c~rehensive prog:"al:l of public postseconda y education be institutions of public postseconda Y education in the District of Columbia ex1st:1ng illmed1ately prior to bch con I solida.tion shall be dee:ied abolished on the effective ,date of ~°"le co~.sclidation Iherea.~e any reference :in a:r law, rule, regu- la~~c or other doc~nt of the United States or of the District Q! Cclt.mi::l a to suc.'1 1nstit1.ltions sr..all be C.ee ed to be a refe ence to the University of the District of Colur.bia Duties of the Board cf Trustees \ "Sec. 206. It shall be the duty of t:he Trustees to a) Review and evaluate the existing public ll'.sti- tutior..s of pcstsecondary education with respect to (1) accreditation 2) present programs and functions 3) actt:al and potential c~abill~ies, and (4) educational. policies and procedures b l) Establish the Ur.1versity of the District of Colt:!Dia consisting of, but not llmited to, two Dajer cor.pc::ants, liberal a.~d i e a.'1d vocatior.al and teci ical ec1.lcat!cn. 11 2) Prepare and f'rcr.i t:ime to time, revise a long-rari.ge plan for the developmmt of the Ur.:1 versity wr.ich shall include the type a."ld scope cf' pro~ offered and envisioned. Such plan shall 17 also include the developm lt, e~ansion, integra- tion, coordination and efficient use of the facilities, physical plant, curricula and standards or public postsecondary education. Such initial I plan and aIJY revisions thereof shall be made avail I able to the public, the Council of the District of Columbia and the Mayor for a pe..riod or not less than sixty days prior to its il:plementation and the Trustees shall hold such hea and public fonlmS as rrs:y be necessary to receive public response and com:nent on such plans c Establish or approve policies a ld procedu:-es governing ad:nissions, curricula, progt'2m graduati.on, the awarding of degrees, and general policy making for the corr.ponents of the Ur.iversity d) P!'epa e and sub~ t to the Mayor• on a date fixed by the Mayor, an annual budget for t i! fiscal. year beg1.ming October l, 1977. Such budget shall include a p Cposed nilancial opera":i.-rig plan for such f':1scal. yec:r, and a capital and ecucat~onal i r~ts plan fer ·such fiscal year and the succeeding four fiscal years for the University D"le Mayor and the Council sha.11, after review and consideration of the budget submitted by the Trustees, establish the nax:1mJm arrount of funds for each of the major cor:ponents of the University and the total University 18 budget which will be allocated to the Trustees e Ihe 'Irustees may transfer&amp;gt; ci1.J:r-4-r.g the fiscal year, any appropriation balance available for one item of appropriation to another item of appropriations or I to a new program in an amount not to exceed $50, 000 I f) Enter into negotiations and b:ind:L"'lg contracts pu Suant to Council regulations regarding: co ltractir..g with the governments of the United States and District of Coli..mDia and other public and private ncies g) E.'1ter into negotiations and b:!nd:1.ng contracts I pursuant to Council regulations to perfo n or~zed researc.11, tra.ining and dem:mstrations on a re:U!tlursable basis for the United States and the goverT'JIIeilt of the District of Colt:nbia and other public and private ae-encies h x tuition for students atte::iding the University 1) Fix fees, in addition to tui 1on, to be paid by resident a'1d nor.resident students atte:odi."lg the tJrl.i- versity. Receipts frcm these fees shall. oe c:leposited 1 l. a revel vi g fund in one or rore nanc12l ir.sti tutions in the District of Colu:rbia, a ld shall be available for such purposes as the Trustees shaJ.l apprc"Ve &amp;gt; w1 thout fiscal year limitation 19 j) Select, appoint, and fix the compensation for a cr..ief executive officer of the University and of such staff for the Board of Trustees as it deems necessary and approve the appointn:ent and compensation 9f the aca demic and adm1nistra.t1ve heads of each of the ccmponents J of the Uni"llersity and of suc..11 other officers as it deems necessary, i.~cluding legal counsel. In no case shall. c.rzy such conpensation be fixed in an amount in excess of that provided for the Mayor 1.JI'l.less specif'ic authorized by leg1slat1 ve act of the Council The c..1iief executive I officer shall serve at the pleasure of the Tr\ stees k Procure tempo:r-c Y a.'rld intermittent services to the same extent as 1s authorized by sect10 3109 of title 5, United States Code, but at daily rates for individuals not in excess of the ma.ximJm daily rate for GS-18 of the General Schedule unde section 5332 of such title 1) Submit recarrmend.ations to the Mayor and the Council cf the tistrict of Col~ia from tine to time relating to leg1s!ation affecting the J.I'li.stra.ticn and programs of the University m) Develop and define, in ccnjunctian with the faculty, a policy governing acader.ic fi'eedom for the University and establish m:chanisms to ensure its pro- tect1on and enforce~nt 20 n) Perform such duties end make such rules and regulations as rra:y be necessa_ry to C2 l'T'Y out the purposes of this Act o) Seek to establish with the Board a Coordina- tion Comnittee to determine areas of cooperation, coordination a."ld assistance. 11 (p) Utilize the services and seek the counsel and advice of the District of Colurri:lia Cc:mi..ssion an Postsecondary Education 1n planning the development of a progra:i for public postseconda.ry edi.ica.t1.on 1n the Dfst~ct cf ColU!!lbia q Generally deterr.rl.ne, control, supervise, m=nage, and govern all affairs of the Un1.vers1ty. of the District of Coll.mt:ia. Towa d this end the Trustees are au:horized to adopt such policies and regµJ.aticns as it rr'ES deer. wise Personnel System "Sec. 207 a) NotwithstaI".d lg any other provision of lai t!1e 'Irustees are hereby authorized to es tab 4 not earlier tr.an one yeaza a.~d not later tha five yea s ai'ter tbe effective date of this Act, a persor:.el syste l (setting forth r!.n1m..Jm stan- Cards) for all e!Ilt'loyees of carpone:lts, facil!ties, and programs of the University, incluc!1ng but net lim1ted to pay, c::intract terms, vacations and sabbaticals, leave, residence, retire:rent, health 23 convenes its first meeting. Except as provided by this Act all functions, powers, and duties of the Board of Higher Education and the Vocational Board under the District of Columbia Public Education Act of 1966 {D.C. Code, Sec. 31-1601) shall be vested in and exercised by the Trustees. All employees, property {real and personal and unexpended balances (available or to be made available) of appropriations, allocations, and all other funds and assets and liabilities of the Board of Higher Education and Vocational Board are authorized to be transferred to the Trustees, except the functions of licensing institutions to confer degrees as aut.~orized by Public Law 89-791 (D.C. Code, Sec. 29-415 All rules, orders, obligations, determinations and any other understandings of the Board of Higher Education and the Board of Vocational Education shall remain in effect until such time as thev mav be lawfully a.mended, modified or repealed by the Trustees Se 4. Title III of the Act {D.C. Code, sec. 31-1721) is a.rnencee to read as follows Title III Authorizations ftsec. 301 a) There are authorized to be appropriated out of any money in the Treasury to the credit of the District of Columbia such sums as may be necessary for carrying ut out the purposes of this Act b) The chief executive officer is authorized to provide for the expenditure of funds, in amounts not to exceed a L 24 total of $5,000, for such purposes as be deemed necessary within limits that may be specified 1n anrl1.lal appropriations llle chief executive officer shall be personally responsible for the expenditure of appro- priations made pu Suant to this section, and such e:xpendi tures shall be supported by vouchers and shal.1 be audited by the District of Columbia Auditor Sec. 5. Title rl of the Act (D.C. Code, secs. 31-1731 31-1736) is ~ded to read as follows Title rl Jf.iscellaneous "Meetings "Sec. 401 Meet:L"lgS rrB:J be called by the Cnairperson or· a zrzj ority of the members of the 'I'rustees. lJo official action ra=:y be taken by the 'Irustees except at a meeting of the Trustees at whic."l a quorum is present Eleven ?n nbe:-s shall cor.sti tute a quc Z:l but a lesser ni.nber may hold hea i.'l"lgs. Each meetir..g cif the 'I'rt:stees shall be open to the public and held in the District of Ccl1i~rhia with appropr ate notice of eac.'1 such m:etiI".g given to the ge eral publl.c, except a Irzj or1 ty of t~e Trt:.stees rrzy elect to go :ir.tc e.xect tive sessicn to take act lt;r. o:i persoI l..el n:atters Ihe 'Irustees shall meet at stated ti.-n:s established by the Boa.rd of Trustees, bt t not less frequently tl:lan f ct.:r t:L~s a year Ad~_scry Cc::mittees "Sec. 402 Ihe 'I:'ustees shall appoint such advisory 25 ca tttees as are necessary to advise on educational policy. Such advisory cc:mm.ttees may consist of members of the Trustees, students faculty Jient:&amp;gt;ers, pa.rents, govenmental, education, buslliess, 1ndustr1al, labor, and commmity representatives Gifts and Contributions "Sec. 403 a lhe Trustees may accept services, moneys, gifts endowmsnts donations, 2 ld bequests. The Txustees i.11 the:Lr discretion retain or not retain suc."l. in the form in wr.ich they are nade b lhe ~tees shall establish in one or more f'l nancial institutions in the strict of ColimDia the District of" Coltmtia Postsecondary Education Fund here shall be deposited 1n such fund all gtfts and ccr.tr1butions 1n whatever form, i\lnes 1n receipt of services rendered, other t:han tuition, and aJ.1 moneys not included in :he annual operating and capita and educatior..al 1.~rovements ft 1Cis appropriated by Congress. Moneys depcsi ted. therein sr.ia.ll be avail.ab le for invest- ment and shall be distributed n suc."l. 2.'XUntS and :in such :a:anner as the r stees Ir.ay dete1 ne me Trustees are authorized to admi.r.ister such fu d 1 l whatever manner the ~tees may deem 'n°ise and p udent, provided that such a.Cmin stration is lawful a11d does not impose any fiscal burden on the District of Coltmtia 26 c) It is not the intent that a:cy incore derived as a result of such f\md shall take the place of any District or Federal appropriations or arq part thereof but that it shall suppleII2nt such appropriations to the end that the Ur.i versi ty rr2:J ir.prove and increase 1 ts functions, may enlarge 1 ts a eas of service and rrey becarre mere useful to a gr"eater r.trler of people. Notbi"lg 1n this section shall be construed to prevent the 'Irustees from recei v ng gifts, donations, and be- quests from any source and frcr. us~.g the same for such lawtul purposes as the donor or donors designate. II Annual Report "Sec. 404 he Trustees sball ?rake an annual report to the general Jbllc ayer, Council; a"ld the Congress on December 31 of eac yea en the operation of prog:-a s a."ld t!'le expenditure of all ~Ul ds for public pcstseco~~c_'l"J' education in the District of ColU ia. Such a.'1l'lua1 report sr.all ir:cluC.e but not be limited to the scu:-ce, am:unt, d1stril::t.:ticn ar.d eX?e tt=e oi' all funds wtat- eve t!le sa.=ce; and ge!!er-c:l s e::t e c nt data including bt4t :lot l1z::1 ted to race sex, age zj er area cf study, previous and current residency and upon graduation or tenninat1on of study, en loymmt placement Ca.ta consiste!'lt with existing statt tes and Department of F.ealth, f.ducaticn and Welf2 e regulations 27 New Authority Granted Boa Ci of Education "Sec. 405 a be Board may transfer, during the fiscal yea;r, any appropriation balance available for one item of' appropriation to another item of appropriation or to a· new pro- gram in an anount not to exceed $50,000 b Ille Board may enter into negotiations and binding contracts pursuant to Council regulations re- gardi."lg contracti.11g with the governments of the United States and District of Colur.i:lia and other pt:Dlic and private agencies to render and recsive services c Ille provisions in section 204 of this Act, relating to cc:rpensation of the Trustees, sball apply to the !Ile!:lbers of the Board of F.ducation Authority .to Council "Sec. 406. Notwi t.hsta."lding any other provis1on of law, er a.rzy rule of law, nothing in tr.is Act shall be construed as 11 it:!J"l..g the authority of the Council to e act arzy ac"t er resolt tion, after January 2, 1975, pursuant to the Dis":rict cf Ccl~ia Self- matter covered by this Act Effective Dates "Sec. 407. Title I al1d sectio l 202 cf this act shall be effective i l:Ilediately. All other provisic:is of this Act shall be effective on January 2, 1976 28 Sec. 6 lis act shall become effective on the day followi_ng the 30-day Congressional review period required of Council leg;islation under section 602 of the Self-Government and Governmental reorganization Act. Docket for the Bill 1-115 Cons idc red in Council July 15, 197 S First vote Tuly 15, 197 5 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNC:ll. Ml'.MnC:R YCS i rfO n. M.A. COUNCIL. MC DClt TCS NO A D.Jlt A. C:OUNCIL CMOCN YI NOl 1 .l.11 o.1 IX I I x X-Jndica!t'S Vote r&amp;gt n.-Prest'nf A. B \bsent R. A.-ncadopscd ?inal vo-:e in Council July 29, 1975 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE C:O UN C: I MCM':CM I YE NO :P.n o Jo A 1 COUl~Cll CMDCn I I I X I DIXON II 1: SID.CKU:TON x I X-Im.li amp cs V o1r R.-Presenl Absent Ii R. } R cop1ed i YC!'i l N O jr.R .I A.o 111 I X I I I i I X I I I .Jost=fsecretary 0£ the Council JG 8 1975 P~cser.ted to the i a:;or aye s action z approve: V fl 1975 dis&amp;lt pprovc Enacted wi thcut Mayor.'s siynature Secretary of the Council) 2 5 JG 1975 </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
