<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-42">
  <num type="law">1-42</num>
  <heading type="short">Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-01-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-42.pdf">D.C. Law 1-42</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 6311</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-42, the “Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-161, which was referred to the Committee on the Budget. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 29, 1975, and October 7, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 24, 1975, it was assigned Act No. 1-59 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> D. C. Law 1-42 In the Council of the District of Columbia January 22, 1976 To remove the requirement that District revenues be collected into and expended from various special funds. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975" Sec. 2. It is the purpose of this act to establish for the District of Columbia a General Fund for the allocating and accounting for appropriations and their expenditure (including obligations and disbursements and for accounting for cash receipts and balances. To that end, it is further the purpose of this act to abolish the Highway Fund of the District of Columbia, the Motor Vehicle Parking Fund, the Metrobus Fund, the Water Fund, the D. C. Sanitary Sewage works Fund, and the Alcoholic Rehabilitation Fund, and to provide that all moneys previously paid into these funds shall be paid into the General Fund of the District of Columbia established by this act 2- Sec. 3 a) All that matter :L"l the f:1 st secticn of the Act of April 23, 1924 (relatir.g to t e mcto fuel ta \ L"'l the District of Col12:lbia D.C. Cede, sec. 47-1901) beg:i 1 JS "All proceeds of the taxes imposed under th-I's Act is a."nended to read as follows All proceeds of the ta."tes Tipcsed U.'1.der this Act, a ld all rr.oneys collected frcm fees charged for the registration and titling of otor ve!'llcles includ:.r.g fees cha.~ed for the issuance of per:r..its to operate motor I vehicles, s.ba.11 te deposited in the General Fur.d. of the District of Columbia as established by the Reve lue F\lnds Availability Act of 1975 b) Tl".e proviso under the ma.i.1"1 head.1 g "Street and Road Improvement a 1.d Repa!r" of the Act entitled "An Act I Appropriations for the District of Colurr.bia for tr.a isca1 year end.1.ri.g June 20, 192611 approved June 7, 1924 (D C. Code sec. 47-1918) is a.-nended by strikir.:g out "arising fran the expenditure of the fund created by the ta lt; on mot·or-vehic.le fuels, shall be paid into the TreasU..j' of the United States http:mot·or-vehic.le I 3- a."ld be credited to and constitute a part of said fund a.'li shall thereafter be available for appropriation in the same manner as t.he proceeds of the tax on motor-vehicle f'~els. II and inserting. in lieu thereof "shall be pa.id into the General Furi.d of the District of Columbia as established by the Reve."lue F\lrl.ds Avail- ability Act of 1975 c} Section 7 of tr.e District cf Columbia Motor Ve.lU.cle Parking Fac111ty Act of 1942 (D.C. Code, sec. 40-808) 1s amended to read as follows Sec. 7. All fees and other moneys collected tmder this Act, including all fees collected pursuant to section ll of the Act of April 4, 1938 (relating to parldrig meters 1n the District of Columbia} (D.C. Code, sec. 40-616) an:i the Act of June 6, 1940 (relating to pa:-king motor vehicles in M.m:tcipa.l Center} (D.C. Code, sec. 4o-604(a arid all moneys de Oj_ved frcm the sale or assigr.:n:.ent of any property real or personal s.hall be deposited 1n the General Fund of the District of Columbia as establisr..ed by tr..e Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975 http:F\lrI.ds -4 d) Section 203 of the Rev-1.sed Statutes relati g to the District of Columbia (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1523) 1s amer.ded to r-wad as follows Sec. 203 be water tax authorized to be lev1ed and collected by this Act sl all be paid i."lto the C-ener-:i l Fur.d of the Dis tr 1ct of Columbia as establishecl by the Revenue Funds Availability Act of 1975 e) Section 217 of the Revised Statutes relating to the District of Columbia (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1524) is amen:ied to read as follows Sec. 217. All water rents derived f Om the Washington Aql educt shall be paid :L lto the General Fund of' the Distr let of Colt:.nbia as established by the Revenue F 1nds Ava.1.1.ability Act of 1975 The District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954 (D.C. Code, secs. 43-1601~3-1624) is a::r.ended as follows 1) Section 202 of such Act (D C. Code, sec. 43-1602) is repealed 2 Section 203 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1603) is a lenC.ed by (A) strikiri.g out "S;,ibject to apprcpr'_a.tions, the D.C. http:Sl'!lenc.ed 5- Sanitary Sewage Works FUnd" a"l"ld inserti.l'lg in lieu thereof 0 Subject to appropriations, amou.i lts in the C-eneral ?und of the District of Columbia (including any special account·therein) as establlshed by the. P..evenue Funds Availability Act of 1975 B) strild.ng out "D. C. Sanitary Sewage Works Fund" in paragraph (b) thereof and inserting in lieu thereof "General Fund of the District of Columbia (including any special account the ein C) striking out "the GeneraJ. Fund" in parag:-aph (f) thereof; and striking out in paragraph (g) thereof "such Sanitary Sewage Works Fund" a."ld i."lSerting in lieu thereof "the purposes of this Act 3) Section 204 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1604) is amended by striking out "tr..e mneys deposited to the credit of the D.C. Sanitary Sewage Works Fund and inserting in lieu thereof money in the General F\Jnd of the District of Colu:nbia (including arry special account therein 4) Section 206 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1605) is amended by str-1.Jdng out "D.C. Sanitary Sewage Works Fund" and inserti."lg in lieu thereof "General Fu."ld cf the District of Columbia as established by the P.evenue Funds Ava.ilabllity Act of 1975 http:Se~'l2.ge -6 5) Section 210 of such Act (D.C. Cede, sec. 43-1609) is amended by striking out "D.C. Sanitary Sew-c=ge Works Fu 1.d" a."l.d insertihg :in lieu thereof "General Fund of the District of Coli mbia as established by the Revenue Fur.ds Availability Act of 1975 6) Section 214 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1614) is amended by strik:L'"lg out but the COII?nissicner of the District of Columbia, prior to authorizi.l"Jg the use oi' moneys f'rcm such u:!d for such work, sr.a.ll deter.nine the percentage of the cost to be borne by the D. C. San1 tary Se~·lage Works Fund ari.d the percentage to be borne by the General Ft r..d 7) Section 2l7(a) of such Act (D.C. C:xie, sec. 43-16l6(a is a.mended by striking out "D.C. Sanitary. Se\'12ge Works Fund" each place it occurs and inserti."1g :in lleu thereof "General Fund. o! the District of Columbia as establlsh ci :in the Revenue Funds Ava:Uabillty Act of 1975 Sec. 4. The Act of Jur.e 12, 1960 (relat!r.g to the Dulles Interceptor Sewer D.C. Code, secs. 43-1620-43-1624) is ame."lded as follows 7 a All but the first sentence of section 2(b) of such Act (D.C. Cede, sec~ 43-162l(b is repealed b) Section 2(c) of su~h Act (D.C. Code, sec. 43-l62l(c is a le?lded by str1ld.ng outn, a.11d the receipts de 1.ved from said ch~s s Jall be deposited to the credit of the D.C. Sanitary Sewage Works FU.~d (created by section 202 of the District of Colt.tnbia Public Works Act of 1954 c) Section 3 of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 43-1622) is amer.ded by striking out "to the Metropolitan Area Sa 11tary Sewage Works Fund } Section 4(a) of such Act {D.C. Code, sec. 43-1623(a is repealed. Sec. 5 a) Section 16 of the Act of August 4, 1947 (relating to the ehabllitation of alcoholics in the District of Columbia} (D.C. Code, sec. 25-llla s repealed b) Section 15 of the District of Columbia Alcoholic F.eba.billtation Act of 1967 (D.C. Code, sec. 24-535) is amended by striki g out Treasury of the United States to tr.ie credit of a trust fund account, which is hereby authorized, a ld r.z:1 be invested http:str1ld.ng -8- and reinvested as trust funds of the District of Colt.lil'l..bia" a l"Jd inserting 1n lieu thereof "General F\md of the District of Columbia as established-in the Revenue Fi.lnds Availability Act of 1975 Sec. 6. Section 3(d) of Title r1 of the District of Columbia Reve lue Act of 1937 (D.C. Cede, sec. 40-103(d 1s amended. to read as follows d) Th.e proceeds fra:t fees payable U lder this title shall be paid i lto the General Fund of the District of Columbia as established in the Revenue Funds A.vejJah111ty Act of 1975 Sec. 7. Th.e Revenue Act of 1975 is ai""Del"'Aied as follows a) Sections 102(b 103, and 20l(b) of su~h a.ct are repealed b) Section 102 of such act is amended. by str king out a)ff imnedia.tely before nsect1on 6(J c) Section 201 of such act is amended by strildng out 11 a inmediately before "The first sentence d) Section 80l(f) of such act 1s areer.ded by str ldr.g cut "103 9- Sec. 8. Pny reference in any law or pertaining to the District of Colurr.bia, er in any paper, rule, regulation, order, or other doci.m-.ent of the District of Columbia government (including ar;y department, agency, or instI"l.mlentallty thereof) to any fund ·which is ab&amp;lt llihed by this act shall be, after the effective date of tr is act, deemed to be a reference to the General Fund of the District of Columbia established by this act. Sec. 9 a) There is established for the District of Columbia the Ge leral Fund of the District of Columbia (here1na ter in this act referred. to as the "C-eneral Tund wrJ.ch s.t all consist of the followi."lg revenues ll Taxes, feeS charges, an::i miscellaneous receipts 2 Federal payments authorized by sect ons 106 and 212 of the District of Columbia Public Works Act of 1954 and by section 502 of the District of Colurr.bia Self-Gover:mient ar.d Governnental Reorganization Act (D.C. Code, sec. 47-250l(d 3) wans advanced to the District of Columbia by the Secretary of the 'IreasUI"'J, and other loans for operating expenses of the District of Columbia gove~nt. C!-1 An:[ moneys for operat1r.g e;cper.se purposes not otr..erwise designated to be deposited in another .f m.d of the District of Columbia government~ http:e;cper.se -10 b) The Cou."lcil of the District of Colt T.bia from tiir.e to time, establish accounts within tr..e General F..md and· inay direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to :institute such account.1.11g procedures as wzy be necesSCL to separately repo.-t the revenue and exper'.ditures related to individual progre..T.S and activit!.es as it raay desig:'late, except that such directi vas shall nc&amp;gt;t be constr..ied as 11m:Lt1."lg the authority to tra.i lSfer furlds betwee.ri accounts established in the General Fund. Within sixty (60) cays or tr..e effective date of the establishment of any such account by the Council of the District of Columbia, the Mayor shall sutm1t fer Council approval by resolution, a list or the specific tax.es, fees, chSrges, other eCeipts and expenditures deemed to ully represe."lt the revenues and expenditures associated with tr..e activity or progrem of eac..11 accou.~t established c) The Council hereby establishes :L"l the General Fund special accounts for receipts and expenditures related to the follow:ing: http:activ1t!.es -11 1) the provision of water service, includi.rig the operation ot the Washington Aqueduct 2) The provision of sewer service L"lcluding the District of Columbia's share of tr.e cost of Potomac interceotor 3) Revenue derived frcm tte owne!'Ship, licensure, and operation of privately-owned automobiles and other modes of private tra lSportation, inclt.:d1rig, but not llm:Lted to, taxicabs and other motorized conveyances not supported in their operation by public funds; ar..d all public expenditures related to hig ways traffic control ar..d, transportation of persons d) Within 180 days of the effective date of tr.is act abolishing certain special fu."lds, the Mayor shall conduct an audit of each fund as closed and sl'.all submit such au:iit report to the Council. Sec. 10. This act shall be deer.ed to :r-.ave taken ettect on July l, 1975, except for subsections (b) a ld (d) of sec~cn 9 which sti..all take er fect as provided for acts of t{l.e Council 1n section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Gove rnlent and Goverr.menta:i Reorganiza~io Act. f \ Docket for the Dill 1-161 Conoldcrcct in Council 7-29-75 7-29-75 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE lo-1-1s RECORD OF C 0 U N C I L V 0 T. E COUNCii. lto\1 1:.l::A I YE:S l NO ir.11 A.o.!ri.A. jl ~llf.ICll. MEMOLn 1vi:s i r~1'P.lt 1!.A. j. COUNC: II c lt•C l't V l 0 D 1 l f I f I l 111 Tuc~_ER· J..1LL i1-11_ocioN 1 x r-1__J=.11sP.Aur..o.u'fu x r 1 MOORE D. I x I J r-li..HARnv I x r f=E J'l&amp;lt;lill.SD I x I I J BARRY I tj I I Ii HOBSON I. x I JivnNTER I I I I 1 C..L.I RKE j_ x I I ]L..M.QQRE. J. 1 x j L_l_J__J! I L I I l COAIES I 1 l x I ll.S.HACKlJ'.c.I.ON x L_L_J_J !1 l._I I I i X-Intiic11!cs Vote R.-Prcscnt A \l•.st•nl n. A Rl amp;ti"'p!r-d Secretary of the Council Presented to the ~ayor 1_0 1_4 1_s l1_e&amp;amp;q- QWJilt.&amp;lt;1.w Secretary of the Council) Me.yor s action approv-e a 2 t. or.r 1975 disapprove Mayor's Signnture) 2 :1: CCT 1975 Enacted without Mayor's signature Sccrct~ry of the Council) t f j \ Dill Docket 1-161 Pafe Two nccon~idcrcd by Council Vote RECCRD OF COUNCIL VOTE r r 1 r j eou c T;~f. r i n 1 f 1 r r 1 iloc o 11Sg l-~ii1rzfJ1'1i2_ i r:.fj BARRY HOBSTI.N ·1 wnrTEP 11 MOORE J 1 1 Etblil'i!S l-1saACKL'ttON 1 i 1 J j J l X-Indic.111 \I otc 11• 1 Prc cnt A. B bscnt It \.-Rcadoi&amp;gt;h·d Secretary of th~ Co'Jncil) Pre nted to the Prc~idcn't Secretary of the Council) St1~stah1 if:ayo S veto Hot Su.c"tu in ~7nyor 5 vc to President of the U.S Submit~ed to the Cong~ess Secretary of the Council Senate action House action res~;lution number resolution nucber Secretary of .the Senate Clerk of the House Enacted without Conr.:ressional action Secretary of the Council)</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
