<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-47">
  <num type="law">1-47</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-02-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-47.pdf">D.C. Law 1-47</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 4683</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-50 on October 7, 1975, and0ctober21, 1975, respectively, Following the Mayor's signature on November 13, 197 5, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-67, published in the November 26, 1975, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 60 2 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law No. 1-47, effective February 19, 1976. STERLING; CK Chairman to the Council D. C. Law 1-47 In the Council of the District of Columbia February 19, 1976 To amend the District of Columbia Teachers' Leave Act of 1949 to authorize the eligibility of temporary salary class 15 employees for advanced additional leave, and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Advanced Additional Leave Act Sec. 2. Section 4 of the District of Columbia Teachers' Leave Act of 1949 (D.C. Code, sec. 31-694) is amended to read as follows Sec. 4. In cases of serious disability or ailments, and when required by the exigencies of the situation, and in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Board of Education may prescribe, the Superintendent of schools may advance additional leave with pay not to exceed thirty days to every probationary or permanent teacher or attendance officer who may apply for such advanced leave, and the superintendent of schools may advance additional leave, with pay, not to exceed the maximum number of days which he would earn during the term of this appointment, to every temporary teacher or attendance officer who may apply for such advanced leave Sec. 3. The amendment made by this act shall be effective on the first day of the first pay period which begins on or after the sixty days following the date this act becomes law according to the provisions of section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, or July 1, 1975, whichever is later I Dockat for the Dill 1-50 Conaidcrcd in Council October 7, 1975 t"iro t vo tc October 7, 19 7 S R E C 0 I~ D 0 F C O· U N C I L V 0 T E GOUUCll ll'Mlll"lt Final vote in Council October21, 1975 RECORD OF C 0 UN C.1 L V 0 TE OCT 3 0 1975 .Presented to the Uayor Mayor's action appro\(e 1975 disapprov_e·r Secretary of the Council) Sign.olure) Enacted without Mayor's signature I i 1975 Dill Docket 1-50 Pa{"e 'l'wo Rccon~idcred by Council Vote RECCRD OF COUNCIL VOTE (Secrel:ary of th~ Co•Jncil) Presanted to the Prczidcnt Secretary of- th~ Council) Sttst::dn i(ayor•s vi to Not Suctt1.in yor•c veto Presid~t of tho U.S Submitted t.o the Congress ll-11-1f lt;lW lt;secretary of the Co~ncil) Enacted without Congressional action Secretary of the Council l I i I I http:SucGti.in</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
