<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-53">
  <num type="law">1-53</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-03-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-53.pdf">D.C. Law 1-53</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 5132</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-51 on November 4, 197 S and November 18, 197 S, respectively. Following the Mayor's signature on December 4, 197 S, this legislation was as signed Act No. 1-73, published in the December 12, 197 S, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 1-53, effective March 12, 197 6 y s TERLIN G TThCKER Chairman tdthe Council i D. C. L.l\.T-7 1-5 3 In the Council of the District of Columbia !1arch 12, l~ 711 To authorize administrative or suoerviso school officers who are granted sabhatical leave to receive one-half of their annual salaries. BE I E"L1\.CTEn BY THE COU!'JCIL OF THE DISTRI~ OF COLtTMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "School Officers Sabbatical Leave Act Sec. 2. Section 4 of t!"le 2\.ct entitled n Act to ~rovide educational P..Mployees of thP ou~lic schools of the District of Columbia with leave of absence, with part pay, for purposes of educational ir:'lprovenent, and for other purposes approved June 12, 1940 (D.C. Code, sec. 31-635) is amended by striking out "or equal to the laraest amount to which any employee in t!ie salary class of elerientary a~n secondary school teachers would be entitled if given educational leave, whichever is less, either" a~d inserting in lieu thereof a coMMa and the word "suc!i Sec. 3. The amendment made hy this act sh all become effective on the first day of the first pay period which beqins on or after the sixtieth day occurring after the date t."1 is act becones law according to the provisions of section I 602(c) of the District of ColTi iia Sel~-Gove e t a"'ld Gover!11"1ental ~eorqaniz~tion Act Dockot for tho Dill 1-51 Connidcrcct in Counci 11 75 Fir&amp;amp;t vote 11-4-75 ECORD OF COUNCIL VOTC Final vote in Council 11-18~75 (Secretary. of the ~ouncil the Council t J)r L I~ Presented to th~ Mayor 11-19-75 (Secretary 4 D.EC E~ f yor 's action 4.DEC 1975 approve l disapprove: Enacted with out Mayor• s sipl t·~re cs cc r ct a r y of the Council Bill Docket 1-51 Page Two Reconsidered by Council Vote RECO R D 0 F c o·u N Cl L 0 TE r I 1 r i COU"Cll. MC MU CR Yl:~iuo P.R. 1A.D.•11.A.I COUNCIL. MC MUCH YC NO l JI. II.fl. 11.1 I COUNCIL Mr nr.H I Yes! IH:&amp;gt; r'.11.!11:0.jn.A 11 F 11 1 I 1- i I I I Y.-lndicuSc Voto P. ll.-PrcscnS A. 13.-Jl.biicns R \,-Readopted Secretary of the Co'.lncil) Presented to the President (Secretary of the Council) Sustain Mayor's veto Not Sus ta in Mayor's veto (President of the u. s Submitted to the Congreos Secretary of the Council) Senate action House action resolution number resolution number Secretary of the Senate Clerk of the House) Enacted without Conf!ressional action Secretary of the Council) http:n.r o.;u.A.11</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
