<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-59">
  <num type="law">1-59</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-03-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-59.pdf">D.C. Law 1-59</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 5473</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-59 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-204, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 2, 1975 and December 16, 1975, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 9, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-84 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE pISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act} the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-204 on December 2, 1975 and December 16, 1975, respectively. Following the Mayor's signature on January 9, 1976, this legislation was assigned i l :z Act No. 1-84, published in the-Febn:rary--2-l,-1-9-1-6, edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c} (1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 1-59, effective March 26, 1976 L STERLIN TUCKER Chairman to the Council D.C. LAW 1-59 In the Council of the District of Columbia March 26, 19 76 To amend the District of Columbia Employee Non-Liability Act to provide for the indemnification of medical employees in certain circumstances. BE IT ENAC~D BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBI.'l\ That this act may be cited as the "Medical Employee Protection act of 1975 Sec. 2. Section 2 of the District of Columbia Employee Non- Liability Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-921) is amended by adding thereto a new subsection h to read as follows h Medical employee of th~ District of Columbia' shall include physicians, dentists, optometrists, podiatrists, nurses, nursing assistants, physicians' assistants, laboratory technicians, physical therapi~ts, osteopaths, chiropodists and chiropractors in the employment of the District of Columbia Sec. 3. Section 6 of the District of Columbia Employee Non- Liability Act (D.C. Code, sec. 1-925) is amended by designating the existing paragraph as subsection a and adding thereto new subsections b and c to read as follows b) Whenever in a case in which the District of Columbia is not a party, a final judgment and order to pay -2- money damages is entered against a medical employee of the District of Columbia on account of damage to or loss of property or on account of personal injury or death caused by the negligent act or omission ~f the medical employee within the scope of his employment and performance of professional responsibilities the District of Columbia shall, to the I extent the medical employee is not covered by appropriate \ in:sura.11ce purchased by the District of Columbia, indem."lify the employee in the amount of said money dacages c) NothL"lg in this section shall be construed to restrict appropriate disciplinary action by the District of Columbia against any e~ployee for a negligent act or omission Sec. 3. This act shall take effect upon becoming law by operation of subsection (c) of section 602 of the Dist=ict of Columbia Self-Gover:unent and Governmental Reorganization Act I l 1 I I Dockot for the Dill 1-204 C~nGidc~cct in Cou~cil 12~2-75 Fir:.t vote 12 -2-75 COUNC I L VOTC I C:C\UPIC: JI r \' r r 0 n t II c: ov C:l-1 i n-c r 1 0 f j r-c:-0-\J c 1 Tt [ \,7 rr I TUC i~ER I i 1 i:&amp;lt;ll_o.rxoN j-x--i-l_j_j\lsr1\UfprNG 1·x-r~J c J 1 oR Q_.J x 1~:Fw 1x 1. 1 1 I 1 i vrr. s.o..Y u L.t_L I x _Ji ~Q P S~O \._f i.I x I V/TTISR I 't' I x I I r vt' 1 x 1 1 11 M.Q.ORJ r. x I 1 11~ 1 I J 11_J_J__J w x l l i 1_;jc f~C~:r'Fi'O:\L! x i I I 11 I i I X-lndicntcs Vote I it-P:cscnl RECORD OF Final vot~ in Cou~cil 12-16-~S c 0 ~i c i l I R E c 0 R D 0 C" c 0 u N c I v 0 T'E I I C:O V!iC:ll t c rt i Y i o n \ .o it.A ii c u1 MtM OC 11 t:S Pi O r· n.:A.!] f(.A c u c Y::s o 1 P a it i TUCKER x i I I I if IX t D!XO~.f I l_J_!i S ULD!NG 2 1_ i_ ] l MOORE I I I x I ii c f Ix I I I li ~AlTTC'i)V x r I i I _M.R'RV I x I I I I II HOSS ON I x i i I lh;VTV7 I i I I I I x I r: r ll R l!'t i x I j -l II MOQ L I x I If I 1 I I i I I I f I I I I I I I il.S.EA.G.KLE TO r r n i't:'S x x I I ir I I i i i I I I X-lnciic:111es Vo!e L csc 13.-A c r A.~R·,L °';i!1 I the. Co~nc i l) Pr·~sentcC. to t~s r·r.ayor· I J fl -L QUJ tJJ J {Secre tai:y of the Cour.ci l) 0~xtJ £rt aJC Me.yor 's act i ~r i J f\ ~75 approve dis a Pt'rove Mayor's S igna tu.=e Y Enacted without Mayor's 5 ~a tu Sc-ere t ar of t 8 Co1.:nci l l Bill Docket 1-204 Paee r o Reconsid~rcd by Co1incil Vote RECCRD OF COUNCIL VOTE Secretary of tha Co~nci l) Pr nted to t h e P~ctidont Secr~tary o f th~ Council S1.tst ln lt;ayor' s V tc ot c foo \ veto Pr~sident of th~ U.S Submitted to the Ccng~ecs Secretary of the Co~ncil Senate action House action resolution nu~be resolution nu~ber {Secretary of the Senate Clerk of 1..ne House) Enz..cte fl .I. i 1CU C1.mgress ional action Secrct~ry of the Council)</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
