<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-63">
  <num type="law">1-63</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-05-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-63.pdf">D.C. Law 1-63</citation>
      <citation type="register">22 DCR 6538</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-63 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-133, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 18, 1975 and December 2, 1975, respectively. Disapproved by the Mayor on December 24, 1975, reenacted on January 19, 1976, and signed by the President on February 27, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-87 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCil OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICL Pursuant to Sec:ticn 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorqani.Zation Act, PI. 931-98 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted first and second readinqs of Bill No. l-133 on November 18, 1975, and December 2, 1975, respectively. Subsequent to the Mayor's disapproval on December 24, 1975, the Council re-enacted Act 1-87 on Tanuary 19, 197 6, published it in the Tanuary 23, 1976~ edition of the D.C. R-egister, and submi~ed it to the President of the United States for consideration on January Z9 1976, in accordance with Section 404 {e) of the Act. Following the President's approval on February 27, 1976, this legislation was transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance With Section 602 {c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review -period has expired and, therefore, cites the followtnq leqislation as D.C. Law 1-63, effective May 6, 1976 j y STERllNG TUC!/ER Chairman to the Council 0. C. LrlW 1-6 3 le Council of the Oist:ict of Columbia May 6, 1976 To insure the further development and specification of Affirmative Action employment plans by all District government aqencies. SE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA That this act may be cited as the •Affirmative Action in District Government Employment Act Sec. 2. The goal _of affirmative action in employment t."lroughout the District government is, and must continue .to be, full representation, in jobs at all salary and waqe levels and scales, in accordance with the representation of all groups in the available work force of the District of Columbia, includ ing, but not limited to, Blacks, Whites, Spanish-speaking Americans, Native Americans, Asian Americans, females, and males. As used in this act available work force• means the total population of the District of Columbia between the aqes of 18 and 65. Sec J very Distr·ict government agency shall develop and submit to the Mayor and Council an affirmative action plan. Such plan shall be submitted within l2 calendar weeks after the effective date of this act, and each year thereafter, at the time each agency's annual budget is submitted to the Council rlaa "tri~itial. et Sec. 4. Each plan shall state t.~e nUI:l!:er ci !e?nales a ld ales who a=e Black, White, St,:anish-speaki::q Ua.tive America l and Asian rln\erican, who would, by usinq the goal of their representation in t le _ava:iJ.able work force in the District, be employed by the aqeney at the actual. employment levels in the aqen~.{ at the time the plan is su!Jmi tted. Such ·numbers shall be broken dcwn l) aqency-wide 2) \olithin each of!ice the agency; a ld (J) within each pay level of each sala Y scale in aqenc:y. These shall be tlje qoals net the quotas, of the plan. The plan· shall also state the actual employr.tent levels in the agency broken down in the same w:iy as the goals, and t e difference between the actual employment and t.~e goals. Sec. S. The .plan shall state the number of hires and promotions t.~e agency projects for the period until the next ~lan is submitted, and the number of hires and promotions of the qroups enumerated in .section 4, projected for that I?eriod. Sue.Soi proj ec:tions shall be broken down in the manner provided L~ section 4. Sec. 6. The plan shall further state what actions the agency is taking to secure the equal employment opport'.lnity within t.he agency of the groups e11ur.ierated in section 4, and of the agi g Sec 7. Eqaal emplcymen t oppo.rtuni ey i.s a ccnti.nui."lq :sspc:m:s~ility of everJ aqenc:y, whether or not the h i:q a d prcmcti.cn gcal.:s i a£!i a.tive ac icm employment plans have been reached. Sec a. The plan shall !u ther state -t:.1le numl:er of h es omotions, a ld ni."la:ior.s (due to :eti=ement, deat."i eductions in servi.ce or force, lack of perlornance, d 3cipl.i a y ac ion, and. all otb.er reasons am indic:a:t.inc the permanent, tampcra:y, or prol=aticna:y status of the tl!.Clinated employees of, and personnel g:ievanca and equal employment complai:lts i:lstitutsd by erson.s ?Clown to be members of the various classes specified i.4 section 6, durinq the period since the previously plan. Sec. 9 be Ma.yQr shall have- the authority and is d.i:ected to detail, on a full-ti::le basis, all' persons who, on the ec:tive data of ~s secticn, a:e employed, on a ful1 time basis, as eqaal employment opportunity officers and equa1 employment opportunity Si'ec:ialist:s by any aqenc:y of the Oist=ict qover:unent other t.1lan t!le Of:!ica of S1J:1an ~qhts, and t.i.e ~i:e Oepar ient, to wor!&amp;lt; in t.1le Ot:!ice of Ruman Riqb.ts as i:lve.stiqa.tcrs or in ot.tier pQsition.s, all cli:ectly involved i..4 the 4 l 1 0,rme OMpc uni y· c:ases i s~{t~ted ~cision oz: equa 1 aca s the Oi.stric-t gove ment or any of its aqencies. iro person so detailed ·shall work on cases instituted aqains the agency f=cm whic:h the perscn is detailed, and in t!le case of the person so detailed f::om the tet:opolitan Police Cepart:nent, such erson shall net be a unifor.med e:tployee cf the Metropolitan l'olic:e force. The Mayor shall assign si:ch details on the effective date of this section. The positions which such persons hold shall be t.rans!erred to t e budget of the Office of IIur.ian Rights i."l anC. for Fiscal Yea: 1977. Sec. lo. This act shall becc:e ef!ective at the end of the period provided ~or Ccnqressional ·review of acts of the Council by section 602(c of the Distri~t of Columbia Self-&amp;lt;iovernment and Governmental Recr~anization Act Docket tor the Bil1 l-133 C~naidcred L"'l Council r1 1s-1s irs vo ll 19-iS RS:CORO OF COU NCIL. VOT R E C 0 R C 0 F C 0 U N C l L. V 0 T S l:&amp;gt;UHC:U CM I t S: HO 1 n.!JWJ.\ 11.A. a ~QUHC:U. MCMaCn TUCKE I I x I x I l 1-l cf a lU .i.ll 1 w t *tsecretary of t e Council Presented tQ the r a:yor 1 2-_t o 1 s ctL;:f c-.Aol I -r.•iayor IS action a-pprove clisa pprcve Secratary of the Counc:il 7fu;t;z4 U.1€ Mayor's ~isna~u:e J Ena.ctad withou"t Mayor's signa:ture Scc:rctary of Council Reconsidered by Council. 1-19-76 Bill Dockct-=1--li 3~3 Paee Two Vote 12-0 RECCRD OF CO U NC I L VOTE Presc~ted to tho President Sustain 1.~ayor~·s v~to Not S\ t in 1 or•s veto Submitted to the Con~ess Sena ts action res~lution-num~er Secretary of the Senate ecretary of tha Co~nci l OvlU 10d { Secr~tary of t he Council President of the U.S {Se cr eta r 1 of the Co~ncil) House action resolution nll!:lber C~l-e-r k_o_f~th e_H_o_u_s_e Enacted without Con~essional action </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-521.08"/>
  </section>
</document>
