<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-70">
  <num type="law">1-70</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-06-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-70.pdf">D.C. Law 1-70</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 533</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-70 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-229, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings and reconsiderations of final reading on February 20, 1976, March 11, 1976 and April 6, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 20, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-106 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE Pursuant to Section 412 of tha District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorqanization Act Pt 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. l-229 on firs't and second readinqs February 20, 1976, and March 11, 1976, respect1vely, with a reconsideration of the final reading- ai April 6, 197 6. Followt.nq the Mayors siqnature on April 20, 1976, this leqislation was assiqned Act No. l-106, published in the May 1 1976, edition of the D. C, Register, and trans- mitted to both Houses of Conqress for a 30-day review, in accordance wtth Sect1on 602 (c l) of the Act The Council of the 01str1ct of Columbia hereby qives notice that the 30-day Conc;ressiaia.l review period has expired. and, therefore, cites the followmc; leqi.slat1on as D.C. Law No. 1-70, effective June 15, 1976. oe I STERI.ING TUCKER Chairman to the Council I D.C. LAW 1-70 In the Council of the Oistr.ict of Columbia June 15, 1976 To provide additional revenue for the Distr-ict of Columbia. B! I~ ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be- cit:ed as tha "Revenue Act of l976w. TI'l'I.&amp;amp; t REGIS~~ION FEES FOR MOTOR VEHICLES ANO TRAILERS S•&amp;lt lOl. Section. 3 ot Tit:le IV ot the- District of ColUJ" Revenue Act of l937i approved Auqust 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 681, o.c Code sec. 40-lOJ) is amended as follows l) The para9raph desiqnated "Class. A• of subsection (b) o i such· section (relatinq to re9istration fees for passenger motor vehicles) is amended to read as follows 1) Wben wholly equipped wi tb pneumatic tires, a recjiatra~i~n fe• shal.l. be charqed accordin~ to the-manufacturer sbippin~ weight as follows nanufacturer's Shiepinq Weight Reqist~ation Fee I Cla.ss I (2800 pounds or less) Class II (2801 3499 pounds) Class tir (3500 3999 pounds) C.l.asa rv (tiOOO pounds or more) District ot Coli ibiu Register sso $57 $83 (2) The paraqraph designated "C.lass S Of subsection (b) 0£ sudl section (relatincr t:o reql.stratioa fees for CTilck.s. t:ac:tors, and. ccta.i.A C'Clllftercia.l. moto: velti.c:las) i.s amended ey "S16J 11 $176 S200 229 S291 SJOO S~oa and "S479 respectj.~e.ly 3) The qrapb. d•signated "Class. c.w· ot sul:2sectioa (t)J of such section {relatinq to reql.strat.ion fe.s tor t:rai.lers) is am9ftded by strildJlcr oat •s15 s22 S.36 S58 11 sa2 s101 s132 11 s115 11 s21s 11 s211 and "S32J and \ I ozz \4 c 1 1 3 143 17G 219 291 361 and 431 i respectively 4) The paragraph designated "Class D" of subsection (b of such section (relating to registration fees for motorcycles, motor bicycles, motor tricycles and. motor wheels is amended by striking out 16" and inserting in l i eu ther~of ·s21 5) The paragraph designated "Class E" of subsection (b of such section (relatinq to reqistration tees for antique motor vehicles is amended by strikinq out 7• and inserting in lieu thereof •sg 6) The paragraph designated "Class F" of subsecti on (b of such section (relatinq to reqistration fees for dealers' identification tags) is·amended by striking out 40• and •s14• and inserting in lieu thereof •ss3• and 19 respectively. TITLE II CISE TAX ON ISSUANCE OF MOTOR VEHICLE TITLE CERTIFICATES l::uroJ. 1. cd Ori i na l -4- Sec. 201. The first sentence of section of Title III of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1949, approved May 27, 1949 (63 Stat. 972; D.C. Code, sec. 40-603 (j is &amp;lt;lmendec! to read as follows In addition to the fees and charges levied under other provisions of this Act, there is hereby levied and ·imposed an excise tax on the issuance of every original certificate of title for a motor vehicle or trai1er in the District and, in the case of a sale, resale, gi~ or other transfer thereof, on the issuance of every subsequent certificate of title (except in the case of a bona fide ~ift betwe~n spouse~ o etwecn parent and child) at the fol.lowing percentage of the fair market value of the motor vehicle or trailer at the time the certificate of title is issued Weight Class Rate of Ta Class I (2800 pounds or less) 4t Class· II (2801 3499 pounds) S• Class III (3500 3999 pounds) 6~ Class IV (4000 pounds or more) 7t -s- For the purposes of this section, the Mayor or his duly authorized representative shall determine the fair market value of a motor vehicle or trailer TITLE I!'I TIME FOR PAYMENT OF REAL ESTATE TAXES AND RATES OF TAXATION OF REAL PROPERTY Sec. 301 The first paragraph of section 5 of the Act of July 3, 1926 (q4 Stat. 833, o.c. Code, sec. q7-1209) is amended to read as follows Real estate taxes are due and payable semiannually in two equal installment tbe first installment to be paid on or before September 15th, and the second installment to be paid o" or hefore March 31st. Personal taxes of all kinds are due and payable semiannually in two equal installments, tile first on or before 5eptem.ber 30th, and the second on or before March 31st. If any instaJ.lment of such taxes is not paid within the time prescribed, the instal..l.ment shall thereupon be in arrears .and delinquent, and there shall be due and collected with said ta~ a penalty of ten percent of the amount of the installment \. \ ~rollo.d Or ic .i. n~l 6- in arrears, plus interest on that installment at the rate of one percent per month or portion of a month until the installment is paid. The installment in arrears, plus the penalty and interest due, shall constitute a delinquent tax to be collected in the manner provided by law sec. 302(a Section 412 of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 88 Stat. 1052, o.c. Code, sec. 47-632) is amended to read as follows Sec. 412. The Council, after public hearing, shall by resolution establish each year, within twenty days after the receipt of the Mayor's recommendation under section 413, a rate of taxation which, except as provided in section ~31, shall be applied, during the tax year, to the assessed value of all real property subject to taxation. The council, acting by resolution, may extend the time for setting the rates of taxation. If the Council does extend the time for setting the rates of taxation of real property, it must establish those rates for the year. If "the council fails to establish the Ezlrollod Orieiu~l 7- rates of taxation of real property by resolution within those twenty days and fails to extend the time for setting the rates, the rates of taxation of real property submitted by the Mayor pursuant to section 413 shall be the rates of taxation of real property b) Section 413(a) of such Act (D.C. Code, sec. 47-633(a) is amended by striking out "JuJ.y is and insertinc; in lieu. thereof nJuly i Sec. 303(a) The Council shall establish different categories of real. property, including by way of example but not by way o~ limitation the following l) single fa.I:lily residential property 2) multifamily property and (3 commercial property b) When the uses ·of a property fall within more than one of the classes enumerated in subsection (a) of this section, the property shall be apportioned into the proper classes and each of the areas resulting from the apportionment shall be taxed at the appropriate real property tax rate. Sec. 304. If the classes of real property established under section 303 of this act and/or the differing rates of taxation of real property set by the Council a.re declared to be invalid or inapplicable to any property, the real property tax rate in effect for that property for the immediately ollcd o A r.i 1n~Li a- preceding year ending June 30th shall be deemed to have continued in effect. Sec. 305. Sections 411, 412, 4l3(a}(l b} c d 414, 415 and 416 of the District of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved September 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 10521 D.C. Code, secs. 47-632, 47-634 (a 1 b c d 47-635 and 47-636) a.re hereby amended by adding the words •or rates• after the word •rate• wherever it appears. TITLE 1:V SALES AND USE TAXES ON PUBLIC UTILITIES, SERVICES, FOOD, DRINK AND LODGINGS Sec. 401. Paragraph 3 of Section 301 of Title III of the Revenue Act of 1975 (D.C. Law No. 1-23, effective October 21 1975) is hereby repealed. Sec. 402. Paragraph 5 of Section 301 of Title III of the Revenue Act of 1975 (D.C. Law No. 1-23, effective October 21, 1975) is hereby repealed 9- Sec. 403. Paragraph 9 of Section 301 of Title III of the Revenue Act of 1975 (D.C. Law No. l-23, effective October 21, 1975) i~ h~reby repealed. Sec. 404. Paragraph 3 of section 302 of Title III of the Revenue Act of 1975 (D.C. Luw No. l-23, effective October 21, 1975) is hereby repealed. Sec. 405. Paragraph 5 of section 302 of Title III of the Revenue Act of 1975 (D.C. Law No. l-23, effective October 21~ 1975) is hereby repealed. sec. 406. Subsection (j) of section 801 of Title VIII of the Revenue Act of 1975 (O.C. Law No. l-23, effective October 21, 1975) is hereby repealed. Sec. 407. Subsection (l) of section 801 of Title VIII of the Revenue Act of l97S•(O.C. Law No. l-23, effective October 21, 1975) is hereby repealed. Sec. 408. Section 125 of the District of Columbia Sal~s Tax Act 63 St.at. 115, o.c. Code, sec. 47-2602) is amended to read as follows 10 Sec. 125. A tax is imposed upon all vendors for the privileg~ of selling at retail certain tangible personal property and for the privilege of selling certain selected services (defined as "retail sale" and sale at retail" in this title The rate of such tax shall be 5 percent of the gross receipts from the sale of or charges for such tangible personal property and services. except that 1) the rate of tax shall be 12 percent of the gross receipts from the sale of or charges for the service of parking or storing of motor vehicles or trailers, except the service of parking or storing of motor vehicles or t=ailers on a parr~ng lot owned or operated by ~he Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and located adjacent to a Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority passenqer s~op or station; ft(2) the rate of tax shall be 8 percent of the gross receipts from the sale of or charges for rcll o.d Ori L~i u~.I. II (A 11- any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations furnished to a tr~n:&amp;gt;ient by any hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin r any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients; and B) food or drink served, prepared for immediate consUr:tption, or sold as described in section ll4(a l) of this title; and C) spirituous or malt liquors, beer and wine sold for consumption on the premises where sold {3} the rate of tax shall be 6 percent of th~ gross receipts from the sale of spirituous or malt liquors, beer and wine sold for consumption off the premises wher~ sold; and the rate of tax shall be 2 percent of the gross receipts from the sale of food or drink as described in section 114 (a) Cl) of thi·s title when sold fran a vending machine 12- Sec. qQ9. Section 212 of the District of Columbia ose Tax Act, {63 Stat. 126, o.c. Code, sec. 47-2702) is amended to read as follows Sec. 212. There is hereby imposed and there shall be paid by every vendor engaging in business in the District and by every purchaser a tax on the use, storage, or consumption of any tangible personal property and services sold or purchased at retail sale. The rate of tax imposed by this section shall be 5 percent of the sales price of such tangible personal property and services, except that 1) the rate of tax shal1 be 12 percent of the gross receipts from .the sale of or charges for the service of parking or storing of motor vehicles or trailers, except the service o~ parking or storing of motor vehic.les or trailers on a parking lot owned or operated by the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority and located adjacent to a Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority passenqer stop or station 13 {2} the rate of tax shal! be 8 percent of the gross receipts from the sale of or charges for A) any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations, furnished to transients by any hotel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, or. any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients; and "CB) food or drink served, prepazed for immediate consumption, or sold as described in section 114(a} (1) of Title I of this Act; and C) spirit:uoas or ma.11: liquors, beer and wine sold for consumption on the premises where sold 3 the rat~ of tax shall be 6 percent of the gross receipts from the sa.le of spirituous or malt liquo.rs, beer and wine sold for consumption oft the premises wbe%e sold and the rate ot tax shall be 2 percent of the gross receipts from the sale of food or drink as described in 14- section 11 a) { 1) of Title I of this Act when sold from a vending machine gt; T!TLE V CIGARETTE TAX Sec. 501. Section 603 of the District of Columbia Cigarette Tax Act 63 Stat. 137, o.c. Code, sec. 47-2802) is amended by striking out n1on and inserting in lieu thereof "13 Sec. 502 a) In the case of cigarette tax stam~s purchased prior .to the effective date of this title and held on the effective date of this title (affixed to a cigarette package or otherwise) by a wholesaler, retailer. or vending mac ine operator licensed under t.he District of Co1umbia Cigarette Tax Act, such licensee shall pay to the Mayor (in accordance with subsection (b) of this section) an amount equal to the difference b~tween the amount of tax represented by such tax stamps on the date of their purchase and the amount of tax which an equal number of cigarette tax •stamps \ Enrollc-4 Ori~inal -15- would repres~nt if purchased on the effective date of this title b) Within twenty days after the effective date of this title, each person licensed under the District of Columbia Cigarette Tax Act (1) shall file with the Mayor, on a form to be prescribed by the Mayor, an affirmed statement showing the number of cigarette tax stamps held by him as of the beginning of the day of the effective date of this title, or if such day is a SUnday, as of the beginning of the immediately following weekday, and (2) shall pay to the Mayor the amount specified in subsection (a) of this section c) Each licenaee shall keep and preserve for the twelve month period iinmediate~y following the effective date of this title the inventories and other records which form the basis for the information furnished to the Mayor ander subsection b) of this section d} For the purposes of this section, a tax stamp shall be considered to be held by a wholesaler, retailer, or vending 16- machine oper~tor if title thereto has passed to such wholesaler, retailer, or vending machine operator {whether or not delivery to him has been made) and if title to such stamp has not at any time been transferred to any person other than such wholesaler, retailer, or vending machine operator e) A violation of the provisions of subsection (a b) or (c) of this section shall be punishable as provided in section 611 of the District of Columbia Cigarette Tax Act (D.C. Code, sec. 47-2810 TITLE VI WATER RATE ANO CHARGE FOR SAN'ITARY SEWER SERV'ICE Sec. 6 O _1. The third full sentence of section 1 of the part entitled -t•water Service" of the Act entitled "An Act making appropriations foI the government of the District of Columbia and other activities chargeable in whole or in part against the revenues of such District for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1931, and for other purposes approved July 3, 1930 (46 Stat. 988; o.c. Code, sec. 43-1520) is amended to 17- read as follows Unless oth~rwise determined pursuant to section 603 of this Act, after June 30, 1976, the rate for water furnished any premises through metered services shall be 39.4 cents for each one hundred cubic feet of water used.n Sec. 602 a) The first sentence of subsection (b) of section 701 of Title VII of the Revenue Act of 1975 (O.c. Law No. 1-23 effective October 21, 1975, is redesignated paragraphs 1 and 2 and amended to read as follows 1) Before July 1, 1976, the charge for sanitary sewer service furnished any premises in the District shall be 90 percent of the charqe for water or water services furnished any such premises from the District of Colwnbia Water supply system and shall be collected in the same manner and at the same time as water cbarg~s are collected 2) Unless otherwise determined pursuant to section 603 of this Act after June 30, 1976, the charge for sanitary sewer service furnished any premises in the District shall be at the rate of 4Q.8 cents for each one hundred (100) cubic 18 feet of water and shall be collected in the same manner and at the same time as water charges are collected b) The second sentence of section 70l(b) of said Act is redesignated paragraph n(3 \ {c) The third sentence of section 70l(b} of said Act is redesignated paragraph 4 Sec. 603 a} (l) On or before Hay _l, 1976, the Mayor shall certirL to the Council that all billings for water and water service rendered through October 19, 1975, have been mailed out 2) The water rates to become e£fective after June 30, 1976, according to the provisions of section 601 of this Act, shall be effective if the Council, acting by resolution, determines prior to June 30, 1976, that the Mayor has properly justified those water rates and if the Uayor submits to the Council the certification referred to in paragraph (1 19 J) The water. rates in effect after June 30, 1975, shall remain in effect after June 3 1976, if the Council does not act pur3uant to paragraph (2) of this subsection b l On or before May 1, 1976, tha Mayor shall certify to the Council that all billings for sanitary sewer service rendered through October 19, 1975, have been mailed out 2) The charge for sanitary sawer service to become effective after June 30, 1976, according to the provisions of section 602(a 2) of this act, shall be effective it the cou.,cil i.cti."1c; by resolution, dctC!:r:ti.r.es p:-ior to June 30 1976, that the z.tayor ha::J properly justified that charge for sanitary sewer service and if the M4l.yor submits to the Council the certification referred to in pa.raqraph (l 3) The charge tor sanit4l.ry sawer service in effect after June 30, 1975, shall remain in effect after June 30, 1976, if the Council does not act pursuant to subsection (b 2) of this section nroll EJ d Orie.in 20- sec. 604. Before September 30, 1976, the Commissioners of the Public service commission of the District· of Columbia shall submit a report to the committee on F~nance and Revenue to the Council (1) stating the information which should be submitted to the Council by the Mayor to justify any increase in the water rate and the charge for sanitary sewer service and any change in the rate structure 2) describing alte~native rate structures and methods of determining the proper wat'er rate and charge for sanitary sewer service to be charged users of the water, water services and sewer services provided by the government of the District of Columbia and recommending a rate structure and method of determining ~roper rates, and (3) suggesting a procedure under which the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia reviews the Mayor's recommended increase in the water rate or charge for sanitary sewer service and renders to the council an advisory opinion concerning the appropriateness and legality of the recommended rates J nroU.otl. Or icin 21- Sec. 605. Before September 30, 1976, the ~eople counsel shall submit a report to the Council (1) stating the effect on consumers of the water rate and charge for sanitary sewer service scheduled to become effective after June 30, 1976, pursuant to sections 601 and 602 of this act 2) stating what issues affecting consumers should be considered by the council in setting the water rate and the charge for sanitary sewer service, and (3) relating the experiences rocedure and law in jurisdictions in which a public service commission determines or recommends the rates to be charged by a government-owned utility. sec. 606. Paraqraph ~2 of section 8 of the Act entitled "An Act making .appropriations to provide for the ex~enses of the government of the Di~trict of Columbia tor the tiscal year ending June 13, 1914, and tor other purposes approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 984; o.c. Code, sec. 43-412) is amended by designating the present paragraph of the section as subsection •ca&amp;gt and adding a new Subsection "Cb to read as follows: Enrolled c-.d c 1 ;1 i 22 Cb) The Mayor shall provide and the Public Service Commission of the District of Columbia and the Off ice of the People's Counsel are authorized to draw from, receive and spend no more than $50,000, as provided in paragraph (2) of this section, for the costs of preparing the reports required to be submitted to the council under sections 60~ and 605 of the Revenue Act of 1976. The $50,000 shall be derived from a $25,000 charge against revenues from water rates and a $25,000 charge against revenues from the charge for sanitary sewer service. The Pu.bli~ service Commission of the District of .Columbia and the Office of the People's Counsel. are authorized to draw, receive and spend up to and including S30,000 and $20,000 respectively. In addition the Commission and the Office of the People's c~unsel are authorized to draw, receive and spend any amount allocated to the other under this paragraph but not spent TITLE VII PAYMENT OF DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA TAXES ANO FEES AT PRIVATE FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS E.nroll~d Oi·i g inal 23- Sec. 701. The Council hereby authorizes the Mayer to contract, for a period not to excE*!d two years from the effective date of the contract, with priva~e financial institutions having an office for the transaction of business with the public located in the District and engaged in business in the District to act as the agent of the District for the receipt, processing and retention of District funds paid as registration ~ees for motor vehicles and trailers excise taxes on certificates of title for motor vehicles and trailers, water rates, charges for sanitary sewer service, fees, user cha.rqes, real property taxes 0% personal i:roperty taxes. sec. 702. A contract entered into by t.he Mayor Wlder section 701 of this act ~ay be made on the basis of competitive bidding or negotiated bi.ddinq sec. 703 a) The Mayor shall in£orm the council of the names and te~ of the bids of each of the financia.l institutions su.bnd ttinq a bid under section 702 of this act E.~rollctl Oricinnl -24- and, for each bidder, the informatio~ submitt~d under subsection {b) of this section, no later than five legislative days before the Mayor enters into a contradt under section 701 of this act b) In entering into contracts under this title it shall be the policy of the government of the District of Columbia to enter into contracts only with those financial institutions which have the best records of serving the citizens of the District through their lending and employment policies. To be eligible for such contracts, an institution must submit, along with its bid whether negotiated or competitive, th~ following information regarding its lending and employment practices in the District for the most recent year 1) That information required to be disclosed under section 304, Title III of P.L. 9~-200 (12 use 2403) as originally enacted, and under any subsequent amendments providing for additional (but not less) disclosure J rolled. Or ~£:.l!l 1 -25 gt 2) The total dollar amounts and percentages of its deposits by Census Tract with sufficient dai.:a to show· those deposits received from within cind without the Districtr and (3) The nwnbers and percentages of its Board of Directors, officers, profassional and nonprofessional employees, respectively, who are A White black or •other and (B) Residents and nonresidents of the District c) In enterinq into contracts under this title, the Mayor Rh;ill give preference to those institutions which, h;is~d on the information submitted under subsection (b) of. this section, show clear evidence of marked and e.~ceptional improvement in their 18lldinq and employment practices in recent years. TITLE VIII ANALYSIS OF THE FRANCHISE TA lt; Sac. 801 a) The Mayor .shall, within twelve months after the effective date of this title, submit to the Canr.tittee on Finance and Revenue of tha Council and to the District of E irollc :L o ir,i.o~l \ -26- Columbia Aitditor, a report analyzing the deductions, exemptions and exclusions available to entities subject to the provisions of the District franchise tax. This report shall include, but not necessarily be limited to, the following information 1) the policy and economic justification for each deduction, exemption, and exclusion 2) a sample of the dollar amounts deducted, exempted, and excluded both in the aggregate and according to the size and the category of the business taxed 3) a sample of the revenue loss to the District resulting from each deduction, exemption and exclusion, both in the aggregate and according to the si%e and the category of the business taxed, and a bill amending the code of laws for the District to close the loopholes occasioned by the presen~ deductions, exemptions and exclusions available to entities subject to the District franchise tax 21 b) The Mayor shall report to r.he Committee on Finance and Revenue of the Council bi-monthly on the status of this report. TITLE IX ANALYSIS OF THE GROSS RECEIPTS TAX ON CERTAIN ENTITIES Sec. 90 1 a) The Mayor shall, within six months after the effective date of this section, submit to the Committee on Finance and Revenue of the Council and to the District of Columbia Auditor, a report analyzing the appropriateness of the level and the manner of taxation of certain financial institutions, assets and insurance companies Tbe financial institutions, assets and insurance companies analy%ed shall include, but not be limited to national banks, incor~orated banks, trust companies, credit unions, guaranty, bonding and title companies savings banks without capital stock, savings and loaD associations, incorporated savings banks, building associations, private banks or unincorporated bankers, note brokers, life insurance companies, life insurance benefits \ 28- mutual insurance companies, industrial sick benefit companies, and workmen's compensation b) The report shall include detailed statements and supporting data relating to (1 whether the present rates and manner of taxation are appropriate 2) how the levels of taxation and tax burdens on the enumerated entities and assets compare with the tax levels and tax burdens of (A) other District entities, and (B) other fin~ncial institutions and insurance companies in the Washington, o.c. metropolitan area and elsewhere in t _he nation 3) bow the various tax levels and tax burdens of the enumerated entities and assets compare with each other, and (U} the impact of changing the method of determining the tax liability of the enumerated entities and assets from a gross earnings or gross receipts methcd to a net income method, noting spe~if ically how smaller or recently established entities would be effected by such a change in .comparison to larger, longer established entities Znro11~a' 0 riiia.:il -29 c) The report shall inclu~e (l) a design or. designs of a net income tax, including rate levels and revenue estimates, for financial institutions and insurance companies, with justifications and (2) a bill amending the code of laws for the District to effect any changes in the present law deemed necessary as a result of the information compiled pursuant to section 801 (b) of this act. TITLE X AMENDMENT OF THE THIRD AMENDMENT TO THE REVENUE ACT OF 1975 ACT Sec. 1001. The fifth line of Section 3(v) of the Third Amendment to the Revenue Act of 1975 Act is amended by strikinq "dies,ft. Sec. 1002 section 6.2 of Chapter I of Title 16 of the o. c. Rules and Requlati°.!1s is amended by striking 2. 5" and insertinq in lieu thereof •2 sec. 1003. Subsection (e) of section 7.5 of Chapter I of Titl.e 16 of the o.c. Rules and Regulations is amended by strikinq n2.sn and insertinq in lieu thereof "2 30- TITLE XI AMENDMENTS TO THE INCOME AND FRANCHISE TAX l\C Sec. 1101. Paragraph 13 of subsection (a) of section 3 of Title III of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 61 Stat. 337; o.c. Code, sec. 47-1557b(a 13 is amended by striking out the l.ast sentence in the first paragraph and the entire second paragraph and inserting in lieu thereof the following new paragraphs A change in a taxpayer's election to claim the optional \ standard deduction or to itemize deductions may be made in the same manner as is required and to the same extent as is \ 31 permitted under the provisions of section ll4(b) of the Federal Internal Revenue Code In the case of a part year re3id~nt whose taxable year is l~ss than twelve calendar months, t.~e optional ~tandard deduction shall be ten percent of his adjusted gross income or $1,000.00 prorated by the number of months in which he was a resident, whichever is lesser. For this purpose, more than one half of a month shall be considered a full month and one half of a month or less shall not be considered Sec. 1102 Section l of Title V of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 (D.C. Code ac. 47-l~G4) is cl.mended by inserting at th~ end thereof the following d) Certificates of Nonresidence Except for elective officers of the United States Government and any member of the Executive Branch of the Onited States Government appointed by the President of the Onited States and subject to confirmation by the Senate of the United States and who serves at the pleasu:e of the President, all individuals described in the second sentence of section 4(s) of Title I of this article shall file with the Mayor of the District of- Columbia a certificate of nonresidence in such form, manner, and at such times a.s the Mayor shall, by regulation, prescribe Enr olle d. Or i i11;J.l 32 TITLE XII Rl\TJ:S OF INCOllE TAX FOR RESIDENTS Sec. 1201 a) Section 3 of Titla VI of the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Ta;c Act of 1947 (D.C. Code, sec. 47-1567b(a)} is amended to read as follows Sec. 3. Imposition and Rates of Tax In the case of a taxable year beginning after December 31, 1975, there is hereby imposed on the taxable income of every resident a tax determined in accordance with the following table If the taxable income is: The tax is Not over $1,000 2, of the taxable income over $1,000 but not over $2,000 20, plus 3% of excess over $1,000 Over $2,000 but not over $3,000 50, plus 4% of excess over $2,000 Over $3,000 but .not over $4,000 90, plus 5% of excess over $3,000 over $4,000 but not over $5,000 140, plus 6% of excess over $4,000 over $5,000 but not over $10,000 200, plus 7% of excess over $5,000 over $10,000 but not over $13,000 550, plus 8% of excess over $10,000 over $13,000 but not over $17,000 790, plus 9% of excess over $13,000 Over $17,000 but not over $25,000 1,150, plus 10% of excess over $17,000 over $25,000 1,950, plus 11% of excess over $25,ooo 33 XIII GROSS r:ARUINGS TAX ON 3UILDIUG ASSOCIATIONS Sec. 1301. Paragraph 9 of section 6 of the Act approved July 1, 1902 (32 Stat. 620: o.c. Code, sec 47- 1704} is amended by striking out "three" and inserting in lieu thereof "two TITLE XIV EFFECTIVE DATES Sec. 1401. T~e amendments made by Titles I and II o'f this act shall take effect on October l, 1976 Sec. 1402. The amendments made by Title III, VI, VII, VIII, IX, and X (except sections 1002 and 1003) of this act shall take effect on the date this act becomes law accordi.ng to the provisions of section G02(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act irollcd Orisiu~l -34- Sec. 1403. The amendments made by Titles IV and V an~ ty sections 1002 and 1003 of Title X shall take effect on the first day of the first month following the idate of enactment of this Act, if the date of enactment falls hetween the first day and the fifteenth day; inclusive, of a month; but such amendment shall take effect on the first day of the first month more than thirty days after such date of enactment, if the date of enactment falls between the sixteenth day and the· thirty-first da_y, inclusive, of a month sec. 1404. The amendments made by Tities XI and XII shall take effect with respect to taxable years beqinning on or after January 1, 1976. Sec. 1405 The amendment made by Title XIII shall take effect with respect to g~oss ea.rnin9s for the year ending June 30, 1977, and for each succeeding year ending on the thirtieth day of June. TITLE XV MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS ·J Snroll cd Orl c; in~l -35 Sec. 15 01 (a The provisions of this act ar~ severablE, and if any provision, sentence, clause, section or ~art is held illegal, invalid, unconstitutional or &amp;gt;inapplicable to any person or circumstances, sach illegality, invalidity, unconstitutionality or inapplicability shall riot affect or impair any of the remaining provisions, sentences, clauses, sections or parts of the act or their application to other persons or circwnstances. It is hereby declared to be the legislative intent that this act would have been adopted if such illegal, invalid, inapplicable or unconstitutional provision, sentence, clause, section or part bad not been included herein and if the person or circumstances to which the act or any .part is inapplicable had been specifically exempted b) The repeal or amendment by this act of any provision of law shall not affect any act done or any right accrued or accruing under such provision of law before the effective date of this act, this act, or any suit or proceeding had or .l::nroll~d Ori iJJal 36- commenced before the effective date of th~s act, but all rights and liabilities under such law shall continue and may be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent as if the repeal or amendnent had not been made. Sec. 1502 (a) No later than ten legislative days after the date this act becomes law pursuant to section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governr.lental Reorganization Act, the Mayor shall submit to the Council proposed regulations implementinq this act b) The Council, acting by resolution, shall approve regulation~ irnple.'llenting this act no later than five legislative days after ~he date the Mayor submits the proposed regulations required by subsection (a) of this section. If the Council fails to act within the five legislative day period, the regulations proposed by the Mayor shall be deemed to have been approved, effective the fifth legislative day after the date the Mayor submitted the proposed regulations pursuant to subsection (a) of this section Docket for the Bill 8 ill 1-2 2 9 \ Considered in Council o 2 20 7._6 First Vota s s-_b RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE C:OUNC:ll 41EM8UI A T IE NAT N.V A.8. C:OUNC:IL 4IEM81E" A YIE NAT N V. A.8. COUNCIL 41EM81E A YIE TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDING x MJOR.E' D. x HARDY x WILSON BARRY x HOBSON x WIN!ER x CL\RKE x KlORE, J x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-tndicU Vote A. B.-Alnem N. Y-Not Voainq µ.~t Q_U).L Secretary of the Counci l) Final Vote in Council 3 1_1 7 6 7- 5- 1 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL. MCM8C" ATC NAT N.v COUNCIL. MCM8C" ATC NAT N.V COUNCIL. MIEM8C" ATC TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDI'OO x M&amp;gt;ORE, D. x HABDY x WIISON BARRY x ROBSON x WINTER CtARKE x M)ORE, J. x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-Indica1- Vot• A. B.-A.bs•m N. V-Not Votinq IM IS S76 P ntad to ~e M~~r By memorandum of April 6, 1976, subject lwaJ.V Secretary of the Council l!g- 0 UJ Secretary of the Council) Blll was returned to Councll for recons Ldera tion Mayor's Action Approved Disapproved Mayor's Signature) NAT x NAY x The Councll moved to reconsider final reading of Blll l-229 to include clarifylng amendments on April 6, 1976. Vote: 11-1-l(abs Enac18d without Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Counci l l N.V N .V x I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
