<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-77">
  <num type="law">1-77</num>
  <heading type="short">Corporate and Unincorporated Business Franchise Surtax Act of 1976</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-07-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-77.pdf">D.C. Law 1-77</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 1218</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-77, the “Corporate and Unincorporated Business Franchise Surtax Act of 1976,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-265, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 6, 1976 and April 20, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on May 18, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-120 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE P:ursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Govemtnent and Gov.ernmental ·Reorganizatior:i. Act, PL 93-198 the Act) th0 Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-265 on first and second readings April 6, 1976 and April 20, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 18, 1976,.this legislation waS as singed Act No. 1-120, published in the May 21, 1976 edition of the D.C. Register. and transmitted to both HouSes of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act e Couilcil of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law 1-77, effective July 27, 1976 J J STERUNG TJCKER Chairman of the Council D.C LAW l-77 In the Council of the District of Columbia July 27, 1976 To provide additional revenue for the District of Columbia. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Corporate and Unincorporated Business Franchise Surtax Act of 1976 Sec. 2. Section 2 of Title VII of the "District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 approved July 16, 1947 (61 Stat. 345, D.C. Code, sec. 47-l57la) is amended to read as follows Sec. 2. For the privilege of carrying on or engaging in any trade or business within the Dis tr Let and of receiving income from sources within the oistr let, there is hereby levled (a) for one taxable year beginning on or after January 1, 1975, a tax at the rate of 12 per centum upon the taxable income of every corporation, whether domestic or foreign except those expressly exempt under Title II of this Article and (bl for the taxable years beginning or or after January l, 1~76, a tax at the rate a·f 9 per cent.um upon 2. t.lic tax.:i.blc incona. o-i: e·-1cr7 co poraticn, \·1hcther 1.mrler itlc II of t~is_ Article anrl {c) for the taxable years l:ie1Jinning on or after .ranu.:i.ry l, lJ7G, but before ,T3.1:1U.ir'J 1, 1970, a sur.tax at the r:i.te of 1'1 pf r centum of_ tl1e ta lt;lcteI i.inc&amp;lt l under cl.:iusa (b) hereof he minimum t;:i ria?ablc under t!1is section shall be $25.00 Sec. 3. S.ection 3 of itlc t I!I of t}1e "District of Columbia Incor.:e incl J:ranc!1ise ax .\ct of 194.7 lt;l gt;rOvt?f! July 16, i·947 (61 5tat 345 c. Code sec 17-.1574b) is a.inentled to read as follo~1s Sec. 3 or th rivilege of carrying on or engaging in any trade or business within t~e District and of. receiving income from sources withiri t.~e District, t?1ere is !1crab1 l&amp;lt viec.1 (a) fa= on~ ta:~al:ile ye.:i.r ~eginning on or aft~r Januar¥ 1, 1975, a ta at the r&amp;lt;lte of 12 per centur.i u~on the taxable inco of of tliis 1\rticle ant.1 (b) for t.l1e ta~al:ile yeilra bctJini1ing on or LJ.!tcr .T intJ ir:t 1, 197C, u. ta it t!ie rate of 9 per centu l u1,on t:.l•c t&amp;lt;J al;lc i:1co ie of every Euroll 01~igin ll 3 except ti1osc c:q&amp;gt;rcs:ll cxcI!!pt. uric1er itle II of thi Article and (c for t~1~ taxable ear hcginninq on .or after J.:inuary 1, 1976 ~ut prior to .Tanuary l, 1977 and for tl1e taxable ear bl'!CJ L"'lning 0!1 or after J.inuar l, 1977 but prior to J&amp;lt;J.nuar:y 1, ig73, a s11rta at t e r&amp;lt;J.te of 10 per centuri of the a dete?rr.1incd u11c1e.r clause (b) hereof 1e ninimu ta ayablc under this section shall be $25.80 Sec. 4. Tl1e !1ayor is hereb~ authori::er! to ironulgate rules anc1. regulations to carr:r 01.it t!1c pro,risions of this act Tl1is act sl1all t.al:e effect. on the date t!'l.is a~t ecor.i.es la\ accorcling to he pro risions of section 602 (c) of the District of Col,.irn.bia Sclf-Governncnt and Gover~_r..cntal ~eorganization Act Docket for the Gill s""n.,1 1 2"6"5 ConsitJered in Council 4c nc 7 First Vote 7 1 S a"b"'s"l RECORD OF COUNCIL. VOTE COUNCii £Mllltll N4' N.V CC:ll,INCll Mlt Dltll NAY N.V. A.O. COUNCii C 1111:11 AYll l N T N.V. u. TUCKER x DIXON x SPAUT..DING I x CORE, D. x HARDY x t-IILSON x BARRY x HOBSON x Wib"TER x CLARKE 1&amp;lt; MOORE J COATES 1&amp;lt; SllACICLETON X-lndicat• Vole A. B-Ab1ent N. V-Not Voting lt;tl!JdQyrw.0 (Secretary of the Council) Final Vote in Council 4 2~0 7~5 9-1-3 (abs) RECORO OF COUNCIL. VOTE lt;:OUNCll Ml:l&amp;gt;lflClll TI N.V. 4.a, I! COUHCll llt 81:R N4' N.V. AA. COUNCii MltM•C:lll A" NAY N.V, A.a. TUCKER II DL'(QN x x I SPAU!.DING x M:IORE, D. x I HARDY x i-lILSON x BARRY v HOBSON v _J WINTER v CLARKE v M:lORE J v I COATES SHACJ LETON x X-lndicafl'!J Vote A. s.-A.b1•at N. V.-Mot VoUng ~cuv Secretary of the Council llllY 1!!l'S Presented to the Mayor Secretary of the Councill Mayor's Action: Approved AY 1976 (Mayor's: Signature) Disapproved Enacted without Mayor's Signature {Secretary of the Councill Reconsidered by Council Bill Docket e 1 u 1-"2"6'"5 Page Two Vote RECORD OF COUNCIL. VOTE COUNCii ll""Bllll COUNC11 C 8Cll TUCKER DlXON 1 lORE, o. HARDY BARRY HOBSON C'LA.RKE MJO!lE, J. COATES SHACKLETON X--1.Qdic:•t• Vot• A. B.-Ah.s•nt Presented to the President Sustain Mayor~s Veto Not Sustain Mayor's Veto MAY 2 5 1976 Submitted to the Congress Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the·Senate) Enacted without Congressional action Secretary of the Council) N,11 COUNCIL CM.llllJll N.V. SPAULDING WU.SON WINTER N. V-Not Votin.9 (Secretary of the Council Secretary of the Council President of the U. S.l t t a u :l t tA t'·v1 Secretilry of the Council) House Action Resolution Number Clerk of the .House </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
