<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-82">
  <num type="law">1-82</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-09-14</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-82.pdf">D.C. Law 1-82</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 2461</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-82 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-237, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 23, 1976, and April 6, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 22, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-135 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>:J LAW 1 n t~e Cour.ci_ of the ~istrict of Col ~m~ia ~o provide additional r even ue o r ocher ?Ur?oses f r the D1str1=t o f o_ u:noia, anc BE IT ENACT!D BY ~HE COUNCIL OF TSE .DISTRICT OF COLCMSIA That this ac t ~ay be c i ted as the •License Fees and Charge~ Act of 1 ~76 itle I 2USINESS LICENSES Sec 101 a ara9raph {a o f section 5 o: the Act en titled NA~ Ac~ t o re~u!ate and l icense pawnbrokers in the C1s tr1ct of Colum~ia approved Augus~ 6, 19 56 (D.C Code, sec 2- 2C05l :s araer.ced oy s cr iki cg out "SSOO" ar inserti~g in lieu er e c f "saoo o) Pu r a; ra?h (a of sec on 6 of sue \ct (C. C. Code sec. 2- 2006) is ane~ced by s tr i ~1ng out "S 25 0 and insert 1ng in l ieu r.her eo f S350 Sec 1U2 Sec~ ion 2 o f t he Act ent i t le An Ac: to regula te e e r ection, hanging, placl~g, paint1nq, di splay a ~c rr.a1ntena nce of ou~door signs anc o t her fo:ms of exte:1 ~r I i I 2- 3, J..73 S 5:a t 1U~5 gt Co:!e s ec. 1-23 2 s a!:lene y sec 103 Section o the Act entitled "An let to c:-ea-;e a re.,enue i n t l Dis";ri:t of Colu:ia .Cia by levyicq a t ax U?on ~l ogs t~erein to make such dogs pe~sonal \ pro?erty aod !or o~her p~rposes appro ved ~une 19, 1878 (20 Sta t 3 1 C. Code sec 47- 2001) is a;iiended by strilr.iog t~e Ei gure 3 and icse=tin~ in lieu thereof the figu=e "S S.?c. 1 0 a Pa=ag =aph 42 of section 7 if the A t e~:it lo1 ttAn Ac aki~g appropr iations to provide !or the ex?enses o: t go?er t of tbe Dist: ict of Columb ia for St 59 0 J C co:ie sec r.;7- 21 01) is fu r t.ber a:nended by st o:i::i~ t~e gut 3100 anc inserting in lieu t hereo! the i q ure soo a ragra?h a of section 7 of such l et {D C. Code se n- 2305) is a:nended by strilting t!le fi gure 11 S12" and icsert in lieu thereo! the figure "SU7 11 I c P3 a n. p :i 9 o section 7 of suc il Ac t J C. C::i :5 e iase:t~D q i l ieu ereo~ t~e ~igu:e "5222 d ar3 g rap!i O of s-action 7 o: sue ct (O. c Coc e, s ec. u7 23 0) is e e:ldP.I! to reac as f::lllovs 0) 0 vne r s or ~a nag ers o: bar~er snops beau:y ?a:~ors b eau~y salo~s va~i ty sho?s, o= shingle shops y whatsoe ve a me called, where h~ir c u~ti~9 ha.i.t-dressin9 i r eyeing a ic uri a ki ndrac acts a=e practice~ s~a ll pay a l icecse of $30 ~e= annu ID addition, any pe;so n vho it~ e?en3ently leases rents, or is otherwise aut i :ed t o occupy a ~arber shop chair a beauty she oo t h fro~ t he ovn Of anr such shop o r estatlis~ment s hall ?av a _icense f ee o f 33 0 pe: a~n~a !or e~ch sucb chair or ~oo t s o leased e~te: o~ othervise occupied e a a;=a ph l l o! section 7 of suc!:i. Act (D. C ode se U7 23ll is amend~d ~r striki~g tbe fi g ure "SS• and i::sert i:ig 1 li eu hereo! t~e !i;ure "S3 00 f ara;ra?il 12 o! s ection 7 of s:.ic:i Act c. Code sec 1.17-2312) is aoended Jy striking t~e !iqure II !5 ft and i~serting in lieu therea! the fi~uce "5152 g aragraph 11.i of se::tioo 7 o! such Act (D. C ode, se u 7 23 lll is a:nended to read as !ol lovs I.I l 3 3S cl o= oi:s o like g"ad e e sol~ sha l ?ay a lice~se fee o! Sl7 pe annum o r eacn ?U use~ i~ c is?eosing sa i d gaso l:ne o r o s { gt v:l e rs o r managers o! esta.blish:Dents l;'here ~erosene o:ls, o r gasoline o! lik~ gra~e are s~ored un~erg=o und sha ll pay a license fee of !80 per a~num, and v ~er~ s~ch like gra d~ kerose~e oils or gasoline are stored in abo ve-g rou tanks ~he license ~ee sha ll be S9Q per annum c) OV:lers o ma nagers of establishments h ~re ros~n o like gra~e is pt for sale shall ?ay a license fee of 9 ?er annum, and v b.ere oil o lt °ease o f like &amp;lt;;r::id.e is xe f~ r sale, the lice nse fee s ha O. be 330 ?e= a n ~um and whe=e c oal is kept for sale, the license tee s~all ~e s 9 e a c, a vhere ke=oseje asoli~e, or o~l i s sold t h ~oug~ a me t ecing device, the license fee s~al.l be S6U per a:ir.ac dj o vne:s o r managers of establishments vbe:e ire wo=Xs are stor~d or a r e kept for sale at vholesale o: at bot h v~o lesale and retail sha.11 pay a l ice nse fee of S760. O vne~s o ana gers of es tab lishments v h e= e fireworks are r.~p~ for s ale at =etail shall pay a lic ense f ee of 100 5 ex?losives c= any kir.d, inclucing am::i~~i~ion bu~ ex=l~cing f:;ewc=ks, a:e sto=ed o: are ke~t =o= sale at wholesale o= at b wholesale and retail shall pay a license :ee o 760 OWne=s pay a lic~se =ee of S47 No licecse shall ~e issued un~er t~is section ol u:nbia se i!ls ti~g in .lieo tile:~o! the !igu:t-e 550 i a=agra?h 17 of sec ion 7 of suet. Act (D.C. Code, sec. c7-2317) is a!le~ced t:&amp;gt ead as !ollo11s l Suopa:ag=a?h (a) of such parag:aph s (2) s:.i~pa=ao aph (b} o f suet gt;a=agra?h is a~eD~e1 by st=i~ing t~e fign 3 5 cd insertin~ in lieu ~hereof tbe !igure "ZJO 2;iro 1e= o na l b 6 5ec i 231 i s aJ:Je~ c&amp;lt s :ollovs l Subpa:-agr a a of suc !l pa r ag r apb is amend~d cy s iki:iq t. he fi gure "575" and i :ise t illq in lieu the=eof the !iqu=e "5239 2 Sub;:ia ra aph I o f s uch parag:-a?h is amende c! by fig ure "S17 k a r aq ra ph 19 of section 7 of sue~ l e t (0. C. Code sec Q7- 23 1 9 is a ~a !lded y striking t be f i9ure "S2" and in- serting in l ieu t b~reof the figure "S S a ra&amp;lt;;ra ?h 2 0 o s ect .t gt;!l 7 o suc h Act 0. c. Code sec 7-232 0) is .ue!ldP as follovs { 21 St gt;pa=aq=a?h (b) of such pa ra9ra pb i s redesi9na ted sub:'aw 7lc ra a and ~s amended by s~riking the igure "S 30 a!l nse i g in lieu t.!le:-eo! the !igure "S4l5 3 Subparagraph {c of su::h paragrap h is r edesig nated su a=a aph {!:} a!d is a1De nde1 :iy insai::ti:ig a!ter the p!\rase "or ent~rt~i~~en~s of any desc=iption t~e words "incluci~g ~heat":ical o r d r a 111a tic per~o't'mances o! any kind Such sllb- a nser~ing in li eu ereof the fi gure "SSC 7 1 a g=a?:l 21 o: S Ction 7 o Uc ct c Cod e s ec n 23 2 s aoenc ed by stri k ig the fig 1Jt:'e 11 &amp;gt;12 11 anc (n a =ag=a? b 23 of s ec't.ion 7 o! such Act (l:.c. Code s ec. U 7 3 23 is a:11et:.d as f ol! ovs Su bpa=a;=a ?h a o s uc b para;=a?b is am2oded ty st=iki~ J t ~e i qure "SS" ana inserting in lieu tb er~of the f i gu=e 11 517 11 2) Sub-para gr'iph (b) of s uc h paragracih i s a 111 ended by st i i i9 the figure "S65" a:id in sert.ing i:i lieu t!:e r of t ie figure "S2 08 o ar~g rap l 2u o! sect ion 7 o! such let (D:c. Code, s ec. rn 23 2 4) is a mended by striking the figUr SlS" and i ~serti~g in lieu thereof t he figu re 31 9 araqraph 25 of section 7 o! such Act (D. C. Code, sec. l.17 232 5) is a=ende:l to read as follovs ro iet c rs r ovners of a ci:=us trans?orted by ~ail oa d i~t o ~he Distri ct o! Columbia shall pay a license !ee o! s _9 00 ~er aay or e ach car l oad of cir:u s e31li? cent, a pr op =ietors or o vne rs of any circus transported by ~aa ons or motor-trucks in t o tbe District o! Columbia shall ?a Y a lic9nse tax of s1 q. oo ~er ~ay fo= each otor- t r uck :o~c o r wa~on loa d o ci r cus egui?Qent. but not to e xceea S 87 5. 0 0 ?e r da y r -a a =agra?h 26 o: section 7 of such C. C gt;de, sec 117- 2 J26) is ~oe::5e3 b y st=iki:ig the f iqure 35 a~c inser-:iog i:i lieu thereof t:ie figure "Sl59 } ?a =agra?il 27 of section 7 of si.:ch Act c. Code, sec. LI 7- 2 327 is a:11endec o read as follows a Cotn111iss ion :nerchants dealing in !ood er food pr ocucts s :ia:l pay a license :ae of S6u5 per ann11m {b) ovners or :nanagers of gt;akeries, bottlin9 establish~P.nts, candy- manufacturing establis~ments, grocery stores, maci~e ?rodocts or !ish sold at retail meat shops, and market stands handling food or food products shal.l pay a e~se f ee of Slll ?er an~um: P: ovided hat if any li=ensee ~eceund~r shall concuct upon the sa me pr emises ao=e a~ ooe o: th~ cal:i:i~s herei~ listed, no adcitional fee s~all be required C Ovne rs or 2anaqers of oelicatesse;is ice ream ?a:lo=s. so~a f ouotai ns, or so!t- drink establishments sha!.l amp;Y a li cense fee of Sl33 per annum: Pr ovided, T~at if any li=e~see he reu nder s hall conduct upoTI the sa=e premises more t ha~ one o the callings herein listed or listed in sut:paragraph gt of this sectio::i no additional fee shall be d) ovne~s ~r managers of ice c:ea~ manufacturing esta~lis~cents s~a~l pay a license fee of Sl OSO per ann um 9- t sa=e e:ises o=e t~a: o~e o t~e calli~gs listed i n e 1) o wners o a~agers o f =estaurants o r private clubs shall pa y a lice~ se !ee based upon seating ca?acity as !ol low 0 10 sea ts S) 11-50 sea ts C) 51-10 O sea ts D) 101 seats a~d over 133 per annuia Sl6 6 per annum Sl99 per anr.um S232 per annu11. W i t~in t~e 2eaninq of t his subparagraph a restaurant shall he a ny ?lace v he~e f ood o r ref=esh~e~ts a=e serTed t o t=ansi~ct custo~e=s to ~e e~ten o~ the pr e~ises vhere sold 2) Li censes to op~rate res t!urants or ea!etatias in t he ~is tri~ o ol~~bia Pub.lie Schools sb~ll be issued at 3 any l icensee he re under sball conduct upon tbe sa::ie premises mo~e than one of t .he callings lis~ed i n sn~~aras b S (b) and (c) hereic, no additional tee shall be require Wholesale de~lers in fisb o r: o t~er marin e o~ ucts shal l pay a license fee o f $429 per an!lu m. I 1 o l o ners iaa.agers dai:-ias shall pay a iicense !ee of 33 300 ?er ~nnu {!l 1 dealers i:i o oc or ood p=od ucts no t listad her or elsew~ere in t bis act s~al_ pay a license fee of Slll pe r a:ioum. 11 (s a =ag a ph 2 of section 7 o! sucll Act (D.C. Code, sec. U7 -2 332) is aaieod~d b y st.r~kiug the !i;ur1t 5" and inserting in lieu thereo! the figuie "3300 t) Pa:agraph 3U of section 7 of such Act l C. Code, sec 7-233 is amended by striking the figure SS" and inserti!lg in lieu thereo! the figure 30 \ aragra?h 35 of sect:.on 7 o sucll Act (D. c. Code s ec l7- 23'?5) is ai:iendad gt;j st.rild!l9 the figura "SS" and i:lserti:ig in lieu tr.ereo: the figu:e "S54 a:as:apa 37 of section 7 o! s ue!l Act (n.c. Code, sec 1.1 7- 2337) is a l)er.ded gt;y s i.k i g the words "five dollars" inse inq in lieu t !ie=eof the figure "Sl58 {v) Pa agraph 38 o! secti o n 7 of sacb Act (I C. Code, sec. LJ 7 3 3S} i s a.i:1ended· by ~ri~ing the figu:-e "Sl O" and ins er iog lieo thereof the figure "528 x a ragraph i:o of section 7 o! such Act (O. c. Code, sec 1.17- 234 0) is a.mended by st:-ikiog the fig:ire "SSO and i!ls tin g io lieu thereof t he fi g ure 300 11 { v J oi;e sec 17 23!!1) is aoe:ided by st iY.ing t.he flql.l t:'e 100 Z a=ag:-a i !1 3 of secti on 7 of s~ch Act (D.C. Code sec U7-23!12) is a:nended gt;y s t=i:.ting tile !igure S250 and ins e =t i g i.:i li e t!le=eo! the f igu::e S550 { a anCJra?h 35 of sectio:l 7 o! suc!l Act (D.C. Code, sec c.7 -2336) is a 2enoed to r~ad as follovs No ?er son sha U sell a.n y article merchandise o r food o r anythin~ whatever exce?ting nevspapers sold at l ar9 e ~nd not from a fi x e d location, upon the public streets, or from ?U~lic S?ac e i :l t he Dis trict of Columbia, w i~bout a license !ir st ~av~n9 ~een obtained under this section ersons s o li~e ~se~ shall be considered as vendors and shaLl be ~esiqnated as either Class A, Class a, or Class C vhethet sel li~g o o a !ixad location, en foot fr e e house t ouse, c o m a 7ehicle o an! description, and s hall pay a license e e per an nuc as follows 1 er soos w~o vend f oo d vhethe fro:n any public sp~c2 o r ;ioor to door (Class A S25 2 ersons vho vend any a r ticle o r merchandise o~~e~ than food f rom public space, but oot !rem doo r to doo t Class3 Sl5 3 Any pe=son vho vends any article of me rchandise 12- o t:i e r th an oo roo d o or t o coo Class C s so v~r? ve ndo so l i ~ensed s~ a~ l be furnis~ec vit~ 3 ~a!9e co espoo~i to t he nu er o~ nis lice nse vhie adge s hall be voro =cns?icuoasl heneyer tra~sact~ng business, and where sales a r e a ade o m a ve~icie such Tendor s hall ~e ?r ovi ded itb a cetal plate containing a number similar t o t he number of ~is l i cense, wbic h plate shall be cor.spic uonsl~ attached to th~ ve hicle at all times when soc~ ven do r is transdct ing busi~ess: Pr o vided h at no license shall be regu i =ed o! any person bringing to and selliDg at the s e veral ~arkets produce of ~is o vn raising: A.nd provl ~e1 f urther, that any pe rson unde: eighteen y~ars of 9e s ha be exempt o m obtaining a l icense if s uc h person is 9 ho:de~ of a valid vork per~it or stree t trade badge ~ssued b y the District of Coluahia Soard of Education, or if soc person is tbe hold er ot a si&amp;amp;ilar per~it issued by aoo~h e= jurisdic~ion. Tbe Council o! the Dis~rict of Colo~~ia i s he=e~y authorized and e mpowered to enforce oecessary regul~tions governing the conduc~ upon the public s~=eets a nc ?U~lic s paces of vendors licensed hereunder, inc l uding the power t o locate the places where licensed ve~~ors on the public streets and public spaces sball s~and and o change them as often as t he pu~ lic interests require 13- Sec 105 sectio::i 606 of ~itle VI o: t~e Act en t i tled n Act t o ?rovi~a ad!itio~al re7e~ue f o r h e Ois~=ict of Co- u i bia a??ro"led a y 27, 19~9 (63 Stat 138; D.C. Code se i 7- 2605) is amended as follows 1) sub pa :agraph A. of such section i s aoended by st:-i1i:i:i g th~ pb rase "fi xe d by t~e co uncil at a rate not t o ex eeo S a nd i::ise:-ting i n lieu ~he=eo! the !iqu.=e 15 Subparagraph i3. o! such sectio:l is amended by st=iking the ?hrase "fixed by the council at a rate ~ot to exceed "S5" and i~serti~g i n lieu tbereo! tbe figure 15 3) Su!)parag::ap!\ c 3) of sucb section is amended by st::iking he ph l! se "fixe by the Cou:icil at a rate not to exc eed "S5 and inserting in lieu t~ereof the figu=e "3 50 Sec. 106 sec~ion 2 of the Act eoti~le ln Act to ?r@veot a ud at public a Qctions i~ the Dist=ict of Colncbia app:ove~ Septe~ber S, 1916 (39 Stat. SQ6, ch. t1 73 o.c. Code, sec 117-220 2) is amended by s~riki:ig the f igure "S50" an d insa cting in lieu t ~ereof the fi9ure "5150 Sec. 107. Section 7 of ~he let entitled "1.n Ac~ to provi~e !o~ the regulation of closing out and fire sales in t he :iistr ict of Colum!:lia a pprov ed Septe m~e l, 1959 (73 Stat o:i9 i e Code, sec. 117-3002) is amended by striking -i e :igu::e "SlOO a:1c! i::iserti g i.n lieu :hereof t~e !igo::e 11 S277 11 Sec 09 Para9::a?h i:s of section 7 o! the Act er. title An act ~aki~g ap~rop=iations to provide o the ex?enses o: t he government of t~e District of Columbia for t:e !iscal yea enjing June thirtieth, ninet een hundred and t~ree an~ for at~e purpos es approved J uly l 1902 (32 S tat. 628, o. c Code, sec. i.7-23tuq as amended, is further a~ended to read as follows The Oist ict of Columbia Council is authorized and e~?overed vhe~ in its d~scretion such is deem ed advisable o req uire a ~icense of other businesse s or call ings not liste1 ir hi s Ac~ or chapter 21 of t~is title and which. in its j e~ent equire ins?ection s upervision, regula tion o a~y ot her ~ctivi ty or expenditure by any municipal ~gencies n~ the Council of t~e Dist=ict of Colu~bia ~s furt ~e= a u t~orized and em po wered to fix the license !ee ~he=e!or i such a= ount as, in its judgecent, vill be not less tha~ the cost to the Distrie"t o: Columcia of such i~spectionr SU?ervision, regulation, or o t he r activity or expenditu e e Council is !urther autborized a~d e~povered i n its discretion to mo~ify any o! the provisions t s Ac~ o~ chapte= 11 of thi s title so ar as e l na ti~g therefrom any business or calling in th i s Act or 15- c~ a?~e= 11 o h is t~t~e :e~~i:ed t o be licensed nd t~e Co~ ncil i s fu=tne= ac t horize d a e~?o~e in its ~is­ c =etioc to r aise or ower the amoun t ~f t~e license f ee ?ro vi~~1 in t~is 1=t o: chapte= 21 o! t~~s title hen in i~s iudgement such inc:ease o r decrease is var:antetl 16 Sec 201 T~e sched~le o ees t o be cha=;ed by tbe ~ist= ict o Co lumbia :or t~e issua~ce o r ipari an pe its is bece~y es~a ishe! as se t for~h in the a~tached "Riparian ?e ts Sch~dule ees =e ee e les a~c latio~s :o= t~e Gove en~ o f ~i?a=ian Ri~~ts a n= Wa~er iv~leges i n e Dist=ict o Co!~ia. Fees f or pe~i~s to fill or C:edge cons~ct, FE ecor.s~=uct c= repair any stru=t~e shall be as follows: Work costing U? to SSOO s 9. 00 Work cos~L f=o~ SS Ol to $1,000 14. 00 Each additional Sl,000 o! increased cos 14. 00 RE?t"N~S refu~d of pe r.it fee sh~ll be made as follows: a. When no wo=k has been done oer aut~ority o! pe~t t e fee in excess of the cost of inspection to ve:i!'y no wo=k having been done, based on SlO per inspector hour, the cost of any engi~eeri examin- ation time previously devoted to approval of p1ans, based on $15 per hou plus Sl4 admi."list=at~ve costs o issuance anc refu.~d shall be refunded 14.00 When work au'=horized -by permit has bee~ only par~ially done and when t~e Dis ict i s satis~ied Ulat no mc=e work will be do~e under he pe:mit, the !ee excess o! t e cost c! a~y engi.~ee=ing pla~s exal:l.i."l tion based on $15 per hour, cost of ins?ections costs :ased en SlO per hour, plus Sl4 acimir..ist:ative costs of "issaa.nee anc re!und" shaJ.J gt e~un.deC 14 o o c. P=-ovidec T~at =ec-~est !er re!u d shall be made wit i.:l six ll:On hs om ca~e o! issuance a.nd the pe ai.t and :eceipt a=e =et~~ed to t he Per.nit Bra ch ENALTY T~e ?enalty tor a pe=&amp;gt;11it to abate notice ct coing wo=k wit~out a pe--rtit shall be 50 pe:cent of ~he =ee. No pexinit fee shall be charqed when supported by evidence ineicati 9 that the applicant is unde: contract o= subcontract to per=or.n the !ollowinq l Wo:k done exclusively for the District of Columbia 2) Work cone uncer c ont=act for t~e o~st:ict 17 tle r L~C:3ICAL s Sec 301 h e schedule of fees t o be charged by the Dist=ict o Colum~ia =o~ the i~spection of elect=ical e_qu i ien t a:id ~or the issua nee o erzi ts to ?erform elect=ica! sgrvices is hereby esta~lished as set for th in t~e attached lectrical Fee Scbeecle SCS U!.E Gro l Wi=i~g Only ou le s eacr. 10 5.00 Octlet ~ear.s and ·inc luees =ece?tacle, swit:h anc i e cctl.ee G=oup 2 ix~u=es ar.c La.ophol~~s-each 10 2 00 Groc? 3. Elect=ic Oischa:ge Si s Group 4. 1st 500 va Each adci tiona s·oo va Eea ti.:ig Eq-~i?Jne.nt Easeboe.:d or soaceheaters lst 10 KW-oe= each KW Each additional KW Or.i~ heaters aces-mo~o=s no t incluaed lst Ea.ch adC.i tiona.l C~ntrols only-each For residential ~P?liances--s~ Miscellaneous ?o= u.r.its with motors--acd appropri~~e motor !rom Group 6. 9 00 5.00 2.00 1.25 ll.00 s.oo 7 00 Groep 5. Coir.:nercial ~eating and Cooki g Appliances G:-ou;i Q Other than G=cu~ 4 Fi:st l 8 KW 9.00 s.oo ll.00 5.00 Each aC.di ticna,l First-over 8 !\W ac.h additional Moto=s a.~d Gene=ators ~ess than~ £.P R.P to l S.P ac~ additional Ove: l 3.P to 5 H.P Zach aceitional Ova: 5 P to 10 E Each ad~itional ove= 10 E.P. to 20 E. P Each addi~ional over 20 E.P. to 30 P..P Each addi~ional over 30 E.P. to 50 H.P ach additional over so E.P. to 75 a.P ach additiona l over 7 5 P p Each adeitional Apply Grou;i 2 9 00 5.00 14 00 5.50 22. 00 9 00 27 oo ll. 00 35.00 16.00 42.00 18 00 Sl.00 22.00 58. 00 27.00 For installation c: more than one motor, be ~he l a=qest mo te= plus t.~e aCCi~:o~al the initial !ee shall :ee :or the s~aller. G=o~p 6 ~xa e: Two 15 P oto=s a~c ~wo 3 n.P. moto: s. G=oup 7 Service ls~ 15 E otc= 2nc 15 S.P. moto: lst 3 E.P. mote: 2 3 a o~or $27 00 11. oo· 14.00 s.so Piped house connectior s Each additio~al Pole line on p=ivate p:ope:~y Each adC.i t.iona.l ConCucto~s, incluC p~le Each adc!i tional Se~ ice conducto=s-each G:ou? a. se:vice and Meter Eqt:i?ment 0 to 200 am ie=es Each addi~io~al 2 0 l t.o 4 0 o ampe.res Ee!.ch aCC.i ~ional 4 01 to 8 0 0 amperes a ch adC.i -tional Ove BOO am::eres Eac l ad di tiona.l 5.0 0 2.0 0 5 00 2.00 7.00 2 00 S 00 1 00 s. oo 16. 00 9 00 31 00 16.00 47. 00 22.00 Reloc~tion eplacement o= original installation, including mete: connection !acilities or inst,llation of more ian one se=vi ce eqi:ipme l the litial i e e shell be for the lc.=ges t se ice e~i t:le~t plus ~e a=.c tic~al !ee !or t.11e s:iialler. ED.MPLE: TWO 4 00 amperes a d two 200 am?eres lst 4. 00 ar.i?eres 2nd 400 aro?eres ls~ 200 am.pe=es 2nd 200 a.I:1peres Sl6.00 9 .00 ll 00 s.oo G=oup 9. T:"ansfonne=-s l to l O Ea.ch adC.i tional ll to 7 5 lCVA ac~ ad~it!onal 7 6 tc 200 l\V'A Each additional Over 200 nrA ac:h addi t i onal Vault ach additional 9 .00 5 00 14. 00 7 00 18.00 9 .00 27.0 0 14.0C 47 00 22.00 r o gi o Elect=ic~l fee schecule cc~tinuee :o= instal la t ion o= mo =e tha~ or.e t=ans fo~e the i n itial fee shall be the larsest t=a~s:or~e lus the fee f o r t he s~aller x M?Ll Two 200 KV;\ ~a lsfo=:ners and two 75 VA t=ans:c mers. lst 200 K'VA ~ansforr.1er 2nd 200 KVA ~a~s=o~er 1st 75 KVA t=ansforme: 2nd 75 t=ansfor:ner $18. 00 9.00 14.00~ 1. o~o G=oup 1 0 T~eat=es o= O~her Places cf Public Assl lbly Spotlights Arc Each aCQ or.al Incandescent Each additional Portable o: ternpora=y arc Each ad.di tional Portable or tempora:y incandescent Each aC.Ci tional Motion ?ictc=e machi~e el Il'1an e:i t Each a.C.c!i tional Portable Eac!l aCC i ional Slide p=o j ecto ach addi tion~l Anlpli!i er Eac!l add i on.al DL"tlme: s ove l :KW Each aCC.i tiooi l Portable swi tc!'ll:&amp;gt;oarc Each acidi ~icnal ortacle T.V. i.~stal~ation lst port.able T.V. receiver Each adeitional receiver Porta.ble ·o= tem~ora:v inca~cescent lair s (o t her tha:l s potlights l to 25 lights 26 to 50 lights 51 to 100 lights Each additional 100 lights Group 11 Tempora::y Installations Decorat i ons, Lawn fetes etc. l to 25 lig s-lst 90 days ach adeitional 90 davs 2 6 o so l ights 1st ~o days Each addi tional 90 days 51 t o 100 lig:its-lst 90 days Each additional 90 days 9. 00 s. oo s.oo 2.00 7.00 s.oo 5. 00 2.00 22. 00 ll. 00 14. 00 7 00 ll. CO 7,0 0 9.00 5.00 1 00 s .oo 9 00 s. oo s oo 4.00 7.00 10.00 14. 00 coo 9 00 s. oo 14.00 7. 00 18 00 9.00 ach acciticnal 1 00 li;hts-ls~ 90 c a ys s Sac~ ac~itio~al 90 davs Use o: c ent on w~=lng appa=at us ane fixtures fo= use pending completion of ir.s~allation-lst 90 days Each additional 90 days t Circ".lses and c a=nivals 3. 00 2.00 18 CO 9 .0 0 lst so a ch additional l 0 0 K"r'l £xhibi~ons, etc. 47. 00· 47 00 lst 3, 000 sa ft Each additional l,000 sq ft Grou? 12. Radi o and Television Eqt:i?ment T:ansmitti~g Station-:i:st Each additional Receivi q Station Antenna and Grour.d Con.~ection Device for Receivers-ls't Each additional 10 can-t=alized Speake: Station-1st ~o Each adci~ional 1 0 Cent=alized Receiver Ampli!ier Each ac:!Ci tional CloseC Ci:cui t Televisi.on Ce.me:a lst Camera Each addi tiona.l Camera G=oup l3. M:scella eous ;1.:c Vapor La:nps-!i st Each addi ional Battery Ch argers Ea.ch add ional Elec=ic Ranges (Residential Eac!'l addi 't.ional Clothes Dryer (Re sidential Each adC.i tional Ga=bage Disposal (Residential Each addi tiona.l X- Ray Machines Each a.dd.i. tional Dishwasher (Residential Each additional Bot Water Heater (Residential ach addi 't.ional Fire Ala=:n Station and Bell Electri c Signs L~cancescent Festoon Lighting Air Conci t:.one.r Cent: al Sys t err. Not over 5 tons (Resicential Fi=st 2nd to 25th Above 2 5 Re c ti ier ach aCC.i onal WelCe=s Eac:t addi ional 20.00 11.00 27.00 1 4. 00 s.oo s. oo 5.00 s. oo 9.00 9 .00 7.00 s.oo 7.00 5.00 10. 00 5.00 S.00 l.25 s.oo l. 25 5. 00 2 00 9.00 s.oo s.oo 2 00 5.00 2.00 Apply Apply Ap;&amp;gt;ly 22.00 7.50 5.0 0 l l 00 5. 00 ll. 00 5.00 GrOI l Gro 2 Group 2 eac ea lec~=Lcal :ee schec~le cor.~i.~ued G=o 13. Miscellaneou s (continued) Min r:n:m :ee S S:oo ?o=~able e91i ant-on ci=c~its 2 0 a e=es o= less.~o :ee Elect=ic naces (residential st 6 9 al I I I I I I• I I. e I I e I .11.00 2!'ld 9 0 0 Over 25, eac 5 00 Electric c=anes fc= const_-uction work 50.00 Reolac~~e~t o e eder conducto=s: per feede old wo=k&amp;gt; 1st 5. oo Each aCC. i ti.anal 2. 0 0 Panel boe d r eola:ement lst panel boa=d (old work 5. 00 Each additional 2 0 0 Installation of empty concuits: Per floor S. 00 DuDlicates el:.mL~a V and fi~al ce~i!icates of oer!or.nance or cor=ection of reco=ds s. oo Qua=~e=ly pe=nits-The fee !o: quarterly permits to install ci=:ui~s, f X~~es and reeeotaeles shall be in accordance w~t::i. the work done, in no case less than $20 paya=le at the ti e the pe=mit is issued 20. 00 De!ect =ei.'lsice=tion fee lo. 00 When t e ap?lican eceives a w=itten notice of defects :ound c~ring e ori;inal inspection an~ the appliea:tt or his a;ent reports ~e cef ects have ~een eor=ec~ec, anc ~pon s~ection of the de=ect, noted origi=lally, i t is =evealec that th~ de!ects have not beeD f ully cor=ec~ec, a char;e of $10 will be made or each ins~eetion tbe=ea er lo. oo NC Whe=e application is ~aae f or a perm.it to cove an elect:ical ins~allation, or alterations previously mace f or which a ?e it has not been issued ne=e s hal l ~e a service charge of 50 pe=cent of t~e regula= fee with a mini.mum o f $10 accition to the regular fee. No service charge shall be mace f a= e!lle gency repai= work if a pe i..t is appliec o= at once 10.00 UNDS: A re:unc of pe~i~ fees shall be made as follows a. When no work has been cone cer a uthority of a pe=:nit, t he fee in excess a the costs of i ns?ection to ver ify no ~o=k having been cone, based on 0 per ins?ec~cr hcu the cost o f any engineering examinatic~ t e previously devoted to ap?rcval of plans, based o 15 per hour, plus $14 adoir.strative costs of ~issua~ce and =e!un s hall be :e~~nde 14. 00 i:-o~led n~icinsl t lect=ical =ee schec~le continued b. When wor k a~tho=i=e~ by pe Tr.it ~as bee~ only pa=tially done a~d when the Dist=ict is sa~is:ied t~at no ~ere wo=k ~ill be done u~der ~be ?e=nit t:le !ee ~n exce s s o: t~e cost o: a~y ensinee=ins lans exa."T a tion basec on Sl5 ?er hou cost o: inspections made, based en SlO pe= hour, plus Sl4 administrative costs of "issuance and refu ld shall be e!unC.eC I 14 o o c, Provided: Tha t t.~e re&amp;lt est !or =eft d shall be made w n six months om t~e d ate o! issuance and the per:ti.t and recei ?t are returned to the Pe:nit Branch. Penalty: The penalty for a pe mit to abate notice of coL~g wcrk without a ?Ea nit shall be 50 percent of tbe fee. WA!V1:a OF RM!T S: No pe l:lit fee shall be chargec when suppor~ec by evidence indicati~g t a~ the e?plica~t is unde= cont=act or subcontract to perform tile following l) work done exclusively for the Oistriet of Columbia 2) Work done u der cont:act for the Dist::ict o! Colur.ibia 3) Wo=k done exclusively for agencies of e U~itec States Gov~~ent 18 Ti~le IV RJ..TES FOR D.C. GZNE U. 30SPI~A D. C. VI:.LrlGE N~ Sec. 401 a The per d i em rates t o be ch~ged f o r in?atient s ervi ces at the Dist:ict o f Columbia Gene:al Hospital a=e he r eby established as follows: Medice.l S Surq ical Pedia t~ics Obstetrics C:-ippled Chil~ren Gynecology 160 00 p e day 160.00 per day 230.00 per day 305 .00 per day 192.00 per day 112, 00 per cay (b The rates t o be charged for outpatient clinic, emergency oom services, clinic abo ticns, and hemodialysis ~reament at t!'le Distri ct of Columbia Genera l Bospital are ~e:-eby established a s =ollows: Out?atient Cl~nic S Emer gency Room Clinic A.bo=t,ion Hemodi alysis Treatment 19.25 29.00 360 00 310.00 per visit per vis i t per a.bo~ion per ~eatmer.t (c The =ates to be charged fo= mental health services, mental re~a:dation clinic se~ices, and home psychiat~ services ~e~dered to patients are her eby e s t ab l i shed a s =ollows l l For Mental Healt.h Se?"Vices A B C l Inpatien~s S Day Patients Outpatients 102 00 pe day 45.25 per day 29 75 per day (2 o ental Retarda~ion Clinic Se:vices 19 A ay ?atients 36.25 ?e= day (B) ou~patients 24.25 per visi 3 For Sc~e Psycb~a~-y Services: Sl9. 00 pe: home visit Sec 402 a The per diem r~te to be char ged for skill ca=e patients at oistrict o= Columbia Village shall be $57 00 b The per eiem ra~e to be charged for intermediate care ?atients at Dist=ict of Columbia Village shall be $36 00. Sec. 40 3 The per die ra~e to be charged patien~s at Glenn Da l e Hospi tal for medical ca:e anc serviee shall be 54. 00 i:rolle~ O~i;inal -20 it.le v OCC~?A~IO AND O?ESS!O~A L!CZ~SES Se iOl a sectio~ 7 o he ~ct entitled l ~ct ~akinq a?pro?=iatio:is t o ?rovi d or the expeos~s o! t~e ;overnme!lt of t~e -nis~r~ct Colu~bia f iscal year e~c iog Ju~e t hi=tieth, n ietee:i ~on eC: aod ee and :o= othe r ?u=r:oses 32 .5tat 51 0 1 Co:i sec. 47-23U~a. {a as a111ended, is :u:t~e: a~en~ed to r ead as follows: 11 (a 0 an t e n:.c.et y C.~ys om uc;ust 11 l97U lO ?e=soc s h~ll in e District of Columbia, dis:ha:ge any of t duties o! all unde axe u~less t~~re hes bee~ iss~ed to 0 7 t aro= o he strict o! Coluobia a lica:ise t he i ore in ull. fore~ and ef!ect Ile fees !or tbe ap?l~:a'!ion !or, issaa~ce of, aDd :e~e~al of licenses a:e ~e y ~sta~~is~ec ~s llovs: II c.:1 lp?licatio:i fe~ for examination !or lice.cse J.S an cn e:-t~ k e 3.?P t:tic S 2) O :i;i.n~l li:ense fee !or ur.der~ake :s a:id a?prentices 5 3 ee !or t!l.e issuance o! courtesy cards to :in d e:~axtars f:-om other j uris~ictions !or the ?ri'1ile-;e of e::o:~i their OCCU?a'!ion in the nistriC Cf o:u i a s 25: i clled Ori&amp;amp;i~el 2 i ln~ual e~e~ al !ee fo licenses f o r unle a ~e~s S25: i! t he re~uest fo r =e~e al i s la te a: adeitional f~e o SS 5) Ar.r.ual rene~ al fee o r lice~ses for a??rent i ces 15 i t he re.oe val is late, a~ additional tee of 5 an d {5) Pee f o r certi! yinq recor ds SlO ll o! t be above !ee s, iocludinq the e xa3i~ati on fee in su!J?a ragra ph gt of t~ i s s e c t ion. sbal l e ?a i d to the D Strict of Coluroibia e a surer; a nd l i c e nses shall be issued at t~e ti~e and in the manner p t ovided in para9r a ph 5 of section 7 of t e Act of July 1 1 1 902 (D. c Code sec. u7- 2305 b) sue Act SUb?araq =aph { of ?ara9rapb 4U k of section 7 of (D. C. Code sec. u7-.23i.4a gt is a a ended b .1 st king t he v o =i Com;:issio.:ie vber e?er it a pea:=s a nd insP-rting in lieu t hereof the vor ayor I t i s ur tber amended by adein; t he ollo wing se~tence at the end thereof to r~ac as ollovs e e xamination !ee fo r app~ican~s wh o desire to become u~dertak ers s hall be SlO. I n lieu of e xa mi na t io n, a~ ap? lica ot ~ay be licensed a s an on~ertaker in t he Dis~=i=t o: Col~mbia i! so licensed in anoth er Stat~ o r Te rritory wh~ r e the quali!ica tion s pr esc=i be~ by such ot he r licensing Z ollcc Crig:~al 22 iceosing wer~ a t least qual t o t~ose ?re scri~ec i e ~is t=ic~ o f Colc~~ia at t~e da~e o: a? plica t ion or a Distri:t o f umbia lice!"lse a~c w e sue~ S~~te o: Ter=itory accepts i~ like manner t~e lice~si~g o! unde :t~kecs of the District o! Colum~ia c St:l:i pa r aqra?ll (d) of parag=aph u:u o! section 7 o! such Ac~ p. c. Code, sec. a7- 231l~a d is a mende d bf. st: i kinq t he words "the Co mmission e and the District o! Col u~bia council and i~sertin9 i n lie u thereof the words "the ~ayo an~ the Council o! t~e District of Columbia o! s~ctio!"l 7 o! such Act i.i. c. Code, secs n 23iu1 (d 3) and (d 4 a r e re?ealed e Subpara g:ap~s (d S} 6} and {7) of para q:-a?h UUA o! section 7 of such Act (D Code secs 7- 2311£0 5 {6) and {7 are redesi~r.ated a s so~par~9ra.plls tel P&amp;gt cc;&amp;gt; a.:i d cs Sec. 50 2. Sectio D 23 of t he Act e ntitled '1 An Act t o pro vide for t~e e xamination and registration of ~rchitects and to :egulate the practice of architec t ure in the Distric~ of Columbia approved Dececiber 1 3 l .9211 (43 Stat. 716, ch 1 D c. Code~ sec. 2-10 23) is a.mende d to read a s follovs 23- nThe es to ~e ?aid ~y an a??licant to the ~ist=ict o Col u i 7reas'1 er r the ap?l a ion =or ssua:lce of, a~d r ene~al o~ a licetse are established as follows a l) Application fee !or exami~ation :or license as a n architect SlO 2) Zxamina tion fee SBO b original license fee !or an a=cbitect SlO c) l:lnual =ene11al fee :or licensee for ao architect 20~ if the request !or renewal is late, an a 3eitional :e~ of SS ldl Fee for the restoration cf an expired ~icens szs {e } Fee for certi~ying records SlO: and ee -tor an application for license by =eci?rocity S90 Sec. 503. Section 4 of the Act entitled "An Act tc =egulate lu~bing aod ga s !itting in the District of Columbi a approved June 18. 1898 30 Stat 77, c~ Q67 i Cooe se 2-l qOS) is amended to read as !ollovs: n~ll ~enevals of e xisting licenses a~c all new licenses a s a mast~r plamoer and gas fitter or mas~er gas !itter shall ~e fo r a period of not ~o=e tha~ one yea and the fee ~or le Ssi;ance of such licensq shall be SS.OD ?e= annu a~1 or th~ reneval of such lice~se, the fee s~all be i30.00 211 er noa o r a lice~se yea r beg i~~ing J ~nuar y l an~ ecding De cec gt;e l. such S?e::ia l l ice:'lse :ee shall le separate f =o o i n a dd i tio n t o any c on tractors• o r busi~ess license tax e reafte= fixed for this ~nd similar occu?atior.s by the Mayor of t~e Dist=ict of Columbia according to law. Licenses issued at any time a!ter the begi~ning of thP. year s ba l l cate !ram the first day of the mont~ in hic h the licgnse is issued and end on the las~ day of the l icense year a nd ?ayment shall be made of a propor~ ional amount of the a~nual license !ee. Any licensee ~ay apply !or a~d receive a license for or OD behalf of any !ir CO?a=tnership or corporation that he is a bona fide meQber o: or a substantial stockholder i n: but all ?lumbiDg or gas fitt i~g done pursua~t to such l icense shall be done ande r e imoed iate perso nal supervision of t~e licensed oa In addition to e fees l isted a'bove, tnere is also establisbec the following fees a) {l) AP?lication fee for e~aminaticn !or license as a ~aster plumber, gas fit~er er master gas fit ter s 5 2 xa:i nation fee 120; II gt ee !or cer~ifying records SlO: if the request for ann ual r e newal is late, au add.itiona! fee of SS o r oal nrc?.l E i.o 25 he yo o he Jist:ic~ of Colu~bia o= his duly authori zed a9e nt s all haYe t he power to sus?and o= revoke a ny plc c~e s or gas fitte s lice~se o r a violaticn o t~e o.m~inq or ;a s fitting reg ulat i ons after a pcblic bearing ;ra~ted t he li :ense o r a!te r con viction i n court fo r such vi olati on or fo r conc!uct illvolv ng :11 oral t ur ?itude 25 Se c 50 T~e fees to be cha=ged by the ~ist=ict of :ol~obia for the issuance of ?Uhlic S?ace ?er~its o= unde=grounf excavations. constructing oanholes, connecting sewers, conduits o ains are hereby estatlished as set !o=t'!l i. e. the attached "P u lic Spac:e ?e=mit ee Schedule 27 i~l e VI I C03?0R!!ION S Sec. 701. Paragraph (1) o! subsection (c) of section :21 o: the Oist=ict of c~lumbia susiaess Cor?oration Act (68 Stat 229 n. c. Code sec 29-936 (c l (1 hereinafter i::i his ac e :er ed t o as the 11 corpol:'a tion Act as a;;iend ed, i s t h e= aoenced by st=i~ing :ro3 t he last proviso thereof the !i;u~e "SlO" and inserting i::i. lieu t ~ereo! the figu=e S2 0 s ec. 702. Pa=aq=apb (3) of subsection (c) of section 122 of the Cor ation Aet (69 Stat. 229: o.c. Code, sec. 29 l.36 { c} {3 as a cended is furt;,er al:le!'ded b y st=iki:ig f=o t he last proviso t hereof t~e figure ns~o n and inserting i::i. lieu thereof the figure ns~O SQc. 703. Subsection (d) of section 121 of the Cor ?orat ion Act (6S Stat. 229; 29 J.C. Code, sec. 29-9 36 (d as amended is tu=ther a me~ded ~y striking t b eref=om the i;u re "S10" ao d i n sert i ng ·i.n lieu t.heceo! the figu=e 25 s e c 70 Subsection (e of sec~~on 121 o! the Cor?o::atioll Act (59 St~t 229; D. c. Code, sec 29- 936(e as amen1ed, is fo:ther amended to read as !ollows e) Each dom.estic c:or:po=atio n on;anized, incorporated, o r r eiocorporated under the p:ovisioos of the Act shall pay at the ate hereinafter set out ao annual 8 P.?O~t !P.e bas ec U?on the a ~oun t of ~ts total au t co =i zed ca?~ta l s toc k o n t~e 15th da y of ~arcr. i;~ecia tely ?recedin~ the da ~e on vt.ic h such annual =epo rt is a ue to be f iled 7 he a~nual repo =t fee shall be pai~ at the time cf =iling the annual re po rt req uired of such cor?oraticns under the ?rovisicns of the ~ct. The amount of the annnal re?o =t fee shall ~e as follovs 4here t he tot al a~t..1-io ized ca?ital stock does oot exceea S25, ooo Sl5 vhe=e the total aut~orized capital s tock ex ceeds S25, 000 but does not exceed $100 000, S35; wh e re t he tota authorized capital stock exceeds Sl 00 000 but coes ~ot excee~ S300,000 SRO; Yhere the total aut hori ~ed ca9ital stock exceeds 1300 000 but does not ex=ee 500 COO, S! SO here the t otal autbori2ed capital s t ock exceed s 5500,000 ~ut does no t e%~eed Sl, 000 ,0 00 S250 and ~urther a suo of $125 !or eac~ Sl,0 00 000 or traction ce=eof in e x=ess of Sl, 000,00 0. Shar es vithout par value, fo: the pu=pose o~ ascertaining the amount of the annual re?ort :ee, but for no other purpos e, shall be taken to he o! t~ e ar value of JlOO each.n Sec. 705. Subsection (g) of sectio n 121 of the co o r at.ion Act (68 Stat. 230: D.c Code, sec. 29-936 (g}) as a ~endee is f u ~ther amended by st kin; the pe==entage 1 -29- per centum" and inserting in lieu thereof the .percentage "2 per centum Title VII E~FECTIV'E DATES AND MISCELLANEOUS Sec. 801. This act, includi ng the amendments made by this act, shall become e f:ective at the end of 'the 30 day ?eriod of Congressional review provided for acts of the Council in section 602 (c of the Dis~ict of Columbia Self-Goverr.ment and Governmental Reo=ganization Act. Sec. 802 a If any provision of this act, including any amendment made by this act, or th.e application thereof to any person or ci=cumstance, is held ·invalid, the re:nainder of the act, includi lg the remaining a.-uend:ments, and ~e application of such· provisions to other persons or cirC\litlsta ces shall not be affected t.~ereby b) The repeal or amendment by this act of any provision of law shall not affect any act done or any right acc~ed or accruing under such provis ion o= law before the effective date of tr.is ac or any suit or proceeding had or commemced before the effective date of this act, but all such rights and liabilities under such law shall continue, and may be en.forced in the same manner and to the same extent, as if such repeal or amendment had not been made cl All offenses committed, and all penalties incurred rior to the effective date of this ac under any provision of law hereby repealed or amended, may be cA o o3l 1..1 lo gt 30 osecc~ec a~c p~ishec in t e same ma::me= a~d wit~ the sa.~e ef =ect as i= tr.is act had not ~een enactec. Sec. 803. Nctwithstancing any othe= provision of law o r ule c! l aw, t he !ees a~c =ates o cha=ges establ~shed by t.h~s ac i~c~ucing ~he amendme=:ts ~ade by is ac s hall be the fees a:!c =ates e! cna=~es !or the licenses and activities or services incicated in this act (including such a ienements unt~l changed by act oi the Council. A y =ei;-t:.lation, e~ecutive e ler, o= ot~ar rule pt o ing to establish a ei!!eren~ such Bill Docket a_i_l_l _N i 2_3_7 Page Two Reconsidered by Council R E CO RD OF C OUNCIL V OTE C:OUHC: l t M l: M 8 1[" j AT I[ N 4 T I N .v. f A.a C:OU H &amp;lt;;lt MU 101 I AYI[ i v I c:ouNe11 1 a&amp;amp;111 I YI: I NA Y oc.v. t T'C'CKER I I I I DIXON I l l SPAUI.DING I I I MJOR D. I I I II HARDY I I I I ~ON I I llRRY I I I ROBSON I I I I l 'WINTER I CL.&amp;gt;\ I I 1'DORE' J I I I COATES I I I SHACKLETON I I I X-llsdica!M Vot• A. B-Ab m N. V-N.:it Votin9 Presented to tile President Susta1n Mayor 's Veto Not Sur.ain Mayor's Veto Submitted to the Congress Senate Action Resolution Number Secretary of the Senate} EnaC1ed without CongrHsional aetion lt;Secretary of the Council S«retary of the Council i Secretary of the Council President of the U.S Secretary of the Council) House Action Resolution Number {Clerk of the House} i I Docket for the Bill 3ill No l-237 Considered in Coun::il 3 23 76 Fi rs t Vote 1_2 o l_(a s RECORD OF CO UN C I L VO TE 1 c ov c11 i eli.11 TC: J y I v j 11 cou NC1L E ER 1 l'E I H AT i N .v a.11 c ou c11 L"4•i:11 f ATE 1 1 N.v I a 1! I I TUCKER Jy DI XON x SPAULDI~G x i I 1'!00R D. I I I I v HARDY I i I i W!ISON l I 3ARRY I v I I I HOBSON x I I WlNTER I x I CI.A.'lKE I I I I MOORE. J. I I n I y l 'X COATES x I I I SR \CKI..ETON Ix I I X-li~dic&amp;amp;lft Vo1~ A E-A.bs nl.I N. V-?iol VotiJ:ali Secretary of the Counci l} Final Vot e in Council 4-6-76 11- 0- 2 (abs) R E C 0 R D OF COUNC I L V OTE COUNCii Ut•18 C" f A.T[ j NA.Y H.v I cou c:u i c1t r i 1 N Y CO\IN Cll. MCM81:1'1 ATC TUCKER I I I DIXON I x I X DORE, D. I I I x HARDY I x BARRY I I I x ·1 HOBSON l x RKE Ix I M:&amp;gt;OR.E. J. x wvC..TES I x i SHACn t"!nN x i X-tnclk&amp;amp;l" Veile A. s-o\.bac:u 6-8- 76 Presented to the Mayor Mayor's Action A pproved N 1976 Disapproved nacted w it hout Mayor's Signo:ure I SPAULDI NG I x I I WILSON I x _J, I 1'1INTER I x t I I N. V.-Not Voting Secret.ary of the Council Secretary of the Councill (Secretary of the Councill I I I I l I I I I I I I i I H V I I I I I 2 JUN 1 o-.i~ioal nro ea PC3t:c S c~ t~~E~GROL"N~ EXC~VA7IO~S FEE ?uel oil etc uel oil C'asol ie anc solve:.t !ill i?es s 51 00 ?uel oil ta~~s withou~ cur i_l s or =es icent ia_ tanks with cu=b !ills 205 00 Nonresi~er.tial tanks wit cu ills 216. 00 Replace!llen~ er repai= of !ill pipes and repairs c ank s S l 0 0 Re?!acement of tan.ks 132. 00 ~Jl l"HOL~S CExce tra sfo::l:\e=&amp;gt and valves or one bouse cor.nection and one associated necessa=y canhole when no other wo=k is i~cluded L~ permit. For construc~ing a single manhole or gas valve without layir.g conduit of main. For rebuild:.ng a manhole, i~cludi~g any change in the size, shape, depth, or l ocation of conduit mace necessary by the work on the ma hole. If a IW?.nhole is reduced in size, t.~e conduit may be extended to the new wall, or altered sli9htly location or deo~h to con~o=m to the new car.hole loca~ic:l wi t 1out adei-:i.onal c~a:ge 31 00 SEV."ER CONN CTIONS All sewe= con.,ections except t.~ose ~o t i n.k sewers w.her. pa:t of a o';lier job 18.00 Sewe: co~.nections to tru sewe=s, whe pa.rt of c O't.!le= job S l. o o ~l sewe: connec~ions excepe t.~ose ~o tr~r.k sewers, when ~ot ncludeC wit oclle work 29.00 Sewer cor..nactions to t=unk sewe:s whe not incluced wit o le= wo:k 63 00 CO~TOtJ!T OR M1 D; co~c ane a.nholes, or main a~d valves 63.00 •</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
