<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-85">
  <num type="law">1-85</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1976-09-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-85.pdf">D.C. Law 1-85</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 2464</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-85, the ‘Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975,’ was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-164, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, and second readings, and reconsideration of second reading, on May 3, 1976, May 18, 1976, June 15, 1976, and June 29, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 23, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-142 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for review</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>/ I I r COUNCIL or THE DISTRICT or COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 1-85 Firearms Control Regulations Act of 197 S September 24, 1976 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, PL 93-198 (the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-164 on first and amended first readinQs May 3, 1976 and May 18, 1976; on second readings June lS, 1976 and reconsideration of second readings on June 29, 197 6. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 23, 1976, this legislation was o assiqned Act No. 1-142, published 1n the Au9ust 10, 1976, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review peribds has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law 1-85, effective September 24, 1976 j L STERLING lucKER Chainnan of the Council (Ref. 23, D.C. Reg. 1091, August 10, 1976) i 1 \ l v ip.n \ 1-14 2 It&amp;gt; Til l COIJNCTl OF TH~ Cl ktl'"T Of COL'JMSlA July 23 I 1976 'T'c rrotf&amp;gt;Ct' thn cit itl"n«; ot thP District frcm lo i Of rropPrty le~t-h rnJ lnJury, hy controllin1i tht» ~v1il..thil1ty ot tlrPdf 1n thP communit y. Hl IT £NAC1E"l HY 'T'Hf! C'O'J'ICIL Of THE DIST;o-IcT OF COLUMPIA, 1'hc1t this dC't 111c1y be CltP'i -tn tl1f FirPcH n Control The C:uuncil of the Oi!"ltriet of Columt1c1 t1n rts thdt in gt;rJPr to prOf"Ote the hi&amp;gt;.tlth, safety •nJ vel faff&amp;gt; Of thP orl• ot thP District_ of :ulWfttia it is nece~"ldry to l P'luire the rPcURtrc1thm of all fir ums that are (2) 1.i111it thP. ty1 ot weapons tJersons rn.5y l&amp;lt;1wfully (J) Assur~ t'.hat "nly -1u"1ified per3ons are allCNE-d to (5 t'tP it mur hff1c:Jlt tor tirE"arrns, JestructiVP 1rv1cPs nJ -tm~unition to movP in illicit Cllml'Tlt&amp;gt;rce ~ithin thP ~istrict uf C'olurib1d 2- 7ITIE l DEflKfTION ec. 101. A~ USP" i1 1 t .hi s ;tCt thf' tPrl!I tl Act s of c~n~r~~s Pd~R (A) dn ~ct to control thf 1 .tn&amp;lt;1 P rn11s wcapun in th~ r)is rict of Co.lumt1a cnanaeru1a tree~s Act of l96t TIPnj~d (TitlP Vil, Un l wful Po~session or Receipt of t ir 1rrr 82 St1t. 2.J 18 tl c. A~pen1ix and (C) an Act tu Arnrnd TitlP 18, United StdtPs Co1e, to Provide tor ~ettPr c~ntrol of the Interstate Trdftic in tirearms Act of 1968 (82 Stat. 1213; ld u.s.c Ammunition" m n~ cartridQe cases, shells, pr0 1"c~ 1 les (includ1nq hot prirnPrs, bullets, prop~llctnt' po~ier, or other devices ur ~dterials desiqned, r~desiqned, ur intPn1r1 for u~e in d firParm or dPstructive device 3 Anti~u~ tircdr m~ans A) any tiredrm (includin~ any firedrm with a matchloc flintlock, pPrcuRRion CdF 1 or Rlrrilar tyfe of i'lnition systt&amp;gt;'TI) rn"nutacturell in or before lt:!9B; and (R) ctny rPpllC''d ot any tiredrrr dPscriheri in 0 C&amp;gt J i) is not desiqnrd or rvdesi~ned tor usinn r1~t1rP ~r convcntiondl cent~rtire tixPd •mmunition, or (ii) uses rimtire or convention•l dmmunition which 1s no lonqer ~anuf•ctured in thP Jnited Statp ani which is no• rPadily avdilatle in thP or •iinary clittnnels ot commezcial trctdP 16 Chief nPans thP Chh&amp;gt;t of Police of t~e MPtropolit.ua Police Det&amp;gt;-trtment of the Ois~rict of columt:ia or n1s desiqnated •gent 5 Crime of Violence" means crim~ of violence as rtcfin~d in sfl'Ct1on l of the hct of July ij, 19J2, as ended (D.C. code, s 22-3201 COT!tmitted in any jurisdiction, hut noes not includP larcPny or atte~ptej larceny amp;} "OealPr's licen~e· aneans d license to buy or sell, rl"!pair tr.1je, or otherwise rieal in fireant1s, destructive devic~s, or ammunition ~s Frovid~d for in Title IV of this Act 7 Destructive device• means A) an explosive, incendiary, or poison qas bom grf?fldde, rock~t, miqeile in or similar device any device hy whatever na~e known ~hich will, or iR dr.siqne or rPJes1gned, or IMY be readily convPrHd or r~storf'rt to Pxpel a frojf'ctil~ by the action of j 0:-1gi l tn Pxplos1vP or othPr rropell"nt throuC"Th d 11rnooth hon• tarrel, Pxcept a shut1un C) ctny dt&amp;gt;vic~ r:ontaininq tear qas or a chPfT'lCd 11 y s im1l.u lrlr:r lmd tor or Rternutator t-y whatever n-tl'fc known U) rPmadc, or readi 1 y convt rte.t or Ct&amp;gt;stored, an&amp;lt;1 intend to stun or disatle a person by l'IP.ane of electric shocK ny combination ot rarts de~1qnei or intenjed for use in convertinq any device into any destructive devicP; or from VhlCh a destructive ~eviee ~ay Cl c be re~1ily assemoled: Prov1 ,h~d rhdt the term shall not include i) any J.:nE&amp;gt;umatic, sprinq, or B-R qun which ex~ls a Ainql~ frojectile not exceeding ltt inch in ·Harnetcr ii) dny dPvicc which is neither desiqncd nor rejesignPd for uRe as a weapon iii) any d~vic~ oriqinally a weapon which has been redesiqned for us~ aA a ftignalinq, lin~ throw1nq, or s3fety device; or iv ny d~vicP which the Chief finds is not 11Kely to be used d~ a weafOn Di~trir:t" mP"ns District of Colu~tid I l •fire.lrm" 111P&amp;lt;1ns dny Wf"d On which 111, or i'l dPRiqned or rPde~iqn Jr\.J~P or CPmade, reddily convertPd or restored nd inten~ed to, expel a projectile or projectiles by th~ action of dn Px~lo~ive: thP frdme or receiver ot any luch drvict or any tirearm muftlP.r or silence: Provided, Th&amp;lt;1t such term shdll not include A) anti-Jue f ire.trm anj/or (Bl dPstruct.ive devi~e!'I C) any devicP useJ exclusively tor linr throwin siqnalinq, or Sdt~ty, and requirPd or reco~menjed by t Co.tst Guar .i or lnterat.at-e commerce Cc:rirrission: or (0) any device used ~xclusively for f irin c explosive rivets, stu1 cirtri1qes, or similar industrial C .t lmunit.ion an1 incapable for UBP as weapon. c (10 M.tchine gun• m~anq any firedrm ~hich shoots, i~ 1es i7ned to shoot, or can be readily converted or r~stored to shoot A) automatically, more than one shot by a (B) eemiautomdtically ore than twelve shots without manual reload1nq 11 Or1anization" m~ans any Fartnersh1p, corrfdny, corporation, or otht-r husinP.99 P.ntity, or any qroup or 0 0 0 purr.&amp;gt;'ie. V.ilidly i~suP1 pursudnt t0 tn1s act ~vincino th~ rP1istration ot a f irP~rm pursu~nt to this a~t 14 F'itle" mPdns .i -trooverl borf&amp;gt; tire.irrr usi.nq a fix i ~Ptdll1c c~rtridqe with d sinql~ projPctile and desi1ned or redesi~ne1. lft&amp;lt;l~P or remade, and intPnJµd to te firt-d trom the shoulder. rttrr"l of lPs~ thdn l~ 1nchPs in Jen~th: or d ti.rP~rlT' m.tJ~ frc i ~hotqun if aoch f1rt.&amp;gt;-irm dS 11 gt;diti&amp;lt;&amp;gt;d h.i~ ctn overdll 1 un-rt of less th_.n 2fi 1nchta~ or any tarrPl ot less than 18 (16 hotqun" l!'leans tt smooth tore f ire.srm uiunq a f1xf&amp;gt;i ~hotqun shPll with eith~r number ot ball shct or a s1nole proj~ctile, a.nrt dPsiqnPJ or re~e~iqned, v e or rPl'la ·I an1 intencied to bf&amp;gt; firt-d from thf&amp;gt; shoul1er 17 Shurt l rrrlP1 ritle T'eans a ritle havinq any l~c gt; th.:tn 26 inch&amp;lt;'8 or any t:Jrrc&amp;gt;l of less than 16 inchPs 1 ~rnll~d Oriei~al r c c 0 0 -1 18&amp;gt i.;ectpon~ oftennP" rM"ttn!'i any violatil.&amp;gt;n in 11111 trctnaft-r in 111ny mctnnPr, receirt, acquisition, pl.lSaession, h..tvin~ un,iPr r-ontrol, use, reµ111ir, rnanut.u~ture, Cctrryin•i, or tr.tns~0rtdtion of ilny fir r ammunition, or &amp;lt;iestructiv~ riPvi ce. TITLE II FlR~AkM: i A~r CfS'I'P U:'TtVt. r£VICES ~ec. 201. Reqistrcttion Requir•d a) Except as otherwi~P frovided in t his dCt, no ~rson or orqanization shall within the District receive, possess, have under his contrJl, transter, otter t~r Sdle, sell, give, or 1~11ver Y 1estructive device, ani no person or orcianiz-ltion shall it h1n the District po~SP~S or hav~ under his or its control any f ire&amp;lt;trm, unless sue~ person or orqanization is ~he holder of a valid reqistr&amp;lt;ttion c~rtificate t~r such tirearm. In the case of an or1dniz~tion reqistration certificate shall ~e issued (l) only to ~n organization which has in its e~ploy one or more com~i~sioned s~eci&amp;lt;tl fOlice officerR or other emrloy~eg lic~nseJ to carry f irearm!'i, and ~hich ar~s quch mployce~ with f irearznq Jur inq such emrloyePs duty ho~rs and (2) only to sue~ or1~nization in its own ndmP and in the n~me of its prPsi1ent ar the chief executive b gt;•11 sf'&amp;gt;cti.on (d h~ll no~ apfly t .o c· 0 c 0 d l) Any l~w @nforcement officer or aqent ~t the ~i~trict ur the Unite tatPff, or any law enforcf"~nt oft icer or ct&amp;lt;lflht of tht&amp;gt; riov&amp;lt;!rnll'lent. of Y State or ~ub~ivis1on therPof, or ctny ~ember of the Ar•ej 'orcea of ~he Un1t~d States, th~ Ndtion~l Guar~ or Orqanized ~eserves, whPn such otficer, dqent, or mPmher is authorizeJ to f&amp;lt;&amp;gt;S&amp;amp;ess such a fire~rm or device ile on ~uty in the perform~nce of officictl authorized function 2) Any person holdino a dealer license; ProviJed, That the tirear~ or d~atructive device i A) ac~u1re1 ty such FerRon in the nor~al conduct of business B) is kept at thP flacP described in thfo dealer's license; and (C) 1s not kept for such person's ~rivate use or prote~t1on, or for the protection of his busineRs 3) With respect to firtoarsns, any non-rPsident of thP District fdrticivating in any lawful recreational f irParm-related dct1vity in the District. or on his w~y to or from such activity in another jurisdiction; Provide ll ~hat such person, whPneVPr in ~01Pedsion ot a fir@ar shall upon .iP!'l-lnd of any rnemter of the M~tropolitan Policf&amp;gt; DP~~rtment, or other tona fide la~ enforce~~nt officPr c c D 0 -9 xhihit proof t.hdt he is on his ~dY to or from such ~ctivity, anrl that hi~ possPssion or control ~f •uch f~rearm is l~wtul in the juris1iction in ~hich hP re8i~~s: Provided turthP-r, thdt quch weapon shdll bP unloct ,1ed, Recun~ly cP.rt it icat P hall t-P i!'l!"Uf' 1 for any ot the tol lcwi nq t yrr~ of f irPdr~s t gt;aweJ-uf f shotqun l lacrane qun c) Short-barrelej r i flP d) Pistol not validly register~j to the current rP.qistrant in the District prior to the effective date of this act and (e) Pistol not possessej by the currPnt reqistrant in ~onform1t.y with the rPqulation~ in effect i~~eliat.ely prior to th~ effective date of this act. sec. 203. Prerequ1sitPs to reqiEtration: appliettion for reqistration d) No regist.ration cert.if icate ~hall be issued to any persJn (and in the Cdse ot a iJf'rson ~Ptween thf&amp;gt; aqes cf lR and 21, to the person and hiq siqnatory parent or guardian) or or~anizdtion unless the Chief determinrs that such pt!'rson c c c 0 o or t'he prPs1dent 1Jr chiPf executive in the CdSt&amp;gt; of .u1 l) is tW nt y-onf! yf'a~A of aq&amp;lt or ol 1er: PrJvidP hat thP Ch1ef m~y iqqur to an d?flicant t~twePn tb&amp;lt;&amp;gt; ct1e&amp;gt;s vl f'iqntef'n dn •i twi:inty-onr yP.sr~ old, dn&amp;lt h0 i q othf&amp;gt;rwise l'lalifi~j, 3 rt&amp;gt;oistration cert1fic.st" if th&amp;lt ctppl icdt ion ls dccomp.m1ed by notd r 1 zed Std terM&amp;gt;nt ot t hf' d~llicant•s ldrent or nudr~i~n A) that the dl't-licctnt hds the llf"rmis!lion of his pc1rent or ,uardian to own an1' use the tirec1rm to te reqisterPd; anrt the p~r~nt or quardian d&amp;amp;sumes civil li.tbility tor dll damaqeE re::iultinq from the actions of such applicant in the use of the tirearm ~o be reqiqt~red: Provided furthP.r, that such rc~istration cert1fic•te shall expire on such pP.rson•s tw~nty-tirst tirthday 2) Has not been convicte.i of a crim~ of violencP, weapons offense, or of 4 violation of thi~ act J) Is not un.Jer indict"'ent for a crime of violence or a we~pons offense 4) Has not heen convictPd w1th1n five ye.trs prior tu th(&amp;gt; dppl1cdt1on of dny c c A) vil&amp;gt;1"tion in any jurisdiction of dny law re~trictlnq the u,.P, fuss ls1on, or s•le ut any ndrr0tic or dan~erou~ druq: or (F) a violdtion ot section 2 of the Act of July lb, 1'112 (C.C. Code, sec. 22-507 (1974 reqarjinq thr~ats to do bodily harm, or BPction t&amp;gt;Oo of the Act ot '4drch 3, l~Ol (C.c. Code, tw1 22-504 (lq73 reqard1nq assaults anj t~re~ts, or any similar ~rovision ot the la~ cf any othPr jur1sd1~tion so as to indicatP. d llKPlihocd to make unlawful use of firearm 5) Within t~ five yedr fPriod i~medid~ely precejinq the ap~licat1on, has nol been acquittej of any crimindl charqe by reaqon of insar.1ty or hdB not bPen aijudicdte1 a chronic alcholic by any court, Pr~vided, That this p~rdqraph shdll not ap~ly if such person shall ~res~nt to th~ Chief with the application, a medical certification indicatinq thdt thP applicant ha~ r~coverP~ trom such insanity or alcholic condition and is capablP of safe and responsible posse~sion of a tirearm 6) Within the five years· immediately 1o1recechnq t-he application, hd s not been voluntary or involuntarily committed to dny mental hosrital or institution; Provid~d, T~at th1s faraqraph Rhdll not dpply, if such person shall Zn~olled Original \ I C"'l 0 c -12- pr.-qent to th~ Ch1~f with thP .it:i-:licant a t&amp;gt;dic.11 eert1t1c-cttion that t-hr c1r:i-l1c.1nt- h s rPr:overec1 trum ~hcttPYPr l.tiy !Jrompte:i euc-h co"'mi t:'IF&amp;gt;nt; Pr OU&amp;lt;•S not J;J df" t.J suftf&amp;gt;r trort d rhysicdl ,i"te.:t 1o1hH"h woulrl t-pn l t .u in hcate that thf" c1pt-:l1c .int ~o ul1 not b~ able to possPSS ~n d u~P a f irP.trm Sdfely ~nJ H'~t gt;n!"lhly i H 1 n..Jt he&amp;gt;Pn td)ue\ic·ctt d nP&amp;lt;lli'lent i1 d tiretrn mishdf.l r.a1JC'li1q de.ith or ~r1cus in)ury tc anathPr i uman reinri 9) Is not otherwiAf&amp;gt; lnPliqible to fJRsr a f1Stol unjPf SPCtion ] Of th~ Act Qf July ff, l~J2 (r.c. Code, sec. 22-3203 10) Hds not fa1le1 to demonstratP satistdctorily c 3 kno-.tled~P ot thP lawo of th~ Ci~trict of Colu~bia pPrt~in1n1 to firedrms and the Sdfe and resronsihle u~ of thP Sc\mP in accordance with t~st. s and stanJards lJCPscrihed hy th" Chiet; ProvideJ, Thctt once thi~ d£&amp;gt;termindt1on iR made with rt-£pf'Ct to a aiven c1ppllcdnt for a pdrticul~r ty~-e of firP~rm, it OPP.d not bP m.tje d~din tor the Sd~ ctpplic~n~ with respect. to a Aubse iu~nt itpplication for t'lE" s~me type ot f 1rearrr: an.1 (llt Ila~ viiuon b£&amp;gt;ttPr tt'lan or e4Udl to that re1uirt'1 to ot•tain a valid i1rivt.'r's licen!l&amp;lt ind&amp;lt;'r thP la l I I 0 1 13- of thP Di~trict of Columbi ProviJ~d. That current lief'!nsure by thP niAtrict ot Columbia. of the plic.nt to 1rivE amp;hall bE" rrima facif vicfonce that such •FPlicant •e vision is ~utticient anj. Provided further. that this cit.•tPr:Tli nation npeJ not hr ma.:1e 1t1ore than once per year per an;l i cant b very ~rson -itJl'l yinq for reqi str.!t ion c &amp;lt gt; r'"ific-H.e shall rrov1:ie on a form pr~scrU:ed by the Chief 1) c 7he full n~~e or any other ndfTI~ ty which thf&amp;gt 2) ThP ~resent ~jdreRs and each ho~e dddresc whPrt? the c1pplicant hds res1 .ied durinct the hve yPar reriod i~l'M:'liately ~r~cedinq the application 1) The pr~sPnt businPss or occupation and any husinP~s or occu~tion 1n which the a~plicant ha~ enqaqed 0 0 -iurinq t.ht&amp;gt; tive-year fPr1oj iirmediately frec&amp;lt;!dinq the aH:l1catl.on and the a -jJre!lses of Ruch husinesses or places (ij) Tht&amp;gt; date an~ place of hirth of thP apflicant S) ThP s~x of the apf l1cant 6) Whether (and if so. the reasons) the District, the Unitej statPs or the qovcrnrnent of •ny State or suhdiviRion of •ny StatP has ~cnied or revokP.J th rT gt I c 0 pP.rtaininq to any fir~arm 7, A dPscripti on of the applicdnt s role in any m1shaF 1nvolv1n~ d firParm, including the date, place. timf&amp;gt circui11~t.ances, and th~ MIM'f of the person 1njurP.d or Kille1 The intended use of the f ir~acm 9) The caliber, llldke, ITIOriel, snanuf icturer s identitication number, serial nu"ter, an1 any other iJent1fyinq marks on the firearm 10, ThP. name and address of the person or orqanization froin whom tt\e fireat'm was obtained, and in the caqe of a dealer. his dealer's l~cense number 11, Where the tirearm will qenerally be kept 12) Whether thr. applicant has applied for any other registration certif icat.es issllt!d and outstandin 13) such other inf ormdtion as the Chief dE&amp;gt;ter:unf?s is necesMry to carry out the provisions of this act {c) EvPry orqaniz,tion ap~lyinq for a reqistration crrtificate shall l) with resp~ct to the president. or chief P.xecutive of such orqanizat.ion, c~m~ly ~ith the requirement&amp;amp; of subsP.ction (b and Enrolled Originel c c 15 2) frovi l~ Ru~h other infor111cttion dB thr ChiPt &amp;lt;iett&amp;gt;C ;YlilleS lS n~CP.FSdry t\l C.trry OUt the }-:rOViSiOn8 Of this a ct re. 204 Finl'lerpr int: 1n'1, pict.ures, pf&amp;gt;reon..tl (cl I'h£' Chief Y r~qui re any pc-rson afflyinl'1 for a juin~~nt, this 19 n~cPss3ry tJ CJnduct dn elficient and ~1P~UdtP invest1qation into th~ mdtters drscrib~j ln section 1 3(.i) and to P.ftc.•ctu~tt- thP. J=urpc!'\f&amp;gt; of ttiie act: Pruvided hdt any person vho h4~ been finqPrfrinted ~y the Chi~f within tive yectrs prior to submittinq the afplicdtion need net, in th~ Chief •s jiscretion, he finqerpr•nteJ aqain if he otters other sat1efact.ory proof of ident1ty h) Each applicant, other than an oroanization, shall ~ub~it with the a~rlication two tull-tace photoqrafhs of himsP1f, 1-J/q ~y l-7 inches in size which shall have teen taken within the thirty- i.sy Pf&amp;gt; riod imrne rHatel y r.receding the filin1 of thfo application C) Every applicdnt (or in the case of an or,aniziticn, the presijent or chief executive, or a rson a •Jthorized in 111ritinq l&amp;gt;y him shall aEJpe"r in person at a ti nd ~lace pr~scrihed by the Chief, and may be required to hrin1 with him th~ firParm for which a reqistration -16- c-1&amp;gt;rt1~1cat~ is sou1ht, which shall be unloadert and M•~urPly t) £..ich dH lic .1nt (the oreoic1ent or chief Pxccut iv~ in the case ot .in orq Jniz.-tt 11.m) st1'4ll s1-1n an o tth or ~ffirmation attestinq tJ thP truth of all ~he infurm-tt1on tc-col'lpan1e.J t-y a non-r~fun .1dhle ft"E" to estat:li!lhrd t-y the dyor: T'r0v1dPd hat such tee ~hcill, in the judqmPnt of thf ayer, r~imburse thP Distri~t foe the cost of servic~s proviied un1er this title. c 0 c. 20b. Filin~ timPs for nP urchasc dnj t1rr~r~s ent-eriri~ th~ District; i;reviously rE&amp;gt;~1stered f ir&amp;lt;&amp;gt;a rms a) An c1~plic&amp;lt;ltion for re~istration certif icatP shall ~e file1 (and d rcqistr1tion certiticate issued) prior t-o taiung ~s~ssion ot d t ireartr1 frcrr cl llcenseJ dealt."r or from ~ny ~erson or or~dnizaticn holdin~ a re~istrdtion cPrtificate~ therPtor. In all other Cdses, an ~pplic1tion for rP,1stration shall he filed im~Pdidtely after cl firearrr is brou t1t into the District. It sh.tll be dt-emed com1=liance w1~h ~hP µrPcP1inq sent~ncP it such fPtAon rersonally c 0 gt; ± -11- dotermined by the ChiPt t .o te sut hcientt •nd t:ravidP"q "uch inforl'llation as inay bP deraan .ied: ProvidPd lhctt such- pt&amp;gt;rson t1lP~ an ~ppllCdtion fo~1 a re1i~tration c~rtificate ~ithin ~8 hours atter such communic~tion b) a.ny t irt&amp;gt;arm v.tli ·Hy rPgister~d under prior ri&amp;gt;qulations must h• reqi~tPrta.3 purAu.tnt to this act in dCCOrddnCf' Wlth proceJur~R to he rromulqctted by thr Chi~f. An appllcctt-ion to:&amp;gt; renistPr ~uch t 1rcdrm ~hdll bt&amp;gt; f &amp;amp;lP.1 µur~uant to this act within 60 d~ys of the ~f tectiv~ date of this .tct. sec. 207. IAAuance of re~istration certifiCclte at Ui&amp;gt;Ofl receil-'t of properly execute.I dlppl icat ion tor rPqistration cP.rtitic3te he Chief, upon deter"ininq throu1h inquiry, investiq~tion, or otherwise, that the "Fflicant 1s ~ntitle-ii •nd q~alif ied under ~he frovisions of this c1ct, theret shall issuP. a reqistration certificate. E~ch re~i~tration certifictte shall be in duplicate and tear a uni1ue rPqistration certificate number and such other information as thP ChiPt deter~ines is nece~~ary to identity the applicant anj the firedr~ reqist~rP.d. 1he duplicate of thP rc~istration certific1t~ 9hall be deliv~reJ to the aprlicant and the Chief sh~ll retain the ori~inal L) T'"it.&amp;gt; Chief shall approve or deny an application for a re1istration certif ic~tP within a 60 d~y feriod teqinnino d- on t-hP datt&amp;gt; the ChiPf rPr.Pivr.s thP cJpplicctti~n, unless qooc! cau~e is ~hown, incluJinq non-rPcPift of lnfor"'at~on·"troJT sourr.Ps outsijc the District qovernntent; Provided, 1h~t in thP tse ot dri at:i lic.ttion t gt; re-Ji~tt~r a .tirPdr111 v·ctlii1ly rP'liStered under prior re~ul~t1cns, the Chief Bh3ll ~ave 4f5 1ay Jtter the reC't&amp;gt;ipt Ot IU~!l an llC~tion tC au rOVP Q[ i~ny ~uch ~rrlicdt1un. The ~hie[ may hold in ahey~n dn tnplication whf&amp;gt;re ther 1c; d revocdtion precef"d1nq p•nrhn4 c 0 3Q~inst such Pf"CBon or or'.t.tni zation. G (c) UiJOn receiµt ot .1 r~qistration cert if icatP, edch .ipfllcant ~hall examinP s.tme to ensure that the infor"ation thereon is ccrrect. 11 the reqiRtration certificate is incorrect in &amp;amp;ny respect, the ~rson or orqanization names tnPrPon shall return it to ~he Chirf ~ith d s1qned st~tPJT'ent showin'l the n.1ture of the error. The ChiPf shall correct the Prror, if it occurre(\ hrouqh arlrrinistrative ~rror. In thP. event t.he P.rror resulte1 from information contctined in the d~plication, th~ apµli~ant shall te rPquired to file an amenJed apflication settinq forth the correct information, and a statement explaining th~ error in the oriqinal ap~li~ation. Eac~ am~nded application shall ~e accorr~anied ~Y d f Pe r~udl to that r~~uired fer thr oriq1n~l dPl'l1cat ion I ltarolled ~ri~lnR c 0 c 0 0 -19 i) In the P.vent th(&amp;gt; Chief lf'arns of an •rror in r~qistrdti gt;n certificatP \lther than as providPi in subRrction lt hc- NY requirr thP holdPr to return t~ r~qistration c~rtificdte for corrt&amp;gt;etion. If the ~rror rr!;ultcj from infor1Mt1on contctinPd in' tht- an l1cation, thf&amp;gt; pPrson or orqan12ation nd!T1P li therein shall rPquired to f1l~ an nor1 afplicdt1on as provide~ in su~section (ct e) F.dch re-Jist.ration cert1ticate issuPd hy the Ch1rt tll he e1ccomµc1nied hy a Rt-tternP.rt settinq forth the r~~istrant•s duties unrler this .act. sec. 208. Ajditional DutieA of ~e~istrantR. Ectch ~erson dnd orqaniz~tion holdinq a req1stration certificate, in addition to any oth~r rf"qu1rements ill'pOsPd by this act, \Jr the Acts of conqress, shall a) notify the Chief in writing of l) the loss, theft, or destruction of the rP.gistrcttion certificate or of a reqistered firearm (inclujinq the circumstdnces, if kncvn) immedidtely upon discovery of such loss, th~ft, or destruction 2) a chanqe in any of the infor"ation •Ffearing on the r~qistra~ion certific~t~ or required ty section 203 of this act 3) thP ~dl tunqfcr er ether di!l~osition cf the firear~ not less than forty-Piqht hours frior to c c c 0 0 Or1slna1 -20- 1Plivery, pursuant to such sale, tr•nsf~r or other disposition, inclu.Hnq CA) identification of the reqist~•n t~ f1redrm an~ ttlf' SP.rial nu"t:er of the reqietration certificdt CO) th~ ntt111e, rcsicience, and busine!lts d1ir~s~ ant ddte of birth of the person ~o who~ tre tiredrrr ha'l been sold er tr•nsferred; anri (CJ whether the firearm wtts sold or how it was ott.~r.t1s~ trdnsterred or ~isfose~ ot b) Return to th~ Chif"f, the registration certificate for any firear~ which is loAt, stolen, destroyeJ, or ~thcrw1s~ tranAterr~d or disposed of, at the time he not1fie~ the Chief cf Ruch loss, theft, destruction, sal transfer, or othPr 11s~osition c) Have 1n his poBBPSsiun, whenever in possession of ct f iredrl'I, th~ req1Btrctt1on certificate for such f irearan, anj P.xhibit the same upon the de~and of a ~ember of the ~etropol1tan Police Dep4rtment, ur other law enforcement ot ticer. sec. 209. Pevoc.\tion. A reiistr~tion certificdte shall te revoked if lt any of the criteri11 in Bf&amp;gt;ction 203 of this act are not currently rtH?t; 0 0 \ 21 2) the reqisterej firearm hdR become •n unreqister•bl~ firearm under the terms of Rection 202·of this act, or d destructive devicP 3) the i-nt"'rmation furnist1ed to tht: Chief on the dpplic~tion tor a reqistr•tion ccrtif icate irovrs tc he intentionally false; or here 1s .s violdtion or omission ot tne dutif"s, 0hli"ldtions or rf&amp;gt JuiremPnts imt-o!'ted t:y section 20A ct this itCt. sec 10. Procedures for deni.sl or revuc•tion a) If 1t •ppcars tv the Chief that an apflication for 3 reqistration certitic~te shocla be denie~ or thdt a reqistration certificate should tlE' revoked, the Chief shall notify tt~ afplicant or regi~trant of thP ·prOfOsed denial or revocation, briefly stating the reason or reasons ~her~for. service may be made ty delivering a copy of the noticP to the apflicant or reqistrant personally, or ty leavinQ a copy thereof at the place of residence identified on the a!Jplication or reqistration with some ferson of suitable a9e ~nd discretion then rcsidinq therein, or by mailinQ a COFY ot the notice by certiti@ dil to the reRidencP address iie&amp;gt;ntifiP-.i on the apµlication or ct&amp;gt;rtificate, i.n which caRe service ~hall be COMflete dB of ~h~ datP the return receipt w~s siqned. In the c~se of an oraanization, servicP may be Zn~olled Or1r.tn~1 -22- l'llct &amp;lt;if" upon the pres1dcnt, r:hief P.xecutive, or other ofticf"r, manaqinq ao~nt or person authorizf"d by pointment or l to rPceive such notice as de~cribed in the precedinq aPnten~ at the business ad~ress of ~he orqanization identif led in the dpplicctt1on or re~1strdtion certificate. The person serv1n~ thP notic~ shall Ke froof therf"of with thr Chief in a l'IJnnPr prPscribPd ny hil'll. In thP CctAe of s~rv1c-P by certific-1 m3il, t:he si1ned return receipt shall be tile&amp;lt;i w1th t .he Chi~f togf"ther with a sioned Rtatell'E'nt h1.n.inq thf' J3te such notice was ~ailed; and i! the return receift does not purport to be siqnej by the rerson named in the notice then specific facts fro~ which the Chief can deter~ine that C' thP person who signed the rece1~t rneets thP a~frOi-Jriate 0 quali tic-it ions for receipt of such notice set out in this c 0 sutsection. The applicctnt or reoistrant shdll have 15 days fro~ the date th~ notice is served in which to submit further evidence in support of the application or ~ualifications to continue to hold a reqistration certificate, as the case mdy be: Provided, that if the ap~licant joes not •ake such a subnission within fifteen days from ~he date of eervice, the applicant or reqistrant qhall be ~eemed to have conceded the validity of thr rPason or redsons stat.ed in t.he notice, and the denial or revoc~tion shall become final. 0 c C" 0 -2 .J- rf'cPiv(&amp;gt;:q such a suhmis~ion, he Bhdll serve upon thl p~licdnt or rPqistrdnt in the nn~r specit1e1 in subsPction (a) notice uf hi~ final decision. The Chief's tilT'P it~1n which t\J filP d notict= of apJ &amp;gt;Pal rursu.int tu thf&amp;gt; code, sPc. l-1501, et sr~.1 or, if such a notic@ of dr~~al i5 filed, dt the till'IP the final orjer or juda~ent ot the ~1str1ct of Columbia Court of ApfPals b~comes etfective c) ftithin qeven days of derision unfavordtlr to the apFlicant or reqistrant bec~~inq final, the •Fflicants or req1strant shall (l) peacP~bly surren~Pr to the Ch1(&amp;gt;f the fire~rm for which the reqistration certificate was revoked in t!1e m~nner providPj in secticra 7C4, or (2) l.t~fully remove such fire~rm from the District for so lonQ as has an intcrt.-st in such firearm, or J) otherwise l~wfully iisfose of his interest in such firear c. 211. certain information not. to te used as evidence. No inforl'lation obt~ined from a person under this titl~ or rPta1nPd ty a ferson in oriPr to comply ~ith any section of this title, sh~ll he useJ ~9 evidence aqainst such person in dny cr11r1nal Frocee(linq it.h resrect to a violation of thi ct. occurrino priJr to or concurrently with th• tilin ot thfl' lntorMtion require.t by thiR title: Provid,ad• Th•t this section 9hdll not ~pply to any violation uf section ti5~ ot the Act ut Mdrch 3, 1901 (D.c. Code, BPC. 22.2S01 or section 701 of this act TI I III f~ATES CO~TAINING fUiEAR"1S c:;pc. lOl. Jc11ht~ tnr1 resron~it-ilit11&amp;gt of ext&amp;gt;cutors and (a) The executor or ajminietratcr ~f an e~t te cont din1nq a t ire.1r111 Rh~ 11 notify tM Chi Pf of the ~ea th of the decetitant within t.hirty JayR of his a11pointmPnt or C qudl1fication, whichevPr iR ~arlier. c- o Until the !Awful dlstribut.ion of such firear~ to an heir or leqat~e or the l•wful ~ale, tranEfer. or dis~~sition cf the firPar~ by the ~state; the executor or a1ministrator of such estate shall he charq£d with the ~uties 3n1 otliqations which would h•ve been imposed by this act upon the deceJent, if th~ decedent ~re Atill alive: Provi1ed, That 8uch extacutor or d1~in1strator shall not be liatle to th~ crl~inal penalti~s of section 705. TITL! IV LICENSING OF FIFEA FUSI~FSSF 2 So ~rson or orlanii&amp;lt;1tion shdll l'll•nufactur@ ctny tiredrlT destruct1ve devicP or r-c1rts thereof, or unition, within the n1strict; Proviriei, Th.it prr!"on~ holJinq rP"1strdtion certif ic4te~ m~y ~nqaqe in hand laadinq, rPlud •iJ.nq, or cu~t OIT' lo.t 'h n ·1 am111uni t ion for his req isterPri firP ,1rmr Providt&amp;gt;I furt'1Pr, thdt such persons !Tidy net hc1nc' l ndJ, r~lJ~i, or cust lodJ drnmunition tur othPrs t NJ pP.rson or o rrldnization sh.ill enq.i~e in thP ~usincss Jl sellinq, purch~q1nq, or re~airinq dny f1rearlT ie~tructive dP.vice, pdrts thert&amp;gt;for, or a~munition, without tirst attaining a dealer's license n1 no 11cens~c shall ~nqa1e in the business of sellin purchasinq, or re~airinq fir~arm~ which c1re unregisterable un1er secticn 202 of this ~ct, destructive device or Fdrts therefor, except fUrsu~nt tu a valid work or purchase order, for those ~ersons spec1fiP:1 1n s~ction 201 (b l) of this act. Sec 02. Eli~ibil1ty for dtdler•s license; aprlication for s~mr; t~e Any person eliQihle to reaister a f ire~rm under thi6 act, and who, if d r~qistrant, has not previously fail to i rtor~ any of the duties imposerl by this act tnd, ctny ~i&amp;gt;rson eliqit&amp;gt;lP. un rlcr the Acts ot ConqreRs to ~n1d~P in such bu~ir~s mdy ohta1n a dedl~r•s licPns or c1 renP111-1l tt1 reof, which shall be V.3lid for a i-eriol1 of not 0 0 C' Ci 0 -26 orP. than one year tro~ the d•te ct iRSUdnce. Thf- J1censP required· hy this act, shall be i.n add it ion to any ottw-r licPnse or 11censinq fr~durP. requi.r~d by law b) Each _ap~licc1t.ion for dealer•s license and e•ch ap~lication for r~new~l thP.reof shall be m4de on d term frescri~~d hy the Chief, shall ~e sworn to or affir~ed by tnP ~pplir~nt, dn~ shall contain l) the inf0rm~tion required ty section 203(a 2) t.hr a Brt-sCJ whPre the. applicant conc1ucts or intenJs to con'iuct his business 3) whether the applicant, prior to the eftective date ot this act, held a license to deal in deadly wea~ons in the District nd (Q) such other intor1t1ation a the chi~f may r~~uire, includinq finqerprints and photoqraphs of the apflicant, to carry out thP. purfoses of this act c) Each applic t1on for a d~aler•s license, or rPnrwal shdll be acco~panied by a fee estatlished ty the Mayor; Prov1de That such fee s~~ll i.n the jujginent of the ~ayor, reimburse ~he Distr1ct tor the cost of services provided under this titlP. sec. QOJ. I~suance of a dealer's lic~nse, froc~~ure Upon receipt of properly executec1 application for de~1Pr 1 s licens or renewal thereof, the Chief, upon c 0 -21- detPrm1ninq throuqh f ur~hPr inquiry. investiqation, er othrrwisc, that the dppli~dnt iz Pnt1tl~d and ~u.tlit&amp;amp;ed unjer tht=&amp;gt; frovis1on~ of this act thereto, shall iaaur dealer's license. Each dP.alPr•s lic~nse shall be in du1licate and hear a unique dealer's license nu~ber, anJ quch other intormdtion as thP. Chiet detPr~1nes is n~c~ssdry to 1Jcntif y the d ~rlicant and premises. The duplicdtv of thP iP~ler•s 11c~nsP sh3ll tP delivPred to the apfli~ant anj the Chief shall retain thP ~ri~inal 1&amp;gt The C:hief shall api;rove or deny an application for a r~qistration certiticdte ~ithin a 6C-day ~eriod beginning on the date the Chit-f rec~1ves the application, unl~ss qood c3use is shown, includinq non-receipt of information from sourcE&amp;gt;s outside the District ov.-rnl'lent. The Chiet Y hold in abeyance an ap~lication where there ie any firear revocation FrOCP.edin~ pending aaainst such person c) Upon receipt ot a &amp;lt;1ealer• s license, each applicant shall examine thP. sa~e to en~ure thdt the infor~ation thereon is correct. If th~ dealer's license is incorrect in any rPspect, the person named ther~on Shdll return the same ~o the ChiP.f vith s11ned state~ent showinq the nature of t error. Th~ ChiPf shall correct the error, if it occurre&amp;lt;i thro11qh ari1T'lnistr .tti Vt ecror. In the event the Prror rP.sulted from inform~tion conta1ned in the c 0 appl 1cation, the applic nt gh.sll ~e r~uired to ti lf tn ctmf"nded application explainin~ thP error in the oriqirwl ap~lication. E.sch arftPnjeJ application shall te acco~fAniPd by a fee e~ua o that required f cr th or1qinal ilpfliCiltion d) In the event. tht- Chif"f learn~ of an E"rror in dP~)Pr l1censP, other than as froviJPd in subsection (c hP. IT'.ty r~u1re thP holder to return the &amp;lt Paler llct•nsc for correc~1on. If th~ error rPsultcd trom infor~ation n contained in t~e af~licat1on, th f rson naD1ed therein shall be re~uired to file an am~nded a~~lication as providPd in subsection (c P) Each dealer•o license·is~ued by thP Chief Rhall be ctccomranied by a statement SPtting forth a dealer•s duties un1er this act. 5P.C 6014. Cuties ot licen9~d dealer records, reports a) Each person hol1in~ a dealer's license, in ad cHtion to any other require1Jents iirposed t:y this act, the Acts of conqress, and otttt&amp;gt;r law, shall l) display the dealer's license in a conspicuous ~lace on the pr~mises 2) notify thl Chief in writinq lled Origi~al 0 0 (A) ot tlit, loss, theft, or dt&amp;gt;atruction cf the dedlr.r•s licenRP (inclut1nq th~ circu~atancea, if knovn) imr-ediately upon the di~covery of such loss, theft, or dP truct.ion B) of a chdnqe in a~y of thP infor~aticn dppPdrinq on the dealP.r 1 R licen~ or rPquired by section ~02 of t-hi s act imme H.-t ~Ply upon the occurrencP ut any such (l) k@eF at thP prPmise~ idcntit1ea in the dPaler•s l1cens~ a truP and current record in book term ot (A) thP na address, ho~ fhOrlf and date of birth of each e~~loyee handlinq firedrms, a~unition, or destructiv~ dev1c~s B) each firear~ or destructive device recPived into invPntory or for repair inclu~inq the i) BPri-tl nurrt-er, caliter, make, 111odel, manufacturer's numter (if any dealer's identification nurnhPr (if any r~~istration certificate numher (if any) ot the f1rearr, and Rimi lar clescript iV~ inforrr tion for icstructive devices ii) na"'e, a idres and dealP.r' s licensP. numb~r (lf dny) of the rson or or~dnization 0 0 JI trom wlio!'I th0 fir~"r" or destructive dt.&amp;gt;vict&amp;gt; was purcha P'1 or 0ttir.rwiAe rf'ceived iil) coninieratiori &amp;lt;liven for the fir.-arir or jpstructlVP Jevice, if any iv ]ii dnc1 time received by thP licen!leP anj in thP caRe ~f re~air, returned to thP i~rson holJinq the r~~i~trdt1on certi!:icdtP tn t (v) n~turr 0f thP repairs mdJ Cl P.dch tirearm or destructive d~vi~e sol~ or transfcrreJ includino the i) s~rial number, Cdliber, make odel, manufacturer's number or dealer's identification numhrr, and registration certiticdtP. nu!'ltrr (if any) of the f ire~r!'I or similar information for destructive ievices ii) na!'lle ridress, reqistration CPrtiticate numh~r or l~cense nu~ber (if any) of the person or orqanization to ~hom transferred iii) the consideration for transfer; and iv) t'ime an ,j date of delivery of the firP.arn or destructive device to the transferee D) ammunition r~ceived into ~nventory inclu1in'1 the l1 i) br•nd •nd number of rounds ~f rach each caliber or q~uQe ii) na"'f s 1icirc-q nd dealer•a license or reqistration numbfar (if any} of the pP.recn or ~rganizdticn from ~hem recPived iii) con~ijeration qiven tor the ammunition; and (iv) datP an 11 time of the receift of tht.&amp;gt; arr.munitJ.on l) a~munition sold or transferr~d includinq i) brand ~nd numter of rounds of each caliber or qau~e ii) namu, address and dealer's license number (it any) of ~hP. fereon or orqanization to whom sold or transferred iii) it thP pureha~er or transf Pree is not a licensee, th~ re~istration certificate number of the firearm tor which the an~unition ~as sold of transferre.\ iv) the c~nsideration for the sale and transf~r: and (v) tht.&amp;gt; date and ti!Tle of sale or transfer ltnrolled Orir,inal -12 r) The record9 requiroJ by B~hsection (d) shall upon ntP.mt-~r of the Metropolitan Police Ct&amp;gt;pclrt ent c) Edch person h.&amp;gt;liiin-t dler•a hrensl" sh.all hPn requi.red liy the Chief in vritinq. eut:mi.t on for111 and for thl gt;f'"rio1s of time specified. anv recor1 information TP·iuirei to b~ mdintd1ned ny Aubsection (a anJ any oth~r 1nformati0n r~~sonahly ohtaindtlc therefrom. SPc. Uf)5. Revocation. A de~l~r•s licensP shJll te revoke1 it a) any of the criteria in 9PCtion uou of this ~ct is no~ currently mP.t, or 0 (b) the information furnishPd to the Chief on the ~ppl1cat1on for a deal~r•s license rrovPs to be intPntionally falsP; or c (c) there is c1 violation or orrission of the duties. o ooli~dtions, or rt!quirernents imposed ty section ~o" ct this act. SPC. 406. Procedure~ for denial and revocation a) If it ap~e3r~ to the Chief that •n clFf lication for dealer's license should be denied or that a dealer's licensP. should te revoked, the ChiPf ehall notify the apFl1cant or re1istrant of the propo~ed denial or revocation br1ef ly ~tdtinq the reaqon or rPasons theretor. service may Z:lroll•d Ori1iaal -1 l- be •dje •S provi~ed tor in Rection 210(a) of thi ct. the •Pflicant or dedler shall have f 1ft~n daya fro~ the date of !tervice in which to suhmit further eviden~ in euppo~t of tht&amp;gt; application or quc1l1tication!'t to continue to hold de~ler•s licPnsc, as th~ case ~ay be: Provi lrj, Thclt 1f thf'o aptJllcant or dec1ler does not. lldlke !tuch a ~ub~ission w1thin l~ aay~ from the date ot servic thP cspJ ;li cant or lied 1.-r Rhci 11 he ·i~eined tc have conce,1ed the c- validity ot the reaRon ~r rec1s~n~ stated in the notice, and c thP denial or rPvocation sh~ll becor11e f insl 0 0 0 C' 0 (b) Within 10 ~ays of the date Ufon which the Chief receives such a &amp;amp;uhm1ssion, the rhiet shall serve upon the apflicant or reqi~trdnt in the manner providrd in section 210(a) ot this act no~ice ot his final d~cision. The Chi~f•s deciRion shall become eff~ctive at the expiration of t.hP t irne within which to file a not icP. of apFPcl l pursuant t-o the District of Columbia Administrdltive Procedure Act (O.c. CodP ec. 1·1501 t SP or, it such a not~ce of a~peal is filed, at the ti~e the tin~l order or judgment of the District of Colum~i~ court of App~als becomes effective CJ ~ithin 45 day~ of a decision becominq effective, which i~ unfavorable to a licensee or to an arplicant for a dPalPr•s license, thP licens~P or apflicant shall L b.urol1ed (l) it hf&amp;gt; is Pli~1blt&amp;gt; to r_.qister tirParrr• pursur nt invE"nl ory AC't: to this dCt, r~qister such firedrms in hi~ as dre ca~able of reqistration r-ureuant to thiA I 2) f i u 11ms ln ti1s a 11 dTnructi v~ peaceatly surr~ndcr \O thP. ChiP.f any 111ventory which he does not req.ist.er, and devices in h1s invt-ntory in thP. 1t1ann••r r rrov1i1P:l tor ln Sf&amp;gt;Ction f ij; c c Cl 0 3) ldwfully re~ovP fro~ the ~1strict ~ny f1re ,1rr in his inventury \l:h1ch he does not reqister and all riestru r 1vf' d("V1ces and ammunition in hie invPntory tcr so lonq df he has an interest in them: or I (4) otherwise lawfully ~isposP ot any tirrdrms I in his inventory ~hich h~ does not reqister and all jP.stru~ivc device~ and am~unition in his invP.ntory. I s c. 001. Ois~lays, em~loyees. No licensed dedler shall displdy any f irear~ or windovs visihle fro~ a street or sidewalk. arms, destructive iP.vices, and a~munition shall be all times in a seeurP.ly locked Fldce aftixed to the pre~ise exc~pt when heinq shown to repairc t or otherwise beinn vorke~ a customer ein~ on. r 35 tt No licenseP Rtlall kn~inqly e~rloy dny pPrs0n an his est blishmPnt it such ~er sun would not te el i&amp;lt;d b }P t c rPq.ister ct firectr:n uwt~r this c1ct s~c. ijQH Firertrm m-trkintts. No l1cen~ec ~hall ~ell or fP1 for sctlP dny tir~dr tihich Joes not hdv imbe:idt&amp;gt; i intu the met .ll 1-ortion of qur.h tirP.tr!Tl ct unl ·lUP mdnuf.ir.turer•s iciPntiticdtlon number or SPri.ll number, unless th e licensPP shdll have imtedde :I into thP mPtal fOrt.i gt;n of such t1redrrr d uni~ue dealer•q idPr.tification nU"\her. sec. ijQ9. CPrtain infJrmation not to be usP.d dS evidenr No information ohtained fro~ or retained by d licensed jpaler to co~~ly ~ith this title shall be usPd as evidf'nce aodin~t such licensed dPalP~ in any criminal froceeding ~ith resrect to a violation of t~is act occurrinq prior to or concurrently with the til1n~ ot cuch infor~ation; Provid~d, Th~t this section shall not ~oply to any violation of qection 85d of the Act of March l. lqo1 (r.c. Code. sec. 22- 2501 or ct sPction 701 of this dct T'ITLE V SALi AND TRA FER Of ft~EAPll.1S, l:ESTRUCTIVE C!VIC£S, AND A~MUNITION ~cc. 501. Pruhibition. No person or or~~nizatiun shall sell, transfer or othPrwisP ~ispos~ of any f ire3rm, destructive device or \.4 7. Y• 41 c -J6- a~~un1t1un in t.he District eKcept as rrovidPd in etion&amp;amp; 5 or 60ij ot this act c. S02. Pf&amp;gt;rmiS~ihle Bales and tranSf Prs d) Any person or org~nization eliqible to t't'!qtster a t 1rc-1tr1T1 Ny sP.ll or othP.nti se t ran~fer a:11rruni t .i on or any firP~rm Pxceµ t tho~P which are unreqistPratle undrr sectjon 202 of t h is act, to a licen~ed dealer h) Any licen~ed dedl~r may sell or other•ise tran~t~r am rr un1tion and any tirP•rm or 1estructivP device whi~h is lawfully a part of such licen~ee•s invPn~ory to l) any nonresi &amp;lt;lent feraon or businPBS licensed un1er thP Acts of conqres~ an~ the jurisdiction where such pe r s on resides ~r conducts such ~usinPss 2) any ot r lic~nsed de-tl&amp;lt;"r 3 ny l entorcetNant officer or agent of the c District or the Uni teJ Std t.es wh~n such officer or agent i a C on duty, and actin'l within thn scope of his dut.ies vhen ac~uiring such f irear dm munition, or destructive devic if the officP-r or Aqent hcss in his ~ossession a Btdte1t1ent from the he•d of hi9 •q~ncy stating that the item is to be u~ed in such officer's or aqent•s official duties c) Any licPneeJ de~l~r may sell or otherwise transfer firP~r excPpt those whi c h are unreq1sterable un~er Af&amp;gt;Ct1on :l02 of ttaiA act, to any perscn or orqaniz.ttion !Enrolled Or!gio•l -37- possess&amp;gt;.n1 d rt.•Jistration certifi te tor such f.irP•r.m: Provijed, 1hat if the Chi~f denies a rPqistration ct-rtiticc1te, he "hc1ll so c1Jvise tt-e 11cPnsee who •h•l-l thereu~on (1) w1thholj delivery until such time as a r~qiqtrdt1on cPrtit1cJtP i~ iRsu~d, or, at the option of the pruchaser 2, dPCl re thP contract null and V.Jid, in whirh ca consider.ition p .ti •i t•&amp;gt; the licensPe shall t:e rf'turned to thP p~rchdser; Prov1dP! further that this eubs~cti0n ~hall c- not .i ie.ly to prrsons C gt;v r.-1 by ~ubseC".tion Ct 0 0 (rt) F.xcept elS pruv1dpj in sul:section b) an1 (i no l1cPns~j 1ec1ler shelll ~ell or other~ise trdnsfer d~~unition unlPSS l) the S&amp;lt;:tle or trantofer is rnarie in Ferson; and (2) the purchaser exhibits, at the time of sale or other transfer, a v~lid registration certificate, or, in thP case ot a nonresiient, Froof that the weapon is lawfully ~ossessej in the jurisdiction whPre such person resideA J) thP dmmunition to he sold or transferred is of tnP same cal iher or qau11e as tl,e f .irearm descr it-ed in the re~iqtration certiticdte, or othPr ~reef in thP Cdse of nonresident; and (4) the purchasar siqns a receiFt for the am~unition ~hich (1n addition to the ether records required Er.rolled Original un.1t&amp;gt;r this ctct) ehcdl ht&amp;gt; in.tintdinC't ty tht liC"ense.i je.t.lt·r t gt;r "µ ri0r! ot onP YPrtr tr m thr H of sctle c) Any licensen J 1lr!r 1'\.ty sell ct1T11runition to ~ny µPrson hJ lJi n~ an .urmunit ion col lPctor certificate on t II ftf&amp;gt;ctivP d:tt» of thl 1ct: r&amp;gt;r.Jvic!t-ci Thdt the collector cPrtiticatt.&amp;gt; f'hctll Lf exhihiti&amp;gt;i to t}1P licen!!ed ciedler whrnPv~r the c0llcctor µruc~~ie mmun1t1on for hi~ cull&amp;lt;-Ctl.on Provii t11rt? w r thJt t:hf' collPC"tor S!'Mll s1 .111 .a c. f&amp;gt; Ol gt;;u ilf»rson sli1ll J.USBP~s cl!T.:T1Unit1on in thr ~i~trict ot Colum~id unlP d) lfp is a licenseci pdler ~ur~uant to Title IV of this 11ct b) h~ i~ an off ict-r tqent, or PITIFloyet&amp;gt lt;Jf he District 0t Culwntia or th~ Unitrn Stdtes ot A~P.r1cc1. on duty and actin it:hin ~hr sco~e uf his duties whPn po~~c~~in~ such ct~~uni~ion c e i:J thf&amp;gt; hol •ier of d valid r qi::Jtrdtion cfO&amp;gt;rtiftcd~P for a t1re~rm of tt1f&amp;gt lMTlf&amp;gt t&amp;lt;lU'lf&amp;gt; or Cdlit-cr as thP dm~unition hP µus II thf' effective Jatf' ot this dct Y'ITLF VII E~FR"l Pi'CVlSll&amp;gt;1 ec 701. Shrill be gt;Pcur1ty tor, Jr he taken or r~c-t&amp;gt;ivP &amp;lt;'l by Y uf dny t) frorr anothf"r µerson iny fir~-irm, de~truct1ve Jevicc, or -im:runi t1 on. Exr.ept tor la• eutorce!'1~nt 1-ersonn~l de!;cr1beJ in sect1on 2 1 (b 1 e~ch re11istcant shc1ll kef'F dny tiredrlT' 1n hi s poss ssion unlo~ded and disasse"'tled or ~cund oy a tr1~qer lock or si"'ilar ~evice unlPss such fir~irm is keFt at his ~ldcP of tusinPss, or while bein~ ur.ed tor lawful recreat1on~l furrosPS within the District of Col u:nbia. Sec. 703. firinq ranqe"I. Any pE&amp;gt;rson Of~ratinq a f iri11Q ranqe in the District, shdll in addition ~c any otner requiremPnt imposeJ ty la rPqi"lter with the ChiPt, on a for rrscrited by hi which sh~ll include the husinnA~ name of the ranqe, the locaticn, the namPs and hom~ adjre~s~s of the owners and Frincipal officers, thP type'l of weapl)ns fired f're, the numter anti tyres ot wPapone norma 11 y stored there, the riayR .tnd hours of operation nd such othrr information as the C'hif'f shall re~u1re. sec. 70 False inform.ltlon, forqery, alter.atJon a) It Rhdll he unldwtul tor any person purcha~inq any fir~arm or ammunition, or afplyinq tor any reqistrdti~n cert1f1cdte or Je~lP.r 1 s licenqe un1er this act, or an ~ivino any intor~~tion pursudnt to thP r~quirel'le'nts of thiq t. to kno~1n~ly ~ive fdl~P infurm~tion or offer fals~ ev1d~ncr of i1Pntlty b) It Rhdll he unl~wful for anyone to t~rqe er altEr any a~~licat1on, rPq1straticn certificate, er dealer•q 11r.ensP gt;uhm1tted, r«•t.aine:i or issu,.d under this .tct. s~c. 705. Voluntary surrenJ~r: immunity a) If a person or orqanization within the District voluntarily an1 peace~bly oelivers and abandons to the Chief ~ny firP.~rm, destructive device or ammunition at an~ time, such delivery shall preclude the arrest and frosecution of 9UCh person on a charye of violdtin~ any provi~ion of this act with respect to the firP~r deRtructive device, or am~unitiun voluntdrily delivered. trlivery unJ~r this s~ction ~dY he md~e dt any p gt;liN&amp;gt; Jistrict, statiQn, or c.-ntr-ll ho:?i19iquart~rs, or by sun1".1Jn1nq d police officer to thP. pP.rson s resi.dPnce or pl a cf&amp;gt; of business. Every firearm ZDrolled ~ri~inal L- I I Sec. 707. Public ~ducation froqram. The Chiet shall carry on a suita~ltt put:licity s:r.OCJr•11 desi~ned to infor~ the citizens of the District of the provisions ot ~hiB act anJ thP rights dnd otli~ations createj by it. SPc. 70d. Rep~dlers d) District of Columtia Reoulationr Nos. oti-15 and 09-7 (ArticlP~ 50 ~o 5~ inclusi~ of the PolicP Regulatione of the District ot COlumhiat are hereby repealed t) Requlat1on 74-JJ dpfroved Cecemter 1. 197 rel.tting to bounty payment~ for the turning i.n of firear1t1s) r is repealed. C c c 0 0 (ct Article of the Polic~ Pequlations of the District of Columt:ia is refcalPd to the extent such article is in conflict with the provisions of ~his act ec. 709. Contl1ct with FPderal law thinq in this act shall te construed, or •rFlied to nP.cessarily require, or excuse noncomFliance ~ith any provision of any Federal Law hiR act and the penalties prescribed in section 605 of this act. for violations of this act, shall not su~erse1e but shall su~rlement all statute~ ot the D1etrict anJ the United State~ in ~hich similar c~nduct is prohibit~d or requlated. 1 I 1 tnroll Or nA Cl r ~ec. 710. Applicc1bility ot f'i!'ltrir.t of Colu"'H" Administrative ProcedurP Act. The provision~ of thP Oiatrtct of Colu~tia Administr11tive Procedur~ Act [:.c. Codt sec. 1-lSOl Pt SP -J shall ctpply tc Petch frocPedinq, dP.cision or oth&amp;lt;-r ct1.:T'1n1fftrdt1ve .1ct1ori s~~J.tieJ in thiR dCt unless ot her 1 S&amp;lt ffpPCi f ical l y pr•JV ide i. sec. 711. Sctvinq~ cl:tu!'Je. If any proviRion uf t~is act or th~ ap~lication thereof to any per~on or circum!itttncP is hPld invalid, the rerr..tinder of this act o1nd thf• application of such provision to othf'r pers gt;nR not simild rly fllit ~J.JtP.d or to other ci rcumstanccs s~all not ~e affected thereby. SPC. 712. FtfPCtiYP. rlate. This ~ct shall t~KP. Pffect pursuctnt to the frovisiona of s~ction 602(c 1) of the District of Columtia Self• C Gov€-rnrnPnt an:i G0vern~ntc11 Rt'"orqaniz.tt ion Act. 0</search-text>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>101</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2501.01"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>203</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>204</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>205</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>206</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>207</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>207a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.07a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>208</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>209</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>210</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.10"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>211</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.11"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>211a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.11a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>212</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.12"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>213</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.13"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>214</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2502.14"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>301</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2503.01"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>401</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>402</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>403</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>404</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>405</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>406</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>407</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>408</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>409</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.09"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>501</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2505.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>502</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2505.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>503</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2505.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>504</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2505.04"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VI</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>601</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2506.01"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VII</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>701</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>702</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>703</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>704</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>705</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>706</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>706a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.06a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>707</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>709</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>710</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>711</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.10"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>712</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2507.11"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VIII</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>801</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>802</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>803</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>804</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>805</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>806</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>807</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2508.07"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <section>
    <num>410</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2504.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>901</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>902</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>903</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>904</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>905</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>906</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>907</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>908</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>909</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.09"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>910</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>911</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2509.11"/>
  </section>
</document>
