<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-87">
  <num type="law">1-87</num>
  <heading type="short">Anti-Sex Discriminatory Language Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1976-10-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-87.pdf">D.C. Law 1-87</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 2544</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-87, the “Anti-Sex Discriminatory Language Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-36, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 15, 1976 and June 29, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 27, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-143 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. Law 1-87 Anti-Sex Discrimina- tory Language Act October 5, 19 7 6 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act PL 93-198) the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-3 6 on first and second readings June 15, 1976 and June 29, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 27, 1976, this legislation was assigned Act No. 1-143, published in the August 10, 1976, edition of the D. C. Register and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C Ref. 23, D.C. Reg. 1134, August 10, 1976 D.C. LAW 1-87 In the Council of the District of Columbia October 1, 1976 To amend certain provisions of the District of Columbia Code in order to eliminate their sex discriminatory aspects. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COL mm IA, That this act nay be cited as the "Anti-Sex Discriminatory Language act Sec. 2. Section 568 of the Act of March 3, 1901, as amended (D.C. Code, sec. 1-511) is further amended by strikinq out "the acknowledgment of any conveyance or other instrument of writing executed by any married woman Sec. 3. Section 17 of the Act of February 27, 1929 (D.C. Code sec. 2-113) is amended by striking out "her" wherever it appears in the fourth sentence and inserting in lieu thereo f "his or her Sec. 4 a) Except as provided in subsection (b the Act o f February 9, 1907 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-401, et seq e Act of Septe!'1ber 6, 1960 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-421, et -2- seq and the Act of September 22, 1961 {D.C. Code, sec. 2- 451, et seq are amended Cl) by striking out "she" wherever it appears and inser~ing in lieu thereof "he or she 2) by striking out "her" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "his or her and (3) by striking out "herself" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "himself or herself b 1) Section 9(c) of the Act of September 6, 1960, {D.C. Code, sec. 2-428 (c is amended by striking out "her" and inserting in lieu thereof "him or her 2) Section 13 of the Act of September 22, 1961 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-462) is amended by striking out "addressed to her" and inserting in lieu thereof "addressed to him or her" and by striking out "her last known address" and inserting in lieu thereof "his or her last known address c 1) Section 12 of the Act of February 9, 1907 (D.c. Code, sec. 2-411) is repealed. The heading of o.c. Code 2-411 and the reference thereto in the table of sections of Chapter 4 of Title 2 of said Code are stricken 2) section 2 of the Act of September 6, 1960 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-421) is amended CA) by striking out subsec~ion (c} and ~r.oll~d. Original 3 B) by redesignating subsections {d) and (e) as (c) and (d respectively 3) Section 2 of the Act of September 22, 1961 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-451) is amended CA) by striking out subsection (b and (B) by redesignating subsections (c {d and {e) as (b {c and {d respectively. Sec. 5. The Act of March 16, 1926, as amended (D.C. Code, sec. 3-110) is further amended Cl) by striking out clause (c and (2) by changing d to "Cc and striking out "including women and children in said clause. Sec. 6. Section 1 of the Act of January 12, 1942 (D.c. Code, sec. 3-126) is amended by inserting in clause (2) thereof "fathers and" after "mothers and Sec. 7. Sections 1, 2, and 3 of the Act of July 23, 1888 (D.C. Code, sec. 4-116, 4-117 and 4-118) are repealed. The headings of D.C. Code 4-116, 4-117 a~d 4-118 and the references thereto in the table of sections of Chapter 1 of Title 4 of said Code are stricken. Sec. 8 a) Paragraph (4) of section 12(a) of the Act of September 1, 1916, as amended (D.C. Code, sec. 4-521) is further amended to read as follows: Enrolle:I Ori.ginal -4 4) The term "widower" means the surviving husband of a member or former member if A) he was married to such member or former member (i) while she was a member, or (ii) for at least one year immediately preceding her death, or (B) he is the father of issue by such marriage b) All references in Chapter 5 of Title 4 of the Distric of Columbia Code to "policemen" and "firemen" are amended to refer to "police" and "firefighters Sec. 9. That section 12 (c} (7) of the Act of September 1, 1916 (D.C. Code, sec. 4-523(7 is amended by striking out "his widow" or "widow" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "the surviving spouse Sec. 10. The second par~graph of section l(a) of the Act of March 1, 1907 (D.C. Code, sec. 6-301 (a is amended by striking out "shall forward to the father of the child, or, if his address is unknown, to the mother and inserting in lieu thereof "shall forward to the parents of the child, or, if one parent's address is not known, to the parent whose address is known nr.c;ille Ori$inal -s- Sec. 11. Section 15-502 of the District of Columbia Code is amended Cl) by striking out "wife" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "spouse and (2) by inserting "or her" after "his Sec. 12. Section 16-304(b 2) of the District of Columbia Code is amended Cl) by striking out "or were married and are" in Clause (A {2) by striking out clauses (C) and (D}; and (3) by redesignating clauses (E F}, and CG) as clauses (C D and (E}, respectively; and (4) by striking out "paragraphs (A) through (E in the redesignated clause (D and inserting in lieu thereof "paragraphs {A) through (C Sec. 13. Section 16-577 of the District of Col umbia Code is amended by striking out "wife" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "spouse Sec. 14 a) Section 16-911 of the District of Columbia Code is amended Cl) by striking out "action by the husband" and inserting in lieu thereof "action by the husband or wife and Eorolled. 9riginal -6 2) by striking out "denied by the wife" and inserting in lieu thereof "denied by the other spouse b) Paragraph (l} of section 16-911 of such Code is amended 1) by striking out "the husband" and inserting in J.ieu thereof "the husband or wife 2) by striking out "wife" and inserting in lieu thereof "other spouse 3) by inserting "himself or" after "for the maintenance of 4) by striking out "committed to her care" and inserting in lieu thereof "committed to such other spouse's care 5) by striking out "to enable her to conduct h~r case" and inserting in lieu thereof "to enable such other spouse to conduc the case and (6) by striking out "whether she is 11 and inserting in lieu thereof "whether as c) Paragraph (2) of section 16-911 of such Code is amended by striking out "of the husband's" and inserting in lieu thereof "of a spouse's d) Paragraph (3) of section 16-911 of such code is amended ltiu'olled Original -7 1) by striking out "if the husband" and inserting in lieu thereof "if a spouse and hi s 2) by inserting "or her" after "sequestrate (e) Paragraph (4) of section 16-911 of such Code is amended by deleting the period at the end of such section and adding the following without conclusive regard to the race, color, national origin, political affiliation, sex, or sexual orientation, in and of itself, of a party Sec. 15. Section 16-912 o f the District of Columbia Code i s amended 1) by striking out "granted to the wi f e" and inserting in lieu thereof "granted to either spouse 2) by inserting "him or" after "may decree 3) by striking out "for her support" and inserti ng in lieu thereof "for his or her support 4) by striking out "assigns to her care" and i nserting in lieu thereof "assigns to that spouse's care Sec. 16 a) Section 16-913 of the District of Columbi a Code is amended 1) by striking out "on husband's application" i n the heading Eilrolled Origiilal -8 2) by striking out "of the husband" and inserting in lieu thereof "of the husband or wife 3) by inserting "or her" after "may require him and (4) by striking out "to the wife" and inserting in lieu thereof "to the other spouse b) The table of sections of chapter 9 of title 16 of such Code is amended by striking out "16-913. Alimony when divorce is granted on husband's application and inserting in lieu thereof "16-913. Alimony when divorce is granted Sec. 17. Section 16-914 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by adding the following sentence at the end of such section With respect to matters of custody and visitation, the race, color, national origin, political affiliation, sex, or sexual orientation, in and of itself, of a party shall not be a conclusive consideration Sec. 18. {a) Section 16-915 of the District of Columbia Code is amended to read as follows Upon divorce from the bond of marriage, the court shall, on request of a party who assumed a new name on marriage and desires to discontinue using it, state in the decree of divorce either the birth-given or other previous name which such person desires Enrolled Original -9 to use b) The heading of section 16-915, and the reference thereto in the table of sections of Chapter 9 of Title 16, of said Code are amended to read as follows 16-915. Change of name on divorce Sec. 19 a) Section 16-916 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking out the heading of such section and inserting in lieu thereof "16-916. Maintenance of spouse and minor children; maintenance of former spouse; maintenance of minor children; enforcement b) Section 16-916(a) of such Code is arnended 1) by striking out "any husband" and inserting in lieu thereof "a husband or wife 2) by striking out "his wife and inserting in lieu thereof "his or her needy spouse 3) by striking out "any father" and inserting in lieu thereof "any parent 4) by striking out "his childrn" and inserting in lieu thereof "his or her children 5) by inserting after the words "upon proper application the phrase and upon a showing of genuine need of a spouse Enrolled· Original -10 6) by striking out "that he shall" and inserting in lieu thereof "that such husband or wife sha11° 7) by striking out "of such wife and children" and inserting in lieu thereof "of such needy spouse and of the children 8) by striking out "that he pay" and inserting in lieu theeof "that he or she pay c) Section l6-916(b) of such Code is amended 1) by striking out "husband" and inserting in lieu thereof 11 spouse11 2) by striking out "former wife" and inserting in lieu thereof "other former spouse 3) by striking out "the former husband" and inserting in lieu thereof "such former spouse by striking out "he" and inserting in lieu thereof "he or she 5) by striking out "her reasonable sums" and inserting in lieu thereof "him or her reasonable sums and (6) by striking out "her maintenance" and inserting in lieu thereof "his or her main-t.enance d) The table of sections of chapter 9 of title 16 of such Code is amended by striking out "16-916. Maintenance of wife and minor children; maintenance of former wife; maintenance of minor children; enforcement and inserting Enroll e-d 0 riginal -11- in lieu thereof "16-916. Maintenance of spouse and minor children; maintenance of former spouse; maintenance of minor children; enforcement Sec. 20. Subchapter II of Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows: {a) section 16-234l(a) of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking out "wife" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "spouse b) section 16-2342 of the District of Columbia code is amended by {l) striking out "paternity" and inserting in lieu thereof "parentage and {2) striking out "father" and inserting in lieu thereof "father or mother, as the case may be {c) section 16-2343 of the District of Columbia code is amended by {l) striking out "mother, child, and the respondent" and inserting in lieu thereof "child, respondent and the oth~r parent if available and (2) striking out "fa ler" and inserting in lieu thereof "father or mother, as the case may be d) Section 16-2345 of tha District of Columbia Code is amended by Enrolled original -12 1) striking out "paternity" and inserting in lieu thereof "parentage and (2} striking out nthe husband" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "each of the parents e) Section 16-2346 of the District of Columbia code is amended by 1) striking out "paternity" and inserting in lieu thereof "parentage and (2) striking out "name of the person adjudged to be t h e father of the child. 11 wherever this phrase appears, and inserting in lieu thereof "names of the persons adjudged to be the father and mother of the child f) section 16-2347 of the District of Columtia Code is amended by 1) striking out "paternity" and inser'ting in lieu thereof "parentage 2) striking out 11 age of 18 years" and inserting in lieu th~reof "age at which the child ceases to be a minor and (3) striking out "his" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof his or her {g) section 16-2348 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by Enrolled Original -13- {l) striking out "mother" and inserting in lieu thereof "other parent and (2) striking out in the section heading "paternity" and inserting in lieu thereof "parentage h) The heading of subchapter II of Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columtia Code is amended by striking out "PATERNITY" and inserting in lieu thereof "PARENTAGE i) The table of sections of subchapter II of Chapter 23 of Title 16 of said Code is amended 1) by changing the word "PATERNITY" in the heading thereof to read "PARENTAGE 2) by changing the word "Paternity" in the listing of section 16-2348 the ein to read "Parentage11 sec. 21. section 16-2701 of the Dist=ict of Columbia Code is amended by striking out "or if the person injured is a married woman, entitle her husband, either separately or by joining with the wife and inserting in lieu thereof "or if the pe=son injured is married, entitle the spouse, eithe separately or by joining with the injured person Sec. 22 a) Section 19-316 of the District of Columbia Code is amended to read as follows Illegitimate children and the issue of illegitimate child=en are capable of taking En~ollcd Original -14- real and personal estate by inheritance from their mother or from their father if parent- hood has been established by judicial proc~ss or pursuant to sec. 19-318, or f ram each other. or from descendants of each other, as the case may be, in like manner as if born in lawful wedlock, and the mother and such father, and their respective heirs, are capable of inheriting from such children b) The table of sections of chapter 3 of title 19 of such Code is amended by inserting father" after mother" in item 19-316 c) Section 19-316 of the District of Columbia code is amended by inserting father" after "mother" in the he~ding t hereof. Sec. 23. Section 20- 1 708 of the District of Columbia Code is repealed. The heading of said section and th~ reference t hereto in Chap~er 17 of Title 20 of said Code are stricken. sec. 24. {a) Section 20-1906 of the District of Columbia code is amended 1) by striking out "to female" in he heading and inserting in lieu thereof "conditioned on attainment of lawful age Enrolled Original 5 2) by striking out "a female" and inserting in lieu thereof "a person 3) by striking out "her" and inserting in lieu th~reof "his or her and (4) by striking out "the female" and inserting in lieu thereof "such person b) The table of sections of chapter 19 of title 20 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking out "20-1906. Bequest to female and inserting in lieu thereof "20-1906. Bequest conditioned on attainment of la~ful age. 11 Sec. 25. Section 20-2301 of the District of Columbia Code is amended Cl) by striking out "wife" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "spouse 2) by striking out "he" wherever it appears and inserting in lieu thereof "he or she 3) by striking out "him" and ins~rting in lieu thereof "him or her 4) by striking out "his" and inserting in lieu thereof his or her and (5) by striking out "her" and inserting in lieu thereof "his or her Enrolled Original 6- sec. 26 a) Section 20-2310 of the District of Columbia Code is amended l) by striking out the heading and inserting in lieu thereof: and 20-2310. Support of absentee's spouse and minor children 2) by striking out "wife and inserting in lieu thereof "spouse b) The table of s e ctions of chapter 23 of title 20 of such Code is amended by striking out "20-2310. Support of absentee's wife and minor children and inserting in lieu thereof "20-2310. Support of absentee's spouse and minor children sec. 27. Section 21-102 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking out other than a married female" and inserting in lieu thereof 11 other than a married infant sec. 28. section 21-107 of the District of Columbia Code is amended l) by striking out clauses (1 2 and {3) and inserting in lieu thereof the following Cl) the parents, or either of them, if living; or d Origi:al 17 2) the spouse if th• infant is married to a person 18 years of aqe or older and (2) by strikinq out •husband• and insert:i.nq in sec. 29 a) sec~on 21-109 of the District of lumbia code is uiended 1) by striJcinq out las.band• in the headinq inserting in lieu thereof •spouse 2) by strikinq out "When a female infant• and nsertinq in lieu thereof •when an infant 3) by stri.Jdnq out •quardian of her estate• Uld insertinq in lieu thereof •guardian of his or her 1state II) by strikinq out "she a1ay select her 1us~and" and insertinq in lieu thereof "he or she a1ay select 1is or her spouse 5 by ~tri.kinq out "Of her estate" and lnsert!Dq in lieu thereof "Of his or her estate and (6) by striking out •ward•s utate to her ausband" and insertinq in lieu thereof •wa d• s estate to his 1r her spouse b) The table of sections of ehapte 1 of title 21 of 1uc:h Code is amended by strikinq cut •21-109. Husband as 1a- guardian of estate amp;Dd in••rtinq in lieu thereof •21- 109 Spouse quardian o tat Sec. 30 a) Section 21-113 of the District of ColUlllhia code i.s amerided 1) by strildnq out the heaclinq and iD•ft'ti.nq iD liea thereof and lieu llljoi.ninq spouse. parent. or test&amp;amp;111e111:ary IJUUdi&amp;amp;n from ill'terferinq vi1:h lllinor•s estate 2) by strildnq out •husl:land• and inse=tinq in thereof •spouse bJ The table of sections of chapter l of title 21 of such Code is &amp;amp;111ended by strikinq out •21-113 njoininq husband, parent. or testament~ quardian from interferinq with minor•s estate and insertinq in lieu thereof •21- 113. Enjoininq spouse. parent. or testamentary quardian ~rom interferinq vi.th minor estate Sec. 31 a) subcbapter III of chapter l of title 21 of the District of Columbia Code is amended Cl) by strikinq out "BOYS" in the .beadinq of :he subchapter and insertinq in lieu thereof "MINOR Enrolled Original -19 2) by striking out "boys" in the heading of section 21-181 and inserting in lieu thereof "minor children 3) by striking out "boys• in section 21-181 and inserting in lieu thereof "minor children and (4) by striking "boys" in section 21-182 and inserting in lieu thereof "minor children b) The table of s~ctions of chapter 1 of title 21 of such Code is amended 1) by striking out "BOYS" in the heading of subchapter III and inserting in lieu thereof "MINOR CHILDREN and (2) by striking out "21-181. Enlistment of indigent boys and inserting in lieu thereof "21- 181. Enlist.~ent of indigent minor children Sec. 32. Section 1292 of the Act of March 3, 1901 (D.C. Code, sec. 30-111 is amended by striking out "unless the father of such person, or if there be no father, the mother and inserting in lieu thereof "unless a parent Sec. 33 a) Section 1154 of the Act of March 3, 1901, as amended (D.C. Code, sec. 30-201) and the heading thereof are amended to read as follows sec. 30-201. RIGHTS OF MARRIED PERSONS TO ACQUIRE, HOLD AND DISPOSE OF Enrolled Original -20- PROPERTY, CONTRACT, ENGAGE IN BUSINESS, AND SUE AND BE SUED The fact that a person is or was married shall not, after the date of enact- ment of this a impair the rights and responsibilities of such person, which are hereby granted or confirmed, to acquire from anyone, and to hold and dispose of, in any manner, as his or hers, property of any kind, or to accept and be bound by any covenant or agreement relating to any property or debt, or to contract or engage in any trade, occupation or business arrangement or in any civil litigation of any sort (whether in contract, tort or otherwise) with or against anyone including such person's spouse, to the same extent as an unmarried person, and neither the spouse of such perscn nor the spouse's property shall be liable because of any contract or tort by such person in which the spouse has not directly or indirectly participated, except that .both spouses shall be liable on any debt, contract or engagement entered into by either of them during their ginal -21- marriage for necessaries for either ot them or for their dep nden t children. A married to the same disabilities, including the requirement for appointment of a guardian of the minor• s estate, as an unmarried minor, eltcept as provided by law. This section be deemed to affect the law relating to dower, o--m~rship of ~roperty held by 'the husband a.nd wife as tenants by the inheritance of property, actions for loss of consortium, family relations, or, to necessari~s purchased during marriag obliqations for marital suppo b) sections ll 70, 1157, 1153, l.152, 1171, 1151 1156, 1166, 1177, 1161, 1162, 1163, and 1164 of the 1901 as amended, {'O.C. Code, secs. 30-202 are repeal and the headings of sa.id o.c. sections are stricken. Section ~9U of th~ Act of March 3, l901 (C.C Sll!C. 30-216) is amended 1) by redesignating t.~e s~cticn as section 19 22 2) by strikinq out •wife and insertinq in thereof •spouse• 1 (3) by strikinq out •her dower• and insertinq thereof ·hi·s or her doWer 1 (4) by strikinq out •she• and insertinq in lieu (5) by atrikinq out •by her• and insertinq in thereof •by him or her• 1 and (6) by strikinq out •her acknowledgement• and tinq in lieu thereof •his or her acknowledgement d) The table of sections of Chapter 2 of Title 30, Code are stricken. Sec 34. Section 20 of the Act of July 10, 1957 (D.c sec. 30-320) is amended to read as follows The natural father and the natural mother of an illegitimate child shall have the duty to support such child while such child· is a minor. The alleqed father's or alleged mother's parenthood of the illeqiti- mate child may be established eit.11er by judi- cial process or by acknowledgment under oath by the person whose parenthood is t.11us detenn.ined l -23- Sections 1 through 4 of the Act of 12, 1888, as amended {D.C. Code, secs. 32-101 h 32-104) are repealed. The headings of said o.c. Chapter l of Title 32, and the table of s thereof and the reference thereto in the table of of said Code are stricken. Sections l through 10 of the Act of 24, 1914, as amended co.c. Code, secs. 36-301 h 36-309a) are repealed. The headings of said o.c. listing thereof in the table of of Title 36 of said Code are stricken Section l of the Act of March 2, 1895 Code, sec. 36-310) is amended by 1) striking out •female" in the heading thereof 2) striking out •All persons who employ females• and in lieu thereof •All employers of persons 3) striking out •all such females• and inserting in thereof •all such employees 4) striking out •female b) The table of sections of Chapter 3 of Title 36 of Code is amended by striking out •female• in the listing Sec. 38. Section 2 of the Act of March 2, 1895 (D.c sec. 36-311) is amended by a) striki."lg out •of !e=.a.le hel b) striking out "f~ale!l" and i lsertir.q in lieu acf "e tployees Sec. 39. Section 25 o! the Act of Se?te::ibei 27 C~e, sec. 4l-324(e is acended by L"lserting dO'.zers a!ter allowa.m:es to wide Sec. 40. Section lllj9 o! t e Act o arch 3, l~Ol .c. Coc!e, 45-913) is re;?e.J.led. The heading of saic! o.c. a section c1 ld t:1e listi lg t e.reof i i t!:e tabla of ions of Cha?ter 9 of itle 45 are st=ic e Sec. 41. Section 21 of t.:1e Conpiled Statutes of t e of ColUI bia (D.C. Code, sec. 45-13~1 is al lt;:nded l:y out "a wo ian Sec. 42. Se~tion lO of ~1e ~ct of Ju."le 19, 190€ (r.c sec. 47-:n:l) is n.:led by st=ikin; out "a 7 fe n.l~ a ld in:3erti lg in lieu t!:ereof "a l pe:son as a Sec. 43 a cept as ~rovide&amp;lt;l L"l subsecticn (b l':lenerte."l.ts 1.ade =y t is act shall ta1:e effect pursua t e ,revisions o= sec~ion ~G2(c) of "t e District of IJ::ia 5el£-r::0ve=r lsnt a liover iental anization Ac~ Stat. OlJ C. Cole, Su I l-147(c 1 25- assi g:i cnts fa= t!rn benefit of c=cditors, nnd bills o f sale u io:-i exenpted articles ex.=cuted nore t!1an si ty c!a :rs a::t e the effective date of tl1is act 2 1e arrendnents nade by sections l2 t!11:"oug h 21, and 33 shall apply ~ith respect to all ~ct.ions roceedin~s, and matters cor:rr~enced or pendi~g, in any admi nistrative or judicial forur on or after t2e eff e~tive date of this act Docket for the Bill B_i_ll_l-_3_6 Considered in Council June 15, 1976 First Vote 1_2 o l RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDING x 1-!00RE, D. x HARDY x WTI.SON x BARRY x HOBSON x WINTER x CLARKE x MOORE, J. x COATES x SHACKLETON x X-Indic:ates Vote A. B.-Absent N. V.-Not Voting ~QW Secretary of the Council) Final Vote in Council June 29, 197 6 11-0 2 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE COUNCIL MEMBE~ AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL. MEMBER AYE NAY N.V. A.B. COUNCIL MEMBER AYE TUCKER x DIXON x SPAULDING MJORE, D. I x HARDY I x WILSON x BARRY x HOBSON -x _J WINTER x CLARKE x MJORE, J. x i COATES x SHACKLETON x X-Inciic:aies Vote A. B.-Absent N. V.-Not Voting J\lL l i 1976 Presented to the Mayor Mayor's Action 0° JUL 1976 Approved Disapproved Enacted without Mayor's Signature Secretary of the Council Secretary of the Counci l Secretary of the Council NAY NAY N.V. A.B. N V A.B. x L1-87 Pages from L1-87 (2)-2</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
