<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-96" flag="true">
  <num type="law">1-96</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-96.pdf">D.C. Law 1-96</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 3744</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-96 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-119, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Criminal Law. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 15, 1976 and October 12, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 19, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-178 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>Distriot ot Columbia Register CGllNC TJ. I.IF 'l·111 IH:.iTRICT rw C&amp;lt;iLUrmJA NO'flCE March 31 1977 n. c r.A~·l 1-96 "Freedom of In formation Act of 1 97 6" Pursu.•nt. to s~ction 412 of the Dis trict of Columbia Self- Government und Government;i l Reorgan i zation Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of t he District of Columbia adopted Bill No l 119 o n f rs and second readings September 15, 1976, and Octc=er 12, 1 976 es~ectivcly. Fellowing the signature o f the ?layer on Nover:.ber 19, 1 ~76, th s legislation was ass i gned Act No. 1- 178 p~bl shed in =he Dece~ber 10 1975, edition of the c.c Pc a nd ansmitt~c ~o both Houses of Congress for a 30- cay rev ie i~ accord ance wi t~ Secti on 602 {c 1 of t he Act. The Counc o: the District of Col wnbia hereby g i ve s not i ce that the 30-d~y Ccngre ssional Review Period has cxpir~d and the ref o re, c tt es !he f ollowi ng leg islation as D. C. La w 1-Q G, cf fcc:j v&amp;amp re 25, 197 7. 7872 STF.RLI N TUCKER Ch.iirmun of the Council J).1nlriot or Cnl stnr 1 o nrc t17! AN ACT 1-178 lN TH'E COUNC.IL Of' TH.£ DIST.RICT OF COLUMBIA November 19. 1976 To CJ;e&amp;amp;te a Freedom of Informa tiort A to ere.ate right JI and for oth~r purposes E IT ~N~CTED BY TH E COUNCIL O? THE DlSTRICT OF COLU~Bt That this act may be cit~d as the •Free \ of ln!ormation Aet of 1976 Sec. 2. The Ois.o:=ic of Colum bia Acmi~istr:r.:ive Proce&amp;lt;!tire Act cn.c. co~e. sec. 1-15~1 et seq as ame~d~d; is turthsr ainen~ej bv addinq ~o the end eof t he fol.lowing PUBLIC POLICY "Sec. 201. Generally the public colicy of the Oistrict of Colombia is t ha a ll persons ar m i led to full an d complete informa~ion r~gardinq the af fairs of qoverrunent and the official ac":s of tllos~ who eprescn~ t~e!'I as public officials and employ~es To that end rovision~ of this 3744 ».t.triot ot Colc~bia ReC"istar 1 0 DEC SS act shall be construed with the view toward ~xpansion ot public access and th~ 111inimi:tat:ion of coses and tisie delays to persons r'!qtlestinq infor111ation IGHT 0.P' ACCESS TO PtJBLZC RECOROS; P.LLO~A.SL COSTS Tl:ME LIMITS •see. 202 amp Any person has a right ~o inspect,and at hi s or h~r discrl!tion. to copy any putlic record ot the Mayor or an aqency, exc~pt as oth'!rwisa expressly provided by section 204 of tllis title, in aeeo~dar.ce with reasonable rules that shall bf issued by the Mayor or an acrency af~er notice and comment. concE.rninq the time an: plac: ot access b) The ~ayor or an agency 11\ay establish anr! collect fees not to exceed th~ actual cost of s~a:c.binq for or ~akinq copies of records. bu~ in no instance shall the total fee for searching exc~ed 10 dollars for each requ~st or purpo~es of this subsection "request ans a sinql~ demand for any number of doc'.llnents mad~ at one t~~e to an individual aqency. DocUJr1ents may _be furr.is~t without charqe or t a reduc cha=qe where th~ Maro or age!ley determ.ln~s that ~aiver or rerluction of the f~e is in the public interest ~ecause furnishinq the inf~rmation can be 3745 l 0 DEC ml consider~ as priaarily benefid.nq th qeneral public. Notwithetandinq the foreqoinq, fe~s shall no~ be c:harqed for e~a•in~tion and reviPw by the Mayor or an aqencyt to detoermin9 if such docum~nts are subiect to disclosure c} Th~ Mayor or an "ag~cy, upon request r~asonably des~ribinq any pu.blic record. shall within 10 days (except Saturday Sundays, an~ legal public holidays) of th r@Ceipt of any sueh request eith~r make 4:h~ requeste~ public record accessibl~ or notify the person making suoh request of its determination not to make th~ reques public record or any part thereof a ccessible and the reasons therefor d l .I.n unas ual cir i.nstances, th~ tim~ limit prescribed in subsection (c of this section May be ~xtended by vritt~n notice to the person making such request setting forth th~ reasons for ~Jtt~nsion dnd expected date for detenninat.i.on. Such exte~ion shall not exceed lC ~ays (except Saturd~ys, sundays and l~gal ~ublic holidays For pur gt;oses of this subse~ion, and only to ~he e~ent necessary for proc:essinq of th~ par:icular requ~st unusual circums~ances• are limited to: 3746 t 0 DEC 1976 l) the need to search for. collect. and appropriat ly examin~ a voluminous aP1ount of separa e and distinct r~cords which are dt"tl\ande~ in a sinqle request or 2 he need for consultation. whic~ shall t conducte1 with all practicable spe~d. with •nother a9ency having substantial interest in the deterr1ination of th~ r~quest o~ among two or mer~ components ot the aqency havino substan~al SlJbje~­ JllAtt er int~rest th~~ein te) Any !ailure on the part of th~ Mayor or an ~qenc:y to comply with a request un~er su.bsec~ion of this s~ction within the time provisions of subs~ctions (c) and {d) of th.is s~ction shall be deeme~ a denial of ~he requ~st. and the person makinq such re-quest shall b9 de@med to ~ave exhausted his adtrli.nist:ative remedies with respect to such request, unless such person choosP-s to p~tition ~he Mayor pursuan~ to section 207 o! this tit.le to reviev the d~med denial of th~ request. 3747 1 0 DEC 4S76 "L!TI'ZRS O~ DENIJ\L "Sec. 203 a) Denial by t.~e Mayor or an aqency of r@qUeSt for any public record shall contain at least th~ followinq l) the sp~cific reasons for the nial. inclu~ing citations to th articular exemption(s) un;er section 20G of this titl~ r~li~d on as authority for t denial 2) t.~e name(S) of t~e public o!~icial(s) or employee(s) resoonsible !or the decision to deny the r~est; and J} no~ification to t he requP.~te= of any a dmini strative or j udicial =ight ~o ap?eal und~r section 207 of this titl Chi The 1ayo= a nd each a~ency of District of colu~bia S!:all maintain a file o! all lett~:s of denial of requests for public records his file sball b~ made availabl~ to any pe~son on r~ques~ for ~u=?Qs~s of i.nspec-;ion and/or copy i ng. 3748 1str1ot ot Co).1 bio F.c t:;tor 1 0 DEC m8 ~EY.E'1PTIONS •s~c. 200 a} The follovinq matters may b exempt f~o111 disclosur under the provisions of this ti~l l) Trade secrets and C03\~~rcial or financial information obtained from outside the gov~rnment, to th~ extent that di~closure would rasult in substan~ial harm to the comp~titive position of &amp;lt h~ peraon from whocn t inf orina ti on was obtained 2) Information of a p'!rsonal nature where th~ public 1isclosur~ th~reof would consti~ute a clearly unwarran ted invasion of cersonal privacy 3) Invest.i.qa~ory records compiled ~or law enforcement purposes, but only to the exten~ tha e production of such r~ords would 1 l.nterfe=-e wi nforce111~nt {Jroceedi!'las B) de?rive a perso n of a riqht to a fair trial or an i mpartial adjudication Cl constitut~ an unwarrant~d inv~sion of personal privacy tDJ disclose the identity of a confiden~ial sourc~ and in the ca~e of a r~cord comoiled hy a 3749 1 o orr S76 1aw enforcem~nt authority in the course of a criminal inv!!s tiqation or by an aq~ncy conductinq a lawful ru:ional security in t elligenc~ investi &amp;lt 3~ion confidential ir.forma4:.ion furnished only by th2 confidential sour ce E) disclose investiqative techniques and procedur S not qenerally known ou~side the qovernmen t F) endanqe~ the life or physical safety of law ~nforceme personne l ij tnter-aqe ncy or intra-aqen cy morandums or let4:.ers wnich wou l d not be availabl e ry law to a party other t.han a n aqe~cv in li~igaeion wi th the aqency CS) Test qu~stions and answ~rs to be used i n fu~ure license, e~ploym~nt o= academic examinations, trot n~t previousl y a dministered examinations or anSW&amp;lt;!rs to questions the~eon {6 nfor:M ~ion s peci f icall y exe~p~ed fro m disclosur Y sta u~ e (oche r than t h i s s~ction rovidmd that such s tatu t e 1&amp;gt;1str1ot or r r 1 o err. ma A) requir~s that the mat~e.rs be withheld from the public in such a inann~r as to leave no discretion on th~ issue, or w(B) estahlish~s ~articular erit~ria for withholdinq or refers to par~icular typP.s of ~atters to he vithheld an {7) Informa1 ion specifically autho~i:ed by Fe~eral la1i1 unner cri~~ria establish~d by a Pr9siden~ial !xecutive order to be kept s~er~t i~ th~ i.~terest of national defense or foreiqn poliey which iff in fact pr9perly classi~i~ pursuant to such ~x~eutive order b) Any r~asonably seqreqable portion of a public recora shall b~ provided to any p~rson requesting sucb record after deletion of those port:.ions which may te withheld from disclosur~ under sucse~ion (a) of this section e) This see i on doe s not autho~~e vitllholding of infonMtion or limit rlle availability of r~cor1s to ~h~ publicr ~xeept. as sp~cifically stat~ in this section. This section is not au hority to ~ithhold ir.fo~mation from th~ Council of the Dist rict of coluDlbia. This 9 e+-ion shall not 3751 1 0 OE:C 197S operate to permit n.,n-disclosure of i nforma-:i on of which disclosure is authori zed or ll'landa~e1 oy o~~er law RECOROrNG OF FINAL VOT~S #Sec. 205 Each a g ency hav inq mo=e ~han one meaber shall ll'l aintain and make available f o r putlic inspe~ion record of the final votes o f each me~ber in each procee~ing of t°hat aqency Il'fFORMATION WHICH MUST 9£ ~i.A.DE P'JBLIC sec. 2C6. Without limiting th e~ninq ot other s~ctions of this t itle. the followi ng c a:egor ies of informa~io~ aze spEcifical ly ma de public i r. fonnation a} the ndmes alaries i~l and dates o f e mployment of all emp loyees and of!ic~rs o: t e Mayor and a n b) admini s t.rative s~aff manuals ann instructions to staf! that af!~c~ a memce r of e ?Utlic {CJ fin a l opinions. including co~cur~inq and dissenting opinions, as wel l a s o~ders mad~ i n the adjudication o~ cas~s: 3752 J.atrict ot Col i n r is tar 1 0 DF.C 197fi d) those statements of policy a nd interpr~ta tions of policy, aets. and rules which have been adopted by the Mayor or an aCfen ev e) correspond~nce and materia1s r~fErred to therein, by an1 with the Mayor or an aqeney relating to any requlatory, sup£rvis.ory. o r enforc:e"'ent responsibilitie s of th$ aq ency. vh~tetv t he aqe n cy deter!l\ines. or states an opinion upon, or is asked to determine or state. an opinion uPon, the riqbts of ~he District, the public. or any private pa.rty f) infor111ation in or tak~n fro~ any account, voucher, or contra~ dealinq with the r~ceipt or expen~iture of p ut:li c o r o!:her f•Jn1s by publi c bodies; an&amp;lt 9) the 111..i.nu~es of all proceeclinqs of all ·AO.~INIS~TIV~ APP~L.S AND ENFORC£~ENT •sec. 207 a} IUly person denied the ~ight to inspect a putli c record of a public body may petition ~e Mayor to reviPV the pJblic r~cord to determine whetha r it may be withheld from public inspection. Such determination shall be ~ade in wr i~inq wi th a ~t~t~ment of reasons therefor in 3753 ~istriat ot Colu~bia Register 1 I D£C 1178 writinq vithin lO days (excludinq Saturdays. Sundays, and l.eqal holidays) of t."l submission of the petition l) I! the Mayor denies the petition or does not 'll&amp;amp;k~ a determination within the ti~e limits provided in this subs~ction, or if a person is deemed to have exhaosted his or her adlninistrAtive reMedies p-orsuant to subsection (e) of section 202, the person seeking disclosure may institute proc~dinqs for injunetiv~ or declaratory relief in ~he Superior court tor the District of ColUlll.bia 2) If the ~ayor decid s that the public r~ord y not be withheld, hP. shall order the public body to disclose tb~ recor:'l im:nediatel y If the publ).c bo-3y continues to wi~~hold the record the person seexinq disclosure ~ay brinq sui~ in t he Super ior ·court tor the District. of Columbia to enjoin the public body from witbholdinq the record and to compel the production ct t.he request~d r~cor bl In any suit filed under subsec-:ion fa) of this s~ction. the superior Court for the District of Colum.bia may en oin th~ public bo~y f.rom vithholdino records and order the production of any 3754 »iati-iot ot Colu~h Reci~ter 1 0 DEC 1975 records improperly withhel.d from the p~rson seeking disclosure. The burden is on the Mayor or the aqeney to sustain its action. In such case5 the court shall deterllline the matter 2!21 an~ may e~allU.ne the content• of such records in camera to determine vh-.th-.r S'Och records or any part thereof shall be withheld under any o! the ~xemptions set forth in section 20Q of this titll!I c) If a person seeking the right to inspeet or to receive a eopy of a public record prevails in whole or in part in sucb suit, he or she nay be awarded r~asonable attorney fet'!s and oth~r co~s of litigation OVERSIGHT •sec. 2C8. on or before the 30th day of June of each calendar year. the Mayor shall corn.pile and submit to the Council of the Di strict of Columbia a report eoverinq he public-rl!'COrd-disclosure activ ities of each aq~ncy and of Executive Branch a s a whol~ during the preceedinq calendar year. The report shall include l) The number of determinations made by each -aqency not t o comply with requests for records made to 3755 1 e DEC ms such •qency under this tit.le and the reasons for each such determination 2) Th~ number of appeals made by persons under Section 207(a) of this title, the result ot such Ppeals, and the reason for the action U?On each app amp;l ~at results in a denial of information 3 nle names and tit1~s or positions ot each person responsible for the denial of records requ~stec under this title, and ~he number of instances of participation for each such perso G A copy oi the f~ schedule an1 the total ainount of fees collected ty each agency for makin9 records availabl~ under t.'iis ti t.l w(Sl sueh ~ber in!orma~ion as indicates effortS to administer fully this title; and •c6&amp;gt; for t.h~ prio r cal~~dar year a listinq of tne tot.al nulll.ber of cases arisinq unj this title, th• t:ctal numter of cases in which a request was deni~ i n vhol~ or in Fart, the to~al num~er of timfts in vhich each exel!l'ption provid~d under s~ction 20 of this title was cited as a r~ason for denial of a request, 3nd the 3756 iat-riot ot Cc11 l:l P.esistar_ 1 11 ore 91 total amount of fees coll~ted under section 202(b) of this act. such report shall also include' a d~scription of the effortS undertaken by the Mayor to eneouraqe aqency compliance with this title DEFINITION wsec. 209. For purposes of this title, the terms "rulemalting person party order relief Proc~edinq putlic r~eo~d and "adjudication• shall ha'9e the meaninq as provided in section 102 of Titl• I of this Act sec. 3. The Distriet of Columbia Aoministrati~e Procedur~ Act co.c. Cod9. see. l-1501 et seq as amen~ed, is further amended by a) renul"l\berinq seetion 3 2 throuah 12 thereof as sections l~l through lll, respeet-ively b) inserting in t.'1 title headi~q "Title I Adlr\inis~rative Procedure" between section l of such Act and section 101 (as renWTl~er@d } 3757 1 e or c 1979 (c strikinq out "A who.rever i~ appears in ·seetions 101 throuqb 111 (as renumbered) and ins~rtinq in lieu thereof "ti tl d) by ~ddir.q t o the end of section 102 (as renumber of such ~ct the follow1"'1 18) the term •public r~cord• includes all books, papers, maps, photoqraphs, car~s. tapes, recordinas, or other documentary materials reoar1less of physical fo~ or characteristics prepared, owned, used, in the pos!;ession of or retained l:y the Mayo and agencies 19 the term •adjucication me~ns th~ a9ency process, other than rule!!takina, for the formulation, issuance and enforcemer.t of an orrler e) by st~ikin secti on 7" in section 105 (as renumh~r~d) of such Act and inser~in~ in lieu thereof s~ction lt' 6 3758 ll1sti-1ot o! C::il 1:-i Bc~t:;tor 1 0 OEC !178 REPEALER see. Q. Mayor's Order 16-109, dated May 4, 1976. is herel;y re~aled. EFFECTIVE DATE Sec s This act shall &amp;lt;;ake effect pursuant to the provisions of sectio n 602 (c l of t ne District of colulllbia self-Gov~rnmen~ an&amp;lt;l Governmental R•orqanization Act 3759 Docke: for the Bill l l_l_9 Cons it.le red in Council Se pter:l ber 15 15 7 6 First Vote September 15, 197 6 RECORD O r COUNCIL V OTE c u t&amp;lt 6( 9 Tr I v I 11 c ouHC:•L c ec" i I J v. j o couHCtL c e c" ATC 1 HAY H 1 .tt 8 Tt:C I x I l Ii DIXON Ix i I l! S \ li!.f&amp;gt;I C I I I x SOH gt; D. I I I X II iJ~;RDY I I I I I! WILSON I I I I l X x gt gt r I I 1x Ii 0 3SQ~.j Ix I I I II WINTER I x I I I c r I x r 11r J. l x I I I I I I COATES I I x ll Sit~C~TON IX I I I I X-fndic z:t"S Vote A. B Uae.u N. V.-No1 VoDA!J Fin e Vo:e in Cour.cil October 12, 1976 {Secretary of the Council) R CORD OF COUNCIL VO TE C C\J ca e r:Jit l .t. Y£ 1 y a co 1 c 1L E'M S CJ:I r r e N•Y 1 f .v I e ti C~VNCIL. M C Mll l" I I I I I S? AL'LOI::G I x 1 I I x 1n!.Soi I (SecretJ of the Cour.c!I Pres~:1t l :o ~he r ayor Sec~:zry o! n·.e Ccu;icil pproved r.~aycr gt; S i ~naw re) Ois2pprovec a d w1 :hc t 1?yor's Si s~ 2:u:e Secrc:i?ry o f the Council l</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>4a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-301.174"/>
  </section>
</document>
