<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 1-98">
  <num type="law">1-98</num>
  <heading type="short">Water and Sewer Repair and Compensation Act of 1976</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-03-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/1-98.pdf">D.C. Law 1-98</citation>
      <citation type="register">23 DCR 9532b</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 1-98, the “Water and Sewer Repair and Compensation Act of 1976,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 1-319, which was referred to the Committee on Transportation and Environmental Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 12, 1976 and November 22, 1976, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 30, 1976, it was assigned Act No. 1-187 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE March 31, 1977 D.C I.AW 1-98 "Water and Sewer Repair and Compensation Act of 1976 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act {PL 93-198 t.he Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 1-319 on first and second readings October 12, l976, and November 22, 1976, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 30, 1976, t his legislation was assigned Act No. 1-187, published in the January 21, 1977, edition pf the o.c. Reaister, and transmitted to both Hou~es of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c) {l) of the Act The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has pired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. c. Law 1- 98, effective March 29, 1977 Ref.23 ,DCReg.4933,January 21, 1977) STERLING Chairman Council D. C. LAW 1-98 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA March 29, 1977 To provide that the District of Columbia shall be responsible for the repair and maintenance of water service pipes and building sewers connecting lots with water mains and the public sewer and shal.l compensate property owners for such prior repairs under certain circumstances. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Water and Sewer Repair and Compensation Act of 1976 the purpose o.f which is to provide that the District of Columbia shall be responsible for the repair and maintenance of water service pipes and building sewers connecting lots with water mains and the public sewer and shall compensate property owners for such ~rior repairs under certain circumstances. Sec. 2. The Act entitled ~An Act to provide for the drainage of lots in the District of Columbia, approved May 19 1896 D.C Code, secs. 6-401 i s amended by adding the following new section 2 5(a For the purpose of t.l:lis section certain words and terms at"e ~e!i.ned as follows Parking" means tha.t area. ot public space which lies between the property line and the edge o! the actual or plau:ed. sidewalk which is 11ea.rer to such property li.ae, a.s such property l~ae a.nd sidewa.lk a.re ~hown ou the records of the Surve1or of the District o! Columbi 0 Property" means rea.l property Property line" ineus the line beyond which a private property owuer has no lega.l or vested property righ~s in any !routing o.r abutting public spa.ce or street; th.e line ot demarcation between privately owned property and any public space 9r street a.s ma.y be shown on ~he records o! tne Surveyor ot the District ot Columbia. 0 t&amp;gt;ui,:1.ic Spa.ce" mea.ns all the publicly owned properi:y between 1 :i es ou a. street, a..s such proper'ty lines are sb.owu on the records ot the Surveyor of the District of Columbia, and includ~s any roadway, tr~ space, sidewalk, or parking between such property lines St:ree'C" means a. public highway as shown on tbe records ot the Surveyor of the District of Columbia whether designated as a street, alley, ave~ue, freeway oad drive lane, place, boulevard, parkwa.7 circle or by some other term 3 b) The Mayor ot the District ot Columbia is authorized to repair and maintain and, wheJ"e necessary, to renew all water service pipes and buildillg sewers from the water main or the public sewer to the property line o! each lot in the District o Columbia. required to be so con:uected by the .tirst section ot this Act a.t the costs ot such owuer or owners a.nd to pertorm all such repairs, as ~re necessary, to ma.intain or improve any roadway, alley mino~ street, highway or other public space above such repaired ox- renewed wa.tar service pipes or buildiJlg sewers. The .Mayor, where he deems such action necessary, may also pertorm ma.intenaace or repair work on private property in which ca.se the eost, includ.1.ng overhea.d expense, sha.11 be paid by the property owner The cost ot any repair or ma.intena.nce work on water ·s&amp;lt;ftrvi.ce pipes or buil.ding sewers beyond the property l i ne 1 !rem the house or structure, made necessary by the negligence or through the ~ction of a property owner or teaant as reasonably determl.ned by the Mayor, shall be charged to the property owner c) The Mayor is !urtb.er authorized and directed to compensate property owners tor any and ail ex;ienses incurred at the direction of the District of Col umbi a for t he direct repair of water ser:ice pipes or building se~ers within the past three 3) years !rom the enactment ot this sec t i on 4- p r o v 1 de d that such repairs at the time o! their performances have met the requirem~ats ot subsection (b o! this section. Compe.a.sation shall- be in ~he !or.n o! pa.yment or tlle remo.val. ot a. lien or assessment again31: such property by the District ot Columbia only to owners who establish uuder the· requirements of subsection (e) of thUI section proof ot actual payment o! repairs under a permit issued by the District o! Columbia. All rights to compensation under the terms of this subsec-eioa shall termiliate two 2 yea.rs !rom the enactment o! this section d) All IU"iOr year compensation pa.ymen-es authorized b y subsect:ioa c o! this s~tion a.J:id all work required. t o be done in the repair, r:la.intena..nce or renewal o! water servi ce pipes a.ad builciing sewers as authorized under subsect i on {b o! tb.is section including surface repair work. not rlthi.n the right-of-way of streets or alleys shall be paid or trom water and sewer rate revenue appropri ated to the Di strict ot Columbia, e::tcept' that all 'surface re-pair work to be o~;ue upon public space withia. the roadway, t~ee space or actual sidewalk right-of-way ot any street shall be pai d o r out of highway revenues appropriated t o t he Dist r i ct a! Columbia e Betore compensation is gr~nted the Yayor sha ll deten:line whether the reapir made under a permi t issued by the District a Columbia would have been aut horized uoder 5 subsection b) ot this· section, noting such other pertinent findings o act as he deems necessary I! the Mayor determines that the repair work would have been eligible under subsection (b of this section had it been ill e!!ect llt the time o! the rep~ir, he shall compen.a.ate any person, who n.s the property owner a.t the time the repairs were made or the cost o UCh repairs provided such owner ca.n establish proof ot payment tor the cost o! the repairs to the reasonable satisfaction o! the Mayor up to the !ull va.lue thereot !or each separate occurrence Any person who 'by means o:t false statement or impersonation, or by other !ra.udulent device obtains. or attempts to obtain or a.ny person who knortngly aids or abel:s suo!i person in abtailling or attempting to obtain (1) any a.ward or payment of compeasa.t1on under the provisions at this section to which he is not entitled 2) a large~ a.mou.n.t or greater reliet ill compensatioa than that to which ~e is entitled, shall be guilt7 ot a misdemeanoT and, shall be sentenced to pay a tine o! not more than $500 00 or imprisoned not to exceed one year, or both. Prosecutions under the provisions ot this subsection shall be in the name of the District ot Columbia by tQe Ot!ice of the Corporation Counsel 6 g) The Mayor is .further a.utnorized to prescribe rules and regula.tion.s governing the maintenance a.nd repair o! such water service pipes a.nd building sewers. by the District ot Columbi~ a.nd the compensation of property owners by the District o~ Columbia or eli~ible prior 1ea.r repairs ot n.ter service pipes, bu1ld1nii :sewers a.ud th·e roadway above such water service pipes and sewers h f any section subsection, or provision ot tlli s a.ct is held to be uncons~itutioua.l or i nvalid, such Wlcoustitution.ality or invalidity shall not a..t.fect the remaining sections, subsections, or provisions of this a.ct See. 3. To the exten~ th~t .the pro~isions of this aet a.re inconsistent wit h the provisions of a.ny other Act or regulation the provisions o! this act shall be deemed. to supersede the provisions of such laws See 4. This a.ct sball take e!tec t at the end o! the 30 day period provided t or Congressional revi ew o t acts of the Council iJl se~ion 602 c of the District of Columbia Sel Government and Government al Reorgani zation Act. r 1-319 Oodcet fer the am Considered in Council October 12, i97S First Vote October 12 197&amp;amp; RECORD OF COUNC.11 Al'C AT 11 OUHC:llo c u TTJ'a!R x OnroN ~tlOtu D. x HARDY Uim.Y X I HOBSON' CL\aKE x MJORE J. COATES x SH.i\CXI ETON iMic amp Vm. A. B Novembe 22 16 Final Vote in Council RECORD OF COUllllQI. aocw•C1t UC I HAY H.Y i CQUl'OQf t::CS.c t ~I DIX:c~ WORE, c. I x I llUDY x I .HOBSON x ~RE, J. CC.\:r!S x ~Otl COUNCIL VOTE 4TIC ¢0uf'tc:u c c c x SPAOU&amp;gt;Th"C x x qn.soN x x· WIN!ER x x x AJIHiit 1 V-N"aa Vedilg Secraiary of the Councill C:OUNC l t OTE HAl c:4t,IHCH, WCM•Clt •1'C x SPAOIJJI!?C I x x wnsow x x llINTER x x x I x-tiaidla&amp;amp Vo&amp;amp;Jt A. 3 U N. V-'foi Voti=q OEt 1. 6 mG Pn!senU!d la th&amp;amp; Mayor {Secmary of ltle Council Sectewy of the Council} I I f v. 1 i I I I I I I Mayor's Action I I j lt[~.1 c0 /{(6 tt9tC 7SiE 3·0 arc 'S7S Approved Cisapproved En.ac2d without Mayor Signarure Mavct's Signan.are of the Councill</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
