<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 21-17">
  <num type="bill">21-100</num>
  <num type="act">21-17</num>
  <heading type="short">Health Benefit Exchange Authority Financial Sustainability Emergency Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Health Benefit Exchange Authority Establishment Act of 2011 to provide for the financial sustainability of the Health Benefit Exchange Authority by adopting an annual broad- based assessment of all health insurance carriers that will support its annual budget.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-03-03</introduced>
    <effective>2015-03-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/33469/Signed_Act/B21-0100-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105122">D.C. Act 21-17</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 3853</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0100">
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-03-26</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Health Benefit Exchange Authority Financial Sustainability Emergency Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Health Benefit Exchange Authority Establishment Act of 2011, effective March 2, 2012 (D.C. Law 19-94; D.C. Official Code § 31-3171.01 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 31-3171.01) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (3A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(3A)</num>
            <text>"Direct gross receipts" means all policy and membership fees and net premium receipts or consideration received in a calendar year on all health insurance carrier risks originating in or from the District of Columbia.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (8C) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(8C)</num>
            <text>"Net premium receipts or consideration received" means gross premiums or consideration received less the sum of premiums received for reinsurance assumed and premiums or consideration returned on policies or contracts canceled or not taken.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 4 (D.C. Official Code § 31-3171.03) is amended by adding a new subsection (f) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Authority shall annually assess, through a "Notice of Assessment,"  each health carrier doing business in the District with direct gross receipts of $50,000 or greater in the preceding calendar year an amount based on a percentage of its direct gross receipts for the preceding calendar year.  These assessments shall be deposited in the Fund.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The Authority shall adjust the assessment rate in each assessable year. The amount assessed shall not exceed reasonable projections regarding the amount necessary to support the operations of the Authority.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Each health carrier shall pay to the Authority the amount stated in the Notice of Assessment within 30 business days after receipt of the Notice of Assessment.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Any failure to pay the assessment in accordance with paragraph (3) of this subsection shall subject the health carrier to section 5 of the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-40; D.C. Official Code § 31-1204).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor, (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
