<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 21-28">
  <num type="bill">21-89</num>
  <num type="act">21-28</num>
  <heading type="short">Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, the Animal Control Act of 1979 to clarify that an educational institution is permitted to have animals for educational and instructional purposes.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-03-02</introduced>
    <effective>2015-03-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/33448/B21-0089-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 21-28</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 4529</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B21-0089">
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-03-27</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 9(h) of the Animal Control Act of 1979, effective October 18, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-30; D.C. Official Code ยง 8-1808(h)), is amended by adding a new paragraph (6) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to educational institutions that possess animals for educational and instructional purposes and that otherwise comply with humane, sanitary, and safe treatment requirements, as set forth in section 502 of the Animal Protection Amendment Act of 2008, effective December 5, 2008 (D. C. Law 17-281; D.C. Official Code ยง 8-1851.02).</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
