<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 21-32">
  <num type="bill">21-98</num>
  <num type="act">21-32</num>
  <heading type="short">Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation Certificate of Need Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996 to exempt the Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation from the certificate of need requirements for a period of one year for the establishment of an ambulatory health care clinic in Ward 8, provided that it establishes 2 mobile health clinics to operate in Wards 7 and 8.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-03-03</introduced>
    <effective>2015-03-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/33457/Signed_Act/B21-0098-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105087">D.C. Act 21-32</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 4538</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0098">
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-03-27</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation Certificate of Need Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 8(b) of the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-191; D.C. Official Code ยง 44-407(b)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (12) is amended by striking the phrase "service; and" and inserting the phrase "service;" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (13) is amended by striking the phrase "Hospital." and inserting the phrase "Hospital; and" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (14) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(14)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Operation by the Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation of an ambulatory care clinic located in Ward 8; provided, that the Not-for-Profit Hospital Corporation also establishes 2 mobile health clinics to operate in Wards 7 and 8 within 180 days after the effective date of the Not-For-Profit Hospital Corporation Certificate of Need Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, effective January 6, 2015 (D.C. Act 20-563; 62 DCR 491).</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The mobile health clinics established pursuant subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall also be exempt from the certificate of need review.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(C)</num>
            <text>The exemptions provided in this paragraph shall expire one calendar year after the effective date of the Not-For-Profit Hospital Corporation Certificate of Need Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, effective January 6, 2015 (D.C. Act 20-563; 62 DCR 491).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor, (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council of the District of Columbia to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
