<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 21-45">
  <num type="bill">21-90</num>
  <num type="act">21-45</num>
  <heading type="short">Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments Tax Abatement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, section 47-4658 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify the real property tax abatement for Lot 808 in Square 5041 and Lot 811 in Square 5056.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2015-03-02</introduced>
    <effective>2015-03-31</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/33449/Signed_Act/B21-0090-SignedAct.pdf?Id=105216">D.C. Act 21-45</citation>
      <citation type="register">62 DCR 4568</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B21-0090">
      <vote date="2015-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2015-03-31</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments Tax Abatement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 47-4658 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The heading is amended by striking the phrase "Parkside Parcel E and J Mixed-Income Apartments;".</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the real property described as Lot 808 in Square 5041 and Lot 811 in Square 5056 shall be allowed an annual real property tax abatement equal to the amount of the real property taxes assessed and imposed by Chapter 8 of this title of up to a total maximum amount for each lot of $300,000 per year for 10 property tax years commencing for Lot 808 and Lot 811 at the beginning of the first month following the date that specific lot is issued a final certificate of occupancy ("commencement date") and ending for each lot at the end of the 10th full real property tax year following the lot's commencement date.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsections (c) and (d) are amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and provided that the final certificate of occupancy is issued on or before September 20, 2018, upon the issuance of a final certificate for Lot 808 or Lot 811, any fees or deposits charged to and paid by the owner of that specific lot for the development of Lot 808 or Lot 811, including private space or building permit fees or public space permit fees ("related fees"), shall be refunded and any prospective related fees forgiven.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>The tax abatements and fees and deposits exemptions provided pursuant to this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or assistance from any other source applicable to the development of Lot 808 or Lot 811.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of March 18, 2015.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
