<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-140">
  <num type="law">12-140</num>
  <heading type="short">Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 Financial Reporting Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1998-07-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-140.pdf">D.C. Law 12-140</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 2978</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0262">
      <narrative>Law 12-140, the “Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 Financial Reporting Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-262, which was referred to Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 3, 1998, and April 7, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 22, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-342 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for the review. D.C. Law 12-140 became effective on July 24, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag e 062 328 944 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-140 "Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 Financial Reporting Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-262 on first and second readings, March 3, 1998 and April 7, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 22, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-342 and published in the May 15, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 2978) and transmitted to Congress on May 19, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-140, effective July 24, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: May June July 19,20,21,22 1,2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 14,15,16,17,20,21,22,23 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12’342 1N THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 23, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 to require Advisory Neighborhood Commissions to file quarterly financial reports approved by the Auditor within 30 days of the end of each quarter, to require the auditor to approve of the report within 7 days of its filing, and to require funds reserved for a Commission to return to the General Fund on the last day of the fiscal year if the Commission failed to file a quarterly report approved by the auditor. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 Financial Reporting Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 16(j) of the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975, effective March 26, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-58; D.C. Code § 1-264(j is amended to read as follows j)(1) The treasurer of a Commission shall prepare a quarterly financial report on a form provided by the Auditor. The financial report shall be presented to the Commission for its consideration at a public meeting of the Commission within 30 days of the end of the quarter. A copy of the approved financial report, signed by the Chairman, the secretary, and the treasurer, shall be filed, along with a record of the vote adopting the report, with the District of Columbia Auditor within 7 days of approval. A financial report shall be available for public inspection during the normal office hours of the Commission 2) No quarterly allotment shall be forwarded to a Commission until all reports of financial activity for the quarters preceding the immediate previous quarter are approved by the Auditor 3) If, on the last day of the fiscal year, a Commission has not received a quarterly allotment because it failed to file a quarterly report approved by the Auditor, the Commission shall forfeit the unclaimed allotment or allotments and the funds shall return to the District’s General Fund. This subsection shall take effect beginning in fiscal year 1999 Section 1-264 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Committee report on Bill 12-262 as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 913; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: April 23, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSEN f COUNCIL PERIOD I’~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COI’NCIL VOTE Docket No. B12-262 A~O~D_T_F EIRST READING, 3-3-98 APPROVED ROLL CALL VOTE Result Co em~¢~ [A ] s Chmn. Cropp Allen Am brose Brazil Catania ounedrnernber Chavous E~ans Jan’is Mason Patterson Councilmembrr Sch~rartz Smith. Jr. Thomas. Sr. I v i L IS’~retary to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORI)ED VOTE ON REQt’ESX ~B hsen ER I IF I 11o% RE(ORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 4-7-98 APPROVED ~BSENT ALL PRESENT [ ] ROLL CALl. VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Calania ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR A) e Na) N ouncllmemher Cha~ou~ E~ans .Jar i~ Mason Patterson tB h~cnl N B (ER I IF I{ t I I0% R~(ORI) the (ouncll Councilmember Sch~artz Smith. Jr. Thomas. St A~,e j Na~ NV I~ I VOI(’E VOTE RI’TORI)ED VOFE ON REQI:EST AB~ENF I I ROLl. CALl. VOTE rcsul ’ouncilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Councilmembrr Chavous Evans Jan’is Mason Patterson X Indicales ole A B ’~ b~e n t AB Counci|membtr Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, Sr. N’¢ AB NV Present not otin~o CERTIFI(ATION RECORD</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
