<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-126">
  <num type="law">12-126</num>
  <heading type="short">Department of Corrections Criminal Background Investigation Authorization Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-06-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-126.pdf">D.C. Law 12-126</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 1232</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0029">
      <narrative>Law 12-126, the “Department of Corrections Criminal Background Investigation Authorization Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-029, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1997, and January 6, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 26, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-260 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-126 became effective on June 19, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S)’ kwiktag 089 697 626 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-126 "Department of Corrections Criminal Background Investigation Authorization Act of 1998 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-29, on first and second readings, December 4, 1997 and January 6, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 26, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-260 and published in the March 6, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 1232) and transmitted to Congress on February 27, 1998 for a 60-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 60-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-126, effective June 19, 1998. S~S @~ LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 60-day Congressional Review Period: 27 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26, 27,30,31 1,21,22,23,24,27,28,29,30 1,4,5,6,7,8,11,12,13,14,15,18,19,20,21,22 1,2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,16,17,18 ENROLLED ORIGINAL DoCo AN ACT ACT 12-260 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 26, 1998 To authorize the Director of the Department of Corrections to conduct criminal background investigations on all employees, including non-probationary employees, of the Department of Corrections. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Corrections Criminal Background Investigation Authorization Act of 1998 See. 2. Authorization of investigation a) The Director of the Department of Corrections Director shall conduct, on a biennial basis, National Crime Information Center NCIC criminal background investigations on all Department employees including non-probationary employees b) At the Director’s discretion, the Director also may conduct NCIC investigations at unspecified times. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Committee Report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. this act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in. section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule New Section 24-448.11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in theDistrict of Columbi egister. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: January 26, 1998 2 I~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLtMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OE OEFIC,AL COt:NC,L ,’OT~ B12--29 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 12-4-97 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV I AB Councilmember y¢ Ns NV AB Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Pa[lerson Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous I]~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I, CouncilmcmberSchwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. [ ER I It I HO% RECORD arv tO the (’oun¢fl ADOPTED FINAL READING, 1-6-98 APPROVEDI]~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST .ABSENT ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Resul! Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB (’ouncdmember t Sa N gB (’ouncilmember Aye Na~ NV AB I Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson B-.A h,~cnt Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV-Present not ruling (ERIIF I 110% RI’.(ORD ¢~etar5 to the ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR A(71"ION &amp;amp; DATE ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ARSENT I I ROLL ALL VOTE Result (’ouncilmember Chron. Cropp Chavoas Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson A~¢ Nay NV AB Couucilmember t~e %ay NV AB (’ouncilmember Aye Na) NV AB X Indicates Vote AB Absent Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secreta~’ to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To exempt, on an emergency basis, from the requirements of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 privatization initiatives of the Department of Corrections to contract-out food, medical, inmate finance, and canteen services, and time and attendance responsibilities, and to contract for the sale and lease-back of the Correctional Treatment Facility. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Corrections Privatization Facilitation Emergency Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Mayor’s contracting authority. Notwithstanding the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-I 181 et seq and any regulations adopted pursuant to that act, the Mayor may contract for the sale and lease-back of the Department of Corrections Correctional Treatment Facility and the provision of services with respect to food, medical, inmate finance, and canteen services, and the performance of time and attendance responsibilities that are currently provided by employees of the Department of Corrections. Sec. 3. Policy, criteria, and standards for privatizing government services in the Department of Corrections a) In contracting out (including a lease or other agreement) for the services referred to in section 2, the Mayor shall use the most competitive process practicable under the circumstances to facilitate the expeditious completion of these initiatives b) In contracting out (including a lease or other agreement or any contracting policies or procedures relating to such contracts) for the services referred to in section 2, the Mayor may make a written determination and findings that the contract will meet the following criteria: Note, Section 1-1181.5b Note, Section 1-1181.5b ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) A cost savings to the District government or improved quality or quantity of service at the same or lower cost will result for the duration of the contract, including all options 2) Increased economic development for the District in terms of entrepreneurial opportunities for District businesses or employment opportunities for District residents may result 3) Strengthening of one or more existing District businesses, creation of one or more new businesses in the District, or relocation of one or more businesses from outside to inside the District may result 4) Performance criteria for the services to be contracted-out can be specified with reasonable exactness 5) Cost, efficiency of operation, and quality and quantity of the service to be contracted-out can be measured with reasonable accuracy; and (6) For a service which is essential to the health or safety of District residents, contracting-out the service will not adversely affect the recipients c) The Mayor may base any determination and findings pursuant to subsection (b) of this section on a written cost/benefit analysis prepared by the Department of Corrections. At a minimum, these analyses shall include, for such service, comparison of the following 1) Current total cost to the District government versus projected total cost to the District government after the contracting-out, if quality and quantity of service remain substantially the same; and (2) Current quality and quantity versus projected quality and quantity of service after the contracting-out, if current total cost to the District government remains substantially the same d) The Mayor may issue rules necessary to implement the provisions of this act, including rules that address the following 1) Cost factors to be considered in evaluating the total cost to the District government of a service currently provided by the government if the service continues to be projected by the government, such as the costs of equipment, facilities, maintenance, personnel, and utilities 2) Cost factors to be considered in evaluating the total cost to the District government if a service currently provided by the government is contracted-out, such as the additional cost of improving any capital assets to be transferred to a contractor, the additional cost of any one-time severance of District government employees, the additional cost of contract administration, the value of any improvement to District government programs resulting from privatized programs which serve the District government, any income to the District government from the lease or sale of District government assets resulting from contracting-out a service and any tax revenue to the District based on income earned by a ENROLLED ORIGINAL contractor who performs a service that is contracted-out; and (3) Methods to be used to identify and measure quality and quantity of service so that accurate cost comparisons can be made between District government and private sector performance e) When the Mayor contracts-out a service referred to in section 2, the Mayor may make reasonable efforts to assist affected District government employees and to promote employment opportunities for District residents based on the action to contract-out. If not already required by a collective bargaining agreement, the Mayor may make reasonable efforts to 1) Consult with union representatives concerning affected District government employees 2) Provide alternative employment in the District government to affected District employees who are qualified; and (3) Encourage the contractor performing the service that is contracted-out to make bona fide offers of employment to all other qualified District residents before extending offers to qualified nonresidents f) Any solicitation for proposed contracts issued pursuant to this act may include information concerning the procedure by which current District government employees may exercise the right to bid on the contracts g) The Director of the Department of Corrections shall publish a Notice of Solicitation in the District of Columbia Register and 2 newspapers of general circulation at least 30 days prior to the letting of any contract for good or services under this act. Sec. 4. Council review of contracts a) Pursuant to section 451 (b) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 803, D.C. Code § 1- 1130(b the Mayor shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia for approval any proposal to contract-out services covered by this act involving expenditures in excess of $1,000,000 during a 12-month period b) Nothing in this act shall be construed to prevent the Mayor from relying upon the procedures of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 as a guide in determining how best to promote competition and greater efficiencies in contracting out for the services specified in section 2. Sec. 5. Repealer. The Department of Corrections Procurement and Privatization Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 1996, effective February 23, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-220; 43 DCR 1176 is repealed. Note, Section 1-1181.5b 3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement a) The Department of Corrections Department projects a 2-year cost savings of $14,989,874, by streamlining the contracting procedures for food services, medical services, inmate finance and canteen services, the automated time-keeping system, and the sale and lease- back of the Correctional Treatment Facility. The costs savings are as follows 1) For food services, the Department estimates a savings of $819,038, annually, for in-house costs when privatized. Exemption from the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181 et seq will allow this privatization initiative to be executed in 1 year or less, and the Department would have an estimated cost savings of $1,638,076 2) For the privatization of inmate finance and canteen services, the Department will save $928,163, annually, in in-house costs. The Department will save an estimated $1,856,326 if these services are performed within 1 year or less 3) For the automated time-keeping system, the Department will save an estimated $1,367,800, annually, if privatized. Passage of this act will allow the privatization initiative to be executed in 1 year or less, and the Department would have an estimated cost savings of $2,512,600 4) According to the preliminary cost data for the Correctional Treatment Facility, the Department will save an estimated $491,436, annually, in in-house costs when privatized. This estimate assumes the sale of the facility of $64,634,000 (which has been adjusted for estimated renovation costs of $466,000) to a private vendor. Passage of this act will allow the privatization initiative to be executed in 1 year or less, and the Department would. have an estimated cost savings of $982,872 b) Additional costs, if any, to implement this act shall be borne by the Department and any contracting parties. Sec. 7. Applicability. This act shall apply as of March 3, 1997. Sec. 8. Effective date. This act shall take effect upon its enactment (approval by the Mayor, or in the event of veto by the Mayor, override of the veto by the Council, and approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Columbia in section ~12(a) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganiz ode § 1-229(a Council of the District of Columbiaf Mayor District of Columbia 5 I I IT~M ON CONSENT O rNDaR I~ ACTION A~ I~ vm~ vo co~e~ v~ on ~ou~ A~ COL~C~L OF DISTIUCT OF COLUMBI~ COUNCIL PgglOD TWgLV[ RgCORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL ADOPTED FINAL READING, 2-2-97 APPROVED CHAIRMAN CLARKE I I ROlL CALL VOTE. Rmlt Com~itmember Aye Nay NV All Conncilmember Chron. Clarke Evans Allen Jnrvis Brazil Mason Chsvous Patterson Cr~pp Schwartz Aye Na NV AB Co~’i| memltluc’r Aye Nat) NX" AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. X |pdirJt~ VOte ~¢gl~l’y IO Ibe Couscil [ J ~M ON CON5~ CALENDAR AB Abaent NV Prea~ult aol ~oliag cErtIEIcAtIOn REcOkD A p ’ G 7 I I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REOUE.~T ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE -Reaul! EvansChron. Clarke Alien Brazil Chavous Cropp Jarvis Mason Patterson Smith, Jr. Thoma mr Aye Nay NV AB (LRIlH I I1)’ KI( ORh ITEM ON CONSEN"T CALENDAR AC’I’ION &amp;amp; DATE I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REOUEST ABSENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE Re~ull Councilnlembcr Aye Chron. Clarke Alien Brazil Chavous Cropp ladieale vole Jar’is Mason PatIerson Schwartz AB ounci|member Aye Nay NV AP Thomas, Sr. NV Prt~eat ~ol VotIng CERTIFI( AllO% RECORD ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT 12-29 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MARCH 18, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1997 Supp. To exempt, on an emergency basis, from the requirements of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 privatization initiatives of the Department of Corrections to contract-out food, medical, inmate finance, and canteen services, and time and attendance responsibilities, and to contract for the sale and lease-back of the Correctional Treatment Facility. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Corrections Privatization Facilitation Emergency Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Mayor’s contracting authority. Notwithstanding the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181 et seq and any regulations adopted pursuant to that act, the Mayor may contract for the sale and lease-back of the Department of Corrections Correctional Treatment Facility and the provision of services with respect to food, medical, inmate finance, and canteen services, and the performance of time and attendance responsibilities that are currently provided by employees of the Department of Corrections. Sec. 3. Policy, criteria, and standards for privatizing government services in the Department of Corrections a) In contracting out (including a lease or other agreement) for the services referred to in section 2, the Mayor shall use the most competitive process practicable under the circumstances to facilitate the expeditious completion of these initiatives b) In contracting out (including a lease or other agreement or any contracting policies or procedures relating to such contracts) for the services referred to in section 2, the Mayor may make a written determination and findings that the contract will meet the following criteria: Note, Section 1-1181.5b Note, Section 1-1181.5b ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) A cost savings to the District government or improved quality or quantity of service at the same or lower cost will result for the duration of the contract, including all options 2) Increased economic development for the District in terms of entrepreneurial opportunities for District businesses or employment opportunities for District residents may result 3) Strengthening of one or more existing District businesses, creation of one or more new businesses in the District, or relocation of one or more businesses from outside to inside the District may result 4) Performance criteria for the services to be contracted-out can be specified with reasonable exactness 5) Cost, efficiency of operation, and quality and quantity of the service to be contracted-out can be measured with reasonable accuracy; and (6) For a service which is essential to the health or safety of District residents, contracting-out the service will not adversely affect the recipients c) The Mayor may base any determination and findings pursuant to subsection (b) of this section on a written cost/benefit analysis prepared by the Department of Corrections. At a minimum, these analyses shall include, for such service, comparison of the following 1) Current total cost to the District government versus projected total cost to the District government after the contracting-out, if quality and quantity of service remain substantially the same; and (2) Current quality and quantity versus projected quality and quantity of service after the contracting-out, if current total cost to the District government remains substantially the same d) The Mayor may issue rules necessary to implement the provisions of this act, including rules that address the following 1) Cost factors to be considered in evaluating the total cost to the District government of a service currently provided by the government if the service continues to be provided by the government, such as the costs of equipment, facilities, maintenance, personnel, and utilities 2) Cost factors to be considered in evaluating the total cost to the District government if a service currently provided by the government is contracted-out, such as the additional cost of improving any capital assets to be transferred to a contractor, the additional cost of any one-time severance of District government employees, the additional cost of contract administration, the value of any improvement to District government programs resulting from privatized programs which serve the District government, any income to the District government from the lease or sale of District government assets resulting from contracting-out a service and any tax revenue to the District based on income earned by a 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL contractor who performs a service that is contracted-out; and (3) Methods to be used to identify and measure quality and quantity of service so that accurate cost comparisons can be made between District government and private sector performance e) When the Mayor contracts-out a service referred to in section 2, the Mayor may make reasonable efforts to assist affected District government employees and to promote employment opportunities for District residents based on the action to contract-out. If not already required by a collective bargaining agreement, the Mayor may make reasonable efforts to 1) Consult with union representatives concerning affected District government employees 2) Provide alternative employment in the District government to affected District employees who are qualified; and (3) Encourage the contractor performing the service that is contracted-out to make bona fide offers of employment to all other qualified District residents before extending offers to qualified nonresidents f) Any solicitation for proposed contracts issued pursuant to this act may include information concerning the procedure by which current District government employees may exercise the right to bid on the contracts g) The Director of the Department of Corrections shall publish a Notice of Solicitation in the District of Columbia Register and 2 newspapers of general circulation at least 30 days prior to the letting of any contract for good or services under this act. Sec. 4. Council review of contracts a) Pursuant to section 451 (b) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 803, D.C. Code §1- 1130(b the Mayor shall submit to the Council of the District of Columbia for approval any proposal to contract-out services covered by this act involving expenditures in excess of $1,000,000 during a 12-month period b) Nothing in this act shall be construed to prevent the Mayor from relying upon the procedures of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 as a guide in determining how best to promote competition and greater efficiencies in contracting out for the services specified in section 2. Sec. 5. Repealer. The Department of Corrections Procurement and Privatization Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 1996, effective February 23, 1996 (D.C. Act 11-220; 43 DCR 1176 is repealed. Note, Section 1-1181.5b ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement a) The Department of Corrections Department projects a 2-year cost savings of $14,989,874, by streamlining the contracting procedures for food services, medical services, inmate finance and canteen services, the automated time-keeping system, and the sale and lease- back of the Correctional Treatment Facility. The costs savings are as follows 1) For food services, the Department estimates a savings of $819,038, annually, for in-house costs when privatized. Exemption from the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181 et seq will allow this privatization initiative to be executed in 1 year or less, and the Department would have an estimated cost savings of $1,638,076 2) For the privatization of inmate finance and canteen services, the Department will save $928,163, annually, in in-house costs. The Department will save an estimated $1,856,326 if these services are performed within 1 year or less 3) For the automated time-keeping system, the Department will save an estimated $1,367,800, annually, ifprivatized. Passage of this act will allow the privatization initiative to be executed in 1 year or less, and the Department would have an estimated cost savings of $2,512,600 4) According to the preliminary cost data for the Correctional Treatment Facility, the Department will save an estimated $491,436, annually, in in-house costs when privatized. This estimate assumes the sale of the facility for $64,634,000 (which has been adjusted for estimated renovation costs of $466,000) to a private vendor. Passage of this act will allow the privatization initiative to be executed in 1 year or less, and the Department would have an estimated cost savings of $982,872 b) Additional costs, if any, to implement this act shall be borne by the Department and any contracting parties. Sec. 7. Applicability. This act shall apply as of March 3, 1997. Sec. 8. Effective date. This act shall take effect upon its enactment (approval by the Mayor, or in the event of veto by the Mayor, override of the veto by the Council and approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization oved _Decemh [, 1973 (87 8; D.C..Code~ § 1-229(a airman -Temp-~ePro a~ Co~cil of the Dis~ict of Col~bi District of Columbia APPROVED: February 24, 1997 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF TI~ DISTIUC’T OF COLUMBIA RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL vOTE ADOPTED F I NAL READING, 2-2-97 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REOUF~T ABSENT. APPROVED CHAIRMAN CLARKE [ I ROlL CALL VOTE Remd! Commeilmeml~r Aye Nsy NV AB Chron. Clarke Allen Brazil Chavous Cropp T to he Couoci! [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR { [ ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Coun¢ilmemDer Aye Nay NV AB Coumgilmbgr Aye Nay NV AB Evans Smith, Jr. darwin Thomas, Sr, AI Al~ent Mnson Patterson ~chwartz CERTIFICATION RECORD NV P~t mot Voting VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Clarke Allen Brazil Chavous Cropp X-indicates oo Couoedmem~.r A~ %as N~ Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson ~chwavtz AB Councilmeml~r Aye Nay NV AB Smith~ Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV.Prt~en! nor voting CERII(’I 11(|’~ Ri ORD ~eevetary to the Coont! ITEM O~ CONSE~T CALENDAR ACTIO amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REDDEST ABSEN’T I I ROLL CALL VOTE Rt’soi! Couocilmemb~r Chron. Clarke Allen Brazil Cbavous Cropp Aye Nat NV AB Couordmembcr ] Ate %s AB (o~ocilolember Evans Thomas, Sr. Mason X Indicates Vote AB Abtcn } Aye Nay NV AB NV ot not Voting CERT|FI( ATION RECORD</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-211.41"/>
  </section>
</document>
