<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-138">
  <num type="law">12-138</num>
  <heading type="short">Residency Requirement Reinstatement Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1998-07-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-138.pdf">D.C. Law 12-138</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 2972</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0137">
      <narrative>Law 12-138, the “Residency Requirement Reinstatement Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-137, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 17, 1998, and April 7, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 22, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-340 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-138 became effective on July 24, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 324 884 (5 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12’340 1N THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA APRIL 22, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to require all newly hired District employees in the Career Service, Excepted Service and Educational Service to maintain residency in the District of Columbia, and to allow the Mayor to exempt hard to fill positions. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be known as the "Residency Requirement Reinstatement Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 801 (D.C. Code §1-608.1) is amended by adding a new subsection (e-l) to read as follows e-l) Notwithstanding any provision of the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Code § 1-2501 etseq and subsection (e) of this section, on the effective date of the Residency Requirement Reinstatement Amendment Act of 1998, any person who is hired to fill a position in the Career Service shall become a bona fide resident of the District within 180 days of the effective date of the appointment, and shall maintain District residency for the duration of employment. Failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency, shall result in the forfeiture of the position 2) All applicants shall submit proof of bona fide residency in a manner determined by the Mayor 3) The Mayor shall be authorized to exempt hard to fill positions and positions located in facilities located outside the District of Columbia b) Section 801(A D.C. Code §1-609.1) is amended by adding a new subsection (d-l) to read as follows d-1) Notwithstanding any provision of the Human Rights Act of 1977, effective Section 1-608.1 Note, Section 1-2501 Note, Section 1-609.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Code §1-2501 et seq and subsection (d) of this section, on the effective date of the Residency Requirement Reinstatement Amendment Act of 1998, any person who is hired to fill a position in the Educational Service shall become a bona fide resident of the District within 180 days of the effective date of the appointment and shall maintain District residency for the duration of employment. Failure to become a District resident or to maintain District residency, shall result in the forfeiture of the position 2) All applicants shall submit proof of bona fide residency in a manner determined by the Board of Education and the Board of Trustees of the University of the District of Columbia Boards 3) The Boards shall be authorized to exempt hard to fill positions and positions located in facilities located outside the District of Columbia c) A new section 751 is added to read as follows Sec. 751. Residency Requirement a)(1) Any person hired by a Service created, after the effective date of the Residency Requirement Reinstatement Amendment Act of 1998, shall be a resident of the District of Columbia or shall obtain residency within 180 days of the effective date of appointment and shall maintain residency during the course of their employment with the District of Columbia Government. Failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position to which the person has been appointed 2) The Mayor shall be authorized to exempt hard-to-fill positions b) The provisions of the Human Rights Act of 1997, effective December 13, 1977 (D.C. Law 2-38; D.C. Code § 1-2501 et seq shall not apply to the provisions of this section d) Section 906 (c D.C. Code § 1-610.6(c is repealed. Sec. 3. This act has no fiscal impact. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Note, Section 1-2501 New Subchapter VII-A, Chapter 6, Title 1 New Section 1-607.51 Note, Section 1-2501 Section 1-610.6 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: April 22, 1998 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~.IBIA COUNCIL PERIOD T~’ELVE RECORD OF OI"FICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Dockc,~o. B12-137 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR R-AD.NG, 3-17-98ACTiON&amp;amp;DATE ADOPTED FIRST t APPROVED, AMBROSE EVANS~AND PATTERSON VOTED NOVOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST A.sE,,T CHAVOUS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmembet Chran. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil Catania I A)re Ney N AB [ Councflmemher Chavous Jarvis Mason Patterson Na) N~ AB Councilmernber Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr X Indicates Vole ~B bscnt S’ Present not otin ’ t Council Date 1 1 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR o+,o ADOPTED FINAL READING, 4-7:98 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUES’I ABSENT oL~ C,,LL VOTE-.esu PASSED Councihnember Aye N’a~ N~,r AB (ouncilmemtwr e ’s,a) Chmn. Cropp X Allen X Ambrose X Brazil X Catania Cha’ otis X Evans X Jarsi~ Mason X Patterson Indicates Vote × ~l| hscnl N AB Councilmember Aye Nay NX AB Schwartz X Smith, Jr. X X Thomas, St. X NV-Prescnt not oling (’ER IIH(A lION RE(’ORD I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I i VOI(TE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result (’ouncilmetnber Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania A.~e Na NV .AB [ Counciimemher c Na NS.’ AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB -Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretar to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
