<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-183">
  <num type="law">12-183</num>
  <heading type="short">Adult Education Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-183.pdf">D.C. Law 12-183</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 12-183, the “Adult Education Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-742. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 30, 1998, and September 22, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 1, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-454 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-183 became effective on March 26, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENRO L NT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-183 "Adult Education Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-742, on first and second readings, July 30, 1998 and September 22, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 1, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of"the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-454 and published in the October 16, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 7451) and transmitted to Congress on January 25, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-183, effective March 26, 1999. LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 2,3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C. ACT 12-454 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER I, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend, on an temporary basis, the District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act to designate the University of the District of Columbia as the agency responsible for supervising the public school education program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Adult Education Designation Temporary Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Public Postsecondary Education Reorganization Act, approved October 26, 1974 (88 Stat. 1423; D.C. Code § 31-1501 et. seq is amended by adding a new section 212 to read as follows Sec. 212. Supervision of adult education program a) Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, the University shall be the state agency responsible for supervising adult education in public schools b) The University with the approval of the Trustees, shall submit to the Mayor, the Council, the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority, the Census Commission, and the appropriate congressional committees, a long-term reform plan, as provided in section 2101 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321; D.C. Code § 2853.1 The plan shall include a description of how the University will accomplish the implementation of a comprehensive and effective adult education and literary program c) The University shall apply for federal funds as provided in the Adult Education Act, approved April 28, 1988 (102 Stat. 302; 20 U.S.C. § 1201 etseq d)(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of District law, the University is authorized to charge fees for all adult education courses. The amount to be charged with respect to each adult shall be fixed annually by the University as the amount necessary to cover the expense of instruction, cost of textbooks and school supplies, and other operating costs associated with each course offered, provided that the amount and changes in the amount fixed by this Note, Section 31-1520 ENROLLED ORIGINAL subsection are set by the’University in accordance with section 6 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (88 Star. 1206; D.C. Code § 1- 1506 Following the final adoption of such amount, the University shall transmit a copy to the Mayor and the Council 2) All amounts received by the University pursuant to this section shall be paid to the D.C. Treasurer and accounted for in the General Fund as a separate revenue source allocable to provide authority for the offering of select adult education courses for which fees will be charged 3) Waivers, in whole or in part, of fees for select adult education courses may be granted by the University only to District residents Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The fiscal year 1999 appropriation for the adult education program is $110,000 in local funds and $1,113,775 in federal funds. The transfer of funds from the District of Columbia Public Schools to the University of the District of Columbia has been reflected in the consensus fiscal year 1999 budget and financial plan for the University. For fiscal year 1999, the University of the District of Columbia is to receive $2.64 million in program enhancements, of which $640,000 is allocated for adult education. Sec. 4 a) This ~ct shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, actiofi by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) This act shall expire atter 225 days of its having taken effect. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 1, 1998 I ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COL~UMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D.~etNo. B12-742 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 7-30-98 APPROVED CATANIA, SMITH AND THOMAS [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Coun¢ilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania x. Indicates Vote I Sec~’etary to the Council I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~| ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Conncilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, St r b NV Present not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 9-22-98 ~} VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED MASON ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couu¢ilmembcr Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicat~ Vote ~the Council I I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AB Cooncilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. NV-Present not voting D~tte I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result I Councilmembcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Couacilmeraber Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 OCT 0 2 1998 Dr. Alice Rivlin Chairman District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority One Thomas Circle, N.W Suite 900 Washington, D.C. 20005 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-454 Adult Education Designation Temporary_ Amendment ACt of 1998 Dear Dr. Rivlin: The above named act is hereby transmitted in accordance with the "District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995 Public Law 104-8. To begin the count of the 7-day review by the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority, please acknowledge receipt of this document on the copy attached. Enclosure Cropp Chairman of the Council Receipt Acknowledged: Name PLEASE PRINT Signature l~ate Time I.HU District of Columbia FinancialResponsibility and Management Assistance Authority Wash.ingto~I P3:56 October 7, 1998: Ms. Phyllis Jones Secretary to the Council Coutacil of the District of Columbia One J~dieiary Square Building 441 Fourth Street, NW Suite 716 Washington, D.C. 20001 R_E Act 12 54 ’Adult F~ducation Desifnation ~e_mpora Amgndment Act, 01"1998" Dear Ms~ Jones: This is to advise you that the Authority, having reviewed the above-captioned Act, does not disapprove the Act or have any recommendations lbr modiIications to it. Sincerely yours dr~l~rtg Officer Phone (202) 504..3400 ¯ Fax (202) 504-3431</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
