<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-171">
  <num type="law">12-171</num>
  <heading type="short">American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5 Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-10-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-171.pdf">D.C. Law 12-171</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 5193</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0589">
      <narrative>Law 12-171, the “American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5 Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-589, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 2, 1998, and June 16, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 8, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-414 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-171 became effective on October 16, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 324 473 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-171 "American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5 Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-589, on first and second readings, June 2, 1998 and June 16, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on July 8, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-414, and published in the August 7, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 5193) and transmitted to Congress on July 29, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-171, effective October 16, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: July Sept. Oct. 29,30,31 8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,18,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30 1,2,5,6,7,8,9,13,14,15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-414 IN TIlE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JULY 8, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code to designate real property owned by the American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5, as tax exempt, and to provide equitable real property tax relief for such property from October 1, 1997, until March 31, 1998. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5 Real Property Tax Exemption and Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents to the chapter is amended by adding a new section designation "§ 47-1046. American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5, lot 33 in square 3508 b) A new section 47-1046 is added to read as follows § 47-1046. American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5, lot 33 in square 3508 Certain property located in the District of Columbia described as lot 33 in square 3508 situated at 202 North Capitol Street, N.E, together with improvements thereon and furnishings therein, with equitable and legal title in the name of the American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5, is hereby exempt from all taxation so long as the same is used in carrying on the purposes and activities of the American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5 and is not used for exclusively commercial purposes, subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47- 1009 Sec. 3. The Council of the District of Columbia orders that all real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against the American Legion, James Reese Europe Post No. 5, on real property, known for assessment purposes as lot 033 in square 3508, located at 3508 North Capitol Street, N.E be forgiven, and that any payments already made be refunded. New Section 47-1046 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia P~egister. Council of the District of Columbia ayor District of Columbia APPROVED: Ju]_y 8, 1998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD I~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B! 2- 589 Dorket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 6-2’98 APPROVED CATANIA, CHAVOUS AND THOMAS ABSENT { I ROLLC&amp;amp;LL VOTE Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay [ NV AB Councilmember Aye Na) N’ AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Brazi! Catania x o Indicate.s. Vote [X ITEM ON CbNSENT ~LENDAR [~ A~ION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECO~E~ VOTE O~ ABSENT Mason Patterson AB Absent NV Present not otin~ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 6-16-98 APPROVED CHAVOUS [ ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote t V secF"’°’ ec°u°cil Aye Nay NV AB Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Abscnt CERTIFICATION RECORD Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Conl~ci|lnember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazi| Catania Aye Nay NV.,AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent CER~IEICATION RECORD Aye Nay NV AB Councilmcmbcr Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. NV Present nnt Voting Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
