<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-225">
  <num type="law">12-225</num>
  <heading type="short">REGIONAL AIRPORTS AUTHORITY AMENDMENT ACT OF 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-225.pdf">D.C. Law 12-225</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 485</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0726"/>
    <search-text>EN L ENT(S) kwiktag ¯ 062 323 829 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-543 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER ii, 1998 To amend the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 to provide the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority police officers certain powers now possessed by the Commonwealth of Virginia police, update other Virginia Code references, and to clarify that amended versions of the Virginia Code apply to the Authority’s police. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Regional Airports Authority Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 8(b) of the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985, effective December 3, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-67; 32 DCR 6098 is amended by striking the phrase "Chapter 3 of Title 15.1, Chapter 11 of Title 16.1, Title 18.2, and Title 46.1 of the Code of Virginia" and inserting the phrase "Chapter 17 of Title 15.2, and Chapter 11 of Title 16.1, Title 18.2, Title 19.2, and Title 46.2 of the Code of Virginia as those rifles may be amended from time to time" in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. There shall be no fiscal impact for the implementation of this legislation. This is merely conforming legislation required under the interstate compact between the District and Virginia for the operation of the Ronald Reagan National Airport and the Washington Dulles International Airport. This legislation extends to the Airports Authority’s police officers the same power granted Virginia police officers under 19.2 of the Virginia Code, it updates other Virginia Code references, and clarifies that amended versions of the Virginia Code apply to the Authority’s police. The Commonwealth of Virginia has already enacted similar legislation to expand the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority’s police officers power. That legislation is scheduled to become effective on July 1, 1998. This legislation is necessary before the legislative changes can be given full effect. ENROLLED ORIGINAL See. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(e)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia APPROVED: December 11, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ~CTION DATE VOICE VOTE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD T~ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12 72 6 Docket No ADOPTED FIRST READING, Ii-I0=98 APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT PATTERSON I I ROLL CALL VOTE R~ull Coungilmcmb~r Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Courtaimtuber Aye Nay NV AB Chavoas Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. X Indicates Vote un¢|l ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE AB AI~eot CERTIFICATION RECORD NV Present not ’~oting ADOPTED FINAL READING 12-01’98 APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ALL PRESENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councdmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catani~ Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember X Indieiles Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Aye Nay NV AB Councilmeraber Aye Nay NV AB AB-Absem I I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I RO~LCALLVOTE-R~ult Coungilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Couneihnemher Aye Nay NV AB Couacilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB ] Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB Absent Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV Prt~atot not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to Ihe Co~odl Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
