<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-227">
  <num type="law">12-227</num>
  <heading type="short">Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-227.pdf">D.C. Law 12-227</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 502</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0625">
      <narrative>Law 12-227, the “Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-625, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 10, 1998, and December 1, 1998 respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 11, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-548 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-227 became effective on April 13, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S)’ kwikta 089 898 380 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-227 "Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1999" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-625, on first and second readings, November 10, 1998 a~qd December 1, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 11, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-548 and published in the January 22, 1999, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46 page 502) and transmitted to Congress on February 3, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-227 effective April 13, 1999. ¯ LINDA W CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 3,4,8,9,10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 Apr 12 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHLNGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Albert Gore, Jr. President of the Senate United States Senate Room S-212 United States Capitol Washington, D. C. 20510 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-548 Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998 Date of Council Action: 12-01-98 Dear Mr. President: The above named act is thereby transmitted in accordance with section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this act, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. To begin the count of the 60-day review by Congress, please acknowledge receipt of this document on the copy attached. Sincerely, Linda W. Cropp Chairman of the Council Enclosure Receipt Acknowledged: Name PLEASE PRINT Signa~re Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT WASHINGTON, D.C. OF COLUMBIA 20004 The Honorable J. Dennis Hastert Speaker of the House U. S. House of Representatives Room H-209 United States Capitol Washington, D. C. 20515 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-548 Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998 Date of Council Action: 12-01-98 Dear Mr. Speaker: The above named act is thereby transmitted in accordance with section 602(c 2)of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198. Attached to this act, for your information, is the report of the Council’s standing committee with jurisdiction over this matter. To begin the count of the 60-day review by Congress, please acknowledge receipt of this document on the copy attached. Sincerely, Linda W. Cropp Chairman of the Council Enclosure Receipt Acknowledged: Name- t~Ag~ Pl~i~f COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Eleanor Holmes Norton Member, U.S. House of Representatives District of Columbia 1424 Longworth House Office Building Washington, D. C. 20515 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-548 Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998 Date of Council Action: 12-01-98 Dear Congresswoman Norton: The above named act is thereby transmitted for your information. A copy of the enclosed act has been transmitted to the Speaker of the House. Sincerely, Linda W. Cropp Chairman of the Council Enclosure COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Thomas M. Davis Chairman, Subcommittee on The District of Columbia United States House of Representatives B349A Rayburn House Office Building Washington, D. C. 20515 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-548 Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testin~ and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998 Date of Council Action: Dear Mr. Chairman: The above named act is thereby transmitted for your information. A copy of the enclosed act has been transmitted to the Speaker of the House. 12-01-98 Sincerely, Linda W. Cropp Chairman of the Council Enclosure COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable George Voinovich Chairman, Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, Restructuring &amp;amp; the District of Columbia United States Senate 601 Hart Senate Office Building Washington, D.C. 20510 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-548 Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998 Dear Mr. Chairman: Date of Council Action: 12-01-98 The above named act is thereby transmitted for your information. A copy of the enclosed act has been transmitted to the President of the Senate. Sincerely Linda W. Cropp Chairman of the Council Enclosure COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 The Honorable Richard J. Durbin Ranking Minority Member Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, Restructuring &amp;amp; the District of Columbia United States Senate 316 Hart Senate Office Building Washington, D.C. 20510 Re: Transmittal of D.C. ACT 12-548 Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections Conforming Amendment Act of 1998 Date of Council Action: 12-01-98 Dear Senator Durbin: The above named act is thereby transmitted for your information. A copy of the enclosed act has been transmitted to the President of the Senate. Sincerely, Linda W. Cropp Chairman of the Council Enclosure ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12’548 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 11, 1998 Codi~catlon District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Govemment Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, to establish a mandatory drug and alcohol testing policy for certain employees of the District of Columbia Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health Services, to ensure that care for residents at the District’s secured and residential facilities for juveniles and persons with mental illness is provided in a safe and secure environment and to amend the Department of Corrections Employee Mandatory Drug and Alcohol Testing Act of 1996 to bring the testing levels in line with other District testing levels. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Department of Human Services and Commission on Mental Health SubchapterXXI-B, Services Mandatory Employee Drug and Alcohol Testing and Department of Corrections chapter 6, Conforming Amendment Act of 1998" Tiae 1 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 etseq is amended by adding a new title XX-B to read as follows TITLE XX-B "MANDATORY DRUG AND ALCOHOL TESTING OF CERTAIN EMPLOYEES OF THE DEPARTMENT OF HUMAN SERVICES AND THE COMMISSION ON MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES Sec. 2021. Definitions For the purposes of this title, the term 1 Applicant" means a person who has filed a written employment application form to work for the Department or the Commission or has been tentatively selected for employment by either the Department or the Commission to work as a high potential risk employee 2 Commission" means the Commission on Mental Health Services 3 Department" means the Department of Human Services. New Section 1-621.61 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4 High potential risk employee" means any Department or Commission employee who has resident care or custody responsibilities in a secured facility or who works in a residential facility 5 Post-accident employee" means any Department or Commission employee who, while on duty, was involved in a vehicular or other type of accident resulting in personal injury or property damage, or both 6 Probable cause" means a reasonable belief by a supervisor that an employee is under the influence of an illegal substance or alcohol such that the employee’s ability to perform his or her job is impaired 7 Probable cause referral" means a referral, based on probable cause, for testing by the Department or the Commission for drug or alcohol use 8 Random testing" means drug or alcohol testing taken by a Department or Commission employee at an unspecified time for the purposes of determining whether any Department or Commission employee has used drugs or alcohol and as a result is unable to satisfactorily perform his or her employment duties 9 Residential facility" means a facility that provides a supervised and sheltered living environment for individuals who need such an environment because of their mental, familial, social, or other circumstances 10 Secured facility" means a hospital or institution that is A) Leased, or owned by the District government B) Operated by the District government; and (C) Equipped and qualified to provide in-resident or in-patient care to detained or committed youth or persons suffering from mental illness Sec. 2022. Employee testing a) The following Deparmaent and Commission employees and prospective employees shall be tested for drug and alcohol use 1) Applicants for positions that would qualify them as high potential risk employees; and 2) Employees who have had a probable cause referral 3) Post-accident employees, as soon as reasonably possible after an accident 4) High potential risk employees b) Only high potential risk employees shall be subject to random testing c) All employees of the Department and Commission shall be given written notice, issued at least 30 days before the implementation of a drug and alcohol testing program, that the Department and Commission will implement a drug and alcohol testing program d) No employee may be tested for drug or alcohol use prior to receiving the notice required by subsection (c) of this section. New Section 1-621.62 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL e) Conditions giving rise to probable cause must be observed and documented. Supervisors shall be trained in substance abuse recognition and shall receive a second opinion from another supervisor prior to making a probable cause referral. An employee shall be given one opportunity to seek treatment following a positive test result g) perform the h) The Department and the Commission shall procure the services of a contractor to tests required by this title. All testing conducted by a vendor shall be implemented pursuant to this title Sec. 2023. Testing methodology a) Testing shall be performed by an outside contractor. The contractor shall be certified by the United States Department of Health and Human Services HHS to perform job related drug and alcohol forensic testing b)(1) For random testing, the contractor shall come on-site to Department or Commission institutions 2) The contractor shall collect urine specimens and split the samples c) The contractor shall perform enzyme-multiplied-immunoassay technique EMIT testing on one sample and store the other sample. Any positive EMIT test shall be confirmed by the contractor using gas chromatography/mass spectrometry GCMS methodology d) Any Department or Commission employee found to have a confirmed positive urinalysis shall be notified of the result. The employee may then authorize the stored sample to be sent to another HHS certified laboratory of his or her choice, at his or her expense, for secondary GCMS confirmation e) Probable cause and post-accident testing shall follow the same procedures set forth in subsections (a) through (d) of this section. In such cases, the employee shall be escorted by a supervisor to the contractor’s test site for specimen collection or breathalyzer f) A breathalyzer shall be deemed positive by the Department’s or Commission’s testing contractor if the contractor determines that 1 milliliter of the employee’s breath (consisting of substantially alveolar air) contains .38 micrograms or more of alcohol Sec. 2024. Implied consent of employees who operate motor vehicles Any Department or Commission employee who operates a motor vehicle in the performance of his or her employment within the District of Columbia shall be deemed to have given his or her consent, subject to the provisions of this title, to the testing of the employee’s urine or breath, for the purpose of determining drug or alcohol content, whenever a supervisor has the probable cause or a police officer arrests such employee for a violation of section 10 of the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1124; D.C. Code 40-716) or has reasonable grounds to believe such employee to have been operating or in physical control of a motor vehicle within the District while that employee’s breath contained .08% or more, by weight, of alcohol, or while under the influence of an intoxicating liquor or any drag or any combination thereof, or while the employee’s ability to operate a motor vehicle was New Section 1-621.63 New Section 1-621.64 3 ENROLLED OR/GINAL impaired by the consumption of intoxicating liquor Sec. 2025. Procedure and employee impact a) The drug and alcohol testing policy shall be issued in writing in advance of program implementation to inform employees and allow them the opporttmity to seek treatment. An employee shall be allowed only one oppommity to seek treatment following his or her t’n’st positive test result. Thereafter, any confirmed positive drug test, or positive breathalyzer test, or a refusal to submit to a drug or breathalyzer test shall be grounds for termination of employment b) The program shall cover all Department and Commission employees, including management, and shall be implemented as a single program of the Department and a single program of the Commission c) The results of any random test conducted pursuant to this title may not be turned over to any law enforcement agency without the employee’s written consent Sec. 3. Section 4 of the Department of Corrections Employee Mandatory Drug and Alcohol Testing Act of 1996, effective September 20, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-158; D.C. Code § 24- 448.3 is amended as follows a) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase 10 and inserting the phrase 08 in its place b) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the number 48" and inserting the number 38" in its place. Sec. 4 Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in New Section 1-621.65 Section 24-448.3 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia APPROVED: December ii, 1998 5 ] ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I ¢’rlON a DATE ]~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D,kc, No. B12-625 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11’10’98 APPROVED AMBROSE, MASON ANDTHOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couacilm¢mbcr Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania x Indicates Vote f Secrclor to Ihe C~ncil ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR 1~ A~ION &amp;amp; DATE I~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Ave Nay J NV AB Councilmember Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absenl CERTIFICATION RECORD Aye Na NV AB NV Present noi Voting \ Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12’01’98 APPRDVED ALL PRESENT [ I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Counc|lmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote ~ta~ Io Ihe Council [ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR A~ION &amp;amp; DATE Counciimtmher Chavous Evans Jar,/is Mason Patterson Nay NV AB Councilmrmber Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Aye Nay NV AB \ Dale VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT [ } ROI~L CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp A|le~ Ambrose Brazil Calania Aye N,Lv NV AB CouncilmemDer Aye Nay NV AB Cnoncilmembcr Aye NJy NV AB X Indicates VoIC Chavoos Evans Jarvis Mason Patlerson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. AB Absent NV Present not CERTIFICATION RECORJ) secretary to lhe Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
