<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-248">
  <num type="law">12-248</num>
  <heading type="short">Compensation Increase for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-248.pdf">D.C. Law 12-248</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1113</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0707">
      <narrative>Law 12-248, the “Compensation Increase for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-707, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998, and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-587 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-248 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikt 062 329 045 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-248 "Compensation Increase for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill 12-707 on first and second readings, December 1, 1998 and December 15, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 24, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act the bill became Act 12-587 and it was published in the February 12, 1999 edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 46, page 1113 The Act was transmitted to Congress on February 10, 1999 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired, and the Act is now D.C. Law 12-248, effective April 20, 1999 f ’ ’ LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Days Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 10,11,12,22,23,24,25 Mar. 1,2,3,4,5,8,9,10,11,15,16,17,18,19,22,23,24,25 Apr. 12,13,14,15,19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12’587 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to increase the compensation for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Compensation Increase for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 201(c) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Code § 45-251 l(c is amended to read as follows c) The Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee compensated at a grade 16 of the District schedule established under Title XI of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-612.1 et seq District schedule The other members of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee at a grade 15 pursuant to the District schedule Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in Section 45-2511 ENROLLED ORIGINAL section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia Approved: December 24, 1998 2 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DA*E COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD T~’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Do.,No. B12-707 ADOPTED. F IRST..READING, i2;0~L98 VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ALL PRESENT. ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couu¢ilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania Patterson } s~¢a o4he Cooncit Councilmember Aye Nay N~’ AB Schwartz Smith, 3r. Thomas, St. NV Present not Voting ADOPTED. F INAL .READING 22~5L 98 l~ VOICE VOTE RECORDEDVOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ¯ THO.MAS [ I ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Counciimember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania IAye Nay NV I AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD i t :cretnry to the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE [ I VQICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT RoLL CALL VOTE Result CounciJmember Chron. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Na.v NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vote Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas. Sr. AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary o the CouucJl Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to increase the compensation for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Compensation Increase for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 201(c) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Code § 45-251 l(c is amended to read as follows c) The Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee compensated at a grade 16 of the District schedule established under Title XI of the District of Columbia Govemrnent Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-612.1 et seq District schedule The other members of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee at a grade 15 pursuant to the District schedule Sec. 3. The Council adopts the" fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in Section 45-2511 ENROLLED ORIGINAL section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-;233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chg, ifman ¢ Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AcTION DATE VOICE VOTE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D No. B12-707 ADOPTED. F IRST READ ING, 12~01=98 APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ALL ,PRESENT I I ROLLCALL VOTE- Result .t I Councilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Couneilmember Aye N|y NV AB Couneilmember Aye Na.’* N% AB Chmn. Cropp Chavous Schwartz Alien Evans Smith, Jr. Ambrose Jarvis Thomas. Sr. Brazil Mason Catania Patterson /’ t Indieatfs Vote AB Absent* ¯ ’e~ re~ ¢o’~be Council 1~ ITEM ON CONSINT CALENDAR gt A~,ON~,DATE ADOPTED. FINAL .READING Z2Z.~Z5L98~ NV Present not Voting VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ¯ THOMAS. ROLL CALL VOTE Result Couttciimember Chmn. Cropp Alien Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye t Na) NV AB ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR Counciimember Aye Nay Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD to the Council NV AB Councilmember Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. Ate Nay N%’ AB NV-Present not yogin2 [ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I vOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST .ABSENT [ I RoLL CALL VOTE- Result Councilmember Aye Na NV AB Chron. Cropp Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote Councilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas. Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absent N’I,’ Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council Date COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICE OF THE GENERAL COUNSEL WASHINGTON, D.C. 20004 TRANSMITTAL OF ENGROSSED LEGIS E D C-4 P12:10 Sho~ Title: Compensation Increase for the Chai~erson of the Rental ~d~Si~’Co~ission ~endment Act of 1998 Bill #12-707 co: Chairman Cropp (with attachment) Legislative Counsel /2-3- y~c Date of Transmittal Received by LSD Staff Date of Receipt cc: Codification Counsel Rev. 1/95 ENGROSSED ORIGINAL A BILL 12-707 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 1 2 3 4 To amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to increase the compensation for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Compensation Increase for the Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 201(c) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Code § 45-251 l(c is amended to read as follows c) The Chairperson of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee compensated at a grade 16 of the District schedule established under Title XI of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-612.1 et seq District schedule The other members of the Rental Housing Commission shall receive annual compensation equivalent to that received by a District employee at a grade 15 pursuant to the "District schedule Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 ENGROSSED ORIGINAL fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect upon its approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3 (a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
