<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-244">
  <num type="law">12-244</num>
  <heading type="short">Year 2000 Government Computer Immunity Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-244.pdf">D.C. Law 12-244</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1080</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0732">
      <narrative>Law 12-244, the “Year 2000 Government Computer Immunity Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-732, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998, and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-581 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-244 became effective on April 20, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>EN LL N (S) kwiktag 062 323 847 (5) ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-581 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To protect the District government and its employees from liability arising from a Year 2000 system failure, to protect District government vendors from liability arising from a Year 2000 system failure if the failure is due to the vendor’s use of systems or equipment owned or provided by the District government, and to require District government contracts to include a warranty for Year 2000 compliance. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Year 2000 Government Computer Immunity Act of 1998 Sec. 2 a) Notwithstanding section 801 of the Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1188.1 no cause of action at law or in equity, nor any administrative action shall be maintained against the District government or its officers or employees, arising from a Year 2000 system failure b) No cause of action at law or in equity, nor any administrative action shall be maintained against a District government vendor, arising from a Year 2000 system failure caused primarily by the vendor’s use of computer hardware, soflavare, or equipment that is not Year 2000 compliant and which is owned or provided by the District government, unless the action is maintained by the District government c) All District government contracts executed after the effective date of this act shall include a warranty of Year 2000 compliance for any goods or services provided pursuant to the contract, and shall state that the vendor is liable for any damages if the goods and services are not Year 2000 compliant d) For the purposes of this act 1) The term "Year 2000 compliance or compliant" means the capability of a computer software program, database, network, information system, computer device, or any equipment using microchips, to interpret, produce, generate, calculate, or to correctly account for a date in the Year 2000 or in subsequent years 2) The term "Year 2000 system failure" means the failure of a computer software program, database, network, information system, computer device, or any equipment New Subchapter Chapter 11A, Title 1 New Section 1-1188.51 ENROLLED ORIGINAL using microchips, to interpret, produce, generate, calculate, or to correctly account for a date in the year 2000 or in subsequent years. Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply to claims arising between the effective date of this act and December 31, 2005, and to contracts executed and in effect between the effective date of this act and December 31, 2005. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star 813; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia New Section 1-1188.52 District of Columbia Approved: December 24, 1998 IN ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I~ ICTION &amp;amp; DATE I voice VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST RECOIU~ OF orrlcP, L COUNCIL VOTE B12- 732 Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING. 12~01;-98 APPROVED ABSENT ALL PRESENT I I ROLL CALL VOTE. Result Co~ncilnleulbir Aye Nay NV Chron. Cropp Allln Ambrose Brazil Calania AB Couocilmemlmr Aye Nay Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr x In~ieates vote AB Al~ent NV Prc~ent not Voting lC~II~ to the C~Icfl Dale I I ITeM ON CONS~T CALENDAR o~ ¯ ADOPTED. F I NA.L .READ ING, 12215298 APPROVED I~ VOIC~ VOTE gBC~D VOT~ ON RBQB£ST A~ENT THOMAS [ I ROLL CALL VOTE lnuli Councilmcrabcr Aye Nay NV Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Calania X Indicat¢~ Vo~ I Mason Patterson ’ AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Cuuncilmembcr Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Schwartz Evans r Smith, Jr. Jarvis ] Thomas, Sr. N~’*Preuot o~ vOtil~I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE I I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT J I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Counciimembcr Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB X Indicates Vole Conncilmember Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Aye Nay NV AB AB A bleiil Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV o Present n~l Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the CouneAi D~Ie</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-381.31"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-381.32"/>
  </section>
</document>
