<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-270">
  <num type="law">12-270</num>
  <heading type="short">Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1999-04-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-270.pdf">D.C. Law 12-270</citation>
      <citation type="register">46 DCR 1111</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0700">
      <narrative>Law 12-270, the “Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-700, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 1, 1998, and December 15, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 24, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-586 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-270 became effective on April 27, 1999.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta 062 329 021 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12-586 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 24, 1998 Co~ficafion District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996 to allow for risk assessments, recommendations, and mental examinations to be made of all offenders who are required to register under the act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 18 of the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996, effective June 3, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-274; D.C. Code § 24-1117 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, and subject to the availability of funds, the Court may at any time 1) Direct the Advisory Council to make an assessment and recommendation concerning any offender who is required to register under this act 2) Order a mental examination of any offender who is required to register under this act, for the purpose of assessing risk under the provisions of this act; and 3) Make the determinations described in section 6(3)(D in conformity with section 6(3)(A C Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Section 24-1117 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbia Approved: December 24, 1998 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DIS’]’RICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD T~,’ELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE D~,et~n. BI2L700. ADOPTED. FIRST..READING, 12’.01=98 I~ VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ALL PRESENT I ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania X Indicates Vote th¢ Council [~ ITEM ON c~bNSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Patterson AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD .t Aye Nay NV AB NV Present not Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING i2L~i5" 98 IX VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED THOMAS ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania IAye I Nay NV I I X Indicates Vote ITEM ON CON T CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE AB Counciimcmber Aye Nay NV AB Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Council Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, C3 NV-Present not votine Da’te ’ I I voice VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ¯ I I ROlL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania Aye Nay NV AB Councilmcraber Aye Nay NV AB CouncilmemDer ,Aye Nay NV AB Chavous ] Schwartz X Indicates Vote Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Codification District of Columbia Code 1999 Supp. To amend the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996 to allow for risk assessments, recommendations, and mental examinations to be made of all offenders who are required to register under the act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Sex Offender Registration Risk Assessment Clarification Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. Section 18 of the Sex Offender Registration Act of 1996, effective June 3, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-274; D.C. Code § 24-1117 is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, and subject to the availability of funds, the Court may at any time 1) Direct the Advisory Council to make an assessment and recommendation concerning any offender who is required to register under this act 2) Order a mental examination of any offender who is required to register under this act, for the purpose of assessing risk under the provisions of this act; and 3) Make the determinations described in section 6(3)(D in conformity with section 6(3)(A C Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia 24-1117 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ~crloN &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE O.,e,~o. B12~700 ADOPTED. FIRST READING, 12 01a98 VOICE VOTE APPROVED RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSEWI" ALL PRESENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE- Result Connei|member Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Aye Nay NV AB Cnun¢ilmembcr Aye NtA" NV All Conncilmeabee Aye Na~ NV AR Chavous Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas~ Sr. MasonBrazil Catania X Indicates Vole th¢ Council i~ ITEM ON CJ)NSENT CALENDAR ACTION DATE CERTIFICATION RECOR ADOPTED. F I NAL .READ I NG £2 L~£5L 98, {~ VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED. ¯ THOMAS. ROLL CALL VOTE Resutl Counciimcmber .Ave [ Nay NV AB Councilmcmber Ave Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp j Chavous Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania x I.d!e.tcs vote t TBM ON CON~NT Evllfls Jarvis Mason Pa[terson AB-Abseol CERTIFICATION RECORD AC’I’ION &amp;amp; DATE Counci|member Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. Aye Na) NV AB vOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST BSENT ¯ RoLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmem~er .Aye Na NV AB Chron. Cropp Chavous Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Catania X Indicates Vote Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, 3r. Patterson Aye Nay NV AB Councilmemb¢r AB Absent NV Present nol oling CERTIFICATION RECORD Seerelury Io the Council Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
