<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-54">
  <num type="law">12-54</num>
  <heading type="short">Paternity Acknowledgment Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-02-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-54.pdf">D.C. Law 12-54</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 6231</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0255">
      <narrative>Law 12-54, the “Paternity Acknowledgment Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-255, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 1, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 3, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-171 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-54 became effective on February 27, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-54 "Paternity Acknowledgment Amendment Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-255, on first and second readings, July 1, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 3, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-171 and published in the October 31, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 6231) and transmitted to Congress on October 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-54, effective February 27, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Oct. 23,24,27,28,29,30,31 Nov. 3,4,5,6,7,10,12,13 Jan. 27,28,29 Feb. 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D, C, ACT 12’171 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 3, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend Chapter 9 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to require each public and private birthing hospital in the District of Columbia to operate a hospital-based program that provides services to facilitate the voluntary acknowledgment of paternity immediately before and after the birth of a child to an unmarried woman, to require each birthing hospital to transmit completed voluntary acknowledgment of paternity forms to the Mayor, and to require the Mayor to provide to the staff of each birthing hospital the forms, materials, and training required to operate the program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Paternity Acknowledgment Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. Chapter 9 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding the phrase "16-909.3. Paternity acknowledgment program requirements for birthing hospitals b) A new section 16-909.3 is added to read as follows § 16-909.3. Paternity acknowledgment program requirements for public and private birthing hospitals a) For the purposes of this section, the term "birthing hospital" means a hospital that has an obstetric care unit or provides obstetric services, or a birthing center associated with a hospital b)(1) Each public and private birthing hospital in the District shall operate a hospital- based program that, immediately before and after the birth of a child, provides to each unmarried woman who gives birth at the hospital and the alleged putative father, if present in the hospital, the following A) Written materials concerning paternity establishment B) Forms necessary to voluntarily acknowledge paternity C) A written description of the rights and responsibilities of New Section 16-909.3 ENROLLED ORIGINAL establishing paternity D) The opportunity to speak, either by telephone or in person, with staff who are trained to clarity information and answer questions about paternity establishment; and E) The opportunity to voluntarily acknowledge paternity in the hospital 2) The Mayor shall provide to each birthing hospital the materials described in paragraph (1)(A) through (C) of this subsection in sufficient amounts to be distributed to all concerned parties under this subsection c) Each public and private birthing hospital shall provide the following services 1) Afford the mother and alleged putative father, if present in the hospital, due process safeguards 2) Inform the mother and alleged putative father, if present in the hospital, that each is required to sign the voluntary acknowledgment of paternity form to effectuate the voluntary acknowledgment of paternity 3) Inform the mother and alleged putative father, if present in the hospital, that their signatures on the voluntary acknowledgment of paternity form must be authenticated by a notary or witness; and 4) Provide for the services of a notary on the premises of the birthing hospital d) The birthing hospital shall transmit each completed voluntary acknowledgment of paternity form to the Mayor within 14 days of completion. The Mayor shall promptly record identifying information from the form and permit the child support enforcement agency for the District timely access to the identifying information and any other documentation recorded from the form that the child enforcement agency needs to determine if a voluntary acknowledgment of paternity has been recorded or to seek a support order on the basis of the recorded voluntary acknowledgment of paternity e) The Mayor shall provide to the staff of each birthing hospital training, guidance, and written instructions necessary to operate the paternity acknowledgment program required by this section f) The Mayor shall assess the paternity acknowledgment program of each birthing hospital each year Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. Enactment of the Paternity Acknowledgement Amendment Act of 1997 will ensure that the District government remains eligible for approximately $13 million in federal funds used in the collection of child support payments from noncustodial parents for the care of children who reside in the District. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116: D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review a~ provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § t-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of~an~M Columb)~f ~Register Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 3, 1997 ENROLLED ORIGINAL veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as ?rovided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of y~~C olumbjv Register.e’l~ai~n an Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 3, 1997 3 kOI N( IL Of IItE DISI RI(T OF COLt MBIA COt NCIL PERIOD TX.VELVE ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR A(TION &amp;amp; DAFE VOICE ¥’OTE RECORDEI) VOTE ON REQ!’EST RECORD OF OFFICIAL COl NCIt. VOTE Docket No. B12-255 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 07-01-97 APPROVED ABSENT BRAZIL, EVANS, JARVIS, SCHWARTZ AND THOMAS [ I ROLL ALL VOTE- Result Counciimemher Aye Na) NV ~B Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous ~the Council I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [X~I ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmemher Xye Na) NV AB (nuncilmember X)c \a) \V ’~B Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson Schwartz AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD t ¢/~V Present not Voting Date ADOPTED FINAL READING, 09-22-97 I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT I I ROLl. CALL VOTE Result (’ouncihnember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous ¯ X-indieatl, no [ ] ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ ] ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Na NV AB Councilmember A.~e Nay NV AB Councilmember A.~e Nay NV AB Dixon Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERI"IFI(:ATION RECORD NV-Present not votin~ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQVEST ~BSENT [ ] ROI,E CALf. VOTE Result (ouacilmember Aye Na NV AB Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Dixon Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Chavous Patterson Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Na~ NV AB Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, St. CER IIFICA II()N RE(ORD NecretaQ Io Ihe Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
