<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-53">
  <num type="law">12-53</num>
  <heading type="short">Supplemental Security Income Payment Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-02-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-53.pdf">D.C. Law 12-53</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 6228</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0254">
      <narrative>Law 12-53, the “Supplemental Security Income Payment Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-254, which was referred to the Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 1, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 3, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-170 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-53 became effective on February 27, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwikta[ ® 062 328 904 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-53 "Supplemental Security Income Payment Amendment Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-254, on first and second readings, July 1, 1997 and September 22, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 3, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-170, and published in the October 31, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 6228) and transmitted to Congress on October 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-53, effective February 27, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Oct. 23,24,27,28,29,30,31 Nov. 3,4,5,6,7,10,12,13 Jan. 27,28,29 Feb. 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-170 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 3, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to eliminate the District supplement to the federal Supplemental Security Income payment for District residents who live independently and re-direct the supplemental payment to persons who receive the Supplemental Security Income benefits and who live in community residential facilities, and to codify the current special living arrangement rates that have been established by rule. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Supplemental Security Income Payment Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-201.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 406 (D.C. Code § 3-204.6) is repealed b) Section 549 (D.C. Code § 3-205.49) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the figure 20" and inserting the figure 40" in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows c) Effective with payments beginning on January 1, 1997, each recipient of Supplemental Security Income who lives in a community residence facility that has 50 or fewer residents shall receive a payment of $631.20 per month, of which $561.20 shall be used for room, board, and care and $70.00 shall be retained by the recipient for clothing and personal needs 3) Subsection (d) is amended to read as follows d) Effective with payments beginning on January 1, 1997, each recipient of Supplemental Security Income who lives in a community residence facility that has a capacity for more than 50 residents shall receive a payment of $741.20 per month, of which $671.20 shall be used for room, board, and care and $70.00 shall be retained by the recipient for clothing and personal needs. At no time shall the total number of persons receiving payments from the District pursuant to this subsection exceed 250 persons Sectioll 3-204.6 Section 3-205.49 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (4) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase "March 10, 1983" and inserting the phrase "January 1, 1997" in its place, and by adding the following sentence after the existing sentence The Mayor may increase the payments for clothing and personal needs authorized by subsections (c) and (d) of this section through rulemaking pursuant to subsection (g) of this section 5) A new subsection (e-l) is added to read as follows e- 1)(1) Each District of Columbia resident who receives a Supplemental Security Income payment pursuant to this section and who lives in a community residence facility shall receive an additional supplemental payment for room, board, and care 2) The additional supplemental payment shall be prorated based upon the amount of supplemental funds forwarded by the District to the federal Social Security Administration divided by the total population of Supplemental Security Income recipients who are residents of the District of Columbia and who live in a community residence facility 3) This subsection shall apply on the later of the following A) The date of written notice by the District to the federal government that the District intends to eliminate payments to noninstitutionalized SSI recipients B) The date the Social Security Administration provides notice to non- institutionalized SSI reci ~ients whose supplemental payments are being eliminated; or C) January 1, 1997 6) A new subsection (h) is added to read as follows h) The Mayor may enter into an agreement with the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Se~wices for the federal administration of supplemental payments. Payments made pursuant to this section shall be made as long as such payments are required by federal law Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. Section 406 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-204.6 authorizes a supplemental payment of $4.70 per month for approximately 20,000 District residents who live independently and who receive a federal Supplemental Security Income payment. The cost of processing the supplemental payment is $5.00 per month per recipient. By eliminating the supplemental payment for residents who live independently, the costs of processing the payments are reduced because the number of persons receiving the supplement has been reduced. The projected savings are approximately $1 million in appropriated funds. Enactment of the Supplemental Security Income Payment Amendment Act of 1997 will ensure that the Department of Human Services achieves its Fiscal Year 1997 and Fiscal Year 1998 spending reduction initiatives to reduce the administrative costs of tl:e Supplemental Security Income program. ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia~gister C~rman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 3, 1997 ITE~.I ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOI(E VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQI;EST CO| NCII F I’llt~ I)IS] RI(I OF OLI MBIA COI’N(’II PERIOD FSVELSE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COl NCIL VOTE D,,e,e,~n, B12-254 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 07-01-97 APPROVED ALLEN, BRAZIL, JARVIS, SCHWARTZ AND THOMAS I I ROLL CALL ~OTE Result Councilmember Aye Na~ NV AB Couneilmember Chron. Cropp Evans Allen Jarvis Ambrose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz I i}e Na) N iB Councilmember t’ Na} NV iB Smith, Jr. Thomas. St. x- tnd[a,es Vo,e the Council ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE +iB Absent CERTIFICA NON RECORD NV Present not +iotin~ ADOPTED FINAL READING, 09-22-97 VOICE VOTE RE(~ORI)ED VOTE ON REQUEST XBSENT APPROVED .DIXON, JARVIS AND THOMAS ROLL CALl, VOTE Result Cl~mn. Cropp ,Mien Ambrose Brazil Chavous ’~ X-indicates no I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I Aye Na.t Dixon ] Seh~vartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD NY-Present not voting I A(I’ION &amp;amp; I)ATE I VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST XBSENT I I ROI,L CALL VOTE Result (ouncihuember Cbmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous Aye Na) NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Na} NV AB X Indicates Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson Schwartz Smith Jr. Thomas. Sr ill bscnt (’ERTIFI(L% I ION RE(ORD Secretar? In the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
