<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-50">
  <num type="law">12-50</num>
  <heading type="short">Small Purchase Authority Amendment Act of 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1998-02-27</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-50.pdf">D.C. Law 12-50</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 6222</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0231">
      <narrative>Law 12-50, the “Small Purchase Authority Amendment Act of 1997,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-231, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 1, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 3, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-164 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-50 became effective on February 27, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 328 808 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-50 "Small Purchase Authority Amendment Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-231 on first and second readings, July 1, 1997, and September 22, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on October 3, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-164, and published in the October 31, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 6222) and transmitted to Congress on October 23, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-50, effective February 27, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Oct. Nov. Jan. Feb. 23,24,27,28,29,30,31 3,4,5,6,7,10,12,13 27,28,29 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26 Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-164 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OCTOBER 3, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the Procurement Practices Act of 1985 to reestablish small purchase authority. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Small Purchase Authority Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 320 is amended by adding a new subsection (j) that reads as follows j) Nothing in this act shall affect the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority’s powers to establish and operate its procurement system and to execute contracts pursuant to the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-111; D.C. Code § 43-1661 et seq b) A new section 321 is added to read as follows 321. Small purchase procurement Special small purchase procedures may be used by the Chief Procurement Officer or his or her designee, in accordance with regulations established pursuant to this act, for procurements not exceeding $25,000. Procurement requirements shall not be parceled, split, divided, or purchased over a period of time in order not to exceed the dollar limitation for use of these small purchase procedures. An employee who violates the provisions of this subsection shall be subject to suspension, dismissal, or other disciplinary action pursuant to District law Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Committee report on Bill 12-231 as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 913; D.C. Code § 1-233 (c)(3 Section 1-1183.2 New Section 1-1183.21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code 233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia APPROVED: October 3, 1997 2 (01 N( IL 01: HIE I)1~1RI(’! Of (’OL IBI-’~ COl NCIL PERIOD TWELVE ] [ ITEM ON CONSENT (ALENDAR [X[ ACI’ION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQI ES] ABSENT RECORD OF OFFI( IAL COl"ff~ll. VOTE Docket No. B12-231 AnOPTED FIRST READ!NG~ 07-0!-97 APPROVED ALLEN, BRAZIL, JARVIS AND SCHWARTZ ROLL ALL O’lE Result oullcilmember Aye Na} NV AB Councilmember ye Na) N AB Chron. Cropp Evans Allen Jarvis Ambrose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz (’ounciimember e \~i? \’~ AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. tar)’ 1o the Council 1 Date [X[ ITE:~I ON CONSENT ALENDAR ADOPTED FINAL READING, 09-22-97 1 ACI’ION &amp;amp; DATE OI(’E VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST APPROVED DIXON, JARVIS AND THOMAS ROLl. CALL VOTE Result i( ouu(:ihl|emberChron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous Aye Nay NX’ AB Councilmember e Na) NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NS AB Dixo~ Schwartz Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St. Mason Patterson X-indica~s no AB-Absent CERTIFI(:ATION RECORD I A(’TION &amp;amp; I)ATE NV-Presenl not vonng I [ VOICE VOTE RECORI)ED VOTE ON REQt:EST gl]SEN’I I I ROLl. C-’d.L VffFE Result Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous Aye Nay N’¢ AB Coul]cilmember Aye Nay NV All ouncilmember Aye Na} NV AB Dixon Schwartz Evans Smith. Jr. Jarvis Thomas, St, Mason Patterson SecretaD 1o the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
