<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-81">
  <num type="law">12-81</num>
  <heading type="short">Technical Amendments Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1998-03-24</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-81.pdf">D.C. Law 12-81</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 745</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0408">
      <narrative>Law 12-81, the “Technical Amendments Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-408, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 4, 1997, and December 4, 1997, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 1997, it was assigned Act No. 12-246 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-81 became effective on March 24, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) kwiktag 069 896 611 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-81 "Technical Amendments Act of 1997" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-408, on first and second readings, November 4, 1997 and December 4, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 22, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-246, and published in the February 13, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 page 745) and transmitted to Congress on January 29, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-81 effective March 24, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Jan. Feb. Mar. 29 2,3,4,5,9,10,11,12,23,24,25,26,27 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D,C, ACT 12-246 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DECEMBER 22, 1997 To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to make grammatical corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 to make punctuation and stylistic corrections; to amend the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996 to make a cite correction; to amend the District of Columbia Securities Act to make terminology corrections to reflect technical terminology changes mandated by subsequent legislation; to amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1992 to make a teclmical terminology conforming amendment; to amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1992 to make a typographical correction; to amend the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Act of 1984 to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978 to make a stylistic correction; to amend Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, reference, punctuation, spelling, stylistic, terminology, and typographical corrections; to amend Title 17 of the District of Columbia Code to make a terminology correction; to amend Title 19 of the District of Columbia Code to make a typographical correction; to amend Title 20 of the District of Columbia Code to make stylistic and punctuation corrections; to amend Title 2 l of the District of Columbia Code to make cite, reference, spelling, punctuation, stylistic, and typographical corrections; to amend the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act to make a stylistic correction; to amend Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code to make cite and spelling corrections; to amend the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996 to make a cite correction; to amend the Insurance Confidentiality of Information Act of 1996 to make a terminology correction required by subsequent legislation; to amend An Act To confer additional jurisdiction upon the Superintendent of Insurance for the District of Columbia to regulate domestic stock insurance companies and to exempt such companies from section 12(g)(1) of the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Life Insurance Act to make stylistic, terminology, and grammatical changes; to amend the Act for the Regulation of Credit Life Insurance and Credit Accident and Health Insurance to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Fire and Casualty Act to make stylistic, punctuation, and terminology ENROLLED ORIGINAL corrections; to amend An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992 to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982 to make grammatical and terminology corrections; to amend the Drug Abuse, Alcohol Abuse, and Mental Illness Insurance Coverage Act of 1986 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Liability Coverage for Child Development Homes Insurance Act of 1990 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992 to make cite, grammatical, and stylistic corrections; to amend the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to anaend the Insurance Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Risk Retention Act of 1993 to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Law on Examinations Act of 1993 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Holding Company System Act of 1993 to make stylistic corrections; to amend the Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Insurance Industry Material Transactions Disclosure Act of 1996 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Insurance Demutualization Act of 1996 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Insurance Redomestication Act of 1996 to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Insurance State of Entry Act of 1996 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Health Maintenance Organization Act of 1996 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996 to make a punctuation correction; to amend An Act To provide for the payment and collection of wages in the District of Columbia to make a reference correction in the organic law; to amend the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1988 to make a reference correction; to amend the Health Care Expansion Benefits Act of 1992 to make a reference correction; to amend the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Telecommunications Competition Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Condominium Act of 1976 to make stylistic corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982 to make stylistic corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to make stylistic corrections; to amend the Title 47, D.C. Code Enactment Act of 1996 to make a reference correction; to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code to make cite, reference, text, and stylistic corrections; to amend the BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; and to amend the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pay Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 to make a reference correction. 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL amend the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pay Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 to make a reference correction. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Technical Amendments Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 203(b D.C. Code § 1-602.3(b is amended by striking the phrase respectively b) Section 1401 (D.C. Code § 1-615.1) is amended by striking the word "the" after the phrase "the District of Columbia Board of Education Sec. 3. Section 104 of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1 t8t.4 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase "1-1152 et seq and inserting the phrase "1-1152 et seq in its place b) Paragraph (SA) is amended as follows 1) By striking the phrase 5A) Violation" and inserting the phrase 4A) Violation" in its place; and (2) By striking at the end of subparagraph (B) the phrase "bases for disbarment and inserting the phrase "bases for disbarment; or" in its place. Sec. 4. Section 2(3) of the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-134; D.C. Code § 1-2271(3 is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code § 47-1801 etseq and inserting the phrase "D.C. Code § 47-801 et seq in its place. Section 1-602.3 Section 1-615.1 Section 1-1181.4 Section 1-2271 Sec. 5. The District of Columbia Securities Act, approved August 30, 1964 (76 Stat. 620; D.C. Code § 2-2601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 7(b D.C. Code § 2-2606(b is amended by striking the phrase "SecuritiesSection and Exchange Department" and inserting the phrase "Securities and Exchange Commission" in2-2606 its place b) Section 10(a)(1)(F D.C. Code § 2-2609(a)(1)(F is amended by striking the phrasesection "Securities and Exchange Department" and inserting the phrase "Securities and Exchange 2-2609 Commission" in its place c) Section 1 l(a)(3 D.C. Code § 2-2610(a)(3 is amended by striking the phrase "or2-2610secti°n of a Commissioner ENROLLED ORIGINAL (d) Section 15 (D.C. Code § 2-2615) is amended as follows: Section 2-2615 (1) By striking in subsection (f) the phrase "each member of the Commission" and inserting the phrase "the Securities Director" in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears, except as indicated in the amendment to subsection (f) indicated in paragraph (1) above, and inserting the word "Department" in its place e) Section 18 (D.C. Code § 2-2617) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and Section inserting the word "Department" in its place~ 2-2617 Sec. 6. Section 2(2)(M) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1992, effective March 17, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-216; D.C. Code § 2-263 l(2)(M is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "Department" in its place. Sec. 7. Section 1403 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1992, effective April 6, 1992 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-214.3 is amended by striking the word "federal" and inserting the word "funeral" in its place. Sec. 8. Section 6a of the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Act of 1984, effective March 6, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-197; DC. Code § 3-605.1 is amended by striking the phrase "be may" and inserting the phrase "may be" in its place. Sec. 9. Section 501 of the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-137; D.C. Code § 6-1961 is amended by striking the phrase "of funds appropriated for" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "that appropriated funds are available to carry out" in its place. Section 2-2631 Section 3-214.3 Section 3-605.1 Section 6-1961 Sec. 10. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 16-309 is amended by designating the undesignated paragraph at the end of subsection (b beginning with the phrase "In determining whether as a new subsection (b-1)Sectionl6_309 and is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place b) Section 16-312(a) is amended by striking the word "adoptor" wherever it appears Seaion 16-312 and inserting the word "adopter" in its place c) Section 16-501(c)(1) is amended by striking the word "Plaintiffs’" and inserting theSectio word "plaintiffs" in its place. 16-SOl (d) Section 16-5~72 is amended by striking the word "Federal" wherever it appears and Section inserting the word "federal" in its place. 16-s72 (e) Section 16-703(e) is amended by striking the phrase "section 15-709(b)(2 and Section 16-703 inserting the phrase "section 15-709(b in its place. 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (f) Section 16-904(b)(3) is amended by striking the word "adultry" and inserting the Section 16-904 word "adultery" in its place g) Section 16-916.1 (0)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "part D of title 4" and section inserting the phrase "Part D of Title IV" in its place. 16-916.1 (h) Section 16-924(a)(2) is amended by striking the word "ages" and inserting the wordSection "age" in its place. 16-924 (i) Section 16-1001 is amended in the lead-in language by striking the word "chapter"Section and inserting the word "subchapter" in its place. 16-~001 Section(j) Section 16-1002(a) and (c) is amended by striking the word "chapter" wherever it 16-1002 appears and inserting the word "subchapter" in its place° (k) Section 16-1005(0 is amended by striking the word "chapter" and inserting the wordSection "subchapter" in its place. 16-100s (1) Section 16-1021 (4) is amended by striking the numeral "1" and inserting the wordSection "one" in its place. 16-1021 (m) Section 16-1109(b) is amended by striking the word "mense" and inserting the word Section "mesne" in its place. 16-1109 (n) Section 16-1112 is amended in the section heading by striking the misspelled wordSection 16-1112 "Expiriation" and inserting the word "Expiration" in its place o) Section 16-1116(2) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Section (p) Section 16-1321 is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the16-1116 Section word "Mayor" in its place. 16-1321 Section(q) Section 16-1332(a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "in their" and inserting the16-1332 phrase "in the Mayor’s" in its place r) Section 16-13 54 is amending by striking the word "Procedures" and inserting the section word "Procedure" in its place. 16-1354 (s) Section 16-1360 is amended by striking the word "accessing" and inserting the wordSection "assessing" in its place. 16-1360 Section (t) Section 16-1908 is amended by striking the word "cutody" and inserting the word16-190s "custody" in its place u) Section 16-23 01 (11) is amended by striking the phrase "section 21-1101 and Section 16-2301 inserting the phrase "section 21-1101 et seq in its place v) Section 16-2302 is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "sections 16-2330 through 16-2302 16-2335" and inserting the phrase "sections 16-2331 through 16-2336" in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word "than" and inserting the word "then" in its place w) Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking in the table of contents and at the respective section headings the section designations "§ 16- 2305a § 16-2305b and "§ 16-2325a" and inserting the section designations "§ 16-2305.1 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "§ 16-2305.2 and "§ 16-2325.1" respectively, in their place x) Section 16-2305(a) is amended by striking the phrase "Department of Human Section 16-2305 Resources" and inserting the phrase "Department of Human Services" in its place y) Section 16-2305a is amended by striking the section designation "16-2305a" and Section inserting a new section designation "16-2305.1" in its place. 16-23os.1 (z) Section 16-2305b is amended by striking the section designation "16-2305b" and Section inserting a new section designation "16-2305.2" in its place. 16-23os.2 (aa) Section 16-2309(a) is amended as follows: Section16-2309 (1) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrases "Department of Human Resources" and "section 107(b) of the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977" and inserting the phrases "Department &amp;amp;Human Services" and "§ 6-2105(b respectively, in their place 2) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase "Department of Human Resources" and inserting the phrase "Department of Human Services" in its place bb) Section 16-2315(c)(1) and (3) is amended by striking the phrase "section 6- Section 1902(b and inserting the phrase "section 6-1902(2 in its place. 16-2315 (cc) Section 16-2322(e) is amended by striking the phrase "section 16-2334" and Section inserting the phrase "section 16-2335" in its place. 16-2322 Section (dd) Section 16-233 l(b)(3) is amended by striking the word "duty" and inserting the 16-2331 word "duly" in its place ee) Section 16-2335 is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrases "sections 16-2330 and 16-16-2335 2331" and "section 16-2332" and inserting the phrases "sections 16-2331 and 16-2332" and "section 16-2333" respectively, in their place 2) Subsection (b)(4) is amended by striking the phrase "section 16-2332" and inserting the phrase "section 16-2333" in its place (f0 Section 16-2341 is amended by striking the phrase "part D in title 4" and insertingSection the phrase "Part D in Title IV" in its place. 16-z341 (gg) Section 16-2345 is amended by striking the phrase "acknowledgment The original" and inserting the phrase "acknowledgement. The original" in its place. S~ction 16-2345 (hh) Section 16-2353(3A) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end. Sectio 16-2353(ii) Section 16-2354(c) is amended by striking the word "relationsip" and inserting theSection word "relationship" in its place. 16-2354 (jj) Section 16-2361(b) is amended by striking the phrase "other wise" and inserting the Sectionword "otherwise" in its place. 16-2361 (kk) Section 16-2362(b) is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, section 16-2329 s~ction 16-2362as renumbered by the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 and inserting the phrase "§ 16-2330 in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL (11) Section 16-2363 is amended by striking the phrase "sections 16-2331 and 16-2332 of Section 16-2363 this chapter, as renumbered by the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 and inserting the phrase "§§ 16-2332 and 16-2333 in its place ram) Section 16-2921 is amended in the fourth sentence by striking the phrase "wholeSeeUon or which" and inserting the phrase "whole of which" in its place. 16-2921 (nn) Section 16-3106 is amended by striking the word "and" and inserting the word "an" Section in its place. 16-3106 (oo) Section 16-3301(b) is amended by striking the word "known" and insetting the word "unknown" in its place. Section16-3301 (pp) Section 16-3907 is amended by striking the word "paments" and inserting the wordSection "payments" in its place. 16-3907 (qq) Section 16-4309 is amended to read as follows: Section "§ 16-4309. Change of award by arbitrators. 16-4309 "On application of a party or, if an application of the Court is pending under section 16- 4310, 16-4311, or 16-4312 on submission to the arbitrators by the Court under such conditions as the Court may order, the arbitrators may modify or correct the award on the grounds stated in section 16-4312(a)(1) and (3 or for the purpose of clarifying the award. The application shall be made within 20 days after delivery of the award to the applicant. Written notice thereof shall be given forthwith to the opposing party, stating he must serve his objections thereto, if any, within 10 days from the notice. The award so modified or corrected is subject to the provisions of sections 16-4310, 16-4311, and 16-4312 Section (rr) Section 16-4317(a)(4) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 16-4317 Sec. 11. Section 17-304(a)(2) of the District of Columbia Code is amended by strikingSection 17-304 the word"Commlss~oner ’ and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place. Sec~ 12. Section 19-113 (c) of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking theSection word "inablility" and inserting the word "inability" in its place. 19-u3 Sec. 13. Title 20 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows: Section (a) Section 20-502(a-1) is amended by adding the phrase "Demand for bond after the20-s02 subsection designation a- 1 b) Section 20-71 l(a) is amended by striking the colon following the phrase "inventorySectio. 20-711 shall c) Section 20-731 (b) is amended as follows: Section (1) By adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a and20-731 (2) By adding the phrase "of this chapter" after the phrase "subchapters II and III d) Section 20-732 is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the 20-732 ENROLLED ORIGINAL phrase "subsection (c 2) Subsection (c) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a e) Section 20-906(a)(4) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Scctio 20-906 (f) Section 20-908(b) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phraseSection "subsection (a 2o-9os (g) Section 20-1104(a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase Scctio subsection (b 2o-11o4 Section(h) Section 20-1303(b)(2) is amended by adding the phrases "of this section" and "of this 20-1303 subsection" after the phrases "subsection (a and "paragraph (1 respectively. Sec. 14. Title 2l of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 21-302 is amended in the section heading by striking the word "jurisdication" Section and inserting the word "jurisdiction" in its place. 21-3o2 (b) Section 21-309(a)(8) is amended as follows: Section (1) By adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraphs (t) 21-309 through (6 and (2) By striking the word "act" and inserting the word "section" in its place c) Section 21-316 is amended by striking the phrase a) A third person" and inserting Section the phrase "A third person" in its place. 21-316 (d) Section 21-317(a)(2) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. S~ctio 21-317 (e) Section 21-318(e) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrases s~¢tio subsection (a and "subsection (c 21-318 (f) Section 21-319(a)(2) is amended by striking the word "personnally" and inserting the Section word "personally" in its place. 21-319 (g) Section 21-320 is amended by striking the phrases a) The custodian shall" and 3) s~ction 21-320 the" and inserting the phrases "The custodian shall" and 3) The" respectively, in their place h) Section 21-321 is amended by striking the phrase a) The District of Columbia seaio~ Uniform Transfer to Minors Act" and inserting the phrase "The District of Columbia Uniform21-321 Transfers to Minors Act" in its place i) Section 21-546 is amended by striking the phrase a) A patient hospitalized" andsectio inserting the phrase "A patient hospitalized" in its place. 21-546 (j) Section 21-56 a) is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the Sectionword "Mayor" in its place. 21-564 (k) Section 21-581 is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" wherever it appears section 21-581 and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place 1) Section 21-584 is amended by striking the word "subpenaed" and inserting the words¢ctio subpoenaed" in its place. 21-584 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (m) Section 21-1111 (a) is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and insertingsectio 21-1111 the word "Mayor" in its place n) Section 21-1114 is amended by striking the phrase "Act (D.C. Code, sec. 6-1651 et sectio seq [§ 6-1901 et seq.],’~ and inserting the phrase "Act of 1978 (D.C. Code § 6-1901 et seq 21-1114 in its place o) Section 21-1115(a) is amended by striking the phrase "Code, sec. 6-1651 et seq S~etio and inserting the phrase "Code § 6-1901 et seq in its place. 21-1n~ Section(p) Section 21-1721 is amended as follows: 21-1721 (1) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "15 USC 801 et seq and inserting the phrase "15 U.S.C 80a-1 et seq in its place 2) Subsection (a- 1)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "15 U.S.C. 80a et seq and inserting the phrase "15 U.SC 80a-1 et seq in its place q) Section 21-1801(a)(4) is amended by striking the word "made" and inserting the Section 21-1801word "make" in its place. Section (r) Section 21-2011(25)(I) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. 21-2on Section (s) Section 21-2042(c) is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (a)(1 and 21-2042 inserting the phrase "subsection (a in its place t) Section 21-2051 (b) is amended by striking the phrase "21-2011 (10 and inserting Section 21-2051 the phrase "21-2011(11 in its place u) Section 21-2057(b) is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (b and insertingsection the phrase "subsection (a in its place. 21-2o57 (v) Section 21-2070(c)(19) is amended by striking the word "uncollectable" and Section inserting the word "uncollectible" in its place. 21-2070 (W) Section 21-2071(4) and (5) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and s~tion 21-2071 inserting the word "section" in its place x) Section 21-2076(a) is amended by striking the phrase "fiduciary stating and Section inserting the phrase "fiduciary stating in its place. 21-2o76 (y) Section 21-2201 is amended by striking the phrase a) The purpose" and insertingsection the phrase "The purpose" in its place. 21-2201 (z) Section 21-2202 is amended by striking the phrase A) A person who" and inserting Sectionthe phrase "A person who" in its place. 21-2202 (aa) Section 21-2205(d) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 21-2204(c and insertingSection 21-2205 the phrase "subsection (c) of this section" in its place. Sec. 15. Section 15 of the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, approved January 24, 1934 (48 Stat. 328; D.C. Code § 25-116 is amended by striking the phrase "residential or first commercial-use district" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "residential or first commercial-use district" in its place. Section 25-116 9 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 16. Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 28:2-209 is amended by striking the word "recission" wherever it appears,Section 28:2-209 including the section heading, and inserting the word "rescission" in its place b) Section 28:9-203(1) is amended by striking the phrase "28-9-116" and inserting the section phrase "28:9-116" in its place. 28:9-203 (c) Section 28:9-302(1)(0 is amended by striking the phrase "28:321" and inserting theSection phrase "28:8-321" in its place. Sec. 17. Section 14(a) of the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-191; D.C. Code § 32-363(a is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, title 1 appendix Sec. 18. Section 16 of the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-191; D.C. Code § 32-365 is amended by striking the phrase "it required" and inserting the phrase "if required" in its place. Sec. 19 a) Section 646 of An Act to establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Star. 1290; D.C. Code § 35-102 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) The Commissioner shall maintain as confidential any documents or information received from the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or insurance departments of other states which is confidential in such other jurisdictions. The Commissioner may share information, including otherwise confidential information, with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or insurance departments of other states so long as such other jurisdictions agree to maintain the same level of confidentiality as is available under District of Columbia law b) The Insurance Confidentiality of Information Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-121; 43 DCR 1538 is repealed. Sec. 20. Section 3(g)(1) of An Act To confer additional jurisdiction upon the Superintendent of Insura~ce for the District of Columbia to regulate domestic stock insurance companies and to exempt such companies from section 12(g)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, approved April 18, 1966 (80 Stat. 123; D.C. Code § 35-213(g)(1 is amended by striking the word "if" at the end. Sec. 21. Section 1(4) of Chapter I of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1128; D.C. Code § 35-302(4 is amended by striking the phrase "Department of Insurance of the District of Columbia" and inserting the phrase "Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation" in its place. Section 32-363 Section 32-365 Section 35-102 Section 35-213 Section 35-302 10 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 22. Chapter II of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1939 (48 Stat. 1129; D.C. Code § 35-401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1 (D.C. Code § 35-401) is amended by striking the word "Superintendents"section 35-401 wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioners" in its place b) Section 16(a D.C. Code § 35-415(a is amended by inserting the word "and" Section before the phrase 2) for nonstock 35-415 (c) Section 23 (D.C. Code § 35-422) is amended by inserting the word "and" before the Section phrase 2) if purchased 35-422 Sec. 23. Chapter V of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1156; D.C. Code § 35-501 et seq is amended as follows: Section(a) Section 5b(j D.C. Code § 35-507(j is amended in the last sentence by striking the35-5o~ phrase "For this section and inserting the phrase 2) For this section in its place b) Section 5c (D.C. Code § 35-508) is amended as follows: Section 35-508(1) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Subsection (k) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 8 (D.C. Code § 35-512) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-512 (d) Section 12 (D.C. Code § 35-517) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (c)(1)(I)(ii) is amended by striking the phrase "insurer and 35-5a~ inserting the phrase "insurer in its place (2) Subsection (h)(2)(A) is amended by striking the word "as" at the end e) Section 26 (D.C. Code § 35-532) is amended as follows: Section 35-532 (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place f) Section 30 (D.C. Code § 35-536) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it 35-536 appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 24. Chapter III of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1143; D.C Code § 35-601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-610) is amended by adding the word "and" after the phrase E) any such option shall not be transferrable except by will or the laws of descent and Section 35-610 11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL distribution b) Section 26 (D.C. Code § 35-626) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-626 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 39 (D.C. Code § 35-637) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-637 (d) Section 40 (D.C. Code § 35-638) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 3~-63s Sec. 25. The Act for the Regulation of Credit Life Insurance and Credit Accident and Health Insurance, approved September 25, 1962 (76 Stat. 580; D.C. Code § 35-1001 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-1002) is amended as follows: Section35-1002 (1) A new paragraph (1A) is inserted to read as follows 1 A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 2) Paragraph (8) is repealed b) Section 6(d D.C. Code § 35-1007(d is amended by striking the phrase "20 days"Section and inserting the phrase "20-days" in its place. 3s-lo07 Sec. 26. Section 763 of Chapter 854 of An Act to establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1310; D.C. Code § 35-1215 is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 27. An Act To authorize fraternal and benevolent corporations heretofore created by special Act of Congress to divide and separate the insurance activities from the fraternal activities by an act of its supreme legislative body, subject to the approval of the Superintendent of Insurance of the District of Columbia, approved April 12, 1930 (46 Stat. 158; D.C. Code § 35-1222 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D. C Code § 35-1223) is amended by striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance of the District of Columbia" and inserting the phrase "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-1225) is amended by striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance" and inserting the phrase "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place, and by adding the word "and" at the end of paragraph (2 Sec. 28. An Act To regulate marine insurance in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1922 (42 Stat. 401; D.C. Code § 35-1401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3(a)(9)(A D.C. Code § 35-1403(a)(9)(A is amended by striking the punctuation at the end and inserting the phrase and" in its place. Section 35-1215 Section 35-1223 Section 35-1225 Section 35-1403 12 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 19(b D.C. Code § 35-1419(b is amended by striking the word Section 35-1419 "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 25 (D.C. Code § 35-1425) is amended by adding the word "and" after the Section phrase E) the rate of the premium 35-1425 (d) Section 27 (D.C. Code § 35-1427) is amended by adding the word "and" after the Section phrase 7) reinsurance received from American companies 35-1427 Sec. 29. The Fire and Casualty Act, approved October 9, 1940 (54 Stat. 1063; D.C. Code § 35-1501 et seq is amended as follows: Section(a) Section 11(1 D.C. Code § 35-1514(1 is amended by adding the word "and" at the 35-1514 end b) Section 16(b D.C. Code § 35-1519(b is amended by striking the word Section "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-1519 (c) Section 41(a)(6 D.C. Code § 35-1545(a)(6 is amended by striking the period at Section the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. 35-1545 (d) Section 52(3 D.C. Code § 35-1552(3 is amended by striking the word Section "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-1552 (e) Section 54 (D.C. Code § 35-1554) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section 35-1554 wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 30. An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved May 20, 1968 (62 Stat. 243; D.C. Code § 35-1701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4(c D.C. Code § 35-1704(c is amended by striking the phrase "10 days" and inserting the phrase "10-days" in its place b) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-1710) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Section 35-1704 Section 35-1710 Sec. 31. The Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992, effective July 22, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1945 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 6(d)(2 D.C. Code § 35-1945(d)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "30 Section 35-1945 days" and inserting the phrase "30-days" in its place b) Section 1 l(b D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1950(b is amended by striking the Section word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-1950 Sec. 32. The Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-155; D.C. Code § 35-2101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1 l(b)(2 D.C. Code § 35-2110(b)(2 is amended by striking the word "Worker’s" and inserting the word "Workers" in its place. Section 35-2110 13 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 12(d) and (f D.C. Code § 35-211 l(d) and (f is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 33. Section 2 of the Drug Abuse, Alcohol Abuse, and Mental Illness Insurance Coverage Act of 1986, effective February 28, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-195; D.C Code § 35-2301 is amended as follows a) A new paragraph (2A) is added to read as follows 2A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities b) Paragraph (21) is repealed. Sec. 34. Section 4 &amp;amp;the Liability Coverage for Child Development Homes Insurance Act of 1990, effective June 13, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-140; D.C Code § 35-2503 is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 35. The Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992, effective October l, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-170; D.C Code § 35-2611 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(6 D.C. Code § 35-2611 (6 is amended by striking the phrases "contract under or 1876" and 42 U.S.C § 13951 or 3995mm and inserting the phrases "contract under section 1876" and 42 U.S.C § 1395mm respectively, in their place b) Section 6(d D.C. Code § 35-2515(d is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting a period in its place. Sec. 36. The Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (DC. Law 10-40; D.C. Code § 35-2701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-2701) is amended to read as follows Sec. 2. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Assessable year" means the calendar year in which the direct gross receipts are received or derived from insurance business in the District of Columbia 1 A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 1B Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation" means the District of Columbia’s regulatory body which is responsible for administering the insurance laws and health maintenance organization laws of the District of Columbia 2 Direct gross receipts" means all policy and membership fees and net premium receipts or consideration received in a calendar year on all insurance risks and annuity contracts originating in or from the District of Columbia. Section 35-2111 Section 35-2301 Section 35-2503 Section 35-2611 Section 35-2515 Section 35-2701 14 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3) Repealed 4 Insurer" means any person, firm, association, or corporation duly licensed in the District of Columbia pursuant to the applicable provisions of District insurance law as an insurer. In addition, Group Hospitalization and Medical Service Incorporated, shall be defined as an insurer 5 Net premium receipts or consideration received" means gross premiums or consideration received less the sum of premiums received for reinsurance assumed and premiums or consideration returned on policies or contracts canceled or not taken 6) Repealed b) Section 5(a D.C. Code § 35-2704(a is amended by striking the phrase "any health" and inserting the phrase "or health" in its place c) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-2709) is amended by striking the phrase "Commissioner and inserting the phrase "Commissioner, the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation in its place. Section 35-2704 Section 35-2709 Sec. 37. The Insurance Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993, effective October 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-35; D.C. Code § 35-2801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-2801) is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (12)(C) and (D) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" 3s-2s01 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Paragraph (13) is amended by adding the phrase "or commissioner" after the word superintendent 3) Paragraph (17) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place b) Section 20(23 D.C. Code § 35-2819(23 is amended by adding the phrase "or section35-2819 commissioner" after the word "superintendent Sec. 38. The Risk Retention Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-46; D.C. Code § 35-2901 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-2901) is amended by striking the phrases 1) Section "Completed operations liability and 1A Commissioner and inserting the phrases 1A)32-2901 "Completed operations liability and 1 Commissioner respectively, in their place b) Section 4(6 D.C. Code § 35-2903(6 is amended by adding the phrase "or Section commissioner" after the word "superintendent 35-2903 Sec. 39. Section 2 of the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-49; DC Code § 35-3601 is amended by striking the phrase 1A Department and inserting the phrase 2A Department in its place. Section 35-3601 15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 40. The Holding Company System Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-44; D.C. Code § 35-3701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3(b)(2)(A D.C. Code § 35-3702(b)(2)(A is amended by striking the Section 35-3702 phrase and" and inserting the phrase and" in its place b) Section 4(b)(1 D.C. Code § 35-3703(b)(1 is amendedby striking the citations Section "35-3704(C)(1 and "35-3704(e)(3 and inserting the citations "35-3704(c and "35-3704(e)"35-3703 respectively, in their place c) Section 4(g)(2 D.C. Code § 35-3703(g)(2 is amended by striking the phrases "20 Section days" and "7 days" and irJserting the phrases "20-days" and "7-days" respectively, in their place. 3s-37o3 Sec. 41. The Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996, effective September 20, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-159; D.C. Code § 35-3721 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-3721) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-3721 wherever its appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-3722) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-3722 (c) Section 4 (D.C Code § 35-3723) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-3723 (d) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-3724) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-3724 Sec. 42. The Insurance Industry Material Transactions Disclosure Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-123; D.C. Code § 35-4101 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4101) is amended as follows: Section 35-4101 (1) By striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance Superintendent and inserting the phrase "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities Commissioner in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place b) Section 4(d)(1 D.C. Code § 35-4103(d)(1 is amended by striking the phrase Section or" and inserting the phrase or" in its place. 35-4103 Sec. 43. The Insurance Demutualization Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-126; D.C. Code § 35-4201 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C Code § 35-4201) is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (1A) is inserted to read as follows 1A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 2) Paragraph (6) is repealed. Section 35-4201 16 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-4202) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-4202 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-4203) is amended as follows: Section (1) By striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance and inserting the phrase 3s-4203 "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place d) Section 5 (D.C Code § 35-4204) is amended by striking the words Section "Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words 35-4204 "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place e) Section 7 (D.C. Code § 35-4206) is amended by striking the words ¯ ¯ SectionSupenntendent’s" and "Superintendent wherever they appear and inserting the words 35-4206 "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place f) Section 8 (D.C. Code § 35-4207) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4207 (g) Section 9 (D.C. Code § 35-4208) is amended by striking the words Section "Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words 35-4208 "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place h) Section 10 (D.C Code § 35,4209) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Sectionand inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4209 (i) Section 11 (D.C. Code § 35-4210) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-4210 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place j) Section 13 (D.C. Code § 35-4212) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4212 Sec. 44. The Insurance Redomestication Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C Law 11-127; D.C. Code § 35-4301 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4301) is amended to read as follows: Section "Sec. 2. Definitions. 35-4301 "For the purposes &amp;amp;this act, the term 1 Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 1A District" means the District of Columbia 2 Redomestication" means the transfer to the District the corporate domicile of an authorized foreign insurance company 3) Repealed 4 Transferring insurer" means any authorized foreign insurance company seeking domestication b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-4303) is amended as follows: Section35-4303 (1) By striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance" and inserting the phrase 17 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-4304) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 45. The Insurance State of Entry Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-128; D.C. Code § 35-4401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4401) is amended to read as follows Sec. 2. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 1A District" means the District of Columbia 2 Non-U. S. insurer" means an insurer organized under the laws of a foreign country. Section 35-4304 Section 35-4401 3) Repealed 4 United States Branch" or "U. S. Branch" means the business unit through which business is transacted within the United States by a non-U. S. insurer and the assets and liabilities of the insurer within the United States pertaining to such business b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-4402) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4402 (c) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-4404) is amended as follows: Section35-4404 (1) By striking the words "Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place; and (2) By striking the phrase f) Refusal or neglect" and inserting the phrase h) Refusal or neglect" in its place d) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 35-4405) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4405 (e) Section 7 (D.C. Code § 35-4406) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner in its place. 35-4406 (f) Section 8 (D.C. Code § 35-4407) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner in its place. 35-4407 Sec. 46. The Health Maintenance Organization Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-235; D.C. Code § 35-4501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(3 D.C. Code § 35-4501(3 is amended by striking the phrase "35-2402 et seq and inserting the phrase "35-2401 et seq in its place. Section 35-4501 18 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 5(b D.C. Code § 35-4504(b is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a)(1 2 or (4 c) Section 13(b)(5 D.C. Code § 35-4512(b)(5 is amended by striking the phrase "liquidation act and inserting the phrase "Insurers Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993, effective May 16, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-35; DC Code § 35-2801 et seq in its place d) Section 18 (D.C. Code § 35-4517) is amended by striking the phrase I) The enrollees" and inserting the phrase c) The enrollees" in its place e) Section 29(a)(5 D.C. Code § 35-4527(a)(5 is amended by striking the colon at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place Section 35-4504 Section 35-4512 Section 35-4517 Section 35-4527 Sec. 47. Section 5(b)(3) of the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-245; D.C. Code § 35-4704(b)(3 is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. Section 35-4704 Sec. 48. Section 4 of An Act To provide for the payment and collection of wages in the District of Columbia, approved August 3, 1956 (70 Stat. 977; D.C. Code § 36-104 is amended by striking the phrase "sections 2 and 4" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "sections 2 and 3" in its place. Section 36-104 Sec. 49. Section 7(e) of the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-186; D.C. Code § 36-1206(e is amended by striking the phrase "1-612.12" and inserting the phrase "1-612.8" in its place. Section 36-1206 Sec. 50. Section 3(a) of the Health Care Expansion Benefits Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-114; D.C. Code § 36-1402(a is amended by striking the phrase "sections 4, 5, 6, and 7 and inserting the phrase "sections 5, 6, and 7 in its place. Section 36-1402 Sec. 51. Section 902 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (DC Law 11-198; D.C. Code § 40-752 is amended by striking the phrase "Sec. 902. The" and inserting the phrase "Sec~ 902.(a) The" in its place. Section 40-752 Sec. 52. Section 10(c) of the Telecommunication Competition Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-154; D.C. Code § 43-1458(c is amended by striking the phrase "and not" and inserting the phrase "or to be" in its place. Section 43-1458 Sec. 53. Section 209(a) of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (DC Law 11-111; D.C. Code § 43-1679(a is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (h and inserting the phrase "subsection (h) of this section in its place. Section 43-1679 19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 54. Section 404(a) of the Condominium Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-89; D.C. Code § 45-1864(a is amended as follows a) Paragraph (13) is amended by striking the word "and at the end b) Paragraph (14) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase and" in its place. Section 45-1864 Sec. 55. The District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-209; D.C. Code § 45-1921 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 45-1922(3 is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (1A) is amended by striking the phrase 1A) The term "associate4s-1922 broker and inserting the phrase 1B) The term "associate broker in its place 2) Paragraph (5C) is amended by striking the phrase 5C) The term "dual agent and inserting the phrase 6A) The term "dual agent in its place 3) Paragraph (6A) is amended by striking the phrase 6A) The term "escrow funds and inserting the phrase 6B) The term "escrow funds in its place 4) Paragraph (TA) is amended by striking the phrase 7A) The term "material fact and inserting the phrase 7B) The term "material fact in its place 5) Paragraph (TB) is amended by striking the term 7B) The term "license and inserting the phrase TA) The term "license in its place b) Section 15a(i)(6 D.C. Code § 45-1934.1 (i)(6 is amended by striking the phrase Section "District of Columbia 45-1934.1 Sec. 56. Section 10(d) of the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 946; D.C. Code § 46-11 l(d is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1)(B) is amended by striking the phrase "or or" and inserting the word "or" in its place b) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase and or" and inserting a period in its place. Sec. 57. Chapter 3 of the Title 47, D.C. Code Enactment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-254; D.C, Code § 47-301 etseq is amended in § 47-317.1 by striking the phrase "§ 47-347.2" and inserting the phrase "§ 47-317.2" in its place. Sec. 58. Chapter 18 of the Title 47, D.C. Code Enactment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C Law 11-254; D.C. Code § 47-1801 et seq is amended by adding section 47- 1801.2 to read as follows § 47-1801.2. Applicability of provisions Taxable years The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the taxable year or part thereof beginning on the 1 st day of January 1947 and to succeeding taxable years Section 46-111 Section 47-317.1 Section 47-1801.2 20 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 59. Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 47-392.25 is amended as follows: section 47-392.25 (1) Subsection (b) is amended as follows A) By striking the phrase "section 2002 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" both times and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2852" in its place; and (B) By striking the phrase "section 2203(d)(2) of such Act" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.13(d)(2 in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase "section 2852(a) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.52(a in its place 3) Subsection (d) is amended as follows A) The lead-in language is amended by striking the phrase "section 2209(b)(1)(B) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "9 31-2853.19(b)(1)(B in its place B) Paragraph (I) is amended by striking the phrase "section 2002 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2852" in its place C) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "section 2209(b)(1)(B) of such Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.19(b)(1)(B in its place b) Section 47-140l(20) is amended by striking the phrase Except and inserting theSection phrase except in its place. 47-1401~ Section (c) Section 47-1446(b) is amended by striking Except and inserting the phrase 47-1446 except in its place d) Section 47-1603 is amended by striking the phrase "47-1501 to 47-1511 and Section’ 47-1603 inserting the phrase "47-1508, 47-1509 in its place. Section(e) Section 47-1604 is amended by striking the phrase "47-1501 to 47-1511 and 47-16o4 inserting the phrase "47-1508, 47-1509 in its place f) Section 47-1813.4(a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "amount the time for Section 47-1813.4payment" and inserting the phrase "amount of time for payment" in its place g) Section 47-2002,3 is amended by striking the phrase "9 9-709" and inserting the Section phrase "9 9-809" in its place. 4%2002.3 (h) Section 47-2202.2(a) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 9-709" and inserting the Section phrase "§ 9-809" in its place. 47-2202.2 (i) Section 47-2753 is amended by striking the phrase "§ 47-2722" and inserting the section 4%2753 phrase "9 47-2752" in its place j) Section 47-2862(a) is amended as follows: section (1) Paragraph (l) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 6-290" and inserting the 47-2s62 phrase "Chapter 29 of Title 6" in its place. 21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phase "§ 6-2911" and inserting the phrase "Chapter 29A of Title 6" in its place. Sec. 60. Section 2 of the BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996, effective April 19, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-250; D.C. Code § 47-845.1 is amended by striking the phrase "Sec. 435a and inserting the phrase "§ 47-845.1. Tax deferral Bureau of National Affairs" in its place. Sec. 61. Section 2(b) of the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pay Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 1997, effective October 23, 1997 (D.C. Law 12-36; 44 DCR 4829 is amended by striking the phrase "Emergency Resolution" wherever it appears in section 1103a and inserting the phrase "Emergency Approval Resolution" in its place. Sec. 62. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 63. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Star 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Council of the District of Columbia Section 47-845.1 Note, Section 1-612.3 District of Columb~ APPROVED: December 22, 1997 22 {)~ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [~[ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICEVOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF File DISTRICT OF COLi’MBIA COUNCIL PERIOD ~VELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Doc~etNo. B12’408 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-4-97 APPROVED A.SE~T JARV I S [ [ ROLL CALL VOTE Result (’ouneilmember Aye Nay NV I AB Coun¢ilmember Chron. Cropp Dixon Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Chavous Patterson x Indicates Vote ~to 1he Council IX[ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I A(-I’ION &amp;amp; DATE Aye ] Nay’ NV ,B Councilmeraber gye Nay’ NV AB Schwartz ’~B J, bsen! CERTIFICATION RE(’ORD Smith, Jr. Thomas, St. 1 NV Present no! Voting ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-4=97 i~ V’OICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Counciimember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous X-inq crates Vote ~y to tbe Cotln¢ll ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember e Nay NV AB Councilmemh¢r Aye Nay NV AB Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson AB-Abscnt CERTIFICATION RECORD Schwartz Smith. Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV-Present aot ~’oting VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Chmn. Cropp Allen A m brose Brazil Chavons Aye Nay NV AB Couneilmember Aye Nay NV AB Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson X Indicates ~ote AB Absent Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV Present not CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary. to the Council Date ENROLLED .ORIGINAL AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 to make grammatical corrections; to amend the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 to make punctuation and stylistic corrections; to amend the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996 to make a cite correction; to amend the District of Columbia Securities Act to make terminology corrections to reflect technical terminology changes mandated by subsequent legislation; to amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1992 to make a technical terminology conforming amendment; to amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1992 to make a typographical correction; to amend the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Act of 1984 to make a grammatical correction; to amend the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978 to make a stylistic correction: to amend Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code to make grammatical, reference, punctuation, spelling, stylistic, terminology, and typographical corrections; to amend Title 17 of the District of Columbia Code to make a terminology correction; to amend Title 19 of the District of Columbia Code to make a typographical correction; to amend Title 20 of the District of Columbia Code to make stylistic and punctuation corrections: to amend Title 21 of the District of Columbia Code to make cite, reference, spelling, punctuation, stylistic, and typographical corrections; to amend the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act to make a stylistic correction; to amend Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code to make cite and spelling corrections; to amend the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996 to make a cite correction: to amend the insurance Confidentiality of Information Act of 1996 to make a terminology correction required by subsequent legislation; to amend An Act To confer additional jurisdiction upon the Superintendent of Insurance for the District of Columbia to regulate domestic stock insurance companies and to exempt such companies from section 12(g)(1) of the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Life Insurance Act to make stylistic, terminology, and grammatical changes; to amend the Ac~ ibr the Regulation of Credit Life Insurance and Credit Accident and Health Insurance to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Fire and Casualty Act to make stylistic, punctuation, and terminology ENROLLED ORIGINAL corrections; to amend An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992 to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982 to make grammatical and terminology corrections; to amend the Drug Abuse, Alco.hol Abuse, and Mental Illness Insurance Coverage Act of 1986 to make terminology corrections: to amend the LiabilitY Coverage for Child Development Homes Insurance Act of 1990 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992 to make cite, grammatical, and stylistic corrections; to amend the Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Insurance Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Risk Retention Act of 1993 to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Law on Examinations Act of 1993 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Holding Company System Act of 1993 to make stylistic corrections; to amend the Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Insurance Industry Material Transactions Disclosure Act of 1996 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Insurance Demutualization Act of 1996 to make terminology corrections; to amend the Insurance Redomestication Act of 1996 to make stylistic and terminology corrections; to amend the Insurance State of Entry Act of 1996 to make terminology and stylistic corrections: to amend the Health Maintenance Organization Act of 1996 to make terminology and stylistic corrections; to amend the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996 to make a punctuation correction; to amend An Act To provide for the payment and collection of wages in the District of Columbia to make a reference correction in the organic law; to amend the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1988 to make a reference correction; to amend the Health Care Expansion Benefits Act of 1992 to make a reference correction; to amend the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Telecommunications Competition Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; to amend the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction: to amend the Condominium Act of 1976 to make stylistic corrections: to amend the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982 to make stylistic corrections: to amend the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act to make stylistic corrections; to amend the Title 47, D.C. Code Enactment Act of 1996 to make a reference correction; to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code to make cite, reference, text, and stylistic corrections; to amend the BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996 to make a stylistic correction; and to amend the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pay Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 to make a reference correction. ENROLLED ORIGINAL amend the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pay Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 1997 to make a reference correction. BE IT ENACTED BY TI~ COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Technical Amendments Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Code § 1-601.1 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 203(b D.C. Code § 1-602.3(b is amended by striking the phrase respectively b) Section 1401 (D.C. Code § 1-615.1 is amended by striking the word "the" after the phrase "the District of Columbia Board of Education Sec. 3. Section 104 of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Code § 1-1181.4 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase "1- l 152 et seq and inserting the phrase "1 1152 et seq in its place b) Paragraph (5A) is amended as follows 1) By striking the phrase SA) Violation" and inserting the phrase 4A) Violation" in its place; and (2) By striking at the end of subparagraph (B) the phrase "bases for disbarment and inserting the phrase "bases for disbarment; or" in its place, Sec. 4. Section 2(3) of the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-134; D.C. Code § 1-227l(3 is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code § 47-1801 el seq and inserting the phrase "DC Code § 47-801 et seq in its place. Section 1-602.3 Section 1-615.1 Section 1-1181.4 Section 1-2271 Sec. 5. The District of Columbia Securities Act, approved August 30, 1964 (76 Stat. 620; D.C. Code § 2-2601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 7(b D.C. Code § 2-2606(b is amended by striking the phrase "SecuritiesSection and Exchange Department" and inserting the phrase "Securities and Exchange Commission" in2-26o6 its place b) Section 10(a)(1)(F D.C. Code § 609(a)(l)(F is amended by striking the phraseSection "Securities and Exchange Department" and inserting the phrase "Securities and Exchange 2-2609 Commission" in its place (c) Section 1 l(a)(3 D.C. Code § 2-2610(a)(3 is amended by striking the phrase "or 2-2610s~cti°n of a Commissioner ENROLLED ORIGINAL (d) Section 15 (D.C. Code § 2-2615) is amended as follows: Section 2-2615 (1) By striking in subsection (f) the phrase "each member of the Commission" and inserting the phrase "the Securities Director" in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Commission" wherever it appears, except as indicated in the amendment to subsection (f) indicated in paragraph (1) above, and inserting the word "Department" in its place e) Section 18 (D.C. Code § 2-2617) is amended by striking the word "Commission" and Section inserting the word "Department" in its place. 2-2617 Sec. 6. Section 2(2)(M) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1992, effective March 17, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-216; D.C. Code § 2-263 l(2)(M is amended by striking the word "Commission" and inserting the word "Department" in its place. Sec. 7. Section 1403 of the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1992, effective April 6, 1992 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Code § 3-214.3 is amended by striking the word "federal" and inserting the word "funeral" in its place. Sec. 8. Section 6a of the District of Columbia Right to Overnight Shelter Act of 1984, effective March 6, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-197: D.C. Code § 3-605.l is amended by striking the phrase "be may" and inserting the phrase "may be" in its place. Sec. 9. Section 501 of the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-137; D.C. Code § 6-1961 is amended by striking the phrase "of funds appropriated for" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "that appropriated funds are available to carry out" in its place. Section 2-2631 Section 3-214.3 Section 3-605.1 Section 6-1961 Sec. 10. Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 16-309 is amended by designating the undesignated paragraph at the end of Sectionsubsection (b beginning with the phrase "In determining whether as a new subsection (b-l)16-309 and is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place b) Section 16-312(a) is amended by striking the word "adoptor" wherever it appears Section 16-312 and inserting the word "adopter" in its place c) Section 16-501(c)(1) is amended by striking the word "Plaintiffs’" and inserting theSection word "plaintiffs" in its place. 16-SOl (d) Section 16-572 is amended by striking the word "Federal" wherever it appears and Section inserting the word "federal" in its place. 16-572 (e) Section 16-703(e) is amended by striking the phrase "section 15-709(b)(2 and Section 16-703 inserting the phrase "section 15-709(b in its place 4 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (f) Section 16-904(b)(3) is amended by striking the word "adultry" and inserting the word "adultery" in its place g) Section 16-916.1 (o)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "part D of title 4" and inserting the phrase "Part D of Title IV" in its place h) Section 16-924(a)(2) is amended by striking the word "ages" and inserting the word "age" in its place i) Section 16-1001 is amended in the lead-in language by striking the word "chapter" and inserting the word "subchapter" in its place j) Section 16-1002(a) and (c) is amended by striking the word "chapter" wherever it appears and inserting the word "subchapter" in its place k) Section 16-1005(f) is amended by striking the word "chapter" and inserting the word "subchapter" in its place 1) Section 16-1021(4) is amended by striking the numeral "1" and inserting the word "one" in its place m) Section 16-1109(b) is amended by striking the word "mense" and inserting the word "mesne" in its place n) Section 16-1112 is amended in the section heading by striking the misspelled word "Expiriation" and inserting the word "Expiration" in its place o) Section 16-1116(2) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end p) Section 16-1321 is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place q) Section 16-1332(a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "in their" and inserting the phrase "in the Mayor’s" in its place r) Section 16-1354 is amending by striking the word "Procedures" and inserting the word "Procedure" in its place s) Section 16-1360 is amended by striking the word "accessing" and inserting the word "assessing" in its place t) Section 16-1908 is amended by striking the word "cutody" and inserting the word "custody" in its place u) Section 16-230l(11) is amended by striking the phrase "section 21-1101 and inserting the phrase "section 21-1101 el seq in its place (v) Section 16-2302 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase "sections 16-2330 through 16-2335" and inserting the phrase "sections 16-2331 through 16-2336" in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the word "than" and inserting the word "then" in its place w) Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking in the table of contents and at the respective section headings the section designations "§ 16- 2305a § 16-2305b and "§ 16-2325a" and inserting the section designations "§ 16-2305.1 Section 16-904 Section 16-916.1 Section 16-924 Section 16-1001 Section 16-1002 Section 16-1005 Section 16-1021 Section 16-1109 Section 16-1112 Section 16-1116 Section 16-1321 Section 16-1332 Section 16-1354 Section 16-1360 Section 16-1908 Section 16-2301 Section 16-2302 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "§ 16-2305.2 and "§ 16-2325.1" respectively, in their place x) Section 16-2305(a) is amended by striking the phrase "Department of Human Section 16-2305 Resources" and inserting the phrase "Department of Human Services" in its place y) Section 16-2305a is amended by striking the section designation "16-2305a" and inserting a new section designation "16-2305.1" in its place z) Section 16-2305b is amended by striking the section designation "16-2305b"’and Section inserting a new section designation "16-2305.2" in its place. 16-230s.2 (aa) Section 16-2309(a) is amended as follows: Section16-2309 (1) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrases "Department &amp;amp;Human Resources" and "section 107(b) of the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977" and inserting the phrases "Department of Human Services" and "§ 6-2105(b respectively, in their place 2) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase "Department &amp;amp;Human Resources" and inserting the phrase "Department of Human Services" in its place bb) Section 16-2315(c)(1) and (3) is amended by striking the phrase "section 6- Section 1902(b and inserting the phrase "section 6-1902(2 in its place. 16-231s (cc) Section 16-2322(e) is amended by striking the phrase "section 16-2334" and Section inserting the phrase "section 16-233 5" in its place. 16-2322 Section (dd) Section 16-2331 (b)(3) is amended by striking the word "duty" and inserting the 16-2331 word "duly" in its place ee) Section 16-2335 is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrases "sections 16-2330 and 16-16-233s 2331" and "section 16-2332" and inserting the phrases "sections 16-2331 and 16-2332" and "section 16-2333" respectively, in their place 2) Subsection (b)(4) is amended by striking the phrase "section 16-2332" and inserting the phrase "section 16-2333" in its place if) Section 16-2341 is amended by striking the phrase "part D in title 4" and insertingSection the phrase "Part D in Title IV" in its place. 16-2341 (gg) Section 16-2345 is amended by striking the phrase "acknowledgment The original" and inserting the phrase "acknowledgement. The original" in its place. Section 16-2345 (hh) Section 16-2353(3A) is amended by striking the word "and" at the end. Section 16-2353(ii) Section 16-2354(c) is amended by striking the word "relationsip" and inserting theSection word "relationship" in its place. 16-2354 (jj) Section 16-2361(b) is amended by striking the phrase "other wise" and inserting the Sectionword "otherwise" in its place. 16-2361 (kk) Section 16-2362(b) is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, section 16-2329 Section 16-2362as renumbered by the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 and inserting the phrase "§ 16-2330 in its place. Section ¯ 16-2305.1 6 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (I1) Section 16-2363 is amended by striking the phrase "sections 16-2331 and 16-2332 of Section 16-2363 this chapter, as renumbered by the Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977 and inserting the phrase "§§ 16-2332 and 16-2333 in its place mm) Section 16-2921 is amended in the fourth sentence by striking the phrase "wholesection or which" and inserting the phrase "whole of which" in its place 16-2921 (nn) Section 16-3106 is amended by striking the word "and" and inserting the word "an" Section in its place. 16-3106 (oo) Section 16-33 01 (b) is amended by striking the word "known" and inserting the word "unknown" in its place. Section16-3301 (pp) Section 16-3907 is amended by striking the word "paments" and inserting the wordSection "payments" in its place. 16-39o7 (qq) Section 16-4309 is amended to read as follows: Section "§ 16-4309. Change of award by arbitrators. 16-4309 "On application of a party or, if an application of the Court is pending under section 16- 4310, 16-4311, or 16-4312 on submission to the arbitrators by the Court under such conditions as the Court may order, the arbitrators may modify or correct the award on the grounds stated in section 16-4312(a)(1) and (3 or for the purpose of clarifying the award. The application shall be made within 20 days after delivery of the award to the applicant. Written notice thereof shall be given forthwith to the opposing party, stating he must serve his objections thereto, if any, within 10 days from the notice. The award so modified or corrected is subject to the provisions of sections 16-4310, 16-4311, and 16-4312 Section (rr) Section 16-4317(a)(4) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. 16-4317 Sec. 11. Section 17-304(a)(2) of the District of Columbia Code is amended by strikingSection 17-304 the word "Commissioner" and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place. Sec. 12. Section 19-113(c) of the District of Columbia Code is amended by striking theSection word "inablility" and inserting the word "inability" in its place. 19-113 Sec. 13. Title 20 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows: Section (a) Section 20-502(a-1) is amended by adding the phrase "Demand for bond aider thez0-~02 subsection designation a- 1 Section(b) Section 20-71 l(a) is amended by striking the colon following the phrase "inventory20-711 shall c) Section 20-73 l(b) is amended as follows: section (1) By adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a and20-731 (2) By adding the phrase "of this chapter" after the phrase "subchapters I1 and III d) Section 20-732 is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the 20-732 ENROLLED ORIGINAL phrase "subsection (c 2) Subsection (c) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase "subsection (a e) Section 20-906(a)(4) is amended by adding the word "and" at the end. Sectio 20-906 (f) Section 20-908(b) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phraseSection "subsection (a 20-90s (g) Section 20-1104(a) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrase Section "subsection (b 20-11o4 (h) Section 20-1303(b)(2) is amended by adding the phrases "of this section" and "of this Section20-1303 subsection" after the phrases "subsection (a and "paragraph (1 respectively. Sec. 14. Title 21 of the District &amp;amp;Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 21-302 is amended in the section heading by striking the word "jurisdication"Seaion and inserting the word "jurisdiction" in its place. 21-302 (b) Section 21-309(a)(8) is amended as follows: Section (1) By adding the phrase "of this subsection" after the phrase "paragraphs (1) 21-309 through (6 and (2) By striking the word "act" and inserting the word "section" in its place c) Section 21-316 is amended by striking the phrase a) A third person" and inserting Section the phrase "A third person" in its place. 21-316 (d) Section 21-317(a)(2) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. section 21-317 (e) Section 21-318(e) is amended by adding the phrase "of this section" after the phrases section "subsection (a and "subsection (c 21-31s (f) Section 21-319(a)(2) is amended by striking the word "personnally" and inserting the Section word "personally" in its place. 21-319 (g) Section 21-320 is amended by striking the phrases a) The custodian shall" and 3) Section 21-320 the" and inserting the phrases "The custodian shall" and 3) The" respectively, in their place h) Section 21-321 is amended by striking the phrase a) The District of Columbia Section Uniform Transfer to Minors Act" and inserting the phrase "The District of Columbia Uniform21-321 Transfers to Minors Act" in its place i) Section 21-546 is amended by striking the phrase a) A patient hospitalized" andSection inserting the phrase "A patient hospitalized" in its place 21-546 (j) Section 21-564(a) is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and inserting the Sectionword "Mayor" in its place. 21-564 (k) Section 21-581 is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" wherever it appears Section 21-581and inserting the word "Mayor" in its place (l) Section 21-584 is amended by striking the word "subpenaed" and inserting the wordscctio subpoenaed" in its place. 21-584 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (m) Section 21-111 l(a) is amended by striking the word "Commissioner" and insertingSection 21-1111 the word "Mayor" in its place n) Section 21-1114 is amended by striking the phrase "Act (D.C. Code, sec. 6-1651 et Section seq [§ 6-t901 et seq.] and inserting the phrase "Act of 1978 (D.C. Code § 6-1901 et seq 21-1114 in its place o) Section 21-1115(a) is amended by striking the phrase "Code, sec. 6-1651 et seq Section and inserting the phrase "Code § 6-1901 et seq in its place. 21-1n5 Section(p) Section 21-1721 is amended as follows: 21-1721 (1) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "15 USC 80a et seq and inserting the phrase "15 U.S.C. 80a-1 et seq in its place 2) Subsection (a-l)(1) is amended by striking the phrase "15 U.S.C. 80a et seq and inserting the phrase "15 U.S.C. 80a-1 et seq in its place q) Section 21-1801(a)(4) is amended by striking the word "made" and inserting the Section 21-1801word "make" in its place. Section (r) Section 21-2011(25)(I) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end. 21-2011 Section (s) Section 21-2042(c) is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (a)(1 and 21-2042 inserting the phrase "subsection (a in its place t) Section 21-205 l(b) is amended by striking the phrase "21-2011(10 and inserting Smion 21-2051 the phrase "21-2011(11 in its place u) Section 21-2057(b) is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (b and insertingsection the phrase "subsection (a in its place. 21-2o57 (v) Section 21-2070(c)(19) is amended by striking the word "uncollectable" and Section inserting the word "uncollectible" in its place. 21-2070 (w) Section 21-2071(4) and (5) is amended by striking the word "subsection" and section 21-2071 inserting the word "section" in its place x) Section 21-2076(a) is amended by striking the phrase "fiduciary stating and Section inserting the phrase "fiduciary stating in its place 21-2076 (y) Section 21-2201 is amended by striking the phrase a) The purpose" and insertingSection the phrase "The purpose" in its place 21-22o z) Section 21-2202 is amended by striking the phrase A) A person who" and inserting Sectionthe phrase "A person who" in its place 21-2202 (aa) Section 21-2205(d) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 21-2204(c and inserting Section 21-2205 the phrase "subsection (c) of this section" in its place. Sec. 15. Section 15 of the Alcoholic Beverage Control Act, approved January 24, 1934 (48 Star. 328; D.C. Code § 25-116 is amended by striking the phrase "residential or first commercial-use district" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "residential or first commercial-use district" in its place. Section 25-116 9 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 16. Title 28 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 28:2-209 is amended by striking the word "recission" wherever it appears, including the section heading, and inserting the word "rescission" in its place b) Section 28:9-203(1) is amended by striking the phrase "28-9-116" and inserting the phrase "28:9-116" in its place c) Section 28:9-302(1)(0 is amended by striking the phrase "28:321" and inserting the phrase "28:8-321" in its place. Sec. 17. Section 14(a) of the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-191; D.C. Code § 32-363(a is amended by striking the phrase "D.C. Code, title 1 appendix Sec. 18. Section 16 of the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-191; D.C. Code § 32-365 is amended by striking the phrase "it required" and inserting the phrase "if required" in its place. Sec. 19 a) Section 646 of An Act to establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1290; D.C. Code § 35-102 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows e) The Commissioner shall maintain as confidential any documents or information received from the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or insurance departments of other states which is confidential in such other jurisdictions. The Commissioner may share information, including otherwise confidential information, with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or insurance departments of other states so long as such other jurisdictions agree to maintain the same level of confidentiality as is available under District of Columbia law b) The Insurance Confidentiality of Information Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-121; 43 DCR 1538 is repealed Sec. 20. Section 3(g)(1) of An Act To confer additional jurisdiction upon the Superintendent of Insurance for the District of Columbia to regulate domestic stock insurance companies and to exempt such companies from section 12(g)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, approved April 18, 1966 (80 Star. t23~ D.C. Code § 35-213(g)(1 is amended by striking the word "it" at the end. Sec. 21. Section 1(4) of Chapter I of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1128; D.C. Code § 35-302(4 is amended by striking the phrase "Department of Insurance of the District of Columbia" and inserting the phrase "Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation" in its place. Section 28:2-209 Section 28:9-203 Section 28:9-302 Section 32-363 Section 32 -36S Section 35-102 Section 35-213 Section 35-302 10 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 22. Chapter II of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1939 (48 Stat. 1129; D.C. Code § 35-401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1 (D.C. Code § 35-401) is amended by striking the word "Superintendents"Section 35-401 wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioners" in its place b) Section 16(a D.C. Code § 35-415(a is amended by inserting the word "and" Sectio before the phrase 2) for nonstock 35-415 (c) Section 23 (D.C. Code § 35-422) is amended by inserting the word "and" before the Section phrase 2) if purchased 35-422 Sec. 23. Chapter V of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1156; D.C. Code § 35-501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 5b(j D.C. Code § 35-507(j is amended in the last sentence by striking theSectio,,35-507 phrase "For this section and inserting the phrase 2) For this section in its place b) Section 5c (D.C. Code § 35-508) is amended as follows: Section 35-508(1) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Subsection (k) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 8 (D.C. Code § 35-512) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-5a2 (d) Section 12 (D.C. Code § 35-517) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (c)(1)(I)(ii) is amended by striking the phrase "insurer and 35-517 inserting the phrase "insurer in its place 2) Subsection (h)(2)(A) is amended by striking the word "as" at the end e) Section 26 (D.C. Code § 35-532) is amended as follows: sectio. 35-532 (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place f) Section 30 (D.C. Code§ 35-536) is amended as follows: Section (1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it~5-536 appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 24. Chapter Ill of the Life Insurance Act, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1143; D.C. Code § 35-601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-610) is amended by adding the word "and" after the phrase E) any such option shall not be transferrable except by will or the laws of descent and Section 35-610 11 ENROLLED ORIGINAL distribution b) Section 26 (D.C. Code § 35-626) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-626 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 39 (D.C. Code § 35-637) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-637 (d) Section 40 (D.C. Code § 35-638) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 3s-638 Sec. 25. The Act for the Regulation of Credit Life Insurance and Credit Accident and Health Insurance, approved September 25, 1962 (76 Stat. 580; D.C. Code § 35-1001 et seq is amended as follows: Section(a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-1002) is amended as follows: 3s-1002 (1) A new paragraph (1A) is inserted to read as follows 1 A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 2) Paragraph (8) is repealed b) Section 6(d D.C. Code § 35-1007(d is amended by striking the phrase "20 days"Section and inserting the phrase "20-days" in its place. 35-1007 Sec. 26. Section 763 of Chapter 854 of An Act to establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1310; D.C. Code § 35-1215 is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 27. An Act To authorize fraternal and benevolent corporations heretofore created by special Act of Congress to divide and separate the insurance activities from the fraternal activities by an act of its supreme legislative body, subject to the approval of the Superintendent of Insurance of the District of Columbia, approved April 12, 1930 (46 Stat. 158; D.C. Code § 35-1222 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-1223) is amended by striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance of the District of Columbia" and inserting the phrase "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-1225) is amended by striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance" and inserting the phrase "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place, and by adding the word "and" at the end of paragraph (2 Sec. 28. An Act To regulate marine insurance in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1922 (42 Star. 401 D.C. Code § 35-1401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3(a)(9)(A D.C. Code § 35-1403(a)(9)(A is amended by striking the punctuation at the end and inserting the phrase and" in its place. Section 35-1215 Section 35-1223 Section 35-1225 Section 35-1403 12 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 19(b D.C. Code § 35-1419(b is amended bv striking the word Section~ 35-1419 "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 25 (D.C. Code § 35-1425) is amended by adding the word "and" after the Section phrase E) the rate of the premium 35-1425 (d) Section 27 (D.C. Code § 35-1427) is amended by adding the word "and" after the Section phrase 7) reinsurance received from American ~ompanies 35-1427 Sec. 29. The Fire and Casualty Act, approved October 9, 1940 (54 Stat. 1063; D.C. Code § 35-1501 et seq is amended as follows: Section(a) Section 11 (1 D.C. Code § 35-1514(1 is amended by adding the word "and" at the 35-1514 end b) Section 16(b D.C. Code § 35-1519(b is amended by striking the word Section 35-1519"Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 41(a)(6 D.C. Code § 35-1545(a)(6 is amended by striking the period at Section the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. 35-1545 (d) Section 52(3 D.C. Code § 35-1552(3 is amended by striking the word ¯ Section Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35q552 (e) Section 54 (D.C. Code § 35-1554) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-1554 wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 30. An Act To provide for regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved May 20, 1968 (62 Stat. 243; D.C. Code § 35-1701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4(c D.C. Code § 35-1704(c is amended by striking the phrase "10 days" and inserting the phrase "10-days" in its place (b) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-1710) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Section 35-1704 Section 35-1710 Sec. 31. The Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992, effective July 22, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1945 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 6(d)(2 D.C. Code § 35-1945(d)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "30 Section 35-1945 days" and inserting the phrase "30-days" in its place (b) Section l l(b D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1950(b is amended by striking the Section word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-1950 Sec. 32. The Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-155; D.C Code § 35-210l et seq is amended as follows a) Section 1 l(b)(2 D.C. Code § 35-2110(b)(2 is amended by striking the word "Worker’s" and inserting the word "Workers" in its place. Section 35-2110 13 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 12(d) and (f D.C. Code § 35-211 l(d) and (f is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 33. Section 2 of the Drug Abuse, Alcohol Abuse, and Mental Illness Insurance Coverage Act of 1986, effective February 28, 1987 (D.C. Law 6-195; D.C. Code § 35-2301 is amended as follows a) A new paragraph (2A) isadded to read as follows 2A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities b) Paragraph (21) is repealed. Sec. 34. Section 4 of the Liability Coverage for Child Development Homes Insurance Act of 1990, effective June 13, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-140; D.C. Code § 35-2503 is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 35. The Medicare Supplement Insurance Minimum Standards Act of 1992, effective October 1, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-170; D.C. Code § 35-2611 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(6 D.C. Code § 35-2611(6 is amended by striking the phrases "contract under or 1876" and 42 U.S.C. § 13951 or 3995mm and inserting the phrases "contract under section 1876" and 42 U.S.C. § 1395mm respectively, in their place b) Section 6(d D.C. Code § 35-2515(d is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by adding the word "or" at the end 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting a period in its place. Sec. 36. The Insurance Regulatory Trust Fund Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-40; D.C. Code § 35-2701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-2701) is amended to read as follows Sec. 2. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Assessable year" means the calendar year in which the direct gross receipts are received or derived from insurance business in the District of Columbia 1A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 1B Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation" means the District of Columbia’s regulatory body which is responsible for administering the insurance laws and health maintenance organization laws of the District of Columbia 2 Direct gross receipts" means all policy and membership fees and net premium receipts or consideration received in a calendar year on all insurance risks and annuity contracts originating in or from the District of Columbia. Section 35-2111 Section 35-2301 Section 35-2503 Section 35-2611 Section 35-2515 Section 35-2701 14 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3) Repealed 4 Insurer" means any person, firm, association, or corporation duly licensed in the District of Columbia pursuant to the applicable provisions of District insurance law as an insurer. In addition, Group Hospitalization and Medical Service Incorporated, shall be defined as an insurer 5 Net premium receipts or consideration received" means gross premiums or consideration received less the sum of premiums received for reinsurance assumed and premiums or consideration returned on policies or contracts canceled or not taken 6) Repealed b) Section 5(a D.C. Code § 35-2704(a is amended by striking the phrase "any health" and inserting the phrase "or health" in its place c) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-2709) is amended by striking the phrase "Commissioner and inserting the phrase "Commissioner, the Department of Insurance and Securities Regulation in its place. Section 35-2704 Section 35-2709 Sec. 37. The Insurance Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993, effective October 15, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-35; D.C. Code § 35-2801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-2801) is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (12)(C) and (D) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" 3s-2s01 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 2) Paragraph (13) is amended by adding the phrase "or commissioner" after the word "superintendent 3) Paragraph (17) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place (b) Section 20(23 D.C. Code § 95 819(23 is amended by adding the phrase "or Section 35-2819 commissioner" after the word "superintendent" Sec. 38. The Risk Retention Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-46; D.C. Code § 35-2901 el seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-2901) is amended by striking the phrases 1) Section "Completed operations liability and IA Commissioner and inserting the phrases 1A) ss-2~o Completed operations liability and 1 Commissioner respectively, in their place b) Section 4(6 D.C. Code § 35-2903(6 is amended by adding the phrase "or Section commissioner" after the word "superintendent" 3s-2903 Sec. 39. Section 2 of the Law on Examinations Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C Law I0-49; D.C. Code § 35-3601 is amended by striking the phrase 1A Department and inserting the phrase 2A Department in its place. Section 35-3601 15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 40. The Holding Company System Act of 1993, effective October 21, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-44; D.C. Code § 35-3701 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 3(b)(2)(A D.C. Code § 35-3702(b)(2)(A is amended by striking the Section 35-3702 phrase and" and inserting the phrase and" in its place b) Section 4(b)(1 D.C. Code § 35-3703(b)(1 is amended by striking the citations Section "35-3704(c)(1 and "35-3704(e)(3 and inserting the citations "35-3704(c and "35-3704(e)"35-3703 respectively, in their place c) Section 4(g)(2 D.C. Code § 35-3703(g)(2 is amended by striking the phrases "20Section days" and "7 days" and inserting the phrases "20-days" and "7-days" respectively, in their place. 35-3703 Sec. 41. The Mutual Holding Company Act of 1996, effective September 20, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-159; D.C. Code § 35-3721 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-3721) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section3S-3721 wherever its appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-3722) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-3722 (c) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-3723) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-3723 (d) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-3724) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place 35-3724 Sec. 42. The Insurance Industry Material Transactions Disclosure Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-123; D.C. Code § 35-4101 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4101) is amended as follows: section 35-4101 (1) By striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance Superintendent and inserting the phrase "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities Commissioner in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place b) Section 4(d)(1 D.C. Code § 35-4103(d)(1 is amended by striking the phrase Section or" and inserting the phrase or" in its place 35-4103 Sec. 43. The Insurance Demutualization Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-126; D.C. Code § 35-4201 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4201)is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (1A) is inserted to read as follows 1 A Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 2) Paragraph (6) is repealed. Section 35-4201 16 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-4202) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"sectto. 35-4202 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-4203) is amended as follows: sectio 1) By striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance and inserting the phrase. 3s-42o3 "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place d) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-4204) is amended by striking the words Section "Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words 3s-4204 "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place e) Section 7 (D.C. Code § 35-4206) is amended by striking the words Section"Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words 3s-4206 "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place f) Section 8 (D.C. Code § 35-4207) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place¯ 35-4207 (g) Section 9 (D.C. Code § 35-4208) is amended by striking the words Section "Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words 3s-420s "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place h) Section 10 (D.C. Code § 35-4209) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4209 (i) Section 11 (D.C. Code § 35-4210) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section 35-4210 and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place j) Section 13 (D.C. Code § 35-4212) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Section and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4212 Sec 44¯ The Insurance Redomestication Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C¯ Law 11-127; D.C. Code § 35-4301 etseq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4301) is amended to read as follows: Section "Sec. 2. Definitions, 35-4301 "For the purposes &amp;amp;this act, the term 1 Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 1A District" means the District of Columbia 2 Redomestication" means the transfer to the District the corporate domicile of an authorized foreign insurance company 3) Repealed 4 Transferring insurer" means any authorized foreign insurance company seeking domestication b) Section 4 (D.C. Code § 35-4303) is amended as follows: Section35-4303 (1) By striking the phrase "Superintendent of Insurance" and inserting the phrase 17 ENROLLED ORIGINAL "Commissioner of Insurance and Securities" in its place; and (2) By striking the word "Superintendent" and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place c) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-4304) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. Sec. 45. The Insurance State of Entry Act of 1996, effective May 24, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-128; D.C. Code § 35-4401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 35-4401) is amended to read as, follows Sec. 2. Definitions For the purposes of this act, the term 1 Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Insurance and Securities 1 A District" means the District of Columbia 2 Non-U.S. insurer" means an insurer organized under the laws of a foreign country. Section 35-4304 Section 35-4401 3) Repealed 4 United States Branch" or "U.S. Branch" means the business unit through which business is transacted within the United States by a non-U.S, insurer and the assets and liabilities of the insurer within the United States pertaining to such business b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 35-4402) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner" in its place. 35-4402 (c) Section 5 (D.C. Code § 35-4404) is amended as follows: Section35-4404 (1) By striking the words "Superintendent’s" and "Superintendent" wherever they appear and inserting the words "Commissioner’s" and "Commissioner" respectively, in their place; and (2) By striking the phrase f) Refusal or neglect" and inserting the phrase h) Refusal or neglect" in its place d) Section 6 (D.C. Code § 35-4405) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner in its place. 35-4405 (e) Section 7 (D.C. Code § 35-4406) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent"Section wherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner in its place. 35-4406 (f) Section 8 (D¯C. Code § 35-4407) is amended by striking the word "Superintendent" Sectionwherever it appears and inserting the word "Commissioner in its place¯ 35-4407 Sec. 46. The Health Maintenance Organization Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-235; D.C. Code § 35-4501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(3 D.C. Code § 35-4501(3 is amended by striking the phrase "35-2402 et seq and inserting the phrase "35-2401 el seq in its place. Section 35-4501 18 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (b) Section 5(b D.C. Code § 35-4504(b is amended by adding the phrase "of this Section 35-4504 section" after the phrase "subsection (a)(1 2 or (4 c) Section 13(b)(5 D.C. Code § 35-4512(b)(5 is amended by striking the phrase Section "liquidation act and inserting the phrase "Insurers Rehabilitation and Liquidation Act of 1993,35-4512 effective May 16, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-35; D.C. Code § 35-2801 et seq in its place d) Section 18 (D.C. Code § 35-4517) isamended by striking the phrase 1) The Section enrollees" and inserting the phrase c) The enrollees" in its place. 35-4517 Section(e) Section 29(a)(5 D.C. Code § 35-4527(a)(5 is amended by striking the colon at 35-4527 the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. Sec. 47. Section 5(b)(3) of the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-245; D.C. Code § 35-4704(b)(3 is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. Sec. 48. Section 4 of An Act To provide for the payment and collection of wages in the District of Columbia, approved August 3, 1956 (70 Stat. 977; D.C. Code § 36-104 is amended by striking the phrase "sections 2 and 4" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase "sections 2 and 3" in its place. Sec. 49. Section 7(e) of the District of Columbia Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D C. Law 7-186; D.C. Code § 36-1206(e is amended by striking the phrase "1-612.12" and inserting the phrase "1-612.8" in its place. Sec. 50. Section 3(a) of the Health Care Expansion Benefits Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-114; D.C. Code § 36-1402(a is amended by striking the phrase "sections 4, 5, 6, and 7 and inserting the phrase "sections 5, 6, and 7 in its place. Sec. 51. Section 902 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-198; D.C. Code § 40-752 is amended by striking the phrase "Sec. 902. The" and inserting the phrase "Sec 902.(a) The" in its place. Sec. 52. Section 10(c) of the Telecommunication Competition Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-154; D.C. Code § 43-1458(c is amended by striking the phrase "and not" and inserting the phrase "or to be" in its place. Sec. 53. Section 209(a) of the Water and Sewer Authority Establishment and Department of Public Works Reorganization Act of 1996, effective April 18, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-111; D.C. Code § 43-1679(a is amended by striking the phrase "subsection (h and inserting the phrase "subsection (h) of this section in its place. Section 35-4704 Section 36-104 Section 36-1206 Section 36-1402 Section 40-752 Section 43-1458 Section 43-1679 19 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 54. Section 404(a) of the Condominium Act of 1976, effective March 29, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-89; D.C. Code § 45-1864(a is amended as follows a) Paragraph (13) is amended by striking the word "and at the end b) Paragraph (14) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase and" in its place. Section 45-1864 Sec. 55. The District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-209; D.C. Code § 45-1921 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 45-1922(3 is amended as follows: Section (1) Paragraph (1A) is amended by striking the phrase 1A) The term "associate4s-1922 broker and inserting the phrase 1B) The term "associate broker in its place 2) Paragraph (5C) is amended by striking the phrase 5C) The term "dual agent and inserting the phrase 6A) The term "dual agent in its place 3) Paragraph (6A) is amended by striking the phrase 6A) The term "escrow funds and inserting the phrase 6B) The term "escrow funds in its place 4) Paragraph (TA) is amended by striking the phrase TA) The term "material fact and inserting the phrase 7B) The term "material fact in its place 5) Paragraph (TB) is amended by striking the term 7B) The term "license and inserting the phrase 7A) The term "license in its place b) Section 15a(i)(6 D.C. Code § 45-1934.1 (i)(6 is amended by striking the phrase Section "District of Columbia 4S-1934.1 Sec. 56. Section 10(d) of the District of Columbia Unemployment Compensation Act, approved August 28, 1935 (49 Stat. 946; D.C. Code § 46-11 l(d is amended as follows a) Paragraph B) is amended by striking the phrase "or or" and inserting the word "or" in its place b) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase and or" and inserting a period in its place Sec. 57. Chapter 3 of the Title 47, DC Code Enactment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-254; D.C. Code § 47-301 et seq is amended in § 47-317.1 by striking the phrase "9 47-347.2" and inserting the phrase "§ 47-317.2" in its place. Sec 58. Chapter t8 of the Title 47, D.C Code Enactment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (DC. Law 11-254; D.C. Code § 47-1801 etseq is amended by adding section 47- 1801.2 to read as follows § 47-1801.2. Applicability of provisions Taxable years The provisions of this chapter shall apply to the taxable year or part thereof beginning on the 1st day of January 1947 and to succeeding taxable years ¯Section 46-111 Section 47-317.1 Section 47-1801.2 2O ENROLLED ORIGINAL Sec. 59. Title 47 of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows a) Section 47-392.25 is amended as follows: Section 47-392.25 (1) Subsection (b) is amended as follows A) By striking the phrase "section 2002 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" both times and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2852" in its place; and (B) By striking the phrase "section 2203(d)(2) of such Act" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.13(d)(2 in its place 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase "section 2852(a) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.52(a in its place 3) Subsection (d) is amended as follows A) The lead-in language is amended by striking the phrase "section 2209(b)(1)(B) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.19(b)(1)(B in its place B) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "section 2002 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2852" in its place C) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "section 2209(b 1 B) of such Act of 1995" and inserting the phrase "§ 31-2853.19(b)(1)(B in its place b) Section 47-1401(20) is amended by striking the phrase Except and inserting the Section phrase except in its place. 47-1401 ’ Section (c) Section 47-1446(b) is amended by striking Except and inserting the phrase 47-1446 except in its place d) Section 47-1603 is amended by striking the phrase "47-1501 to 47-1511 and Section 47-1603 inserting the phrase "47-1508, 47-1509/’ in its place. Section(e) Section 47-1604 is amended by striking the phrase "47-1501 to 47-1511 and 47-16o4 inserting the phrase "47-1508, 47-1509 in its place (f) Section 47-1813.4(a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "amount the time for Section 47-1813.4payment" and inserting the phrase "amount of time for payment" in its place g) Section 4%20023 is amended by striking the phrase "§ 9-709" and inserting the Section phrase "§ 9-809" in its place. 47-2002.3 (h) Section 47-2202.2(a) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 9-709" and inserting the Section phrase "§ 9-809" in its place. 47-2202.2 (i) Section 47-2753 is amended by striking the phrase "§ 47-2722" and inserting the Section~ 47-2753 phrase "§ 47-2752" in its place j) Section 47-2862(a) is amended as follows Section (1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "§ 6-290" and inserting the 47-286z phrase "Chapter 29 of Title 6" in its place. 21 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phase "§ 6-2911" and inserting the phrase "Chapter 29A of Title 6" in its place. Sec. 60. Section 2 of the BNA Washington, Inc Real Property Tax Deferral Amendment Act of 1996, effective April 19, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-250; D.C. Code § 47-845.1 is amended by striking the phrase "Sec. 435a and inserting the phrase "§ 47-845.1. Tax deferral Bureau of National Affairs" in its place. Sec. 61. Section 2(b) of the Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act Pay Limit Temporary Amendment Act of 1997, effective October 23, 1997 (D.C. Law 12-36; 44 DCR 4829 is amended by striking the phrase "Emergency Resolution" wherever it appears in section 1103a and inserting the phrase "Emergency Approval Resolution" in its place. Sec. 62. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Star. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 Sec. 63. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved. December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register ’is, Council of the District of Columbia Section 47-845.1 Note, Section 1-612.3 Mayor District of Columbia 22 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COl NCIL PERIOD "I’WELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE Doeke, No. B12-408 ADOPTED FIRST READING, 11-4-97 APPROVED JA RV I S ROLL CALL VOTE Result &amp;amp;ye Nay NV AB Councilmember{ our~cilmembcr Chmn. Cropp Dixon Allen Evans Ambrose Jarvis Brazil Mason Chavous Patterson t ’ Indicates Vote L ¢ltetar)’ to Ihe Council (’ouncilmeraber &amp;amp;.se Na~ NV &amp;amp;B Schwartz ~mith. Jr. Thomas, Sr amp;B hsenl ~’ N~,’ Present nol Vo{ia~ Date ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACIION &amp;amp; DATE CERTII-I( x I ION REX ORD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 12-4-97 VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQI:EST ~BSENT APPROVED ALL PRESENT ROLL C.XLL X’OTE Result (ouncilmemher Chmn. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous [ I ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR [ I IION &amp;amp; I)~FE ¯ e Nay NV &amp;amp;B ouncilmember e \a~ NX xB (ouncdmember Aye Nay Dixon Schwartz Evans Smith. Jr. Jarvis Thomas. St. Mason Patterson B-&amp;amp;bsent (’ERTD-I( t 11o’, RE(ORD L/ Dale ’ ICE t. OTE RE(’ORI)ED OTE 0% REQt EST gBSENT I ROLL (’~I.L OTE Result (’ounctlmemher Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil } Cha~ous t ¢~1 Na N kB (ouncdmember ~r Nas NX gB nuncilmember &amp;amp  Nay NV Dixon Schwartz Esans Smith, Jr. Ja~’is Thomas. St. Mason Patterson B bsent ¢ER1 IFICA FION RECORD Secretar to the Council Dale</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
