<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-8">
  <num type="law">12-8</num>
  <heading type="short">DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA REGIONAL AIRPORTS AUTHORITY AMENDMENT ACT OF 1997</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1997-08-01</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-8.pdf">D.C. Law 12-8</citation>
      <citation type="register">44 DCR 3371</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0146"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLMENT(S) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-8 "District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Amendment Act of 1997 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-146, on first and second readings, April 29, 1997 and May 15, 1997, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on May 20, 1997, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-80 and published in the June 13, 1997, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 44 page 3371) and transmitted to Congress on June 11, 1997 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-8, effective August 1, 1997. LINDA W. CROPP Acting Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: June 11,12,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26,27 July 7,8,9,10,11,14,15,16,17,21,22,23,24,25,28,29,30,31 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C. ACT 12-80 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA MAY 2O, 1997 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985 to increase the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority from 11 members to 13 members. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Amendment Act of 1997 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Regional Airports Authority Act of 1985, effective December 3, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-67; D.C. Code § 7-1101, note is amended as follows a) Section 5 is amended to read as follows See. 5. Membership; terms; officers a) The Authority shall consist of 13 members appointed as follows: 5 appointed by the Governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 3 appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia, 2 appointed by the Governor of the State of Maryland, and 3 appointed by the President of the United States. Members representing the District of Columbia shall be subject to confirmation by the Council of the District of Columbia. For the purposes of doing business, 7 members shall constitute a quorum. The failure of a single appointing official to appoint 1 or more members, as provided in this act, shall not impair the Authority’s creation when the other conditions of this creation have been met b) Members shall not hold elective or appointive public office, shall serve without compensation, and shall reside within the Washington Standard Metropolitan Statistical Area, except that the members appointed by the President of the United States shall be registered voters of states other than Maryland or Virginia or the District of Columbia. Members of the Authority shall be entitled to reimbursement of their expenses incurred in attending the meetings of the Authority or while otherwise engaged in the discharge of their duties c) Appointments to the Authority shall be for a period of 6 years, except that initial appointments shall be made as follows: each jurisdiction shall appoint 1 member for a full 6- Note, Section 07-1101 ENROLLED ORIGINAL year term, a second member for a 4-year term, and in the case of the Commonwealth of Virginia and the District of Columbia, a third member for a 2-year term. The Governor of Virginia shall make the final 2 Virginia initial appointments for one 2-year term and one 4-year term. The President shall make one of his initial appointments pursuant to the Metropolitan Washington Airports Amendments Act of 1996, approved October 9, 1996 (110 Stat. 3213 for a 4-year term. The President shall make subsequent appointments for 6-year terms d) Eight affirmative votes shall be required to approve bond issues and the annual budget of the Authority e) Each member may be removed or suspended from office only for cause and in accordance with the laws of the jurisdiction from which the member is appointed f) The Authority shall elect annually 1 of its members as chairman and another as vice-chairman and shall also elect annually a secretary and a treasurer, or a secretary-treasurer, who may or may not be members of the Authority. The Authority shall prescribe the powers and duties of these officials. The Authority may also appoint from its staff an assistant secretary and an assistant treasurer, or an assistant secretary-treasurer, who shall, in addition to other duties, discharge such functions of the secretary and the treasurer g) A vacancy among the members shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made. Members of the Authority shall continue to serve until their successors are duly appointed. Any person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the unexpired term. Any member of the Authority shall be eligible for reappointment for 1 additional term h) Members of the Authority, including any nonvoting members, shall not be personally liable for any act done or action taken in their capacities as members of the Authority, nor shall they be personally liable for any bond, note, or other evidence of indebtedness issued by the Authority b) Section 6(5) is amended by striking the phrase "and to establish a board of review Sec. 3. Enactment of this act will have no fiscal impact on the District of Columbia. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Self- ENROLLED ORIGINAL Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code §1-233~(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register ti~)g Chairman Couricil of the District of Columbia District of Columb?A~ APPROVED: May 20, 1997 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-146Docket No. ADOPTED FIRST READING, 04-29-97 APPROVED ABSENT CHAVOUS AND SMITH ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Chmn. Jarvis Evans Thomas, Sr. Allen Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz Cropp Smith, Jr. x lndicat~Vote Seci Re Council ]~ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR AB Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD ACTION &amp;amp; DATE NV Present not Voting7 ADOPTED FINAL READING, 05-15-97 I~VOICE VOTE RECORDEDVOTEONREQUEST APPROVED ABSENT ALLEN, MASON, AND SMITH ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmember Chmn. Cropp Jarvis AlLen Evans Am brose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz l f~)l .li l 1 X"imllicntes n° Aye Nay NV AB AB-Absent CERTIFICATION RECORD Coullcilmember Aye Nay NV AB Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr D~aP~c~-Present not voting t [ ] VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT ROLL CALL VOTE-Result Councilmember Aye Nay NV AB Councilmem~r Aye Nay NV AB Counciimem~r Aye Nay NV AB Chron. Cropp Jarvis Allen Evans Ambrose Mason Brazil Patterson Chavous Schwartz X Indicates Vote AB Al~ent Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV Pre~ent not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secretary to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
