<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 12-90">
  <num type="law">12-90</num>
  <heading type="short">Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 1998</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1998-04-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/12-90.pdf">D.C. Law 12-90</citation>
      <citation type="register">45 DCR 1308</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B12-0167">
      <narrative>Law 12-90, the “Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 1998,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 12-167, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 4, 1997, and January 6, 1998, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 26, 1998, it was assigned Act No. 12-263 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 12-90 became effective on April 29, 1998.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENR LLMENT(S) kwiktag 062 326 013 (5) COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D.C. LAW 12-90 "Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 1998" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 "the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 12-167, on first and second readings, December 4, 1997 and January 6, 1998, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on January 26, 1998, pursuant to Section 404(e) of "the Act and was assigned Act No. 12-263, and published in the March 13, 1998, edition of the D.C. Register (Vol. 45 pagel308) and transmitted to Congress on February 27, 1998 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and therefore, cites this enactment as D.C. Law 12-90, effective April 29, 1998. LINDA W. CROPP Chairman of the Council Dates Counted During the 30-day Congressional Review Period: Feb. 27 Mar. 2,3,4,5,6,9,10,11,12,13,16,17,18,19,20,23,24,25,26 27,30,31 Apr. 1,21,22,23,24,27,28 ENROLLED ORIGINAL AN ACT D.C, ACT !2-263 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA JANUARY 26, 1998 Codification District of Columbia Code 1998 Supp. To amend the Illegal Dumping Enforcement Act of 1994 to define terms, to make the unlawful disposal of solid waste for a commercial purpose a felony, to make the unlawful disposal of medical waste a felony, and to increase the criminal penalty for the unlawful disposal of hazardous waste. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 1998 Sec. 2. The Illegal Dumping Enforcement Act of 1994, effective November 20, 1993 (D.C. Law 10-62; D.C. Code § 6-2911 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Code § 6-2911) is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (1) is added to read as follows 1 Commercial purpose" means for the purpose of a person’s economic gain 2) The existing paragraph (1) is redesignated as (1A 3) A new paragraph (2A) is added to read as follows 2A Hazardous waste" means any waste or combination of wastes of a solid, liquid, contained gaseous, or semisolid form which, because of its quantity, concentration, or physical, chemical, or infectious characteristics, as established by the Mayor, may A) Cause, or significantly contribute to an increase in mortality or an increase in serious irreversible, or incapacitating, reversible, illness; or (B) Pose a substantial present or potential hazard to human health or the environment when improperly treated, stored, transported, or disposed of, or otherwise managed. Such wastes include, but are not limited to, those which are toxic, carcinogenic, flammable, irritants, strong sensitizers, or which generate pressure through decomposition, heat, or other means, as well as containers and receptacles previously used in the transportation, storage, use or application of the substances described as a hazardous waste 4) A new paragraph (3A) is added to read as follows: Section 6-2911 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3A Medical waste" means solid waste from medical research, medical procedures, or pathological, industrial, or medial laboratories. Medical waste includes, but is not limited to, the following types of solid waste A) Cultures and stocks of infectious agents and associated biologicals, including cultures from medical and pathological laboratories, cultures and stocks of infectious agents from research and industrial laboratories, wastes from the production ofbiologicals, discarded live and attenuated vaccines, and culture dishes and devices used to transfer, inoculate, and mix cultures B) Pathological waste, including tissues, organs, and body parts that are removed during surgery or autopsy C) Human blood waste and products of blood, including serum, plasma, and other blood components D) Sharps that have been used in patient care or medical research, or industrial laboratories, including hypodermic needles, syringes, pasteur pipettes, broken glass, and scalpel blades E) Contaminated animal carcasses, body parts, and bedding of animals that were exposed to infectious agents during research, production ofbiologicals, or testing of pharmaceuticals F) Waste from surgery or autopsy that was in contact with infectious agents, including soiled dressings, sponges, drapes, lavage tubes, drainage sets, underpads, and surgical gloves G) Laboratory waste from medical, pathological, pharmaceutical, or other research, commercial, or industrial laboratories that was in contact with infectious agents, including slides, and cover slips, disposable gloves, laboratory coats, and aprons H) Dialysis waste that was in contact with the blood of patients undergoing hemodialysis, including contaminated disposable equipment and supplies such as tubing, filters, disposable sheets, towels, gloves, aprons, and laboratory coats I) Discarded medical equipment and parts that were in contact with infectious agents J) Biological waste and discarded materials contaminated with blood, excretion, exudates and secretion from human beings or animals who are isolated to protect others from communicable diseases; and K) Such other waste material that results from the administration of medical care to a patient by a health care provider and is found by the Mayor to pose a threat to human health or the environment 5) Paragraph 6 is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting in its place a new sentence to read as follows 6 Solid waste" means combustible or incombustible refuse b) Section 3 (D.C. Code § 6-2912) is amended as follows: 2 ENROLLED ORIGINAL (1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows a) It shall be unlawful for any person to dispose or cause or permit the disposal of solid waste, hazardous waste, or medical waste in or upon any street, lot, park, public place, or any other public or private area, whether or not for a commercial purpose, unless the site is authorized for the disposal of solid waste, hazardous waste or medical waste by the Mayor 2) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows b)(1) Any person who violates subsection (a) of this section shall be liable to arrest 2) Any person who disposes of solid waste which is neither hazardous nor medical waste in violation of subsection (a) of this section, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $1,000 for each offense, or shall be imprisoned for a period not to exceed 90 days, or both. Any person who disposes of solid waste for a commercial purpose shall be guilty of a felony, and shall be subject to a fine for each offense not to exceed $25,000, or shall be imprisoned for a period not to exceed 5 years, or both 3) Any person who knowingly disposes of hazardous waste in violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be guilty of a felony, and subject to a fine for each offense not to exceed $25,000, and a term of imprisonment not to exceed 5 years 4) Any person who knowingly disposes &amp;amp;medical waste in violation of subsection (a) of this section shall be guilty of a felony, and subject to a fine for each offense not to exceed $25,000, and a term of imprisonment not to exceed 5 years Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the Committee Report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(3 See. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203 (a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat.~116; D.C. Code § 47-392.3(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Section 6-2912 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Code § 1-233(c)(1 and publication in the District ~er C~rman f/ Council of the District of Columbia District of Columbi~~’~ APPROVED: January 26, 1998 4 ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR ACTION &amp;amp; DATE COUNCIL OF TIlE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA COUNCIL PERIOD TWELVE RECORD OF OFFICIAL COUNCIL VOTE B12-167 Docket No, ADOPTED FIRST READING, 12-4-97 VOICE VOTE RECORDED ~OTE ON REOUEST APPROVED ABSENT ALL PRESENT I ] ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye [ Nay NV AB IChron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Chavous IX ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR iX ACTION &amp;amp; DATE Councilmem bet Dixon Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson %as NV AB Councilmember A_ve Na? NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. tar)’ to the (ER I Itl( il ilO% Rt]{()RD ADOPTED FINAL READING, 1-6-98 IX VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST APPROVED ,ABSENT ALL PRESENT ROLL CALL VOTE Result Councilmember Aye Nay Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania ~’~ X IndicatesTo’e Sle~retary to the Council [ [ ITEM ON CONSENT CALENDAR I I ACFION &amp;amp; DATE NV AB (’ouncilmrmher e %a? NS SB Chavous Evans Jarvis Mason Patterson SB h~rnt ouncilmember Aye Na NV AB Schwartz Smith, Jr. Thomas, Sr. NV-Preseut not voting (ERI I F I 1 I0% RE( ORD I "l VOICE VOTE RECORDED VOTE ON REQUEST ABSENT I I ROLL ALL VOTE- Result (’ouncilmember Chron. Cropp Allen Ambrose Brazil Catania I e Nay NV AB (’ouncilmrmber r %a~ [ NS’ AB (’ouncilmember Aye Na NV AB Chavous Schwartz X Indicates Vote Evans Smith, Jr. Jarvis Thomas, Sr. Mason Patterson AB Absent NV Present not Voting CERTIFICATION RECORD Secreta~’ to the Council Date</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
