<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-204.112</num>
  <heading>Process.</heading>
  <text>Any elected officer of the District of Columbia government (except the Delegate to Congress for the District of Columbia) may be recalled by the registered electors of the election ward from which he or she was elected or by the registered electors of the District of Columbia at large in the case of an at-large elected officer, whenever a petition demanding his or her recall, signed by 10 percent of the registered electors thereof, is filed with the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics. The 10 percent shall be computed from the total number of the registered electors from the ward, according to the latest official count of registered electors by the Board of Elections and Ethics which was issued 30 or more days prior to submission of the signatures for the particular recall petition. In the case of an at-large elected official, the 10 percent shall include 10 percent of the registered electors in each of 5 or more of the City’s wards. The District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics shall hold an election within 114 days of its receipt of a petition as provided in <cite path="§1-204.102">§ 1-204.102</cite>. If a previously scheduled general, primary, or special election will occur between 54 and 114 days of its receipt of a petition as provided in <cite path="§1-204.102">§ 1-204.102</cite>, then the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics may present the recall question at that election.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-46" type="History" path="§2">Mar. 10, 1978, D.C. Law 2-46, § 2, 24 DCR 199</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-1" type="History">June 7, 1979, D.C. Law 3-1, § 5, 25 DCR 9454</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 1-192.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-292.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
