<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-301.155</num>
  <heading>Financial reporting.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No later than December 1, 2014, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, until the approval of the Fiscal Year 2016 budget and financial plan, the Chief Financial Officer shall provide a report to the Council on the following subjects:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Progress toward ensuring that the Fiscal Year 2016 budget will be balanced, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Savings achieved to date;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Additional revenue certified through revised revenue estimates; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Additional revenue that may be certified through revenue enhancements;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An analysis of procurement reform efforts in Fiscal Year 2014, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Contracts reviewed for potential cost savings;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Savings secured through the renegotiation of existing contracts; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>A report from the Office of Contracting and Procurement to the Chief Financial Officer regarding subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph,</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An analysis of personnel review efforts, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Positions left vacant or eliminated as a result of cost-savings initiatives; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Savings secured through personnel savings; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any other operating budget savings achieved or targeted in Fiscal Year 2014.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Agencies shall report on their progress toward limiting personal and nonpersonal expenditures whether one-time or recurring.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History" path="§1142">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §  1142, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of section, see §  1142 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of section, see §  1142 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of section, see §§  1142 and 1143 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
