<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>1-325.231</num>
  <heading>Bank Fees Special Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Bank Fees Special Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Chief Financial Officer in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Beginning October 1, 2013, the following sources shall be deposited into the Fund:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All interest earned on public funds under the custody of the Chief Financial Officer in a general fund account that is not otherwise restricted; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Such amounts from the unassigned General Fund of the District of Columbia balance as may be required to pay bank fees and charges, as they come due, in excess of the interest earned on public funds as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used to pay bank fees and charges.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History" path="§7042">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 7042, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7041 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Bank Fees Special Fund Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7042 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 7042 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
