<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-1817.02</num>
  <heading>Tax credit for Qualified High Technology Company employment relocation costs; exceptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term “relocation costs” means amounts paid to, or on behalf of, a qualified employee:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>For reimbursement of actual moving expenses; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To assist the employee in financing the purchase of a residence, or the required security deposit or lease payments for the first 12 months of a lease for a residence under a lease of at least one year, which purchase or lease is entered into after December 31, 2000.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2000, a Qualified High Technology Company shall be allowed a credit not to exceed:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>$5,000 against the tax imposed by <cite path="§47-1817.06">§ 47-1817.06</cite> for the relocation costs for each qualified employee relocated to the District from a location outside the District; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>$7,500 against the tax imposed by <cite path="§47-1817.06">§ 47-1817.06</cite> for the relocation costs for each qualified employee relocated to the District from a location outside the District, which employee also relocates his or her principal residence into the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The credit may be claimed for costs incurred after December 31, 2000, in connection with qualified employees relocated to the District after that date.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The annual credit under subsection (b) of this section shall not exceed, in the aggregate:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>$250,000 for the credit allowed under subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>$1,000,000 for the credit allowed under subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The credit under subsection (b) of this section shall not be allowed:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Until the Qualified High Technology Company relocates at least 2 qualified employees into the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Until the Qualified High Technology Company has employed the qualified employee for at least 6 months in the District;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>As a credit for employees who work less than 35 hours per week;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>If the qualified employee is a member of the board of directors of the Qualified High Technology Company, directly or indirectly owns a majority of its stock, or is related to a member of the board of directors or a majority stockholder as a spouse, domestic partner, or a relative listed in the definition of “dependent” in section 152 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, without regard to source of income; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>If the Qualified High Technology Company has claimed a deduction for the relocation costs.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If the amount of the credit allowable under this section exceeds the tax otherwise due from a Qualified High Technology Company, the unused amount of the credit may be carried forward for 10 years.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-256" type="History">Apr. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 13-256, § 201(b), 48 DCR 730</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-231" type="History">Sept. 12, 2008, D.C. Law 17-231, § 41(n), 55 DCR 6758</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-231">D.C. Law 17-231</cite>, in subsec. (c)(2)(D), substituted “spouse, domestic partner,” for “spouse”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
