<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-2901</num>
  <heading>Discrimination because of race or color prohibited in licensed places of amusement; penalty.</heading>
  <text>It shall not be lawful for any person or persons who shall have obtained a license from this Corporation for the purpose of giving a lecture, concert, exhibition, circus performance, theatrical entertainment, or for conducting a place of public amusement of any kind, to make any distinction on account of race or color, as regards the admission of persons to any part of the hall or audience room where such lecture, concert, exhibition, or other entertainment may be given; provided, that any person applying shall pay the regular price charged for admission to such part of the house as he or she may wish to occupy, and shall conduct himself or herself in an orderly and peaceable manner, while on the premises; and any person or persons offending herein shall forfeit and pay to this Corporation for each offense a fine of not less than $10 nor more than $20 to be collected and applied as are other fines. That all acts or parts of acts inconsistent with this section be, and the same are hereby repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 10, 1869, ch. 36, p. 22, Corp. Laws of Wash., 66th Council, §§ 1, 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Extension of section’s area of applicability: Order No. 56-874, dated May 3, 1956, issued by Commissioners of the District of Columbia, extended the area of applicability of this section to the District of Columbia outside the limits of the City of Washington.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-2901.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-2901.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§47-2903">§ 47-2903</cite> and <cite path="§47-2904">§ 47-2904</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Discriminatory practices in public accommodations, prohibition, see <cite path="§2-1402.31">§ 2-1402.31</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
