<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-340.07</num>
  <heading>Financing and closing documents.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council approves the financing documents to which the District is a party in substantially the form in which these documents are filed by the Council with the Office of the Secretary to the Council, and authorizes the Mayor to make modifications to these documents that are within the limitations of the Home Rule Act, and that the Mayor considers appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to prescribe the final form and content of all financing documents and all closing documents to which the District is a party that may be necessary or appropriate to issue, sell, and deliver bonds and to make loans to applicants. Each of the financing documents and each of the closing documents to which the District is not a party shall be approved, as to form and content, by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to execute in the name of the District, and on its behalf, any financing documents and any closing documents to which the District is a party by the Mayor’s manual or facsimile signature.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The official seal of the District, or a facsimile of it, shall be impressed, printed, or otherwise reproduced on the financing documents and the closing documents to which the District is a party.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor’s execution and delivery of the financing documents and the closing documents to which the District is a party shall constitute conclusive evidence of the Mayor’s approval, on behalf of the District, of the final form and content of the executed financing documents and the executed closing documents.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to deliver the executed and sealed financing documents and closing documents, on behalf of the District, prior to or simultaneously with the issuance, sale, and delivery of the bonds, and to ensure the due performance of the obligations of the District contained in the executed, sealed, and delivered financing documents and closing documents.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-46" type="History">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-46, § 8, 42 DCR 3603</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-340.7.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
