<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-4665.01</num>
  <heading>The Advisory Board Company — definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of §§ <cite path="§47-4665.02">47-4665.02</cite> through <cite path="§47-4665.05">47-4665.05</cite>, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Abatement period” means October 1, 2020, through September 30, 2030, the time during which the incentive will be applied.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Accumulated New District Resident Hires” is the goal for Net New District FTE Hires pursuant to the incentive agreement.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Annual reporting date” means September 30 preceding every tax year of the Abatement Period.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Company” means The Advisory Board Company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Community Benefits Agreement” means the agreement entered into between the Mayor and the Company pursuant to <cite path="§47-4665.04">§ 47-4665.04</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“District resident” means an FTE whose principal place of residence is located within the District and who is on the annual reporting date subject to District personal income tax.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“FTE” means an employee of the Company, or one of its subsidiaries or affiliates, who is eligible for the full employee healthcare benefits of the Company, or its applicable subsidiary or affiliate, in accordance with its standard policies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Incentive agreement” means the agreement entered into between the Mayor and the Company outlining the Company’s incentive requirement, which shall include incentives for hiring 1,000 Net New District FTE Hires.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“Lease commencement” means the date on which the Company occupies the Property with its employees.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Lease execution” means the date on which the Company signs the lease for the Property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Net New District FTE Hires” means the aggregate number of District residents whose primary workplace is located in the District in excess of the resident employment baseline.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“Project” means the initial tenant improvements to the premises located on the Property undertaken by the Company or its contractor to construct the space for initial occupancy.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Property” means Lots 25, 39, 41, 800, 825, 830, 831, and 832, Square 450.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Resident employment baseline” means the total number of District residents whose primary workplace is located in the District, as established in the incentive agreement, as of the date of the lease execution.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“Total employment baseline” means the total number of FTEs, whose primary workplace is located in the District, as established in the incentive agreement, as of the date of the lease execution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-71" type="History">Feb. 26, 2016, D.C. Law 21-71, § 2(b), 63 DCR 1</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
