<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>47-405</num>
  <heading>Certificate of taxes and assessments due; furnishment; fee.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall furnish whenever called upon, a certified statement of all taxes and assessments, general and special, that may be due at the time of making the certificate; and the certificate when furnished shall be a bar to the collection and recovery from any subsequent purchaser of any tax or assessment omitted from and which may be a lien upon the real property mentioned in the certificate, and the lien shall be discharged as to such subsequent purchaser, but shall not affect the liability of the person who owned the real property at the time such tax was assessed to pay the same, mentioned in the certificate. The Mayor shall collect a fee for each certificate of taxes issued.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to taxes and assessments, general and special, for which a lien has been recorded at the Recorder of Deeds.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to taxes owed, or which shall be owed, under <cite path="§47-850.02|(c)|(2)">§ 47-850.02(c)(2)</cite> or <cite path="§47-863|(g)|(2)">§ 47-863(g)(2)</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c-1)</num>
    <text>This section shall not apply to real property taxes deferred under §§ <cite path="§47-845">47-845</cite>, <cite path="§47-845.01">47-845.01</cite>, <cite path="§47-845.02">47-845.02</cite>, and <cite path="§47-845.03">47-845.03</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The certified statement may be furnished in the form of a physical certificate or via an electronic medium, at the discretion of the Mayor. When furnished via an electronic medium, a digital signature shall be deemed a signature and official seal for purposes of subsection (a) of this section; provided, that in the absence of the digital signature, the last update to the electronic file as evidenced by the records of the Mayor, immediately prior to transfer of the real property for which the certified statement was obtained, shall be deemed the certified statement.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 6, 1879, 20 Stat. 283, ch. 50</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">May 13, 1892, 27 Stat. 37, ch. 74</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1917, 39 Stat. 1005, ch. 160</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1925, 43 Stat. 1222, ch. 477</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 25, 1938, 52 Stat. 1202, ch. 702, § 11</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-57" type="History">Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-57, § 2, 24 DCR 5426</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-254" type="History">enacted, Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-254, § 2, 44 DCR 1575</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-305" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-305, § 508(e)(1), 48 DCR 334</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-282" type="History">Apr. 4, 2003, D.C. Law 14-282, § 11(b), 50 DCR 896</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct, 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 1143(a), 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 1143(a), 1144 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(b) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-510, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 10247).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(b) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-456, July 23, 2002,  49 DCR 8107).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 12(b) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-381, June 6, 2002,  49 DCR 5674).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8(e)(1) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-22, March 16, 2001,  48 DCR 2706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(b) of Tax Clarity and Related Amendments Temporary Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-228">D.C. Law 14-228</cite>, March 23, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2741).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 12(b) of Tax Clarity and Recorder of Deeds Temporary Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-191">D.C. Law 14-191</cite>, October 5, 2002, law notification  49 DCR 9549).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 8(e)(1) of Real Property Tax Clarity and Litter Control Administration Temporary Amendment Act of 2001 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-8">D.C. Law 14-8</cite>, June 13, 2001, law notification  48 DCR 5916).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> added subsec. (c-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-282">D.C. Law 14-282</cite>, in subsec. (b), substituted “Subsection (a) of this section” for “This section”; and added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The Collector of Taxes shall furnish whenever called upon, a certified statement, over his hand and official seal, of all taxes and assessments, general and special, that may be due at the time of making said certificate; and said certificate when furnished shall be a bar to the collection and recovery from any subsequent purchaser of any tax or assessment omitted from and which may be a lien upon the real estate mentioned in said certificate, and said lien shall be discharged as to such subsequent purchaser, but shall not affect the liability of the person who owned the property at the time such tax was assessed to pay the same, mentioned in said certificate. The charge for each certificate of taxes so issued shall be $6.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-305">D.C. Law 13-305</cite> rewrote the section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 47-306.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 47-405.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 1144 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> provided that §§ 1142 and 1143 shall apply to tax periods beginning after September 30, 2005.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Office of Collector of Taxes abolished: See Historical and Statutory Notes following <cite path="§47-401">§ 47-401</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
