<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>43-114</num>
  <heading>Distance from City and from dwellings.</heading>
  <text>No person or persons or cemetery association shall lay out any new cemetery, or part of any cemetery, within the City of Washington, in the District of Columbia, nor in said District, within one and one-half miles from the boundaries of said City; no person or cemetery association shall, in said District, lay out any cemetery, or part of any cemetery, within less than 200 yards of any dwelling house, except with the written consent of the owner, lessee, and occupant of such house, nor without a permit to do so from the Mayor of said District.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 3, 1901, 31 Stat. 1295, ch. 854, § 670</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 26, 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§43-115">43-115</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 27-114.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 27-114.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
