<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-115">
  <num type="act">26-115</num>
  <num type="bill">26-189</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Tranquility Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Residential Tranquility Act of 2010 to prohibit persons targeting a residence for purposes of demonstration from using sound amplifying devices in a residential zone between 7:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m., to prohibit the use of unattended sound amplifying devices emitting sound while targeting a residence, and to prohibit a person from launching or throwing an object onto the residential property of another with the intent to cause fear, intimidate, or harass any person living or working at that residence; and to amend the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997 to provide that the term expiration date for a Council appointment to the Corrections Information Council shall be December 7th of the year in which the term expires.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-03-24</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2025-11-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57415/Signed_Act/B26-0189-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=217821">D.C. Act 26-115</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 8167</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0189">
      <vote date="2025-06-17" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-07-21</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-189 would prohibit persons targeting a residence for purposes of a demonstration from using sound amplifying devices in a residential zone between 7:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m. It would also prohibit a person from launching or throwing a projectile onto the residential property of another with the intent to cause fear, intimidate, or retaliate against the occupants of that residence. It also clarifies the term expiration date for a Council appointment to the Corrections Information Council. </summary>
      <committee>Judiciary and Public Safety</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Residential Tranquility Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Residential Tranquility Act of 2010, effective May 26, 2011 (D.C. Law 18- 374; D.C. Official Code § 22-2751 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 22-2751) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase ", for the purpose of persuading one or more individuals, or the public, or to protest some action, attitude, or belief." and inserting a period in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "human beings" and inserting the word "individuals" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (4) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>"Sound amplifying device" means any machine, device, or loudspeaker that amplifies sound of the human voice, music, or any other sound. The term "sound amplifying device" shall not include automobile audio systems when used and heard only by the occupants of the vehicle in which the automobile audio system is installed.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 22-2752) is amended by adding new subsections (a-1), (a-2), (a-3), and (a-4) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(a-1)</num>
          <text>It is unlawful for a person to target a residence for purposes of a demonstration by using a sound amplifying device between 7:00 p.m. and 9:00 a.m. where the targeted residence is, in fact, located in a Residential Zone, Residential Flat Zone, or Residential Apartment Zone, as those terms and Zones are defined at the time of the of the conduct giving rise to the violation in the District of Columbia Zoning Regulations.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(a-2)</num>
          <text>It is unlawful to leave an unattended sound amplifying device emitting sound to target a residence for purposes of a demonstration where the targeted residence is, in fact, located in a Residential Zone, Residential Flat Zone, or Residential Apartment Zone, as those terms and Zones are defined at the time of the of the conduct giving rise to the violation in the District of Columbia Zoning Regulations.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(a-3)</num>
          <text>It is unlawful to continue or resume targeting a residence in violation of subsection (a-1) or (a-2) of this section after being instructed by a law enforcement officer to cease targeting a residence in violation of this law.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(a-4)</num>
          <text>The Mayor and Metropolitan Police Department may seize and impound any unattended sound amplifying devices targeting a residence for purposes of a demonstration in violation of subsection (a-2) of this section.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new section 3a is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <num>3a</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Throwing objects at residential property.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>It is unlawful for any person to knowingly launch or throw an object onto the residential property of another with the intent to cause fear, intimidate, or harass any person living or working at that residence.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>A person who violates this section, upon conviction, shall be fined no more than the amount set forth in section 101 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Amendment Act of 2012, effective June 11, 2013 (D.C. Law 19-317; D.C. Official Code § 22-3571.01), or incarcerated for no more than 90 days, or both.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 11201a(b)(2) of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, effective October 2, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-233; D.C. Official Code § 24-101.01(b)(2)), is amended by adding a new subparagraph (B-1) to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="2">
      <text>(B-1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the term expiration date for a Council appointment to the Corrections Information Council shall be December 7th of the year in which the term expires.</text>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 60-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
