<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-161">
  <num type="act">26-161</num>
  <num type="bill">26-305</num>
  <heading type="short">Peace DC Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, Title 6-A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to make conforming changes; to amend the Metropolitan Police Department Application, Appointment, and Training Requirements Act of 2000 to allow applicants for sworn officers of the Metropolitan Police Department to count certain credit hours for completion of the initial training program towards the requirement that certain applicants complete 60-hours of post-secondary education at an accredited college or university; to amend section 23-581 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify the authority of Metropolitan Police Department warrantless arrest requirements; to amend the Act to Regulate Public Conduct on Public Passenger Vehicles to provide that the adjudication of fare evasion citations shall be pursuant to the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985; to amend Chapter 8 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify that offenses eligible in the future for automatic sealing are currently eligible for sealing by motion; to amend the Secure DC Omnibus Amendment Act of 2024 to amend the sunset date of certain provisions regarding pretrial detention; to amend the Criminal Justice Coordination Council for the District of Columbia Establishment Act of 2011 to change the deadline for certain reports; and to amend the Clemency Board Waiver Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2025 to clarify the effective date.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-06-30</introduced>
    <effective>2025-10-23</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/58059/Signed_Act/B26-0305-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=225580">D.C. Act 26-161</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0305">
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-10-07" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-10-23</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Peace DC Omnibus Temporary Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 1101 of Title 6A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (6A DCMR §1101), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The section heading is amended by striking the phrase "SECTION 4-114" and inserting the phrase "SECTION 5-129.02" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection 1101.1 is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "Code §4-114 (1981)" wherever it appears and insert the phrase "Code § 5-129.02" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 202(e)(1) of the Metropolitan Police Department Application, Appointment, and Training Requirements Act of 2000, effective October 4, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-160; D.C. Official Code § 5-107.01(e)(1)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>Successfully completed 60 hours of post-secondary education at an accredited college or university; except, that, if the Metropolitan Police Department enters into an agreement with an accredited college or university to award credit hours to recruits successfully completing the Department's initial training program for recruits, an applicant may satisfy up to 20 credits of the 60-credit hour requirements by earning credits through the initial training program for recruits;</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>Section 23-581(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (2) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (C) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Theft of property valued less than $250" and insert the phrase "Theft of property that has some value" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "section 111 [D.C. Official Code, § 22-3211]" and insert the phrase "section 112 [D.C. Official Code § 22-3212(b)]" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (D) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "Theft of property valued in excess of $250" and insert the phrase "Theft of property valued at $1,000 or more; Theft twice or more in a 6-month period with an aggregate value of $1,000 or more" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "section 111 [D.C. Official Code, § 22-3211]" and insert the phrase "section 112(a) [D.C. Official Code § 22-3212(a)]" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (E) is amended by striking the phrase "Unauthorized Disposal of Solid Waste" and inserting the phrase "Unauthorized disposal of solid waste, hazardous waste, or medical waste" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (3) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "section 9(b-1) (D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.04(b-1))" and insert the phrase "section 9(c) (D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.04(c))" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "section 10(b) (D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.05(b)) [Repealed]" and insert the phrase "section 3b (D.C. Official Code § 50-2206.11)" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "Operating or physically controlling a vehicle when under the influence of intoxicating liquor or drugs, when operating ability is impaired by intoxicating liquor, or when the operator's blood, breath, or urine contains the amount of alcohol which is prohibited by section 10(b)" and insert the phrase "Driving under the influence (DUI) of alcohol or a drug" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Strike the phrase "section 13(e) (D.C. Official Code § 50-1403.01(e))" and insert the phrase "section 13(f) (D.C. Official Code § 50-1403.01(f))" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <text>Section 5(a) of the Act to Regulate Public Conduct on Public Passenger Vehicles, effective September 23, 1975 (D.C. Law 1-18; D.C. Official Code § 35-254(a)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "of this section" and inserting the phrase "and (1A) of this section" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (2)(A) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Violations penalized under this subsection shall be adjudicated by the Office of Administrative Hearings in accordance with the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Official Code § 2-1801.01 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <text>Chapter 8 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 16-805(c)(1) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase "prior to the effective date of the Second Chance Amendment Act of 2022, passed on 2nd reading on December 20, 2022 (Enrolled version of Bill 24-63)" and inserting the phrase "on or before September 30, 2027" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase "the effective date of the Second Chance Amendment Act of 2022, on 2nd reading on December 20, 2022 (Enrolled version of Bill 24-63), shall be sealed" and inserting the phrase "October 1, 2027, shall be sealed by October 1, 2027, or" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 16-806 is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a)(1)(B) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>The offense is not an offense listed in § 16-805(b) and the person cited, arrested, or charged files a written motion prior to October 1, 2027; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>The offense is an offense listed in § 16-805(b); and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (i) is amended by adding a new paragraph (7) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(7)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (6) of this subsection, the dismissal of a motion under this section between March 1, 2025, and the effective date of the Peace DC Omnibus Emergency Amendment Act of 2025, effective July 14, 2025 (D.C. Act 26-109; 72 DCR 8013), shall not preclude a movant from filing and the Court from entertaining subsequent motions sooner than one year after the date on which the initial motion was resolved.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <text>The Secure DC Omnibus Amendment Act of 2024, effective June 8, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-175; 71 DCR 2732), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 18(c)(2) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall expire December 31, 2026.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 30 is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (f)(1)(H) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <num>(H)</num>
            <text>A new paragraph (9) is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include>
              <para>
                <num>(9)</num>
                <text>Committed a crime of violence, as that term is defined in § 23-1331(4); except, that robbery where the victim does not sustain a physical injury and burglary in the second degree shall not be subject to the rebuttable presumption of detention under this subsection.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (k) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(k)</num>
            <text>Subsections (f), (g), and (h) of this section shall expire December 31, 2026.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <text>Section 1505 of the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council for the District of Columbia Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 22-4234), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b-9) is amended by striking the phrase "May 7, 2025" and inserting the phrase "September 30, 2026" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subsection (b-10) is amended by striking the phrase "May 7, 2025" and inserting the phrase "September 30, 2026" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>9</num>
    <text>Section 4(a) of the Clemency Board Waiver Authority Temporary Amendment Act of 2025, effective July 24, 2025 (D.C. Law 26-21; 72 DCR 4888), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(a)</num>
        <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 60-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2)).</text>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>10</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>Section 6 shall apply as of March 1, 2025.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>11</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>12</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 60-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2)).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
