<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-104" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">26-104</num>
  <num type="bill">26-286</num>
  <heading type="short">Juvenile Curfew Emergency Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Juvenile Curfew Act of 1995 to authorize the Mayor to extend the juvenile curfew hours in the District when appropriate to protect public safety or public or private property, to authorize the Chief of Police to establish extended juvenile curfew hour zones in specified circumstances, to start the juvenile curfew hours at 11 p.m. every day in June, July, and August 2025, and to extend the applicability of the juvenile curfew to 17-year olds.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-06-13</introduced>
    <effective>2025-07-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57931/Signed_Act/B26-0286-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=217099">D.C. Act 26-104</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0286">
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Agendized;"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Agendized;"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Final"/>
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Amendment"/>
      <enacted>2025-07-07</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Juvenile Curfew Emergency Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Juvenile Curfew Act of 1995, effective September 20, 1995 (D.C. Law 11-48; D.C. Official Code § 2-1541 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="§2-1542">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 2-1542) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(1)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:replace/>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"Chief of Police" means the Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (1A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(1)" num-value="(1A)"/>
            <num>(1A)</num>
            <text>"Curfew hours" means:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>During every month except July and August:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>From 11:00 p.m. on every Sunday, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, and Thursday, until 6:00 a.m. on the following day; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>From 12:01 a.m. until 6:00 a.m. on every Saturday and Sunday;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>During the months of July and August, from 12:01 a.m. until 6:00 a.m. every day;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, during the months of June, July, and August 2025, from 11:00 p.m. on every day until 6:00 a.m. on the following day;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>Extended curfew hours established by the Mayor pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.01">section 3a</code-cite>; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>Extended curfew hours in extended juvenile curfew zones established by the Chief of Police pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.02">section 3b</code-cite>.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(5)">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the phrase "under the age of 17 years" and inserting the phrase "under the age of 18 years" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>under the age of 17 years</find>
          <replace>under the age of 18 years</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (6A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <codify:insert after="(6)" num-value="(6A)"/>
            <num>(6A)</num>
            <text>"Notice of violation of curfew" means a verbal warning, authorized by an official that informs a group of juveniles that they are violating the terms of a curfew, that they may be arrested if they continue to violate the curfew, and identifies reasonable steps that they can take to leave the area to avoid arrest.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 5, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>New sections 3a and 3b are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="2|15|III" after="§2-1542" num-value="2-1542.01" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>3a</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Temporary extensions of juvenile curfew hours.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Mayor may, by issuance of an administrative order pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-204.22|(11)">section 422(11) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, effective December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 790; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.22(11)</code-cite>, extend the juvenile curfew hours in the District, or any part of the District, beyond the hours established in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542|(1A)|(A)">section 3(1A)(A)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542|(1A)|(B)" codify:value="(B)">(B)</code-cite>, and <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542|(1A)|(C)" codify:value="(C)">(C)</code-cite>, if the Mayor determines that such an extension is appropriate to protect public safety or public or private property.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>An administrative order issued by the Mayor under subsection (a) of this section shall:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>State the basis for the extension of the juvenile curfew hours;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>State the locations in the District where the extended juvenile curfew hours shall apply or state that the extended juvenile curfew hours shall apply throughout the District; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>State the days and hours during which the extended juvenile curfew hours shall be in effect; provided, that the extended juvenile curfew hours:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Shall not begin earlier than 8:00 p.m., nor extend past 6:00 a.m., on any day;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Shall not remain in effect for more than 4 consecutive days, except as provided in subsection (e) of this section; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Shall not apply to groups of 8 or fewer individuals.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>Except where emergency circumstances, as determined by the Mayor and described in the administrative order issued under subsection (a) of this section, warrant otherwise, extended juvenile curfew hours imposed under this section shall not take effect until at least 24 hours after the issuance of the administrative order.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>Notice of the issuance of each administrative order issued under this section shall be promptly posted on the main website of the District government and on the website of the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>The Mayor may extend the time period during which extended juvenile curfew hours imposed by this section shall remain in effect by issuing subsequent Mayor's orders extending the time period; provided, that each such extension of the time period shall not exceed 30 days.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>If members of the Metropolitan Police Department discover juveniles in the designated extended juvenile curfew hours zone during the hours of curfew, the Metropolitan Police Department shall:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Where there:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Is not an imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least 2 clearly audible and understandable notices of violation of curfew; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Is imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least one clearly audible and understandable notice of violation of curfew;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Provide juveniles a reasonable and adequate time to disperse; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Capture on body-worn camera each component of the order to return home described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3a">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3a</annotation>
          <codify:emergency-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.01" interim-path="§2-1542" perm-eff="2025-07-07"/>
          <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.01" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
            <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 5, 2025.*
      </text>
          </codify:insert>
        </section>
        <section>
          <codify:insert path="2|15|III" after="§2-1542.01" num-value="2-1542.02" history-prefix="as added"/>
          <num>3b</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Temporary designations of extended juvenile curfew hour zones.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Chief of Police may designate any area of the District as an extended juvenile curfew hours zone, in which extended juvenile curfew hours determined by the Chief of Police shall apply, if the Chief of Police determines that the designation of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone is appropriate to protect public safety or public or private property in the extended juvenile curfew hours zone.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>To designate an extended juvenile curfew hours zone, the Chief of Police shall issue an order that includes:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The basis for the designation of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The boundaries of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>The days and hours of the extended juvenile curfew hours in the extended juvenile curfew hours zone; provided, that the extended juvenile curfew hours in the extended juvenile curfew hours zone:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Shall not begin earlier than 8:00 p.m., nor extend past 6:00 a.m., on any day;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Shall not remain in effect for more than 4 consecutive days, except as provided in subsection (e) of this section; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Shall not apply to groups of 8 or fewer individuals.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>In determining whether to designate an extended juvenile curfew hours zone, the Chief of Police shall consider the following:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Within the preceding 30 days, the occurrence of:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Juvenile curfew violations in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Police reports of disturbances of the public peace described in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1301">section 1 of An Act To confer concurrent jurisdiction on the police court of the District of Columbia in certain cases, approved July 16, 1912 (37 Stat. 192; D.C. Official Code § 22-1301)</code-cite>, <span codify:value="">sections</span><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1307">6</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1309">3</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1312">9</code-cite>, <span codify:value="">or </span><code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1318">16 of An act for the preservation of the public peace and the protection of property within the District of Columbia, approved July 29, 1892 (27 Stat. 323; D.C. Official Code § 22-1307, § 22-1309, § 22-1312, or § 22-1318)</code-cite>, <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1321">section 211 of the District of Columbia Law Enforcement Act of 1953, approved June 29, 1953 (67 Stat. 98; D.C. Official Code § 22-1321)</code-cite>, or <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§22-1322">section 901 of An Act relating to crime and criminal procedure in the District of Columbia, approved December 27, 1967 (81 Stat. 742; D.C. Official Code §  22-1322)</code-cite>, in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>Police reports of dangerous crimes, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§23-1331|(3)">D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(3)</code-cite>, in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>Police reports of crimes of violence, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§23-1331|(4)">D.C. Official Code § 23-1331(4)</code-cite>, in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Police reports of destruction of or damage to public or private property in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Intelligence or verifiable information indicative of an intent of 10 or more juveniles to gather in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone in such a manner that is likely to result in substantial harm to the public safety, or the safety of those gathering, or substantial damage to public or private property; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Any other verifiable information from which the Chief of Police may ascertain that public safety or public or private property in the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours zone is likely to be endangered by the presence of unaccompanied juveniles in the extended juvenile curfew hours zones.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <text>Upon the designation of an extended juvenile curfew hours zone the Chief of Police shall post notice of the designation on the website of the Metropolitan Police Department and shall post signs in the immediate area of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(e)</num>
            <text>The Chief of Police may extend the duration of the designation of an extended juvenile curfew hours zone to 30 days by issuing a subsequent order extending the duration of the designation.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(f)</num>
            <text>If members of the Metropolitan Police Department discover juveniles in the designated extended juvenile curfew hours zone during the hours of curfew, the Metropolitan Police Department shall:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Where there:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Is not an imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least 2 clearly audible and understandable notices of violation of curfew; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Is imminent danger of bodily injury or significant damage to property, issue at least one clearly audible and understandable notice of violation of curfew;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Provide juveniles a reasonable and adequate time to disperse; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Capture on body-worn camera each component of the order to return home described in paragraph (1) fo this subsection.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(g)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>An Advisory Neighborhood Commission, business improvement district, or Main Street organization may petition the Chief of Police to establish an extended juvenile curfew hours zone in an area covered by, or adjacent to the area covered by, such entity. Such petition shall be approved by a formal vote of the members of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission, the members of the board of the business improvement district, or the members of the board of the Main Street organization.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>A petition submitted pursuant to this subsection shall include the following information:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The proposed boundaries of the extended juvenile curfew hours zone;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>The proposed hours of the extended juvenile curfew;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>The proposed duration, in days, of the proposed extended juvenile curfew hours;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>The reasons why the Advisory Neighborhood Commission, business improvement district, or Main Street organization is requesting the designation of an extended juvenile curfew hours zone; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>Such other information as the Chief of Police may require.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Consideration of a petition submitted under this section, and the determination of whether to designate an extended juvenile curfew hours zone in response to the petition, shall be at the sole discretion of the Chief of Police.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-48" type="History" path="§3b">Sept. 20, 1995, D.C. Law 11-48, § 3b</annotation>
          <codify:emergency-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.02" interim-path="§2-1542" perm-eff="2025-07-07"/>
          <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1542.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
            <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on October 5, 2025.*
      </text>
          </codify:insert>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
