<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-14" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">26-14</num>
  <num type="bill">26-84</num>
  <heading type="short">Youth Workforce Development Programs Emergency Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Criminal Background Checks for the Protection of Children Act of 2004 to expand the definition of a covered child or youth services provider to include employees or volunteers of host employers participating in summer youth programs administered by the Department of Employment Services; and to amend the Youth Employment Act of 1979 to authorize the Department of Employment Services to conduct background checks and motor vehicle record checks of employees or volunteers of a host employer or grantee with direct contact or unsupervised access to youth participating in youth employment programs.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-02-03</introduced>
    <effective>2025-02-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57032/Signed_Act/B26-0084-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=206598">D.C. Act 26-14</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0084">
      <vote date="2025-02-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-02-20</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Youth Workforce Development Programs Emergency Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section codify:path="§4-1501.02|(3)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 202(3) of the Criminal Background Checks for the Protection of Children Act of 2004, effective April 13, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-353; D.C. Official Code § 4-1501.02(3)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include lvl="1">
      <para>
        <codify:replace/>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>"Covered child or youth services provider":</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Means any District government agency providing direct services to children or youth and any private entity that is licensed by or contracts with the District to provide direct services to children or youth, or for the benefit of children or youth, that affect the health, safety, and welfare of children or youth, including individual and group counseling, therapy, case management, supervision, or mentoring.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>The term "covered child or youth services provider" does not include foster parents or grantees.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the term "covered child or youth services provider" includes an employee or volunteer of a host employer or grantee participating in programs established pursuant to <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-242">section 2a of the Youth Employment Act of 1979, effective January 5, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-46; D.C. Official Code § 32-242)</code-cite>, who has direct contact with or unsupervised access to youth participating in such programs.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1501.02"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1501.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on May 21, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1501.02(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section codify:path="§32-242">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 2a of the Youth Employment Act of 1979, effective January 5, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-46; D.C. Official Code § 32-242), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para codify:path="(h)">
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Subsection (h) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para codify:path="(1)">
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>;</find>
          <replace>; and</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(2)">
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (2) is repealed.</text>
        <codify:repeal/>
      </para>
      <para codify:path="(3)">
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "closing ceremony" and inserting the word "activities" in its place.</text>
        <codify:find-replace count="1">
          <find>closing ceremony</find>
          <replace>activities</replace>
        </codify:find-replace>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (i) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(h)" num-value="(i)"/>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The Department of Employment Services is authorized to perform criminal background checks and traffic record checks for employees and volunteers of host employers or grantees participating in programs established pursuant to this section in accordance with <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="4|15">the Criminal Background Checks for the Protection of Children Act of 2004, effective April 13, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-353; D.C. Official Code § 4-1501.01 <em>et seq.</em>)</code-cite>.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-242"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-242" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on May 21, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation affecting this section, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-242(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
