<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-117" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">26-117</num>
  <num type="bill">26-299</num>
  <heading type="short">Streatery Program Endorsement Extension and Medical Cannabis Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, section 25-113 of the District of Columbia Official Code to continue the extension of the Streatery Program endorsements through December 31, 2025, and to clarify endorsement deadlines for certain classes of licensees; and to amend the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999 to make a clarifying amendment.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-06-30</introduced>
    <effective>2025-07-21</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/58050/Signed_Act/B26-0299-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=217823">D.C. Act 26-117</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 8173</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0299">
      <vote date="2025-07-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-07-21</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Streatery Program Endorsement Extension and Medical Cannabis Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section codify:path="§25-113|(a)|(6)">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-113(a)(6) of the District of Columbia Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Strike the phrase "2022 and 2023" wherever it appears and insert the phrase "2022, 2023, 2024, and through December 31, 2025" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="4">
        <find>2022 and 2023</find>
        <replace>2022, 2023, 2024, and through December 31, 2025</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <para codify:path="(A)|(i)|(II)">
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Subparagraph (A)(i)(II) is amended by striking the semicolon and inserting the phrase "annually with the fee for 2025 due by April 1, 2025; except, that an on-premises retailer licensee, class C/T, D/T, C/N, or D/N, or a manufacturer licensee class B, shall pay the fee for 2025 by September 30, 2025;" in its place.</text>
      <codify:find-replace count="1">
        <find>;</find>
        <replace> annually with the fee for 2025 due by April 1, 2025; except, that an on-premises retailer licensee, class C/T, D/T, C/N, or D/N, or a manufacturer licensee class B, shall pay the fee for 2025 by September 30, 2025;</replace>
      </codify:find-replace>
    </para>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 19, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-113(Perm)">Past Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section codify:path="§7-1671.06|(q)">
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 7(q)(1) of the Legalization of Marijuana for Medical Treatment Initiative of 1999, effective July 27, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-210; D.C. Official Code § 7-1671.06(q)(1)), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(q)</num>
        <para>
          <codify:replace path="(1)"/>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>A retailer or internet retailer shall not locate within any residential district or within 400 feet of a preschool, primary or secondary school, or recreation center; except, that a license holder or an applicant who has applied prior to <span codify:value="December 17, 2024">the effective date of the Medical Cannabis Clarification and Program Enforcement Amendment Act of 2024, effective December 17, 2024 (D.C. Law 25-255; 71 DCR 13505),</span> shall not be permitted to locate within 300 feet of a preschool, primary or secondary school, or recreation center.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, an unlicensed establishment license holder or applicant that applied for a retailer or internet retailer license during the 90-calendar day open application period set forth in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.06a|(a)|(1)">section 7a(a)(1)</code-cite> shall be permitted to locate within 300 feet of a preschool, primary or secondary school, or recreation center where the main entrance to the preschool, primary school or secondary school, or recreation center is actually on or occupies ground zoned commercial or industrial according to the official atlases of the Zoning Commission of the District of Columbia.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.06"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.06" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on October 19, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1671.06(Perm)">Past Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>The Streatery Program Endorsement Extension Temporary Amendment Act of 2024, effective March 7, 2025 (D.C. Law 25-294; 72 DCR 337), is repealed.</text>
    <codify:repeal doc="D.C. Law 25-294"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
