<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-205">
  <num type="act">26-205</num>
  <num type="bill">26-219</num>
  <heading type="short">Malcolm X Extension of Disposition Authority and Term Sheet Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Malcolm X Surplus Declaration and Disposition Approval Act of 2022 to extend the time limit for the disposition of certain District-owned real property located at 1351 Alabama Avenue, SE and to approve an amendment to the term sheet for the disposition of the property.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-04-02</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-01-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57513/Signed_Act/B26-0219-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227823">D.C. Act 26-205</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 13502</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0219">
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-11-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-11-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-219 would extend the time limit for the disposition of certain District-owned real property located at 1351 Alabama Avenue, S.E.</summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Malcolm X Extension of Disposition Authority and Term Sheet Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Malcolm X Surplus Declaration and Disposition Approval Act of 2022, effective March 10, 2023 (D.C. Law 24-316; 70 DCR 848), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2(6) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>"Project" means a mixed-use project that will include approximately 150 residential units, 7,500 square feet of daycare space, and 2,000 square feet of retail space, as further described in the amended term sheet and draft land disposition and development agreement transmitted by the Mayor to the Council with the Malcolm X Extension of Disposition Authority and Term Sheet Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on November 4, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-219).</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3 is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (i) is amended by striking the phrase ", as further described in the executed term sheet and draft land disposition and development agreement documents transmitted by the Mayor to the Council with this act." and inserting the phrase "as further described in the amended term sheet and draft land disposition and development agreement transmitted by the Mayor to the Council with the Malcolm X Extension of Disposition Authority and Term Sheet Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on November 4, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-219)." in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (j) is amended by striking the phrase "transmitted by the Mayor with this act" and inserting the phrase "transmitted by the Mayor with the Malcolm X Extension of Disposition Authority and Term Sheet Amendment Act of 2025, passed on 2nd reading on November 4, 2025 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-219)" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 4(c) is amended by striking the phrase "2 years after the effective date" and inserting the phrase "4 years after the effective date" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
