<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-202">
  <num type="act">26-202</num>
  <num type="bill">26-35</num>
  <heading type="short">Uniform Commercial Code Financing Statement Forms Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the Uniform Commercial Code to provide that the Recorder of Deeds may not refuse to accept a written initial financing statement in the form provided by the International Association of Commercial Administrators or in a form adopted by the Chief Financial Officer by rule and to permit the Chief Financial Officer to promulgate rules setting fees for filing and indexing of initial financing statements.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-09</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-01-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56902/Signed_Act/B26-0035-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227784">D.C. Act 26-202</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 13490</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0035">
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-11-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-11-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 26-35 would provide that the Recorder of Deeds may not refuse to accept a written initial financing statement in the form provided by the International Association of Commercial Administrators or in a form adopted by the Chief Financial Officer by rule. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Uniform Commercial Code Financing Statement Forms Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Article 9 of Subtitle I of Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 28:9-521 is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <prefix>§</prefix>
          <num>28:9-521</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Uniform form of written financing statement and amendment.</heading>
          <para>
            <num undesignated="true">(a)</num>
            <text>Except for a reason set forth in § 28:9-516(b), a filing office that accepts written records may not refuse to accept a written record for a filing authorized by this article if the record conforms to a format that is:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>Currently approved by the International Association of Commercial Administrators; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Adopted by rule issued by the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to § 28:9-526.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 28:9-525(a) is amended by striking the word "Mayor" and inserting the phrase "Chief Financial Officer" in its place.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section § 28:9-526 is amended by striking the word "Mayor" both times it appears and inserting the phrase "Chief Financial Officer" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3)).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
