<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-276">
  <num type="act">26-276</num>
  <num type="bill">26-135</num>
  <heading type="short">Purple Heart License Plate Amendment Act of 2026</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937 to require the Mayor to design and make available for issue a motor-vehicle identification tag that identifies the owner of a motor vehicle as a recipient of the Purple Heart award or as the surviving spouse of a Purple Heart award recipient; and to amend the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001 to make conforming changes.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-02-21</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-05-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57226/Signed_Act/B26-0135-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=234656">D.C. Act 26-276</citation>
      <citation type="register">73 DCR 5063</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0135">
      <vote date="2026-02-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2026-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2026-03-20</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-135 would require the Mayor to design and make available for issue a motor-vehicle identification tag that identifies the owner of a motor vehicle as a recipient of the Purple Heart award, or as the surviving spouse or child of a Purple Heart award recipient. </summary>
      <committee>Transportation and the Environment</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Purple Heart License Plate Amendment Act of 2026".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2a(b)(4) (D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.02a(b)(4)) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new section 2o is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <num>2o</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Issuance of Purple Heart award recipient motor vehicle identification tags.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>The Mayor shall design and make available for issue motor vehicle identification tags with a design, identifying words, or emblem that designates the owner of the motor vehicle as a Purple Heart recipient or as the surviving spouse of a Purple Heart recipient; provided, that the surviving spouse has not remarried.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>A resident ordering a Purple Heart award recipient motor vehicle identification tag shall pay a one-time application fee of $10, or such other amount as may be established by the Mayor by rule. There shall be no annual display fee assessed for a Purple Heart award recipient motor vehicle identification tag.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>The application fee shall be deposited in the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund, established by section 705 of the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28, D.C. Official Code § 49-1004).</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>No identification tags may be issued to any individual under this section unless due proof is submitted that the individual is a bona fide recipient of the Purple Heart medal as may be demonstrated to the Mayor at the time of the application for the identification tags by submission of:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>DD-214 Certificate of Release or Discharge from Active Duty, or DD-215, issued by the United States Department of Defense, or its successor agency;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>WD-AGO 53-55 Enlisted Record and Report of Separation Honorable Discharge;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>General or permanent orders listing the award issuance, which shall be accompanied by a copy of the photo identification of the applicant;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(4)</num>
              <text>A certificate of the award issuance signed by the secretary of the service branch, or a general officer or flag officer; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(5)</num>
              <text>Other documentation that may be accepted by the Department of Motor Vehicles in consultation with the Office of Veterans Affairs.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.03) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (a)(1) is amended by adding a new subparagraph (S) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <num>(S)</num>
            <text>Any person ordering a Purple Heart award recipient motor vehicle identification tag shall pay the fee set forth in section 2o(b)(1).</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (d) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (15) is amended by striking the phrase "; and" and inserting a semicolon in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (16) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase "; and" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (17) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(17)</num>
              <text>The fees collected for the Purple Heart award recipient motor vehicle identification tag under section 2o shall be deposited into the Office of Veterans Affairs Fund, established by section 705 of the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28, D.C. Official Code § 49-1004).</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 705(b) of the Office of Veterans Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, established October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 49-1004(b)), is amended by striking the phrase "sections 2a(b)(2) and 2b(b)(1) of Title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-1501.02a(b)(2) and 50-1501.02b(b)(1))," and inserting the phrase "sections 2a(b)(2), 2b(b)(1), and 2o(b)(1) of Title IV of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 679; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-1501.02a(b)(2), 50-1501.02b(b)(1), and 50-1501.02o(b)(1))," in its place.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code §1-206.02(c)(l)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
