<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-200">
  <num type="act">26-200</num>
  <num type="bill">26-10</num>
  <heading type="short">Veteran Spouse Homestead Deduction Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend section 47-850 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow a surviving spouse or domestic partner of a disabled veteran to claim the disabled veteran's homestead deduction.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-01-03</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-01-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/56836/Signed_Act/B26-0010-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=227782">D.C. Act 26-200</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 13479</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0010">
      <vote date="2025-10-21" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-11-04" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-11-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced Bill 26-10 would provide that a surviving spouse or domestic partner of a veteran may claim the Disabled Veterans Homestead Exemption. </summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Veteran Spouse Homestead Deduction Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 47-850(a-2) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The lead-in language is amended by striking the word "veteran" and inserting the phrase "veteran or eligible spouse" in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>Veteran has been classified (or, in the case of an eligible spouse, had been classified at the time of the veteran's death) by the United States Department of Veterans Affairs as having a total and permanent disability as a result of a service-incurred condition or service-aggravated condition or is paid (or, in the case of an eligible spouse, had been paid at the time of the veteran's death) at the 100% disability rating level as a result of unemployability; and</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the word "Veteran's" and inserting the phrase "Veteran's or eligible spouse's" in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (3) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "the veteran" both times it appears and insert the phrase "the veteran or eligible spouse" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Strike the phrase "the veteran's legal guardian" and insert the phrase "the veteran's or eligible spouse's legal guardian" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase "this subsection." and inserting the phrase "this subsection. Upon the filing of an application by an eligible spouse pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the District of Columbia Office of Veterans Affairs shall certify to the Office of Tax and Revenue that the deceased veteran met the disability requirements for the deduction provided pursuant to this subsection at the time of the veteran's death." in its place.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (4) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="2">
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term "eligible spouse" means the surviving spouse or domestic partner of a deceased veteran whose real property was validly receiving the deduction provided under this subsection at the time of the veteran's death or whose real property would have been eligible for such deduction at the time of the veteran's death had the veteran applied for such deduction.</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of October 1, 2025.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code ยง 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
