<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-250">
  <num type="act">26-250</num>
  <num type="bill">26-367</num>
  <heading type="short">Public Benefits Security Amendment Act of 2026</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982 to require the Department of Human Services to issue electronic benefit transfer cards with theft prevention technology and to restore stolen public benefits; and to amend section 31c of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005 to extend the operation of the Flexible Rent Subsidy Pilot Program by one year through Fiscal Year 2027.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-09-24</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-03-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/60364/Signed_Act/B26-0367-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=231728">D.C. Act 26-250</citation>
      <citation type="register">73 DCR 1069</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0367">
      <vote date="2025-12-16" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2026-01-06" reading="AMENDMENT"/>
      <vote date="2026-01-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2026-02-02</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-367 would require the Department of Human Services to issue electronic benefit transfer cards with theft prevention technology and to restore public assistance lost due to theft.</summary>
      <committee>Human Services</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Public Benefits Security Amendment Act of 2026".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 1982, effective April 6, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-101; D.C. Official Code § 4-201.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 101 (D.C. Official Code § 4-201.01) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (1E) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(1E)</num>
            <text>"Cloning" means using data acquired by unlawful means to create a duplicate copy of a recipient's EBT card.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (3A) is redesignated as paragraph (3C).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>New paragraphs (3A) and (3B) are added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(3A)</num>
            <text>"EBT card" means a method to access public assistance issued to a recipient or a recipient's authorized representative through an electronic payments system.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3B)</num>
            <text>"EMV technology" means the integration in a method of payment of a microchip that generates a dynamic, one-time-use code for each payment transaction.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (5D) is redesignated as paragraph (5E).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (5D) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(5D)</num>
            <text>"Phishing" means a technique for attempting to acquire sensitive data, such as EBT card information, through a solicitation in which the solicitor purports to be other than who the solicitor is.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (8A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(8A)</num>
            <text>"Skimming" means using technology unlawfully installed on an automated teller machine, point-of-sale terminal, or similar device to capture data associated with a recipient's EBT card.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (10A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(10A)</num>
            <text>"Theft" shall have the same meaning as in section 111 of the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Official Code § 22-3211).</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 205 (D.C. Official Code § 4-202.05) is amended by adding a new subsection (f) to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <num>(f)</num>
          <text>The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 <em>et seq</em>.), may issue rules to implement the provisions of the Public Benefits Security Amendment Act of 2026, passed on 2nd reading on January 6, 2026 (Enrolled version of Bill 26-367).</text>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>New sections 583 and 584 are added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <num>583</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Prevention of theft of electronically transferred benefits.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>By October 1, 2027, the Department shall issue, to all recipients receiving public assistance on electronic benefit transfer cards, updated EBT cards that incorporate EMV technology.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>The Department shall seek reimbursement for the costs of transitioning to the use of EMV technology from the Food and Nutrition Service of the Department of Agriculture to the fullest extent permissible under federal law.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <num>584</num>
          <heading proof="needed">Reimbursement for theft of electronically transferred benefits.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>If a recipient reports the theft of public assistance by fraudulent means to the Department within 6 months of the theft, and if an investigation by the Department shows that a recipient's correctly issued public assistance was lost due to theft by fraudulent means, the Department shall restore up to 2 months of correctly issued public assistance lost due to theft by fraudulent means.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>For the purposes of this section:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>Public assistance is "correctly issued" if the amount of, and the recipient's eligibility for, public assistance was accurately calculated under applicable law;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Theft is "by fraudulent means" if it is done by phishing, skimming, cloning, or otherwise with the intent to obtain the property of another by means of a false or fraudulent pretense, representation, or promise;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>If incidents of theft that occurred in multiple months are reported simultaneously, the value of "2 months of correctly issued public assistance" subject to restoration shall be calculated on the basis of the 2 months during which public assistance was lost due to theft in which the correctly issued benefit amounts were the highest;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(D)</num>
                <text>In calculating the value of "2 months of correctly issued public assistance," the Department shall exclude any special or additional payments received by the recipient during the months that serve as the basis for the Department's calculation, including any amount received in compensation for past underpayment;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(E)</num>
                <text>A recipient need not perfect a report of theft by providing any supporting documentation requested by the Department within the timelines established by this subsection for a report of theft to be considered timely made; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(F)</num>
                <text>The term "public assistance" does not include public benefits programs administered by agencies other than the Department or the minimum annual benefit  established by section 5083(c) of the Food Stamp Expansion Act of 2009, effective March 3, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-111; D.C. Official Code § 4-261.03(c)).".</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Not later than 20 days after a recipient informs the Department of the loss of public assistance due to theft, the Department shall:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>If the Department determines that the recipient lost public assistance due to theft by fraudulent means, restore the lower of:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The stolen public assistance in the amount that was lost; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>Two months of correctly issued public assistance;</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>If the Department determines that the recipient lost public assistance due to theft, provide the recipient with a new EBT card; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(3)</num>
              <text>Notify the recipient in writing of:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(A)</num>
                <text>The Department's decision whether to restore public assistance;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>The amount of public assistance to be restored, if any; and</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>If the Department finds that public assistance was not lost due to theft by fraudulent means or if the Department restores less in public assistance than the recipient alleged was lost due to theft by fraudulent means:</text>
                <para>
                  <num>(i)</num>
                  <text>The reason for the Department's decision;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(ii)</num>
                  <text>The recipient's right to a fair hearing on the Department's decision;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(iii)</num>
                  <text>The method for requesting a fair hearing;</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(iv)</num>
                  <text>The right to representation in a fair hearing; and</text>
                </para>
                <para>
                  <num>(v)</num>
                  <text>The availability of, and means of contacting, free legal counsel.</text>
                </para>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(c)</num>
            <text>If a recipient disputes the amount of public assistance restored under subsection (a) of this section or the Department's determination that no restoration is due, the recipient may request a fair hearing within 90 days of the date of the Department's determination.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(d)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>This section shall apply as of October 1, 2027.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the Department's ability to restore public assistance lost due to theft before October 1, 2027.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Section 31c(e) of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, effective October 8, 2016 (D.C. Law 21-160; D.C. Official Code § 4-756.05(e)), is amended by striking the phrase "September 30, 2026" and inserting the phrase "September 30, 2027" in its place.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Applicability.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 shall apply upon the date of inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Chief Financial Officer shall certify the date of the inclusion of the fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan and provide notice to the Budget Director of the Council of the certification.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Budget Director shall cause the notice of the certification to be published in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The date of publication of the notice of the certification shall not affect the applicability of the provision identified in subsection (a) of this section.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
