<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-215">
  <num type="act">26-215</num>
  <num type="bill">26-375</num>
  <heading type="short">Green Housing Coordination Temporary Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on a temporary basis, the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988 to insert net zero energy requirements for residential and mixed-use construction projects receiving assistance from the Housing Production Trust Fund; to amend the Clean Energy DC Building Code Amendment Act of 2022 to require periodic reporting on the development of universal net zero energy building code regulations that will apply to residential and mixed-use construction; and to amend the Green Building Act of 2006 to remove those net zero energy compliance provisions inserted by the Greener Government Buildings Amendment Act of 2022 that apply to residential and mixed-use projects and add a requirement for adding renewable energy systems when half or more of a rooftop is being replaced for residential projects.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-10-02</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-02-12</effective>
    <temporary/>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/60396/Signed_Act/B26-0375-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=230013">D.C. Act 26-215</citation>
      <citation type="register">73 DCR 3</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0375">
      <vote date="2025-11-04" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2025-11-04" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2025-12-02" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-12-19</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Green Housing Coordination Temporary Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code §§ 42-2801 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended by adding a new section 6 to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <num>6</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Net zero energy requirements for subsidized projects.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>Any request, excluding substantial rehabilitation as that term is defined in section 103(34) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3501.03(34)), for housing proposals involving the Fund shall include a requirement that proposals for new construction receiving Fund support must be designed with the intent to obtain Enterprise Green Communities Certification Plus, as defined in the EGCC or an equivalent standard as determined by the Department in consultation with the Department of Buildings.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Any request, excluding substantial rehabilitation as that term is defined in section 103(34) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3501.03(34)), for housing proposals involving the Fund shall include a requirement that proposals for new construction receiving Fund support be all-electric.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the applicability of any other environmental standards, including the Green Building Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-234; D.C. Official Code § 6-1451.01 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>This section shall expire upon the effective date of final regulations promulgated pursuant to section 2(b)(1) of the Clean Energy DC Building Code Amendment Act of 2022, effective September 21, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-177; D.C. Official Code § 6-1453.01(b)(1)).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>For purposes of this section, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"All-electric" means that no combustion equipment is included in the building project, except for emergency backup power.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>"EGCC" means the current Enterprise Green Communities Criteria issued by Enterprise Community Partners.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>The Clean Energy DC Building Code Amendment Act of 2022, effective September 21, 2022 (D.C. Law 24-177;69 DCR 9924), is amended by adding a new section 2a to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <num>2a</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Report on barriers to net zero energy ready affordable housing development.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>No later than March 1, 2026, and every 6 months thereafter, the Department of Buildings ("Department") shall submit to the Council a report detailing its progress toward developing the regulations required by section 2.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Each report shall include a discussion of major questions that the Department needs to resolve before it can issue the regulations, plans to resolve those questions, and comments on any existing laws that pose significant challenges to successful development and implementation of the regulations. The Department may also include recommended changes to existing laws that would allow substantial affordable housing development and preservation to continue while still securing meaningful, immediate reductions in energy waste, greenhouse gas emissions, and onsite fossil fuel combustion.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>In preparing each report required under this section, the Department shall hold at least one public meeting with the Department of Energy and Environment, local climate advocacy organizations, and housing development and preservation professionals with substantial experience delivering high-efficiency projects in the District.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to establish a new cause of action to challenge the validity of any regulations issued pursuant to section 2(b)(1).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>This section shall expire upon the effective date of final regulations promulgated pursuant to section 2(b)(1).</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>Section 3(a) of the Green Building Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-234; D.C. Official Code § 6-1451.02(a)), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (3)(C) is amended to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="3">
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>In the case of new construction or substantial rehabilitation, as that term is defined in section 103(34) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3501.03(34)), in which a roof replacement or repair of 50% or more of the roof area is within the scope of the project in accordance with the District of Columbia Building Code (Title 12A of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations), the developer shall incorporate rooftop renewable energy systems on-site wherever feasible except when:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>There is not adequate solar access as determined by Chapter 13 of Title 12-I[CE] of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Mechanical equipment, HVAC systems, or other essential rooftop infrastructure are present;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Rooftop amenities such as pools, decks, or recreational areas exist;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iv)</num>
            <text>Structural constraints, shading, or design limitations, as defined by DOB or DOEE, prevent effective solar generation; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(v)</num>
            <text>Other conditions identified in regulations issued by DOB or DOEE that render installation impracticable.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase "shall maintain net zero energy compliance and fulfill" and inserting the phrase "shall fulfill" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>This act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
</document>
