<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-325">
  <num type="bill">26-396</num>
  <num type="act">26-325</num>
  <heading type="short">Transfer and Recordation Tax Appeals Amendment Act of 2026</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend the District of Columbia Real Estate Deed Recordation Tax Act to authorize transferors or transferees of real property to petition for review of the fair market value used in calculating taxes imposed on the transfer of the property; and to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow transferors or transferees of real property to appeal final determinations of a real property's fair market value to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia and then to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, provided under the law.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-10-03</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-07-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/60456/Signed_Act/B26-0396-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=239522">D.C. Act 26-325</citation>
      <citation type="register">73 DCR 8169</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0396">
      <vote date="2026-03-31" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2026-05-05" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2026-05-28</enacted>
      <summary>BIILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-396 would amend the District’s deed transfer and recordation tax laws to allow transferors and transferees to appeal the fair market value used for calculation of the transfer and recordation taxes.</summary>
      <committee>Business and Economic Development</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Transfer and Recordation Tax Appeals Amendment Act of 2026".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 304 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 12; D.C. Official Code § 42-1104), is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <num>(d)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The transferor or transferee of real property or an economic interest in real property may, pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-825.01a(d), file a petition for review of the determination of fair market value made under subsection (c) of this section or under section 303(a). The notice of final determination issued by the Office of Tax and Revenue on the petition for review may be appealed to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia as provided in D.C. Official Code § 47-825.01a(e).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>A transferor or transferee aggrieved by a fair market value determination under subsection (c) of this section or under section 303(a) may appeal the determination to the Superior Court as provided in D.C. Official Code § 47-825.01a(g).</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the terms "transferor" and "transferee" shall have the same meaning as provided in D.C. Official Code § 47-901(10) and (11), respectively.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 47-825.01a is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subsection (c)(4) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase "assessment and classification" and inserting the phrase "assessment and classification or, as appropriate, fair market value" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase "assessment and classification" and inserting the phrase "assessment and classification or, as appropriate, fair market value" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Subparagraph (C) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Strike the word "member" and insert the word "members" in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Strike the phrase "or both," and insert the phrase "or both, or fair market value," in its place.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subsection (d) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>A new paragraph (2A) is added to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="1">
            <para>
              <num>(2A)</num>
              <text>With respect to an appeal of a determination of the fair market value of real property made pursuant to § 42-1103(a), 42-1104(c), or 47-903(a)(1)(B), the transferor or transferee may petition OTR for an administrative review of the fair market value determination within 45 days after the transfer tax associated with the fair market value determination is imposed.</text>
            </para>
          </include>
          <aftertext>.</aftertext>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase "a proposed assessed value or classification" and inserting the phrase "a proposed assessed value, classification, or fair market value determination" in its place.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase "the value or classification of the real property for the tax year at issue" and inserting the phrase "the assessed value or classification of the real property for the tax year at issue or to the fair market value for the transfer at issue" in its place.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Subsection (e) is amended as follows:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(A)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (1) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase "notice of final determination on a petition for administrative review, the" and inserting the phrase "notice of final determination on a petition for administrative review regarding an assessed value or classification, the" in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>A new subparagraph (C) is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="2">
              <para>
                <num>(C)</num>
                <text>If a transferor or transferee is aggrieved by a notice of final determination regarding a fair market value determination, the transferor or transferee may file an appeal from the determination of fair market value within 45 days after the date of the notice of final determination. The transferor or transferee may supplement the original filing if new information has become available that was not available prior to the filing deadline by delivering a copy of the supplemental filing to the Commission and OTR no later than 20 days after the filing of the appeal.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(B)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (4)(A) is amended by adding a new sub-subparagraph (ii-I) to read as follows:</text>
          <include lvl="3">
            <para>
              <num>(ii-I)</num>
              <text>A determination of fair market value;</text>
            </para>
          </include>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(C)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (5) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>The existing text is designated as subparagraph (A).</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>A new subparagraph (B) is added to read as follows:</text>
            <include lvl="2">
              <para>
                <num>(B)</num>
                <text>The Commission shall notify OTR of any decision on an appeal from a determination of fair market value at the same time that the Commission notifies the transferor or transferee.</text>
              </para>
            </include>
            <aftertext>.</aftertext>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(D)</num>
          <text>Paragraph (6) is amended as follows:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(i)</num>
            <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase "OTR or an owner aggrieved by a proposed assessed value or classification may seek a rehearing before the Commission." and inserting the phrase "OTR, an owner aggrieved by a proposed assessed value or classification, or a transferor or transferee aggrieved by a determination of fair market value, may seek a rehearing before the Commission." in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(ii)</num>
            <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase "owner or OTR" and inserting the phrase "owner, transferor, transferee, or OTR" in its place.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(iii)</num>
            <text>Subparagraph (D) is amended by striking the phrase "changes the proposed assessed value" and inserting the phrase "changes the proposed assessed value or determined fair market value" in its place.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Subsection (g) is amended by adding a new paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>A transferor or transferee aggrieved by a determination of fair market value may appeal the determination to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia in the same manner and to the same extent as provided in §§ 47-3303 and 47-3304 within 45 days after the final fair market value determination is issued by the Commission; provided, that the transfer tax or recordation tax associated with the determination of fair market value being appealed by the transferor or transferee shall first have been paid to the D.C. Treasurer together with any penalties and interest due thereon; provided further, that the transferor or transferee shall have in good faith first appealed the determination to the Commission immediately preceding the appeal to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 47-904 is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as subsection (a).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>The transferor or transferee of real property, or an interest therein, may, pursuant to § 47-825.01a(d), file a petition for review of the determination of fair market value under subsection (a) of this section. The notice of final determination issued by the Office of Tax and Revenue on the petition for review may be appealed to the Real Property Tax Appeals Commission for the District of Columbia as provided in § 47-825.01a(e).</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>A transferor or transferee aggrieved by a fair market value determination under subsection (a) of this section may appeal the determination to the Superior Court as provided in § 47-825.01a(g).</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
