<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-309">
  <num type="act">26-309</num>
  <num type="bill">26-400</num>
  <heading type="short">Statutory Neglect Amendment Act of 2026</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend section 16-2301 of the District of Columbia Official Code to consolidate and standardize the statutory definition of neglect, to clarify that a parent, guardian, or custodian's eligibility for, or use of, public benefits, nor homelessness, or lack of stable housing, alone, shall not be sufficient to establish that the parent, guardian, or custodian's failure to provide adequate care is due to the lack of financial means.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-10-06</introduced>
    <effective projected="true">2026-06-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/60460/Signed_Act/B26-0400-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=236895">D.C. Act 26-309</citation>
      <citation type="register">73 DCR 6825</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0400">
      <vote date="2026-03-03" reading="First"/>
      <vote date="2026-03-31" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2026-04-24</enacted>
      <summary>BILL SUMMARY - As introduced, Bill 26-400 would update the statutory definition of neglect and clarify that the Child and Family Services Agency shall not use a parent or guardian’s eligibility or use of public benefits as the sole evidence that parental failure is unrelated to neglect. It would also clarify that homelessness or lack of stable housing shall not be used as sole evidence of neglect.</summary>
      <committee>Youth Affairs, Judiciary and Public Safety</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Statutory Neglect Amendment Act of 2026".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 16-2301 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (9) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(9)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The term "neglected child" means a child:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>who has been abused by their parent, guardian, or custodian, or whose parent, guardian, or custodian has failed to take actions that are reasonable under the circumstances to protect the child from abuse;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>who is suffering or is at substantial risk of suffering serious physical, mental, or emotional harm, due to the parent, guardian, or custodian's failure to provide adequate care, including minimally necessary supervision, subsistence, and education as required by law based on a consideration of a totality of the circumstances, and the failure is not solely due to the lack of financial means of his or her parent, guardian, or custodian; provided, that eligibility for, or receipt of, public benefits, alone, shall not be sufficient to establish that the failure is not due solely to the lack of financial means;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <text>who is suffering or is at substantial risk of suffering serious physical, mental, or emotional harm, because the parent, guardian, or custodian is unable to discharge their responsibilities to the child due to mental incapacity;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <text>whose parent, guardian, or custodian refuses, is unavailable, or states that they are unable to continue providing for or assume the child's care, control, or subsistence;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(v)</num>
                <text>who is in imminent danger of being abused and another child living in the same household or under the care of the same parent, guardian, or custodian has been abused;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(vi)</num>
                <text>Repealed;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(vii)</num>
                <text>who has been abandoned;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(viii)</num>
                <text>who is born dependent on a controlled substance or has a significant presence of a controlled substance in their system at birth;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ix)</num>
                <text>in whose body there is a controlled substance as a direct and foreseeable consequence of the acts or omissions of the child's parent, guardian, or custodian; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(x)</num>
                <text>who is regularly exposed to illegal drug-related activity in the home.</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(xi)</num>
                <text>Repealed.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new subparagraph (D) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <num>(D)</num>
            <text>Homelessness or lack of stable housing alone shall not be sufficient to establish that a child is a neglected child.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (23) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(23)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The term "abused", when used with reference to a child, includes:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>infliction of physical injury;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>infliction of mental injury;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <text>sexual abuse or exploitation;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <text>mistreatment of the child by withholding adequate food, clothing, shelter, or medical care;</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(v)</num>
                <text>interfering with a child's breathing; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(vi)</num>
                <text>threatening a child with a firearm, a knife, or any prohibited weapon described in section 14 of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 654; D.C. Official Code § 22-4514), or using such a weapon on a child.</text>
              </para>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Subparagraph (B) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="2">
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The term "abused" does not include physical discipline administered by a parent, guardian, or custodian to their child; provided, that the child is at least 3 years of age, and the physical discipline is reasonable in manner and moderate in degree.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (24) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>A new paragraph (52) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include lvl="1">
        <para>
          <num>(52)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(A)</num>
            <text>The term "abandoned" means a child:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(i)</num>
              <text>whose parent, guardian, or legal custodian has not made reasonable efforts to maintain a parental relationship with the child for a period of at least 4 months; or</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(ii)</num>
              <text>who has resided in a hospital located in the District of Columbia for at least 10 days following the birth of the child and the parent of the child did not undertake any action or make any effort to maintain a parental relationship or contact with the child or hospital.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(B)</num>
            <text>The term "abandoned" does not include a child who is surrendered in accordance with Title I of the Newborn Safe Haven Amendment Act of 2010, effective May 27, 2010 (D.C. Law 18-158; D.C. Official Code § 4-1451.01 <em>et seq.</em>).</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect after approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
