<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-316" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">26-316</num>
  <num type="bill">26-630</num>
  <heading type="short">Rate Plan Vacatur Interim Protections Emergency Amendment Act of 2026</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999 to disallow electricity service disconnection in a period of time after an order approved by the Public Service Commission is vacated and remanded.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2026-03-30</introduced>
    <effective>2026-04-29</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/61495/Signed_Act/B26-0630-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=236946">D.C. Act 26-316</citation>
      <citation type="register">0 DCR 0</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/Legislation/B26-0630">
      <vote date="2026-03-31" reading="Amendment"/>
      <vote date="2026-03-31" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2026-04-29</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Rate Plan Vacatur Interim Protections Emergency Amendment Act of 2026".</text>
  <section codify:path="34|15">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-107; D.C. Official Code § 34-1501 <em>et seq</em>.), is amended by adding a new section 106b to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <codify:insert after="§34-1506.01" num-value="34-1506.02" history-prefix="as added"/>
        <num>106b</num>
        <heading proof="needed">Disconnection of service during remand interim period prohibited.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this section, the term "remand interim period" means the period of time after the issuance of a judicial order vacating a multi-year rate plan approved by the Commission and before a new rate plan is approved and instituted.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>An electric company may not disconnect electric service for non-payment of a bill or fees during the remand interim period or for 15 calendar days after the end of the remand interim period, unless the household has an average outstanding balance of more than $1,000:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>For any single-family residence, or any unit within a multifamily residence at which each unit's electricity usage can be measured; or</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Per unit for any multifamily residence at which each unit's electricity usage cannot be measured, to be calculated by dividing the amount of the total arrearage assigned to the property by the number of units at the property at the time of the proposed disconnection, regardless of the amount of debt held by the owner or an individual tenant.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-107" type="History" path="§106b">May 9, 2000, D.C. Law 13-107, § 106b</annotation>
        <codify:emergency-new-sec doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1506.02" interim-path="§34-1506.01" perm-eff="2026-04-29"/>
        <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§34-1506.02" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
          <text>
      *NOTE: This section was created by emergency legislation that will expire on July 28, 2026.*
      </text>
        </codify:insert>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto) and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
