<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-58" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">26-58</num>
  <num type="bill">26-192</num>
  <heading type="short">On-Premises and On-Site Extended Hours Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow the Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Board to extend the hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages for cultural events, sporting events, or tourism-related events for licensees registered with the Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Board.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-03-26</introduced>
    <effective>2025-04-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57437/Signed_Act/B26-0192-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=210305">D.C. Act 26-58</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 4924</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0192">
      <vote date="2025-04-01" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-04-22</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "On-Premises and On-Site Extended Hours Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section codify:path="§25-723">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 25-723 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>A new subsection (g) is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <para>
          <codify:insert after="(f)" num-value="(g)"/>
          <num>(g)</num>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Except as provided in <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-724">§ 25-724</cite>, for a licensee operating under an on-premises retailer's license, manufacturer's license holding an on-site sales and consumption permit, or a temporary license, the Board may extend the hours of sales, service, and consumption of alcoholic beverages until 4:00 a.m., and the hours of operation to 24 hours a day, for cultural events, sporting events, or tourism-related events, if the licensee:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Registers with the Board;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Pays a minimum registration fee of $100; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>Provides written notice no later than 3 calendar days before the first day of the cultural event, sporting event, or tourism-related event to the Board of its extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The Board shall provide written notification to the Metropolitan Police Department at least 48 hours before extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption under this subsection will take effect. The written notification shall include the list of establishments eligible to participate in the extended hours under this subsection.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>To the extent feasible, the Board shall provide notice of extended hours of operation, sales, service, and consumption pursuant to this subsection in the District of Columbia Register, and shall, within 24 hours of that publication, post notice of these extended hours on ABCA's website.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>The fees collected pursuant to this subsection shall be deposited into the Alcoholic Beverage and Cannabis Administration Fund established by <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-210">§ 25-210</cite>.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>"Cultural event" means an event or gathering that aims to highlight the customs, arts, music, dances, or cuisines of various cultures through performances and displays of artistic expression.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>"Sporting event" means a professional or amateur event involving a game or athletic competition that occurs either once annually or every 4 years that is organized by a league or association.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>"Tourism-related event" means an event, such as a major festival, convention, or trade show, with the potential to attract visitors from outside a 50-mile radius of the District, and that is likely to produce a significant positive financial impact for the District.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723"/>
      <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
        <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on July 21, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§25-723(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
      </codify:insert>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
