<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" id="D.C. Act 26-78" codify:doc="D.C. Code">
  <num type="act">26-78</num>
  <num type="bill">26-241</num>
  <heading type="short">Clemency Board Waiver Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2025</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, due to congressional review, section 205 of the Clemency Board Establishment Act of 2018 to authorize the Clemency Board to, for applicants seeking a pardon, grant a waiver of the 5-year waiting period.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2025-05-05</introduced>
    <effective>2025-05-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.gov/downloads/LIMS/57674/Signed_Act/B26-0241-Signed_Act.pdf?Id=212567">D.C. Act 26-78</citation>
      <citation type="register">72 DCR 6461</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B26-0241">
      <vote date="2025-05-06" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2025-05-28</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Clemency Board Waiver Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2025".</text>
  <section codify:path="§24-481.05">
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Section 205 of the Clemency Board Establishment Act of 2018, effective December 13, 2018 (D.C. Law 22-197; D.C. Official Code § 24-481.05), is  amended by adding a new subsection (f) to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <para>
        <codify:insert after="(e)" num-value="(f)"/>
        <num>(f)</num>
        <text>The Board may, upon written request of the applicant, grant a waiver of the requirements of subsection (c)(1) of this section; provided, that:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(1)</num>
          <text>The Board shall only grant a waiver under this subsection where the Board is in receipt of notice from the Office of the Pardon Attorney that the Pardon Attorney or the President of the United States has provided the applicant with a waiver of the 5-year requirement pursuant to § 9-140.112 of the Department of Justice Manual;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>The Board may decline to grant a waiver under this subsection even when the Board is in receipt of the notice described in paragraph (1) of this subsection;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The Board shall not grant a waiver under this subsection when the applicant is on probation, parole, or supervised release;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The Board may request additional information from the applicant to support their request for a waiver of subsection (c)(1) of this section, which may include a request to meet with the applicant to discuss their waiver request;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>The Board shall provide the applicant with written notice of the Board's decision to grant or deny a waiver request pursuant to this subsection; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>Prior to the Board making a determination whether to grant a request for a waiver pursuant to this subsection, the applicant's application shall be deferred until a determination is made.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.05"/>
    <codify:insert doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.05" before="heading" history="false" display-template="">
      <text>
      *NOTE: This section includes amendments by emergency legislation that will expire on August 26, 2025. To view the text of this section after the expiration of all emergency and temporary legislation, click this link: <cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-481.05(Perm)">Permanent Version</cite>.*
      </text>
    </codify:insert>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading proof="needed">Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
