<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>23-1323</num>
  <heading>Detention of addict.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Whenever it appears that a person charged with a crime of violence, as defined in section 23-1331(4), may be an addict, as defined in section 23-1331(5), the judicial officer may, upon motion of the United States attorney, order such person detained in custody for a period not to exceed three calendar days, under medical supervision, to determine whether the person is an addict.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon or before the expiration of three calendar days, the person shall be brought before a judicial officer and the results of the determination shall be presented to such judicial officer. The judicial officer thereupon (1) shall treat the person in accordance with section 23-1321, or (2) upon motion of the United States attorney, may (A) hold a hearing pursuant to section 23-1322, or (B) hold a hearing pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person who is an addict may be ordered detained in custody under medical supervision if the judicial officer —</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>holds a pretrial detention hearing in accordance with § <cite root="23-1322">23-1322</cite>(d);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>finds that —</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>there is clear and convincing evidence that the person is an addict;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>based on the factors set out in § <cite root="23-1322">23-1322</cite>(e), there is no condition or combination of conditions of release which will reasonably assure the safety of any other person or the community; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>on the basis of information presented to the judicial officer by proffer or otherwise, there is a substantial probability that the person committed the offense for which he is present before the judicial officer; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>issues an order of detention accompanied by written findings of fact and the reasons for its entry.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The provisions of § <cite root="23-1322">23-1322</cite>(h) shall apply to this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 646, Pub. L. 91-358, title II, § 210(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-125">July 3, 1992, D.C. Law 9-125, § 4, 39 DCR 2134</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="23-1324">23-1324</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 23-1323.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 23-1323.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
