<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>23-1110</num>
  <heading>Designation of official to issue citations or take money or bond.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Releasing official” means a sworn member of a law enforcement agency, as defined in § <cite path="§23-501">23-501</cite>(2), appointed by the judges of the Superior Court to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Act as a clerk of the court with authority to issue citations pursuant to § <cite path="§23-584">23-584</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Take money pursuant to § <cite path="§5-335.01">5-335.01</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Take bond imposed upon the issuance of a bench warrant by a judicial officer of the Superior Court, from persons charged with offenses triable in the Superior Court;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Release persons eligible for release pursuant to § <cite path="§23-584">23-584</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Tender offers to resolve criminal charges using post-and-forfeit procedures pursuant to § <cite path="§5-335.01">5-335.01</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Superior Court” means the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The judges of the Superior Court may remove releasing officials at any time.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A releasing official shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be subject to the orders and rules of the Superior Court in the discharge of his or her duties; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Receive no additional compensation for duties performed as a releasing official other than his or her salary as an official of the Metropolitan Police Department or other law enforcement agency operating in the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 638, Pub. L. 91-358, title II, § 210(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-151" type="History">Aug. 20, 1994, D.C. Law 10-151, § 101(a), 41 DCR 2608</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 283(e), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-243" type="History">Apr. 24, 2015, D.C. Law 20-243, § 2(b)(2), 61 DCR 8320</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Capitol Police Citation Release: For designation of a member of the Capitol Police to have responsibility for citation release, and to take bail, collateral, or bond in the same manner as an official of the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia under this section, see § 108 of Pub. L. 104-186, 110 Stat. 1719.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 283(e) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(a) of the Omnibus Criminal Justice Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-255, June 22, 1994,  41 DCR 4286).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-243">D.C. Law 20-243</cite> substituted “to issue citations or take money or bond” for “to take bail or collateral when court is not in session; issuance of citations” in the section heading; and rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in [§ <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>]” for “not more than the maximum provided for the misdemeanor for which such citation was issued” in (b)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 23-1110.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 23-1110.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§25-781">25-781</cite>, § <cite path="§25-785">25-785</cite>, and § <cite path="§25-1002">25-1002</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
