<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>23-1901</num>
  <heading>Crime victims’ bill of rights.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Officers or employees of the District of Columbia engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of crime or the judicial process shall make their best efforts to see that victims of crime are accorded the rights described in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A crime victim has the right to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be treated with fairness and with respect for the victim’s dignity and privacy;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Be reasonably protected from the accused offender;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be notified of court proceedings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Be present at all court proceedings related to the offense, including the sentencing, and release, parole, record-sealing, and post-conviction hearings, unless the court determines that testimony by the victim would be materially affected if the victim heard other testimony or where the needs of justice otherwise require;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Confer with an attorney for the prosecution in the case which does not include the authority to direct the prosecution of the case;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>An order of restitution from the person convicted of the criminal conduct that caused the victim’s loss or injury;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Information about the conviction, sentencing, imprisonment, detention, and release of the offender, and about any court order to seal the offender’s criminal records;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Notice of the rights provided in this chapter and under the laws of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Be notified of any available victim advocate or other appropriate person to develop a safety plan and appropriate services.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>This section does not create a cause of action or defense in favor of any person arising out of the failure to accord to a victim the rights enumerated in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-301" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-301, § 302(b), 47 DCR 7039</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-307" type="History">May 5, 2007, D.C. Law 16-307, § 3(b)(1), 54 DCR 868</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-239" type="History">Oct. 23, 2010, D.C. Law 18-239, § 206(c), 57 DCR 5405</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§23-1902">23-1902</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-307">D.C. Law 16-307</cite>, in subsec. (b)(4), substituted “and release, parole, record-sealing, and post-conviction hearings,” for “and release or parole hearings,”; and, in subsec. (b)(7), substituted “offender, and about any court order to seal the offender’s criminal records” for “offender”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-239">D.C. Law 18-239</cite>, in subsec. (b), deleted “and” from the end of par. (7), substituted “; and” for a period the end of par. (8), and added par. (9).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes"><cite doc="D.C. Law 20-139">D.C. Law 20-139</cite> designated §§ <cite path="§23-1901">23-1901</cite> through <cite path="§23-1906">23-1906</cite> as subchapter I of this chapter.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
