<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>23-1907</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Confidential communication” means information exchanged between a sexual assault victim and a sexual assault victim advocate during the course of the advocate providing counseling, support, and assistance to the victim, including all records kept by the advocate and the sexual assault program concerning the victim and services provided to the victim.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“DC Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Program” or “DC SANE Program” means the program that provides comprehensive care to adult victims of rape, sexual assault, and other sex crimes, operated by the Office of Victim Services, in collaboration with the Network for Victim Recovery DC, or its successor entity, and the Medstar Washington Hospital Center, or its successor entity, where medical forensic exams are conducted.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Forensic nurse examiner” means a nurse with specialized training in medical forensic evidence collection who participates in the DC SANE Program.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Hospital” means the MedStar Washington Hospital Center, or any medical facility where a forensic nurse examiner conducts a sexual assault forensic evaluation of the sexual assault victim.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“Interview” means any interview by the MPD or other law enforcement agency with a sexual assault victim that occurs in conjunction with a sexual assault victim receiving any medical treatment or forensic evidence collection related to sexual assault at the hospital and any subsequent in-person interview with law enforcement relating to the sexual assault.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>“MPD” means the Metropolitan Police Department.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>“Sexual assault” means any of the following offenses: §§ <cite path="§22-1901">22-1901</cite> (incest); <cite path="§22-3002">22-3002</cite> (first degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3003">22-3003</cite> (second degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3004">22-3004</cite> (third degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3005">22-3005</cite> (fourth degree sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3006">22-3006</cite> (misdemeanor sexual abuse); <cite path="§22-3009.03">22-3009.03</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a secondary education student); <cite path="§22-3009.04">22-3009.04</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a secondary education student); <cite path="§22-3013">22-3013</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a ward, patient, client, or prisoner); <cite path="§22-3014">22-3014</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a ward, patient, client, or prisoner); <cite path="§22-3015">22-3015</cite> (first degree sexual abuse of a patient or client); <cite path="§22-3016">22-3016</cite> (second degree sexual abuse of a patient or client); or <cite path="§22-3018">22-3018</cite> (attempts to commit sexual offenses); provided, that the sexual assault victim is 18 years of age or older.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>“Sexual assault victim” means an individual 18 years or age or older against whom sexual assault has been committed or is alleged to have been committed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>“Sexual assault victim advocate” means a trained advocate employed by a community-based advocacy organization that is a member of the DC SANE Program or its successor program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-139" type="History">Nov. 20, 2014, D.C. Law 20-139, § 101(c), 61 DCR 5913</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
