<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>23-562</num>
  <heading>Execution and return.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A warrant issued pursuant to this subchapter shall be executed by the arrest of the person named. The officer need not have the warrant in his possession at the time of the arrest, but upon request he shall show the warrant to the person as soon as possible. If the officer does not have the warrant in his possession at the time of the arrest, he shall inform the person of the offense charged and of the fact that a warrant has been issued.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A summons shall be served upon a person by delivering a copy to him personally, by leaving it at his dwelling house or usual place of abode with some person of suitable age and discretion then residing therein, or by mailing it to the person’s last known address.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The officer executing a warrant shall make return thereof to the judicial officer before whom the person is brought for preliminary examination. At the request of the appropriate prosecutor, any unexecuted and unexpired warrant shall be returned to the issuing court or judicial officer and shall be canceled.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>On or before the return day the person to whom a summons was delivered for service shall make return thereof to the court or officer before whom the summons is returnable.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>At the request of the appropriate prosecutor made at any time while the complaint is pending, a warrant returned unexecuted and not canceled or expired or a summons returned unserved or a duplicate thereof may be delivered by the judicial officer to the marshal or other authorized person for execution or service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A law enforcement officer within the District of Columbia making an arrest under a warrant issued pursuant to this subchapter, making an arrest without a warrant, or receiving a person arrested by a special policeman or other person pursuant to § <cite path="§23-582">23-582</cite>, or a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department receiving a person arrested by a law enforcement officer within the District of Columbia or a special policeman or other person pursuant to § <cite path="§23-582">23-582</cite>, shall take the arrested person without unnecessary delay before the court or other judicial officer empowered to commit persons charged with the offense for which the arrest was made. This subsection, however, shall not be construed to conflict with or otherwise supersede section 3501 of Title 18, United States Code. When a person arrested without a warrant is brought before a judicial officer, a complaint or information shall be filed forthwith.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Before taking an arrested person to a judicial officer, a law enforcement officer or a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department, may perform any recording, fingerprinting, photographing, or other preliminary police duties required in the particular case, and if such duties are performed with reasonable promptness, the period of time required therefor shall not constitute a delay within the meaning of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 628, Pub. L. 91-358, title II, § 210(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-284" type="History">June 12, 1999, D.C. Law 12-284, § 8(b), 46 DCR 1328</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Execution of warrants by police force, see § <cite path="§5-127.05">5-127.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 23-562.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 23-562.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>Section 8(b) of D.C. Law 12-282 inserted “or a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department receiving a person arrested by a law enforcement officer within the District of Columbia or a special policeman or other person pursuant to § 23-582 (1981 Ed.)” in (c)(1); and in (c)(2), inserted “or a designated civilian employee of the Metropolitan Police Department.”</text>
      <text>Section 13(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-282">D.C. Law 12-282</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 8(b) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization and Street Solicitation for Prostitution Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-428, August 6, 1998,  45 DCR 5884).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 8(b) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Legislative Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-506, November 10, 1998,  45 DCR 45 8139), and § 8(b) of the Metropolitan Police Department Civilianization Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-13, February 8, 1999,  46 DCR 2333).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
