<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1216</num>
  <heading>Appropriation.</heading>
  <text>Appropriation is hereby authorized to be made to carry out the provisions of this chapter, and the Mayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to include in his annual estimates provision for all the expenses of the Office of the Director incident to such purposes, and for personnel.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>July 2, 1940, 54 Stat. 740, ch. 527, § 15</annotation>
      <annotation>Oct. 28, 1949, 63 Stat. 972, title XI, ch. 782, § 1106(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(m), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-279">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-279, § 201(j), 54 DCR 903</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 40-1016.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 40-715.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-279">D.C. Law 16-279</cite> substituted “Office of the Director” for “Office of the Director and Recorder”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite root="1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
