<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2301.02</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purpose of this chapter:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The term “Department” means the Department of Motor Vehicles, established pursuant to § <cite root="50-901">50-901</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The term “Director” means the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles or his or her designee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The term “District” means the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The term “infraction” means any conduct subject to administrative adjudication under the provisions of this chapter and with respect to which the Corporation Counsel does not commence a proceeding in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The term “lessor” means any owner of a vehicle engaged in the business of renting or leasing vehicles to be used or operated in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5A)</num>
    <text>The term “motor vehicle” means all vehicles propelled by an internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam. The term “motor vehicle” shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon stationary rails or tracks, personal mobility devices, as defined by § <cite root="50-2201.02">50-2201.02</cite>(12), or a battery-operated wheelchair when operated by a person with a disability.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The term “operator” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any person, corporation, firm, agency, association, organization, federal, state or local governmental agency in the business of renting or leasing vehicles to be used or operated in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>An owner who operates his own vehicle; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>A person who operates a vehicle owned by another.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The term “owner” means:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Any person, corporation, firm, agency, association, organization, federal, state or local governmental agency or other authority or other entity having the property of or title to a vehicle used or operated in the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Any registrant of a vehicle used or operated in the District; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Any person, corporation, firm, agency, association, organization, federal, state or local government agency or authority or other entity in the business of renting or leasing vehicles to be used or operated in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The term “related vehicle conveyance fee” means a vehicle conveyance fee that is related to a civil fine because the imposition of each arises from the same parking infraction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>The term “vehicle conveyance fee” means the charge for moving (by towing or otherwise) an unattended vehicle parked in violation of any traffic regulation (except overtime parking of less than 24 hours) to a legal parking place, other than at an impoundment facility.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-104">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-104, § 102, 25 DCR 1275</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-176">Mar. 15, 1985, D.C. Law 5-176, § 4, 32 DCR 748</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-289">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-289, § 302(a), 48 DCR 2057</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-235">Mar. 25, 2003, D.C. Law 14-235, § 11, 49 DCR 9788</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 90(a), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-224">Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-224, § 209, 53 DCR 10225</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-303">Mar. 20, 2009, D.C. Law 17-303, § 4(a), 55 DCR 12803</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="50-1621">50-1621</cite> and § <cite root="50-2201.02">50-2201.02</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 40-602.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 40-1102.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-289">D.C. Law 13-289</cite> rewrote pars. (1) and (2) which had read:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(1) The term ‘Department’ means the District of Columbia Department of Transportation.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2) The term ‘Director’ means the Director of the District of Columbia Department of Transportation.”</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-235">D.C. Law 14-235</cite> rewrote par. (5a) which had read as follows: “(5a) The term ‘motor vehicle’ means all vehicles propelled by an internal-combustion engine, electricity, or steam. The term ‘motor vehicle’ shall not include traction engines, road rollers, vehicles propelled only upon stationary rails or tracks, and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour.”</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in par. (5a), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-224">D.C. Law 16-224</cite>, in par. (5a), revived the provisions of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-235">D.C. Law 14-235</cite> that expired on October 1, 2005, and substituted “personal mobility devices, as defined by § <cite root="50-2201.02">50-2201.02</cite>(12), or a battery-operated wheelchair when operated by a person with a disability” for “electric personal assistive mobility devices, as defined by § <cite root="50-2201.02">50-2201.02</cite>(12), and battery-operated wheelchairs when operated by a handicapped person at speeds not exceeding 10 miles per hour”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, in par. (5a), purported to substitute “person with a disability” for “handicapped person”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-303">D.C. Law 17-303</cite> added pars. (8) and (9).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 11 of Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-85">D.C. Law 16-85</cite>, April 4, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 3344).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 11 of Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-237, December 22, 2005,  53 DCR 249).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 11 of Motor Vehicle Definition Electric Personal Assistive Mobility Device Exemption Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-323, March 23, 2006,  53 DCR 2567).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 209 of Personal Mobility Device Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-528, December 4, 2006,  53 DCR 9826).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Expiration of Law</heading>
      <text>Expiration of Law 14-235</text>
      <text>Section 14 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-235">D.C. Law 14-235</cite> provided that the act shall expire on October 1, 2005.</text>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
      <annotation>The functions of the Department of Transportation were transferred to the Department of Public Works by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
