<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2624</num>
  <heading>Administrator of General Services to enforce regulations.</heading>
  <text>Nothing contained in this section and subchapter II of Chapter 24 of this title [§ <cite root="50-2421.01">50-2421.01</cite> et seq.]. shall be construed to interfere with the charge and control committed to the Administrator of General Services over the public buildings and property of the United States in the District of Columbia or any other officer charged with the custody and control of property of the United States in the District of Columbia and such officers with respect to such property, under their respective jurisdiction and control, are hereby authorized and empowered to make and enforce all regulations for the parking of vehicles upon the property of the United States in the District of Columbia (other than public highways), to remove and impound any vehicle, parked, stored, or left in violation of this section and subchapter II of Chapter 24 of this title [§ <cite root="50-2421.01">50-2421.01</cite> et seq.]. and to keep the same impounded until the owner thereof, or other duly authorized person, shall deposit collateral for his appearance in court to answer for such violation, the amount of collateral to be fixed by the officer charged with the custody and control of property of the United States in the District of Columbia in an amount not to exceed $25. Violations of regulations for the parking of cars upon the property of the United States in the District of Columbia shall be subject to the penalties prescribed in subchapter II of Chapter 24 of this title [§ <cite root="50-2421.01">50-2421.01</cite> et seq.]. and all prosecutions for the violations thereof shall be upon information filed by the United States Attorney in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Jan. 15, 1942, 56 Stat. 6, ch. 4, § 2</annotation>
      <annotation>Apr. 1, 1942, 56 Stat. 190, ch. 207, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 570, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 155(a)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-35">Oct. 28, 2003, D.C. Law 15-35, § 13(e)(2), 50 DCR 6579</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Regulation of traffic, power to promulgate regulations, see § <cite root="50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 40-813.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 40-811.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-35">D.C. Law 15-35</cite> substituted “subchapter II of Chapter 24 of this title” for “§ <cite root="50-261">50-261</cite>” throughout the section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 13(e)(2) of the Removal and Disposition of Abandoned, Dangerous and Other Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Reform Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 15-104, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5534).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 13(e)(2) of Removal and Disposition of Abandoned and Other Unlawfully Parked Vehicles Reform Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-171, October 6, 2003,  50 DCR 9163).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Transfer of Functions</heading>
      <annotation>All functions of the Federal Works Administrator and the Commissioner of Public Buildings were transferred to the Administrator of General Services by § 103(a) of the Act of June 30, 1949, 63 Stat. 380.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Application of 15-35: Section 15 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-35">D.C. Law 15-35</cite> provided: “This act shall apply to all vehicles impounded after its effective date. This act shall also apply to all vehicles impounded prior to its effective date provided that notice is sent to the owners and lien holders in accordance with the provisions of subsections 7(b) or (c), as is applicable.”</text>
      <text>Effect of repeal provisions: Section 14 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-35">D.C. Law 15-35</cite> provided: “Any repeal of a law or regulation by this act shall not invalidate any enforcement action, adjudication, or any other action made or taken pursuant to such law or regulation.”</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
