<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1802</num>
  <heading>Use of safety belts required; exceptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in Chapter 17 of this title, the driver and all passengers in a motor vehicle shall wear a properly adjusted and fastened safety belt while the driver is in control of the vehicle.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>This section does not apply to operators or passengers under the following circumstances:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Riders in a motor vehicle manufactured before July 1, 1966;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Riders who possess a written verification from a licensed physician that the rider is unable to wear a safety belt for medical reasons;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Riders who are passengers in a vehicle if all seating positions with seat belts in the vehicle are occupied by other persons. The driver shall insure that children 16 years of age and under have preference to seating positions with seat belts over persons more than 16 years of age; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Operators of taxicabs who possess valid taxicab licenses while picking up or transporting passengers for hire between the hours of 6:00 p.m. and 6:00 a.m.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Two years following June 9, 2001, the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission shall submit to the Council a report on the impact on driver safety of subsection (b)(4) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-73" type="History">Dec. 12, 1985, D.C. Law 6-73, § 3, 32 DCR 6344</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-57" type="History">Mar. 7, 1992, D.C. Law 9-57, § 3, 38 DCR 7283</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-244" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-244, § 2(a), 44 DCR 1155</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-307" type="History">June 9, 2001, D.C. Law 13-307, § 4, 48 DCR 600</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-1602.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-307">D.C. Law 13-307</cite>, in subsec. (b), deleted “or” at the end of par. (2), substituted “; or” for the period at the end of par. (3), and added par. (4); and added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">Expiration of Law 6-73</text>
    <text type="Expiration of Law">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§50-1801">50-1801</cite>.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
