<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1301.46</num>
  <heading>Effect of Mayor’s finding that insurer obligated to pay judgment.</heading>
  <text>No license, registration or nonresident’s operating privilege of any person shall be suspended under the provisions of this subchapter if the Mayor shall find that an insurer was obligated to pay the judgment upon which suspension is based, at least to the extent and for the amounts required in this chapter, but has not paid such judgment for any reason. A finding by the Mayor that an insurer is obligated to pay a judgment shall not be binding upon such insurer and shall have no legal effect whatever except for the purpose of administering this section. Whenever in any judicial proceedings it shall be determined by any final judgment, decree or order that an insurer is not obligated to pay any such judgment, the Mayor, notwithstanding any contrary finding theretofore made by him shall forthwith suspend the license and registration and any nonresident’s operating privilege of any person against whom such judgment was rendered, as provided in § <cite path="§50-1301.43">50-1301.43</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 83-2-ch222" path="§46">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 132, ch. 222, § 46</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-462.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-446.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
