<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1507.06</num>
  <heading>Fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The fee for a trip permit shall be $50.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Vehicle registration fees for IRP registrants, and all interest earned on those fees, shall be deposited into a designated account entitled the IRP Fund to be used to reimburse IRP member jurisdictions and after such reimbursement to offset the costs of implementing this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Any monies remaining in the IRP fund after the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection have been met shall be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All funds received but not expended in a fiscal year shall revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-14" type="History">Sept. 5, 1997, D.C. Law 12-14, § 7, 44 DCR 3620</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-307" type="History">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-307, § 302, 52 DCR 1700</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-33" type="History">Oct. 20, 2005, D.C. Law 16-33, § 6032, 52 DCR 7503</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9102, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-126.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-307">D.C. Law 15-307</cite> rewrote this section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“The Mayor shall establish a registration fee schedule for commercial vehicles to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. The fees which this subchapter generates shall be placed in a designated account and used to offset the cost of implementing the provisions of this subchapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> rewrote subsec. (b), which had read as follows: “(b) Vehicle registration fees for IRP registrants, and all interest earned on those fees, shall be deposited into the IRP Fund and shall be used, first, to reimburse IRP member jurisdictions and, second, to offset the costs of implementing this subchapter. The IRP Fund shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in this section. All monies collected under this section and all interest earned on those monies, shall be deposited into the IRP Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All monies deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this section, subject to authorization by Congress.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (b)(2), substituted “shall be deposited into the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia” for “may be used by the Department of Motor Vehicles to defray operating costs”; and rewrote subsec. (b)(3), which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(3) All monies collected under this subsection and all interest earned on those monies shall be deposited into the IRP Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation, shall not revert to the fund balance of the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this subsection, subject to authorization by Congress.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§50-1507.01">50-1507.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6032 of Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-168, July 26, 2005,  52 DCR 7667).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title of subtitle D of title VI of Law 16-33: Section 6031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-33">D.C. Law 16-33</cite> provided that subtitle D of title VI of the act may be cited as the International Registration Plan Agreement Amendment Act of 2005.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
