<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1541.11</num>
  <heading>Action required on creation of certificate of title.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On creation of a written certificate of title, the Harbor Master promptly shall send the certificate of title to the secured party of record or, if none, to the owner of record, at the address indicated for that person in the files of the Harbor Master. On creation of an electronic certificate of title, the Harbor Master promptly shall send a record evidencing the certificate of title to the owner of record and, if there is one, to the secured party of record, at the address indicated for that person in the files of the Harbor Master. The Harbor Master may send the record to the person’s mailing address or, if indicated in the files of the Harbor Master, an electronic address.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the Harbor Master creates a written certificate of title, any electronic certificate of title for the vessel is canceled and replaced by the written certificate of title. The Harbor Master shall maintain in the files of the Harbor Master the date and time of cancellation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before the Harbor Master creates an electronic certificate of title, any written certificate of title for the vessel must be surrendered to the Harbor Master. If the Harbor Master creates an electronic certificate of title, the Harbor Master shall destroy or otherwise cancel the written certificate of title for the vessel which has been surrendered to the Harbor Master and maintain in the files of the Harbor Master the date and time of destruction or other cancellation. If a written certificate of title being canceled is not destroyed, the Harbor Master shall indicate on the face of the certificate of title that it has been canceled.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-215" type="History" path="§12">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-215, § 12, 61 DCR 13083</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-215">D.C. Law 20-215</cite>: Section 32 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-215">D.C. Law 20-215</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2016.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
