<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1301.69</num>
  <heading>Transfer of registration to defeat purpose of chapter.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If an owner’s registration has been suspended hereunder, such registration shall not be transferred nor the vehicle in respect to which such registration was issued registered in any other name until the Mayor is satisfied that such transfer of registration is proposed in good faith and not for the purpose or with the effect of defeating the purposes of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall in anywise affect the rights of any conditional vendor, chattel mortgagee or lessor of such a vehicle registered in the name of another as owner who becomes subject to the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall suspend the registration of any vehicle transferred in violation of the provisions of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 138, ch. 222, § 69</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-469.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-485.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
