<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1403.03</num>
  <heading>Suspension of minor’s motor vehicle operator’s permit for alcohol violation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall suspend the motor vehicle operator’s permit of a person under 21 years of age convicted of violating, or adjudicated in violation of <cite path="§25-130" proof="true">§ 25-130</cite>. The suspension shall be for the duration required by <cite path="§25-130" proof="true">§ 25-130</cite>. A copy of the conviction or adjudication shall be forwarded to the Mayor by the court or the administrative body authorized to adjudicate violations under <cite path="25|1">Chapter 1 of Title 25</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any person found guilty of operating a motor vehicle in the District during the period for which the person’s license or privilege is suspended, shall, for each offense, be fined not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>, imprisoned for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-2-ch443" path="§13b">Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 443, § 13b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-122" type="History">as added May 24, 1994, D.C. Law 10-122, § 4, 41 DCR 1658</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 268(d), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 25-130 and <cite path="25|1">Chapter 1 of Title 25</cite>, referred to in this section, are part and all, respectively, of Title 25, D.C. Official Code, which title was amended and enacted by <cite doc="D.C. Law 13-298">D.C. Law 13-298</cite>, effective May 3, 2001. For disposition of the subject matter of former Title 25, see the Disposition Table preceding <cite path="§25-101">§ 25-101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 268(d) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in <cite path="§22-3571.01">§ 22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $1,000” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-302.2.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
