<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1602</num>
  <heading>Comprehensive Bicycle Transportation and Safety Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There shall be established in the District of Columbia a Comprehensive Bicycle Transportation and Safety Program to promote the safe and convenient use of the bicycle as a means of transportation and recreation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The scope of the program shall include, but not be limited to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Planning and supporting road improvements for bicyclists, such as wide curb lanes, smooth shoulders, bicyclist-oriented signs and signals, and removal of hazards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Improving access for bicyclists on the road network and on all modes of public transportation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Monitoring construction and repair projects to ensure that no additional hazards or obstacles to bicyclists are created as the transportation system is built or rebuilt;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Assisting, organizing, and coordinating the planning, design, construction, improvement, repair, and maintenance of bicycle facilities, such as bicycle paths and bicycle lanes, both within and separate from the highway rights-of-way;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Promoting the installation of secure and convenient bicycle parking facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Organizing safety education and training programs for young and adult bicyclists, as well as for motorists, to reduce bicycling accidents and foster safe use of bicycles; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Promoting effective traffic law enforcement to protect the rights of all road users and to encourage good bicycling habits.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-179" type="History" path="§3">Mar. 16, 1985, D.C. Law 5-179, § 3, 32 DCR 764</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-1402.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
