<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1301.79</num>
  <heading>Self-insurers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person in whose name more than 25 vehicles are registered in the District of Columbia may qualify as a self-insurer by obtaining a certificate of self-insurance issued by the Mayor as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may, in his discretion, upon the application of such a person, issue a certificate of self-insurance when he is satisfied that such person is possessed and will continue to be possessed of ability to pay judgments obtained against such person. Such certificate may be issued authorizing a person to act as a self-insurer for either property damage or bodily injury, or both, and shall provide for the payment of benefits to the extent required by the Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Upon not less than 5 days notice and a hearing pursuant to such notice, the Mayor may upon reasonable grounds cancel a certificate of self-insurance. Failure to pay any judgment within 30 days after such judgment shall have become final shall constitute a reasonable ground for the cancellation of a certificate of self-insurance.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 139, ch. 222, § 79</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-155" type="History">Sept. 18, 1982, D.C. Law 4-155,§ 14(c)(7), 29 DCR 3491</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Compulsory/no-fault motor vehicle insurance, “self-insurer” defined, see § <cite path="§31-2402">31-2402</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-114.01">5-114.01</cite>, § <cite path="§31-2402">31-2402</cite>, and § <cite path="§50-1301.53">50-1301.53</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-478.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-494.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982,” referred to at the end of the last sentence in subsection (b) of this section, is <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 4-155">D.C. Law 4-155</law-cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
