<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1605</num>
  <heading>Helmet use requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any person under 16 years of age to operate or to be a passenger on a bicycle or any attachment to a bicycle on a public roadway, public bicycle path or other right-of-way, unless that person wears a protective helmet of good fit, fastened securely upon the head with the straps of the helmet.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for any parent or legal guardian of a child under 16 years of age to knowingly permit the child to operate or to be a passenger on a bicycle on a public roadway, public bicycle path, or other public right-of-way, unless at all times when the child is so engaged, he or she wears a protective bicycle helmet of good fit, fastened securely upon the head with the straps of the helmet.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The parents or legal guardians of any child under 16 years of age found in violation of this section shall be liable for paying a fine of $25. However, the fine shall be suspended for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>First time violators; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Violators who subsequent to the violation, but prior to the imposition of fine, purchase a helmet of the type required by this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The penalties provided for pursuant to subsection (c) of this section shall not be enforced until 90 days after May 23, 2000.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Any helmet sold or rented, or offered for sale or rent, for use by operators and passengers of bicycles shall be conspicuously labeled in accordance with the standard described in § <cite path="§50-1609">50-1609</cite>(5).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A person regularly engaged in the business of renting bicycles shall require each person seeking to rent a bicycle to provide his or her signature, either on the rental form, or on a separate form containing each of the following:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A written explanation of the provisions of this subchapter and the penalties for violations; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A statement concerning whether a person under 16 years of age will operate a bicycle in an area where a helmet is required.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person regularly engaged in the business of renting bicycles shall provide a properly fitted helmet to any person who will operate the bicycle in an area requiring a helmet, if the person does not already have a helmet in his or her possession. A reasonable fee may be charged for the helmet rental.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A person regularly engaged in the business of selling or renting bicycles who complies with this subchapter shall not be liable in a civil action for damages for any physical injuries sustained by a bicycle operator or passenger as a result of the operator’s passenger’s failure to wear a helmet or to wear a properly fitted or fastened helmet in violation of this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-179" type="History">Mar. 16, 1985, D.C. Law 5-179, § 6, 32 DCR 764</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-112" type="History">as added May 23, 2000, D.C. Law 13-112, § 2(b), 47 DCR 1985</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">General helmet use law, see § <cite path="§50-1651">50-1651</cite> et seq.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-1612">50-1612</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
