<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1507.03</num>
  <heading>Registration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall implement a program for owners and apportioned operators to obtain apportioned registrations for their fleets as promulgated under the IRP.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any vehicle qualifying for IRP and that the lists the District of Columbia as the established place of business must declare the District of Columbia as its base jurisdiction for purpose of the IRP and obtain a base plate from the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Vehicles qualifying for the IRP and engaged in interjurisdictional movement, but not apportioned or covered by reciprocity, shall acquire a trip permit prior to entering the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Trucks and truck tractors, combinations of vehicles having a combined gross vehicle weight of 26,000 pounds or less may be proportionally registered at the option of the registrant.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>At no point during operation, shall the gross weight of a vehicle registered pursuant to this subchapter, or of the combination of vehicles of which the vehicle is a part, exceed the gross weight on the basis of which it is registered.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Any owner or apportioned operator who fails to comply with subsection (b), (c) or (e) of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or jailed not longer than 180 days, or both, for each violation. In addition, a police officer may impound the vehicle until a valid registration or a trip permit is obtained.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-14" type="History">Sept. 5, 1997, D.C. Law 12-14, § 4, 44 DCR 3620</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-289" type="History">Apr. 27, 2001, D.C. Law 13-289, § 202, 48 DCR 2057</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-279" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-279, § 404, 54 DCR 903</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 269, 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-1401.02">50-1401.02</cite> and § <cite path="§50-1501.02">50-1501.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-123.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-289">D.C. Law 13-289</cite> added subsecs. (e) and (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-279">D.C. Law 16-279</cite>, in subsec. (d), deleted “and buses used in transportation of chartered parties” following “or less” following “pounds or less”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “of not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not to exceed $500” in (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§50-1507.01">50-1507.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 269 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority to the Director of the Department of Motor Vehicles to Implement the International Registration Plan, see Mayor’s Order 2005-21, January 25, 2005 ( 52 DCR 2841).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
