<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1904.02</num>
  <heading>Chemical testing after arrest.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, when a law enforcement officer has reasonable grounds to believe that a person was operating or in physical control of a motor vehicle within the District while intoxicated or while the person’s ability to operate a motor vehicle is impaired by the consumption of alcohol or a drug or a combination thereof, after arrest of the person, the person shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, be deemed to have given his or her consent, subject to the provisions of this chapter, to submitting 2 specimens for chemical testing of the person’s blood, breath, or urine, for the purpose of determining alcohol or drug content; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Submit 2 specimens for chemical testing of his or her blood, breath, or urine for the purpose of determining alcohol or drug content when he or she is involved in a collision in the District.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When a person is required to submit specimens for chemical testing pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, a law enforcement officer shall elect which types of specimens will be collected from the person and the law enforcement officer or a medical professional shall collect the specimen subject to the restriction in § <cite path="§50-1903">50-1903</cite>(a); provided, that the person may object to a particular type of specimen collection for chemical testing on valid religious or medical grounds. If a person objects to blood collection on valid religious or medical grounds, that person shall only be required to submit breath or urine specimens for collection.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>In addition to submitting specimens for chemical testing as provided in this section, a person may also submit specimens for chemical testing administered to him or her by a medical professional of his or her own choosing. The failure or inability of the person to obtain additional specimens or chemical tests shall not preclude the admission of chemical tests results that were the product of the law enforcement officer’s request under this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Before collecting specimens for chemical testing, the law enforcement officer shall advise the operator of the motor vehicle about the requirements of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-519" type="History">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1017, Pub. L. 92-519, § 4b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 101(d)(1), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-1905">50-1905</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 101(d)(1) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 101(d)(1) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 101(d)(1) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second  Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
