<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1211</num>
  <heading>Satisfaction of liens — Duties of Recorder; procedure when certificate lost.</heading>
  <text>The Recorder, upon receipt of a certificate whereon a lien is marked “Satisfied” as set forth in § <cite path="§50-1210">50-1210</cite>, shall enter on the face of the certificate and on the instrument, if any, filed in the Recorder’s office as hereinafter provided, his said record number, or, if no such instrument is on file, a brief description sufficient to identify the lien, and in either case the word “released,” a facsimile of his signature and the date. Where for any reason a lien-holder upon satisfaction of his lien has failed to mark the certificate as herein provided and the lien-holder cannot be located, or where the certificate after being so marked has been lost or destroyed and a duplicate certificate issued, the Recorder upon receipt of evidence satisfactory to him that the lien has been satisfied shall release it upon the certificate or duplicate certificate, and instrument, if any, as above set forth. Whenever any lien has been released as provided in this section for a period of more than 3 years, the Recorder of Deeds may destroy the instrument that created the lien.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 2, 1940, 54 Stat. 739, ch. 527, § 11</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">June 5, 1952, 66 Stat. 126, ch. 370, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-89" type="History">Aug. 5, 1963, 77 Stat. 119, Pub. L. 88-89, § 4</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-279" type="History">Mar. 14, 2007, D.C. Law 16-279, § 201(f), 54 DCR 903</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-1011.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-711.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-279">D.C. Law 16-279</law-cite>, in the first sentence, deleted “and on the card described in § <cite path="§50-1206">50-1206</cite>” following “face of the certificate”; in the penultimate sentence, deleted “the aforesaid cards” following “duplicate certificate”; and, in the last sentence, substituted “that created the lien” for “which created such lien and the index card upon which the lien information was entered; provided, that no other unsatisfied lien is shown on any such index card”.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
