<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1907</num>
  <heading>Judicial review.</heading>
  <text>Any person aggrieved by a final order of the Mayor revoking his or her license or denying him or her a license under the authority of this subchapter, may obtain a review thereof in accordance with § <cite path="§2-510">2-510</cite>.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-519" type="History">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1018, Pub. L. 92-519, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 101(d)(4), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-507.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-1007.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> substituted “his or her license” for “his license”; substituted “denying him or her” for “denying him”; and substituted “this subchapter” for “this chapter.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 101(d)(4) of Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-429, July 30, 2012,  59 DCR 9387).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 101(d)(4) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012, 59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(d)(4) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 101(d)(4) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
