<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1904.01</num>
  <heading>Preliminary breath test.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When a law enforcement officer has reasonable grounds to believe that a person was operating or in physical control of a vehicle within the District while intoxicated or while the person’s ability to operate a vehicle is impaired by the consumption of alcohol or a drug or a combination thereof, the law enforcement officer may, without making an arrest or issuing a violation notice, request that the person submit to a preliminary breath test, to be administered by the law enforcement officer, who shall use a device which the Mayor has approved by rule for that purpose.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before administering the test, the law enforcement officer shall advise the person to be tested that the preliminary breath test is voluntary and that the results of the test will be used to aid in the law enforcement officer’s decision whether to arrest the person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The results of the preliminary breath test shall be used by the law enforcement officer to aid in the decision whether to arrest the person, and the results of the test shall not be used as evidence by the District in any prosecutions and shall not be admissible in any judicial proceeding except in any judicial or other proceeding in which the validity of the arrest or the conduct of the law enforcement officer is an issue.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 92-519" type="History" path="§4a">Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 1017, Pub. L. 92-519, § 4a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 101(d)(1), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 101(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> designated §§ <cite path="§50-1905">50-1905</cite> to 50-1907 as subchapter II of this chapter.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 101(d)(1) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second  Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 101(d)(1) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 101(d)(1) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
