<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1501.05</num>
  <heading>Provisions not affected.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect the power of the Council of the District of Columbia, under the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925 [<cite path="§50-2201.01">§ 50-2201.01</cite> et seq.], as amended, to make rules and regulations, not inconsistent with the provisions of this subchapter, with respect to the registration of motor vehicles.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to relieve any person from the payment of any license tax under Chapters 28 and 30 of Title 47.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 75-1-ch690" path="§5">Aug. 17, 1937, 50 Stat. 682, ch. 690, title IV, § 5</annotation>
    <text type="References in Text">The District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, as amended, referred to in subsection (a), is the Act of March 3, 1925, 43 Stat. 1121, ch. 443.</text>
    <text type="References in Text"><cite path="47|30">Chapter 30 of Title 47</cite>, referred to in subsection (b), was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 5-136">D.C. Law 5-136</cite>, effective March 13, 1985.</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402 (292, 293, 295 to 299) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.11">§ 1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, <cite path="§1-207.14|(a)">§ 1-207.14(a)</cite>), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-105.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Taxation of personal property, exemption for motor vehicles and trailers, see <cite path="§47-1508">§ 47-1508</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
