<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1301.03</num>
  <heading>Administration.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall administer and enforce the provisions of this chapter. The Mayor may issue rules necessary to implement the provisions of this chapter, including, but not limited to, the amendment and revision of Chapter 8 of 18 DCMR. The fee for the reinstatement of a license or of a registration certificate shall be $98.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall receive and consider any pertinent information upon request of persons aggrieved by their orders or acts under any of the provisions of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall prescribe and provide suitable forms requisite or deemed necessary for the purpose of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall retain records required for the administration of this chapter for a period of 5 years, after which the Mayor may destroy or otherwise dispose of such records.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this chapter shall diminish or affect, or be construed to diminish or affect any rights, duties, or obligations of any person under the Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 83-2-ch222" path="§3">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 121, ch. 222, § 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 86-730" type="History">Sept. 8, 1960, 74 Stat. 862, Pub. L. 86-730, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-106" type="History">Oct. 31, 1969, 83 Stat. 175, Pub. L. 91-106, title IV, § 406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-97" type="History">Apr. 3, 1982, D.C. Law 4-97, § 3, 29 DCR 765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-155" type="History">Sept. 18, 1982, D.C. Law 4-155, § 14(c)(1), 29 DCR 3491</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-24" type="History">Aug. 2, 1983, D.C. Law 5-24,§ 7, 30 DCR 3341</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 1704(a), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(294) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">The “Compulsory/No-Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982”, referred to at the end of subsection (e) of this section, is <cite doc="D.C. Law 4-155">D.C. Law 4-155</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1704(a) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1704(a) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1704(a) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “$98” for “$30”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-419.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-403.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
