<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-1301.05</num>
  <heading>Abstract of operating record.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall, upon request, furnish any person a certified abstract of the District of Columbia operating record of any person subject to the provisions of this chapter, which abstract shall include enumeration of any motor vehicle accidents in which such person has been involved and reference to any convictions of said person for violation of the motor vehicle laws as reported to the Mayor and a record of any vehicles registered in the name of such person. The Mayor shall collect for each abstract the sum of $7.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of Motor Vehicles and the Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia are authorized to certify, for any purpose, an operating record abstract.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall upon request furnish any person an uncertified abstract of the District operating record of any person subject to the provisions of this chapter, which abstract shall include enumeration of any motor vehicle accidents in which such person has been involved and reference to any convictions of said person for violation of the motor vehicle laws, as reported to the Mayor. The Mayor shall collect for each such uncertified abstract a sum equal to the cost to the District of furnishing such abstract, as such cost may be determined by the Mayor from time to time.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 122, ch. 222, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-97" type="History">Apr. 3, 1982, D.C. Law 4-97, § 4, 29 DCR 765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-30" type="History">Aug. 17, 1991, D.C. Law 9-30, § 5, 38 DCR 4215</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-307" type="History">June 5, 2003, D.C. Law 14-307, § 1704(b), 49 DCR 11664</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-307" type="History">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-307, § 202, 52 DCR 1700</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-405.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed. § 40-421.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 14-307">D.C. Law 14-307</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “$7” for “$5”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-307">D.C. Law 15-307</cite>, in subsec. (a), designated the existing text as par. (1), and added par. (2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 109 of Omnibus Budget Support Temporary Act of 1991 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 9-19">D.C. Law 9-19</cite>, June 21, 1991, law notification  38 DCR 5786).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1704(b) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Emergency Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-544, December 4, 2002,  49 DCR 11700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1704(b) of the Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-27, February 24, 2003,  50 DCR 2151).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 1704(b) of Fiscal Year 2003 Budget Support Amendment Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-103, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5499).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
