<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-1301.39</num>
  <heading>Suspension of unlicensed or licensed person after certain convictions; proof of financial responsibility required; certificate of conviction to be forwarded to Mayor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a person by final order or judgment is convicted of or forfeits any bail or collateral deposited to secure an appearance for trial for driving a motor vehicle within the District of Columbia at a time when his license is suspended or revoked, the operating privilege of such person shall be suspended and no license shall thereafter be issued to such person, but if such person has obtained a license prior to the time the Mayor has issued an order precluding the issuance of such license, then such license shall be suspended; and no vehicle shall continue to be registered or thereafter be registered in the name of such person as owner, unless such person shall give and thereafter maintain proof of financial responsibility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be the duty of the clerk of the court in which any such conviction or forfeiture is ordered to forward immediately to the Mayor a certified copy of said order, which certified copy shall be prima facie evidence of the facts stated therein.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">May 25, 1954, 68 Stat. 131, ch. 222, § 39</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 85-792" type="History">Aug. 28, 1958, 72 Stat. 956, Pub. L. 85-792, § 10</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 90-589" type="History">Oct. 17, 1968, 82 Stat. 1152, Pub. L. 90-589, § 1</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-439.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-455.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
