<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2608</num>
  <heading>Appropriations; employment of director; salaries of members of agency.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor shall include in his annual budget such amounts as may be required from the highway fund established in § <cite path="§47-2301">47-2301</cite> for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Feb. 16, 1942, 56 Stat. 93, ch. 76, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">Oct. 28, 1949, 63 Stat. 992, title XI, ch. 782, § 1106(a)</annotation>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 87-408" type="History">Mar. 2, 1962, 76 Stat. 18, Pub. L. 87-408, § 602</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-139" type="History">Mar. 3, 1979, D.C. Law 2-139, § 3205(n), 25 DCR 5740</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-108" type="History">Sept. 26, 1980, D.C. Law 3-108, § 3(a), 27 DCR 3781</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-175" type="History">Nov. 16, 2006, D.C. Law 16-175, § 4(f), 53 DCR 6499</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-636.02">1-636.02</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-810.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-809.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-175">D.C. Law 16-175</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “The Mayor shall include in his annual budget such amounts as may be required from the highway fund established in § <cite path="§47-2301">47-2301</cite>, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter. The Mayor is authorized to employ a director and such other personal services as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter. The Mayor shall fix the compensation of the members of said Agency without reference to the provisions of the Classification Act of 1923; provided, however, that the compensation of any members shall not exceed $500 per annum; and provided further, that no compensation for services as a member of such agency shall be provided for any member who holds a salaried public office or position, in the District of Columbia or the federal government.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
