<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2003</num>
  <heading>Insurance discounts.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All insurance companies authorized to sell motor vehicle insurance in the District of Columbia shall provide a discount in the amount charged for a motor vehicle insurance policy to individuals 50 years of age and older who have successfully completed an approved course.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any schedule of rates or any rating plan for a motor vehicle insurance policy approved by the Department of Insurance shall provide for an appropriate 2-year discount in the premiums for individuals 50 years of age and older who have successfully completed an approved course.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The requirement in subsection (b) of this section shall be satisfied if an insurance company’s schedule of rates or rating plan provides a discount in the premiums for all individuals 50 years of age and older based upon factors related to the individual’s age.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A certificate of completion issued pursuant to § <cite path="§50-2002">50-2002</cite>(c) shall qualify an individual for the discount set forth in subsection (b) of this section during the 2-year period immediately following issuance of the certificate.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>An individual shall complete an approved course every 2 years in order to continue to be eligible for a discount in the premiums of a motor vehicle policy of insurance provided pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-46" type="History">Feb. 9, 1984, D.C. Law 5-46, §§ 5, 6, 30 DCR 5638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-51" type="History">Dec. 13, 2013, D.C. Law 20-51, § 2(c), 60 DCR 15155</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-493.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-51">D.C. Law 20-51</cite> substituted “50 years of age” for “55 years of age” throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
