<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2601</num>
  <heading>Findings and declaration of necessity.</heading>
  <text>It is hereby declared that the free circulation of traffic of all kinds through the highways of the District is necessary to the health, safety, and general welfare of the public, whether residing in said District, or traveling to, through, or from said District in the course of lawful pursuits; that in recent years the greatly increased use by the public of motor vehicles of all kinds has caused serious traffic congestion on the highways of the District; that the parking of motor vehicles on the highways of the District has contributed to this congestion to such an extent as to interfere seriously with the primary use of such highways for the movement of traffic; that such parking prevents the free circulation of traffic in, through, and from said District, impedes rapid and effective fighting of fires and the disposition of police forces in the District, threatens irreparable loss in valuations of property in the District, which can no longer be readily reached by vehicular traffic, and endangers the health, safety, and welfare of the general public; that this parking nuisance can be reduced by providing sufficient off-street parking facilities conveniently located in the several residential, commercial, industrial, and governmental areas of the District; that adequate off-street parking facilities have not been provided by private enterprise; that it may be necessary to supplement private parking spaces by off-street parking facilities provided by public undertaking; and that the enactment of this subchapter, as well as the use of land for the purposes set forth in this subchapter, is hereby declared to be a public necessity.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 77-2-ch76" path="§1">Feb. 16, 1942, 56 Stat. 90, ch. 76, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-170">D.C. Law 17-170</cite>, see § 2 of Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-557, October 27, 2008,  55 DCR 12006).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-170">D.C. Law 17-170</cite>, see § 2 of Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-428, July 16, 2008,  55 DCR 8252).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of D.C. Act 17-320, see § 2 of Performance Parking Pilot Zone Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-355, April 17, 2008,  55 DCR 5375).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 8 of Performance Parking Pilot Zone Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-320, March 19, 2008,  55 DCR 3432).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) additions, see §§ 2 to 8 of Performance Parking Pilot Zone Temporary Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-170">D.C. Law 17-170</cite>, June 5, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 6975).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 17-170">D.C. Law 17-170</cite>, see § 2 of Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Temporary Amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-243">D.C. Law 17-243</cite>, October 21, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 11706).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-802.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-802.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
