<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-2209.03</num>
  <heading>Agreement with private entity to provide records and services.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor may enter an agreement with a private entity to obtain relevant records regarding registration information or to perform tasks associated with the use of an automated traffic enforcement system, including, but not limited to, the operation, maintenance, administration or mailing of notices of violations.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 903, 43 DCR 4569</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Automated traffic enforcement systems, adjudication of citations, see § <cite path="§50-2209.02">50-2209.02</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Capitol Grounds, traffic rules and regulations, fines and penalties, prosecution, see § <cite path="§10-503.25">10-503.25</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Compulsory/no-fault motor vehicle insurance, offenses, fines pursuant to this chapter, see § <cite path="§31-2413">31-2413</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Hazardous materials transportation, fines and penalties, adjudication of violations, see § <cite path="§8-1404">8-1404</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>National Capital Region Transportation, revenues allocated to the Metrorail/Metrobus Account, see § <cite path="§9-1111.15">9-1111.15</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Regulation of traffic, penalties for violations, see § <cite path="§50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Traffic violations, speeding and reckless driving, civil fines, see § <cite path="§50-2201.04">50-2201.04</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 40-753.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 904 of Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-226">D.C. Law 11-226</cite>, April 9, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 2584).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Temporary Amendment Act of 2002 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 14-226">D.C. Law 14-226</cite>, March 25, 2003, law notification  50 DCR 2739).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Temporary Amendment Act of 2003 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-103">D.C. Law 15-103</cite>, March 10, 2004, law notification  51 DCR 3623).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Temporary Amendment of 2004 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 15-252">D.C. Law 15-252</cite>, March 17, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 4128).</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 2 and 3 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-281">D.C. Law 18-281</cite> added sections to read as follows:</annotation>
      <annotation>“Sec. 904. Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(a) Effective April 9, 1997, there is established the Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund (‘Fund’) as a lapsing fund, to be administered by the Mayor as an agency fund as defined in D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§47-373">47-373</cite>(2)(I), into which shall be deposited funds to be used exclusively for the administration of the automated traffic enforcement system.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(b) Authorized expenditures from the Fund include:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(1) Vendor payments pursuant to an agreement reached under section 903 of this title;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(2) Salaries, benefits, and overtime incurred by members of the Metropolitan Police Department in the administration of the system;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(3) Adjudication costs resulting from use of the system;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(4) Supplies and equipment purchases related to use of the system;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(5) Utilities;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(6) Fleet acquisition and operation;</annotation>
      <annotation>“(7) Facility improvements, rent, and occupancy; and</annotation>
      <annotation>“(8) Any other expense determined by the Mayor or his designee to be required for the administration of the system.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(c) The Fund shall be financed through fines and fees received from enforcement and regulation of the activities described in section 902 of this title and through other funds as may be appropriated to the Fund. Revenue deposited into the Fund and all interest earned thereon shall revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia on September 30 of each fiscal year, but shall, during the fiscal year, be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this section, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act.</annotation>
      <annotation>“(d) The Fund shall be accounted for under procedures established pursuant to D.C. Official Code §§ <cite path="§47-371">47-371</cite> through <cite path="§47-377">47-377</cite>. “Sec. 3. As of the effective date of the Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2010, effective September 29, 2010 (D.C. Act 18-536; 57 DCR  __), an amount up to but not exceeding $9 million shall be reprogrammed from the Metropolitan Police Department (FA0) Special Purpose Revenue operating budget to the pay-go Capital Budget within Agency PA0 for purposes of supporting future automated traffic initiatives. Notice of the reprogramming authorized by this section shall be transmitted to the Council prior to its taking effect.”</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-281">D.C. Law 18-281</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 904 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-302, July 25, 1996,  43 DCR 4181), § 904 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-429, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6151), and § 904 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-2, February 19, 1997,  44 DCR 1590).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§50-2209.04">50-2209.04</cite>, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-604, January 7, 2003,  50 DCR 689).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§50-2209.04">50-2209.04</cite>, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-422, July 17, 2002,  49 DCR 7619).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of § <cite path="§50-2209.04">50-2209.04</cite>, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2002 (D.C. Act 14-493, October 23, 2002,  49 DCR 9779).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-189, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9497).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-327, January 28, 2004,  51 DCR 1595).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-590, November 1, 2004,  51 DCR 10727).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-536, September 29, 2010,  57 DCR 9292).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Automated Traffic Enforcement Fund Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-671, December 28, 2010,  58 DCR 123).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
