<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2206.55</num>
  <heading>Revocation of permit or privilege to drive.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor or his or her designated agent shall revoke the operator’s permit or the privilege to drive a motor vehicle in the District of Columbia, or revoke both such permit and privilege, of any person who is convicted or adjudicated a juvenile delinquent as a result of the commission in the District of any of the following offenses:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A violation of sections § <cite path="§50-2206.11">50-2206.11</cite>, § <cite path="§50-2206.12">50-2206.12</cite>, § <cite path="§50-2206.14">50-2206.14</cite>, or § <cite path="§50-2206.16">50-2206.16</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A homicide committed by means of a motor vehicle;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A violation of § <cite path="§50-2201.05c">50-2201.05c</cite> or § <cite path="§50-2201.05d">50-2201.05d</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Aggravated reckless driving;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Operating or being in physical control of a vehicle while intoxicated or impaired by the consumption of alcohol or a drug or any combination thereof where such operation or physical control leads to bodily injury; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is involved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Whenever a judgment of conviction of any offense set forth in subsection (a) of this section has become final, the clerk of the court in which the judgment was entered shall certify such conviction to the Mayor or his or her designated agent, who shall thereupon take the action required by subsection (a) of this section. A judgment of conviction shall be deemed to have become final for the purposes of this subsection if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No appeal is taken from the judgment, upon the expiration of the time within which an appeal could have been taken; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An appeal is taken from the judgment, the date upon which the judgment, having been sustained, can no longer be appealed from or reviewed on a writ of certiorari.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-145" type="History">Sept. 14, 1982, D.C. Law 4-145, § 3t</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 103(e)(3), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-316" type="History">June 8, 2013, D.C. Law 19-316, § 6, 60 DCR 1713</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-316">D.C. Law 19-316</cite> substituted “Aggravated reckless driving” for “Reckless driving” in (a)(4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 103(e)(3) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013, 60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6 of the Reckless Driving Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-75, May 23, 2013,  60 DCR 7597, 20 DCSTAT 1428).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 103(e)(3) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-316">D.C. Law 19-316</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of June 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
