<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2209.02</num>
  <heading>Liability for fines; notice of infraction; hearing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Absent an intervening criminal or fraudulent act, the owner of a vehicle issued a notice of infraction shall be liable for payment of the fine assessed for the infraction.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>When a violation is detected by an automated traffic enforcement system, the Mayor shall mail a summons and a notice of infraction to the name and address of the registered owner of the vehicle on file with the Department of Motor Vehicles or the appropriate state motor vehicle agency. The notice shall include the date, time, and location of the violation, the type of violation detected, the license plate number, and state of issuance of the vehicle detected, and a copy of the photo or digitized image of the violation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An owner or operator who receives a citation may request a hearing which shall be adjudicated pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 23 of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The owner or operator of a vehicle shall not be presumed liable for violations in the vehicle recorded by an automated traffic enforcement system when yielding the right of way to an emergency vehicle, when the vehicle or tags have been reported stolen prior to the citation, when part of a funeral procession, or at the direction of a law enforcement officer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198" type="History" path="§902">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 902, 43 DCR 4569</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-81" type="History">Mar. 24, 1998, D.C. Law 12-81, § 51, 45 DCR 745</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-307" type="History">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-307, § 206, 52 DCR 1700</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-187" type="History">Oct. 23, 2012, D.C. Law 19-187, § 2(b), 59 DCR 10149</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§1-629.05">1-629.05</cite>, § <cite path="§50-331">50-331</cite>, and § <cite path="§50-2201.03">50-2201.03</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-752.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-307">D.C. Law 15-307</cite>, in subsec. (a), substituted “the name, driver’s license number, and address of the person who leased, rented, or otherwise had care, custody, or control of the vehicle; except that if the vehicle was in the temporary care, custody, or control of a business, the owner need only provide the name and address of that business” for “the name and address of the person who leased, rented, or otherwise had care, custody, or control of the vehicle”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-187">D.C. Law 19-187</cite> rewrote (a); and substituted “Department of Motor Vehicles” for “Bureau of Motor Vehicle Services” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 902 of Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-226">D.C. Law 11-226</cite>, April 9, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 2584).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 903 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-302, July 25, 1996,  43 DCR 4181), § 903 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-429, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6151), and § 903 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-2, February 19, 1997,  44 DCR 1590).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
