<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-211.07</num>
  <heading>Employee transportation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>On or before December 31, 2012, the Mayor shall transmit a report to the Council discussing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>How District government employees travel within the Washington, D.C. metropolitan region for work-related business;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>How the cost of work-related travel could be decreased;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether the use of alternative transportation, such as Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (“WMATA”) services, Circulator, Bikeshare, and taxicabs by District government employees for work-related business could be increased and, if so, how; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Which District agencies offer transit benefits to employees, and to which employees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On or before March 15, 2013, the Members of the Council shall submit and the Secretary to the Council shall compile a report to the Council discussing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>How Council employees travel within the District for work-related business;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>How the cost of work-related travel could be decreased;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Whether the use of alternative transportation, such as WMATA services, Circulator, Bikeshare, and taxicabs by Council employees for work-related business could be increased and, if so, how; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Whether the Council offers transit benefits to employees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-223" type="History" path="§107">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-223, § 107, 59 DCR 13537</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-223">D.C. Law 19-223</cite> provided that §§ 101, 102, 104, 105(a), 105(b), 106, 107, 201(a), 201(b), 201(c), 202, 203, and 301 of the act shall apply as of Mar. 5, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-211.02">50-211.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
