<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2534</num>
  <heading>Expenditure of Performance Parking Pilot Program revenue.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Performance Parking Program Fund shall be used for non-automobile transportation investments in each zone. These investments shall supplement or substantially accelerate investments that would otherwise be made by the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall involve performance parking pilot zone residents, businesses, ANCs, and Ward Councilmembers in prioritizing non-automobile transportation improvements. The improvements may include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Enhancements to bus and rail facilities to improve access and level of service such as electronic real-time schedule displays outside of stations and stops, display of large, full-color bus and rail maps, bus-only and bus priority lanes, and programs to increase electronic fare payment technologies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Enhancements to increase the safety, convenience, and comfort of pedestrians, such as new or improved sidewalks, lighting, signage, benches, improved streetscapes, countdown crosswalk signals, and neighborhood traffic calming;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Improvements to bicycling infrastructure, such as painted and separated bicycle lanes, installation of public bicycle racks, and way-finding signage for bicyclists; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Improvements, which support retail and small businesses, that enhance the pedestrian and customer experience within the zone, such as clean-up and hospitality activities, public safety initiatives, and streetscape and storefront upgrades.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>DC Surface Transit, Inc. shall serve as an official advisory body to the District Department of Transportation for performance parking implementation within the Central Washington Area (as defined in 10 DCMR § 16), except where the Central Washington Area overlaps with preexisting performance parking zones.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-279" type="History">Nov. 25, 2008, D.C. Law 17-279, § 5, 55 DCR 11059</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 6083(d), 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6042(d), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-2531.01">50-2531.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, in subsec. (b), deleted “and” from the end of par. (2), substituted “; and” for a period the end of par. (3), and added par. (4).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> rewrote (a); and added (c).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
