<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2301.08</num>
  <heading>Report to Council.</heading>
  <text>By June 30th of each year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council a report on parking and traffic enforcement for the previous calendar year. The report shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The number of persons hired as hearing examiners:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The level of compensation for each hearing examiner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The length of time each hearing examiner has served in that capacity; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The qualifications for hearing examiners;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The number of notices of infraction issued:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of notices of infraction issued for moving infractions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of notices of infraction issued for parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The number of notices of infraction issued by each agency authorized to issue notices of infraction;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The number of answers filed for moving infractions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of “admit” answers filed for moving infractions:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The number of hearings held for respondents who admit the commission of moving infractions; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The number of suspensions and revocations of respondents who admit the commission of moving infractions;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of “admit with explanation” answers filed for moving infractions; the number of suspensions and revocations of respondents who admit with explanation the commission of a moving infraction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The number of “deny” answers filed for moving infractions:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The number of determinations of liability of respondents who deny the commission of moving infractions;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The number of dismissals of respondents who deny the commission of moving infractions; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>The number of suspensions and revocations of respondents who deny the commission of moving infractions;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The number of suspensions for failure to answer notices of infraction; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>The number of suspensions for failure to appear at a hearing;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The number of answers filed for parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of “admit” answers filed for parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of “admit with explanation” answers filed for parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The number of “deny” answers filed for parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>The number of determinations of liability of respondents who deny the commission of parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>The number of dismissals of respondents who deny the commission of parking, standing, stopping and pedestrian infractions;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>The number of notices of infraction for which sanctions are imposed:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of notices of infraction for which a civil fine is imposed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of notices of infraction for which a penalty is imposed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The number of notices of infraction for which attendance at traffic school is required;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>The number of notices of infraction issued to lessors covered under § <cite path="§50-2303.04">50-2303.04</cite>:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The penalties and fines imposed for infractions under § <cite path="§50-2303.04">50-2303.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The penalties and fines actually paid under § <cite path="§50-2303.04">50-2303.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The number of outstanding infractions under § <cite path="§50-2303.04">50-2303.04</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The amount of fines and penalties outstanding under § <cite path="§50-2303.04">50-2303.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>The number of appeals filed with the appeals boards:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of decisions set aside by appeals boards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of decisions affirmed by appeals boards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The list of attorneys available for service on appeals boards;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The list of citizens available for service on appeals boards; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>A list of each appeals board appointed by the Director;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>The number of appeals filed with the Superior Court of the District of Columbia:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of decisions set aside by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of decisions affirmed by the Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>The number of appeals filed with the District of Columbia Court of Appeals:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of decisions set aside by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of decisions affirmed by the District of Columbia Court of Appeals;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>The number of vehicles towed and booted:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of vehicles towed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of vehicles booted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The average cost of each tow; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>The average cost of each booting;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>The total revenues generated by this chapter:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The total collected in fines and penalties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The total collected in towing fees; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>The total collected in booting fees; and</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>The number of requests for reconsideration filed after an initial finding of liability:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>The number of violations dismissed after reconsideration; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The number of violations affirmed after reconsideration.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-104" type="History">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-104, § 108, 25 DCR 1275</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-127" type="History">July 23, 2014, D.C. Law 20-127, § 3(c), 61 DCR 5711</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-608.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-1108.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite> added (12) and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite>, § 5, see § 7009 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014,  61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite>, § 5, see § 7009 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014,  61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite>, § 5, see § 7009 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015,  62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite>: Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7009, provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-127">D.C. Law 20-127</cite>, as amended by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7009, provided that the act shall apply as of October 1, 2014.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
