<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2605</num>
  <heading>Establishment of parking facilities.</heading>
  <text>Parking facilities may be established in any section or portion of the District except that no parking facilities shall be established upon any property zoned residential without the approval of the Zoning Commission of the District. The Zoning Commission may grant such approval only after public notice and hearing in accordance with § <cite path="§6-641.03">6-641.03</cite>. Neighborhood municipal off-street parking facilities shall not be located in districts zoned C-3-B and C-R, nor shall they be established on lots on which housing currently exists.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 77-2-ch76" path="§5">Feb. 16, 1942, 56 Stat. 93, ch. 76, § 5</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-108" type="History">Sept. 26, 1980, D.C. Law 3-108, § 3(c), 27 DCR 3781</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-98" type="History">Mar. 29, 1988, D.C. Law 7-98, § 3, 35 DCR 1048</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-807.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-806.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Mayor authorized to establish advisory committee: Section 17 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 10-153">D.C. Law 10-153</cite> provided:</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(a) Notwithstanding any other law, in the implementation of Chapter 8 of Title 40 chapter 26 of Title 50, 2001 Ed., the Mayor shall establish an advisory committee of not more than 7 residents from the Adams Morgan community for the purpose of advising the Mayor on the size of a public parking facility to be built in the Adams Morgan community and the parking facility’s compatibility with the neighborhood.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(b) The 7 committee members shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council by resolution. If the Council does not approve the nomination of a committee member within 45 days after submission by the Mayor, the nomination shall be deemed approved.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">“(c) The advisory committee shall remain in existence until such time as the Mayor determines the size and design of the parking facility or until the Mayor determines not to proceed with the parking facility.”</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
