<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2551</num>
  <heading>Ward 1 Enhanced Residential Parking Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established a Ward 1 Enhanced Residential Parking Program (“Program”). Any Ward 1 Advisory Neighborhood Commission (“ANC”) may, by resolution of that ANC, vote to include blocks within the ANC in the Program. The Program will consist of the following requirements:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any block that participates in the residential permit parking in Ward 1 shall have at least 50% of the legal residential parking spaces on that block designated as Zone 1 Permitted Parking Only;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A visitor parking pass program shall be available to residents similar to the program in Mount Pleasant required by § <cite path="§50-2537">50-2537</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any resident owning a vehicle registered at an address on a Ward 1 residential block may be granted a Zone 1 residential parking sticker, in accordance with the process developed by the Mayor pursuant to § <cite path="§50-2552">50-2552</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Blocks within a streetscape construction project impact zone, as designated by the Mayor, shall be excluded from the Program until the Mayor declares that all major construction associated with the streetscape has been completed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Program shall not apply within one block of a ward boundary. Streets within one block of a ward boundary shall instead be designated so that vehicles displaying a valid residential permit for either adjacent ward may park on any such block that was a residential permit parking street before the institution of the Program.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-240" type="History" path="§2">Oct. 26, 2010, D.C. Law 18-240, § 2, 57 DCR 7186</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-157" type="History">July 13, 2012, D.C. Law 19-157, § 5(a), 59 DCR 5598</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Residential Parking Protection Pilot Emergency Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-159, October 11, 2011,  58 DCR 8883).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 2 of Residential Parking Protection Pilot Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-592, November 3, 2010,  57 DCR 10472).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-157">D.C. Law 19-157</cite> added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-2552">50-2552</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
