<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-211.02</num>
  <heading>Application; exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, this subchapter shall apply to all subordinate agencies.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The following subordinate agencies are exempt from §§ <cite path="§50-211.03">50-211.03</cite>, <cite path="§50-211.04">50-211.04</cite>, <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>, <cite path="§50-211.06">50-211.06</cite>, and <cite path="§50-211.07">50-211.07</cite> and shall designate their own fleet managers to perform fleet management functions:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Metropolitan Police Department for all vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Department of Corrections for specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department for emergency and specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education for student transportation vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The Office of the Chief Medical Examiner for specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The Homeland Security and Emergency Management Agency for specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services for specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>The District Department of Transportation for specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>The Department of Parks and Recreation for specialized vehicles;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>The Department of General Services for specialized vehicles; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission for specialized vehicles.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Council is exempt from § <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>(a) and may procure its own vehicles; provided, that the procurement complies with §§ <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>(b) and <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>(c).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Council shall designate its own fleet manager to perform fleet procurement and management functions set forth in §§ <cite path="§50-211.03">50-211.03</cite>, <cite path="§50-211.04">50-211.04</cite>, and <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor or the Director shall not have the authority to monitor, review, or establish standards, procedures, regulations, or rules for the procurement or management of vehicles by the Council or Council employees, unless the Council enters into a memorandum of understanding with DPW for procurement and management of its vehicles under the Fleetshare program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An independent agency or instrumentality that owns or leases 10 or fewer vehicles may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Designate its own fleet manager to perform fleet procurement and management functions set forth in §§ <cite path="§50-211.03">50-211.03</cite>, <cite path="§50-211.04">50-211.04</cite>, and <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Establish a memorandum of understanding with DPW for procurement and management of its vehicles.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An independent agency or instrumentality that owns or leases more than 10 vehicles:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Shall comply with § <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite> and procure vehicles through the Director; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>May designate its own fleet manager to perform the Director’s fleet management functions set forth in §§ <cite path="§50-211.03">50-211.03</cite> and <cite path="§50-211.04">50-211.04</cite>; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>May establish a memorandum of understanding with DPW for management of its vehicles.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>This subchapter shall not be construed to affect or limit the powers or duties of the Chief Procurement Officer as set forth in Chapter 3A of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-351.01">2-351.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-223" type="History" path="§102">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-223, § 102, 59 DCR 13537</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-211.05">50-211.05</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-223">D.C. Law 19-223</cite> provided that §§ 101, 102, 104, 105(a), 105(b), 106, 107, 201(a), 201(b), 201(c), 202, 203, and 301 of the act shall apply as of Mar. 5, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
