<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2201.32</num>
  <heading>Speed limit assessment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>By November 1, 2013, the Mayor shall complete a District-wide assessment that evaluates the speed limits on the District’s arterials and other streets. The report of the assessment shall include the criteria used for assessing the speed limits. Upon its completion, the assessment shall be posted to the District Department of Transportation’s website. The assessment shall identify a list of recommended speed limits for all District streets based on each of the following independent approaches:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Utilize factors common among transportation officials for the determination of speed limit;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Use factors based on safety and mobility needs of pedestrians, bicyclists, transit drivers and all other potential road users, as well as factors based on input from local neighborhood representatives and organizations that promote road safety including Advisory Neighborhood Commissions, the Pedestrian Advisory Council, and the Bicycle Advisory Council;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Evaluate whether comparable arterials should have comparable speed limits, and similarly do so for other streets; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Include, based solely on an engineering perspective, speed limits for the District’s arterials and other streets.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>By January 1, 2014, the Mayor shall revise, through rulemaking, existing speed limits throughout the District, as appropriate. Notwithstanding this requirement, the Mayor shall not cause an anti-deficiency as determined by a fiscal impact statement obtained by the Mayor from the Chief Financial Officer.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-307" type="History" path="§104">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-307, § 104, 60 DCR 2753</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 104 of the Safety-Based Traffic Enforcement Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-50, April 22, 2013,  60 DCR 6339, 20 DCSTAT 1356).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-307">D.C. Law 19-307</cite>: Section 401(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-307">D.C. Law 19-307</cite> provided that this section shall apply as of May 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
