<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2201.05c</num>
  <heading>Leaving after colliding.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Any person who operates or who is in physical control of a vehicle within the District who knows or has reason to believe that his or her vehicle has been in a collision shall immediately stop and:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Where another person is injured, call or cause another to call 911 or call or cause another to call for an ambulance or other emergency assistance if necessary, remain on the scene until law enforcement arrives, and provide identifying information to law enforcement and to the injured person;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Where real or personal property belonging to another is damaged or a domestic animal is injured, provide identifying information to the owner or operator of the property or the owner of the domestic animal or, where the owner or operator of the property or the owner of the domestic animal is not present, provide or cause another to provide identifying information and the location of the collision, to law enforcement or 911; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Where real or personal property or a wild or domestic animal, as a result of the collision, poses a risk to others, call or cause another to call 911 and provide identifying information, the location of the collision, and a description of the nature of the risk posed to others.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It is an affirmative defense to a violation of subsection (a) of this section, which the defendant must show by a preponderance of the evidence, that the defendant’s failure to stop or his or her failure to remain on the scene was based on a reasonable belief that his or her personal safety, or the safety of another, was at risk and that he or she called 911, or otherwise notified law enforcement, as soon as it was safe to do so, provided identifying information, provided a description of the collision, including the location of the collision or event, and followed the instructions of the 911 operator or a law enforcement officer.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>It is not a defense to a violation of this section that the defendant:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Was intoxicated, impaired in any way, or distracted; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Was not at fault for the collision.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A person violating subsection (a)(1) of this section shall upon conviction for the first offense be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or incarcerated for not more than 180 days, or both.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A person violating subsection (a)(1) of this section when the person has a prior offense under subsection (a)(1) of this section and is being sentenced on the current offense shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>A person violating subsection (a)(2) or (a)(3) of this section shall upon conviction for the first offense be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or incarcerated for not more than 30 days, or both.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>A person violating subsection (a)(2) or (3) of this section when the person has a prior offense under subsection (a)(2) or (a)(3) of this section and is being sentenced on the current offense shall be fined not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>, or imprisoned not more than 90 days, or both.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 68-2-ch443" path="§10c">Mar. 3, 1925, 43 Stat. 1124, ch. 443, § 10c</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-266" type="History">as added Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-266, § 102(g), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 271(d), 59 DCR 12957</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-2206.55">50-2206.55</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-266">D.C. Law 19-266</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not more than $1,000” in (d)(1)(A), for “not more than $2,500” in (d)(1)(B), for “not more than $250” in (d)(2)(A), and for “not more than $500” in (d)(2)(B).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of section, see § 102(g) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-508, October 26, 2012,  59 DCR 12774).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 102(g) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-3, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 2762, 20 DCSTAT 410).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 271(d) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 102(g) of the Comprehensive Impaired Driving and Alcohol Testing Program Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-51, April 17, 2013,  60 DCR 6344, 20 DCSTAT 1360).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
