<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2302.03</num>
  <heading>Exception for serious offenders.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the provisions of this subchapter shall not apply to a person alleged to have committed an infraction who, during the 18-month period immediately preceding the date of the infraction, has been assessed 12 or more traffic points pursuant to § 2.305 of Title 32 of the District of Columbia Rules and Regulations. Such person shall be subject to criminal prosecution by the Corporation Counsel for such offense in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia and, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine of not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite> or imprisonment of up to 10 days, or both, in addition to any penalties imposed for driving after suspension or revocation.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director shall promptly inform the Corporation Counsel of an infraction by any person who has accumulated 12 or more traffic points pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. If the Corporation Counsel asserts jurisdiction over such person, he may be prosecuted without respect to the provisions of this chapter; provided, that if the Corporation Counsel affirmatively declines to take jurisdiction or does not assert jurisdiction over such offender within 15 calendar days of his receipt of notification by the Director of a violation by such person, such violation shall be adjudicated in the manner of civil infractions pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person, over whom the Corporation Counsel asserts jurisdiction pursuant to this section, shall be notified that his infraction shall be subject to criminal prosecution. Such notification shall be sent by the Corporation Counsel by certified mail directed to the recorded address of such person. No actions or statements of the respondent made in compliance or attempted compliance with this chapter before the receipt of such notice, including but not limited to admissions or admissions with explanation, shall be admissible in any such criminal proceeding.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-104" type="History" path="§203">Sept. 12, 1978, D.C. Law 2-104, § 203, 25 DCR 1275</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 275(a), 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-2302.01">50-2302.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-613.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-1111.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> substituted “of not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not to exceed $300” in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 275(a) of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Title 18 of the DCMR (Vehicles and Traffic) (June, 1987) has replaced Title 32 of the District of Columbia Rules and Regulations, referred to in (a).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite>: Section 401 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</law-cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
