<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2632</num>
  <reason>Repealed</reason>
  <heading>Parking of automobiles in Municipal Center; regulations; violations and penalties.</heading>
  <text>Repealed.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History" doc="Stat. 76-3-ch253" path="">June 6, 1940, 54 Stat. 241, ch. 253, §§ 1, 2, 3</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-317" type="History">June 11, 2013, D.C. Law 19-317, § 277, 60 DCR 2064</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-2632" type="History">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-2632, § 11, 61 DCR 12690</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Delegation of functions: Reorganization Order No. 18, dated October 23, 1952, created in the Department of General Administration under the direction and control of the Director of General Administration, an Administrative Services Office. This office was assigned the duties of maintaining records of space allotted to District employees for parking privately owned motor vehicles on District or Federal property and also to review requests for and make recommendations for assignments and execute control of approved assignments. Reorganization Order No. 18 was revoked by Organization Order No. 3, dated December 13, 1967, Part IVA of which continued the Administrative Services Office and the parking functions thereof. The Administrative Services Office and the functions stated in Part IVA of Organization Order No. 3 were transferred to the Director of the Department of General Services by Commissioner’s Order No. 69-96, dated March 7, 1969.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite>: Section 401 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> provided that the act shall apply only to offenses committed on or after June 11, 2013.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</cite>: Section 12(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</cite> provided that §§ 2(a), 2(b)(1), 2(b)(2)(A), 2(b)(2)(B), 2(b)(2)(C), 2(c), 3, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and 11 shall apply as of March 11, 2015.</text>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(301, 302, 303) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 277 of the Criminal Fine Proportionality Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-45, April 1, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-317">D.C. Law 19-317</cite> substituted “not more than the amount set forth in § <cite path="§22-3571.01">22-3571.01</cite>” for “not to exceed $25” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 40-604a.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-711.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Cross References">Regulation of parking, allocation of collected revenues, see § <cite path="§50-2607">50-2607</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
