<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-2506</num>
  <heading>Executive Director.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Board shall appoint an Executive Director who shall be the chief administrative officer of the Authority. The Executive Director shall not be a member of the Board and shall serve at the pleasure of the Board. The Executive Director shall be a District resident throughout his or her term and failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In addition to any other duties set forth in this chapter, the Executive Director shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Supervise and manage all business affairs and operation and management of properties of the Authority;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sign and execute all authorized bonds, contracts, and other obligations in the name of the Authority;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Perform all administrative duties as may be required by the Authority; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Perform all other duties as the Authority may require to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 10-153" type="History">Aug. 23, 1994, D.C. Law 10-153, § 7, 41 DCR 4652</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-108" type="History">Feb. 6, 2008, D.C. Law 17-108, § 216(a), 54 DCR 10993</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-846.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-108">D.C. Law 17-108</cite>, in subsec. (a), inserted “The Executive Director shall be a District resident throughout his or her term and failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
