<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-332</num>
  <heading>Enforcement and issuance of citations; report.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Taxicab Commission and the Metropolitan Police Department shall concurrently enforce and issue citations relating to Taxicab requirements.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On November 1st of each year the Mayor shall provide to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment, or a successor committee with oversight of the Taxicab Commission, a report on the number of civil citations issued pursuant to 31 DCMR § 825 and laws and regulations of the District of Columbia, and a report on any criminal infractions issued during the prior fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>On a quarterly basis, beginning in FY 2002, the Taxicab Commission shall issue a report to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment, or a successor committee with oversight of the Taxicab Commission, containing the number of civil infractions issued pursuant to 31 DCMR § 825, by Taxicab Hack Inspectors. This document shall also indicate the number of infractions that were deemed liable through the adjudication process.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 505, 43 DCR 4569</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-28" type="History">Oct. 3, 2001, D.C. Law 14-28, § 2502, 48 DCR 6981</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 40-1722.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 14-28">D.C. Law 14-28</law-cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “The Metropolitan Police Department shall enforce and issue citations relating to taxicab requirements including notices of civil infractions issued pursuant to  31 DCMR 825. The Metropolitan Police Department shall provide to the Taxicab Commission, on a an annual basis, a report on the number of citations issued to vehicles for hire.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 505 of Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 11-226">D.C. Law 11-226</law-cite>, April 9, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 2584).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 505 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-302, July 25, 1996,  43 DCR 4181), see § 505 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-429, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6151), and see § 505 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-2, February 19, 1997,  44 DCR 1590).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2302 of Fiscal Year 2002 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-124, August 3, 2001,  48 DCR 7861).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
