<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-301.29b</num>
  <heading>Registration of private vehicle-for-hire operators.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>To become a private vehicle-for-hire operator, an individual shall submit an application to register with a private vehicle-for-hire company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Before approving a registration application submitted under subsection (a) of this section, a private vehicle-for-hire company shall have a third party that is accredited by the National Association of Professional Background Screeners or a successor accreditation entity conduct the following examinations:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A local and national criminal background check;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The national sex offender database background check; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A full driving record check.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A private vehicle-for-hire company shall reject an application submitted under subsection (a) of this section and shall permanently disqualify an applicant who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>As shown in the local or national criminal background check conducted in accordance with subsection (b)(1) of this section, has been convicted within the past 7 years of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An offense defined as a crime of violence under § <cite root="23-1331">23-1331</cite>(4);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>An offense under subchapter II of Chapter 30 of Title 22 [§  22-3002 et seq.];</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>An offense under § <cite root="22-3102">22-3102</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Burglary, robbery, or an attempt to commit robbery under §§ <cite root="22-801">22-801</cite>, <cite root="22-2801">22-2801</cite> and <cite root="22-2802">22-2802</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Theft in the first degree under § <cite root="22-3212">22-3212</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Felony fraud or identity theft under § <cite root="22-3221">22-3221</cite> or § <cite root="22-3227.02">22-3227.02</cite>; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>An offense under any state or federal law or under the law of any other jurisdiction in the United States involving conduct that would constitute an offense described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F) of this paragraph if committed in the District;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Is a match in the national sex offender registry database;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>As shown in the national background check or driving record check conducted in accordance with subsections (b)(1) and (b)(3) of this section, has been convicted within the past 7 years of:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Aggravated reckless driving under § <cite root="50-2201.04">50-2201.04</cite>(b-1);</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Fleeing from a law enforcement officer in a motor vehicle under § <cite root="50-2201.05b">50-2201.05b</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Leaving after colliding under § <cite root="50-2201.05c">50-2201.05c</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Negligent homicide under § <cite root="50-2203.01">50-2203.01</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Driving under the influence of alcohol or a drug, driving a commercial vehicle under the influence of alcohol or a drug, or operating a vehicle while impaired under § <cite root="50-2206.11">50-2206.11</cite>, § <cite root="50-2206.12">50-2206.12</cite>, or § <cite root="50-2206.14">50-2206.14</cite>;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Unauthorized use of a motor vehicle under § <cite root="22-3215">22-3215</cite>; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>An offense under any state or federal law or under the law of any other jurisdiction in the United States involving conduct that would constitute an offense described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), and (F) of this paragraph if committed in the District; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Has been convicted within the past 3 years of driving with a suspended or revoked license under § <cite root="50-1403.01">50-1403.01</cite>(e), according to the driving record check conducted in accordance with subsection (b)(3) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A motor vehicle used as a private vehicle-for-hire shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Have a manufacturer’s rated seating capacity of 8 persons or fewer, including the private vehicle-for-hire operator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Have at least 4 doors and meet applicable federal motor vehicle safety standards for vehicles of its size, type, and proposed use; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Be no more than 10 model years of age at entry into service and no more than 12 model years of age while in service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person registered with a private vehicle-for-hire company as a private vehicle-for-hire operator under this section shall be deemed by the District to hold the necessary authorization to operate in the District as may be required by another jurisdiction or interstate authority.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-97">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, § 20j-2</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-197">as added Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-197, §  2(k), 61 DCR 12430</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite> provided, in part, that §§ 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the act shall apply as of March 10, 2015.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
