<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-301.07</num>
  <heading>Duties of Commission; jurisdiction; powers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Commission is charged with the continuance, further development, and improvement of the public vehicle-for-hire industry within the District, and for the overall regulation of limousines, sedans, taxicabs, taxicab companies, taxicab fleets, and taxicab associations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A majority of the appointed Commissioners shall constitute a quorum for transacting business and for taking official action or votes; provided, that public hearings may be conducted without the presence of a quorum.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have the authority, power, and duty to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establish reasonable rates for taxicab service for the transportation of passengers and their property within the District, including all charges incidental and directly related to the provision of taxicab services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establish criteria, standards, and requirements for the licensing of public vehicle-for-hire owners, operators, companies, associations, and fleets, including the setting of reasonable license fees;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Establish standards, conditions, and requirements of public vehicle-for-hire service;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Establish standards for driver and passenger safety, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Within one year of October 22, 2012, providing for the installation of security devices in all taxicabs; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Increased enforcement by vehicle inspection officers, including during late evening and early morning hours, of unlicensed or out-of-jurisdiction operators of public vehicles-for-hire attempting to provide passenger service in the District;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Establish standards and requirements relating to the modernization of equipment and equipment design;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>In situations of public emergency or because of extraordinary circumstances affecting the taxicab industry, regulate the rates charged for the lease of taxicabs by taxicab companies, associations, and fleets considered necessary to protect the public interest;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Establish reasonable civil fines and penalties for violations of rules and orders issued by the Commission, including penalties consisting of license suspension and revocation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Advise government agencies and authorities with jurisdiction over public transportation or public highways and public space within the District regarding the routing of taxicabs and the location of taxicab stands;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Advise the Mayor regarding the execution, modification, and termination of reciprocal agreements with governmental bodies in the Washington Metropolitan Area regarding taxicabs;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Establish primary public vehicle-for-hire operator training courses, driver refresher training courses, and training for operators of wheelchair-accessible taxicabs, and determine how often these courses will be offered; provided, that the primary training course shall be offered as needed and shall be taken by operators as necessary, as established by rulemaking, pursuant to § <cite path="§47-2829">47-2829</cite>(e)(2)(A);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Provide for the training and oversight of vehicle inspection officers, who shall be responsible for enforcing all rules and regulations promulgated by the Mayor governing public and private vehicles-for-hire, particularly with respect to taxicabs and limousines, pursuant to § <cite path="§50-301.30">50-301.30</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Establish policies encouraging energy conservation, the reduction of pollution, including through the use of alternative-fuel vehicles, the reduction of traffic congestion, an increase in services to persons with disabilities, and policies that promote a more livable city;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Create incentives for and study taxicab service in underserved areas, which may include the placement of public vehicle-for-hire stand locations in underserved areas, the study of GPS data to inform transportation policy, and examining the supply of taxicabs in the District, as established through rulemaking;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Receive, hear, respond to, and adjudicate complaints lodged in the Office of Taxicabs against the vehicle-for-hire industry, including taxicab operators, companies, associations, fleets, and taxi dispatch services, by consumers and officials or employees of government involved in public vehicle-for-hire enforcement or administration, or refer such contested matters to the Office of Administrative Hearings, pursuant to § <cite path="§50-301.32">50-301.32</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>When determined to be necessary to protect the public interest, hear complaints and disputes occurring within the taxicab industry, including complaints and disputes between companies, associations, operators, or owners; and, to address industry-wide problems, issue reasonable rules for the governance of intra-industry relationships;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>Hear and decide appeals taken from license denials and proposed revocations or suspensions issued by the Office of Taxicabs, or refer the contested matter to the Office of Administrative Hearings;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>Hear and decide complaints and appeals taken from any order, act, practice, or policy implemented by the Office of Taxicabs relating to the taxicab industry;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>Undertake the investigation of any aspect of taxicab operations and practices necessary to protect public safety;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>Establish any rule relating to the regulation and supervision of the public vehicle-for-hire industry not specifically delineated in this subchapter, so long as the rule is consistent with this subchapter and related to the furtherance and protection of the public interest in public vehicle-for-hire transportation; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>Charge and collect reasonable fees for services it is authorized to provide under this subchapter and § <cite path="§47-2829">47-2829</cite>(e)(2), with funds to be deposited in the Public Vehicles-for-Hire Consumer Service Fund created by § <cite path="§50-301.20">50-301.20</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>In exercising the rulemaking and ratemaking authority vested in it, the Commission shall adhere to and be subject to the requirements of subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], which shall apply to the Commission. The Commission shall, in giving notice of intended action in accordance with § <cite path="§2-505">2-505</cite>, afford interested persons an opportunity to make public comment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A public hearing shall be required when a ratemaking or rulemaking action is referred to a panel for deliberation. Adequate notice of such hearing shall be given as required by rules of the Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>In exercising its rulemaking and ratemaking authority, the Commission shall act by majority vote. No proxy by a member shall be allowed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Commission may issue orders which shall have binding effect in exercising any authority conferred by this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Appeals from final decisions of the Commission may be taken to the Office of Administrative Hearings, pursuant to Chapter 18A of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-1831.01">2-1831.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-97">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, § 8, 33 DCR 703</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-109">May 10, 1988, D.C. Law 7-109, § 2(b), 35 DCR 2181</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-59">Jan. 30, 1990, D.C. Law 8-59, § 2(a), 36 DCR 7384</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-107">May 1, 1990, D.C. Law 8-107, § 2(a), 37 DCR 1623</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-198">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-198, § 501(c), 43 DCR 4569</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264,§ 46, 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-184">Oct. 22, 2012, D.C. Law 19-184, § 2(g), 59 DCR 9431</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-270">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-270, § 2(b), 60 DCR 1717</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-197">Mar. 10, 2015, D.C. Law 20-197, § 2(b), 61 DCR 12430</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-320">50-320</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 40-1707.</annotation>
      <annotation>2001 Ed., §  50-307.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> added (c)(20) and made related changes.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite> substituted “vehicle inspection officers” for “public vehicle inspection officers” in (c)(4)(B) and (c)(11); substituted “public and private vehicles-for-hire” for public vehicles-for-hire” in (c)(11); and substituted “against the vehicle-for-hire industry, including taxicab operators, companies, associations, fleets, and taxi dispatch services” for “against taxicab operators, companies, associations, fleets, and taxi dispatch services” in (c)(14).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 501(c) of Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Temporary Amendment Act of 1996 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-226">D.C. Law 11-226</cite>, April 9, 1997, law notification  44 DCR 2584).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Taxicab Commission Temporary Amendment Act of 1999 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 13-36">D.C. Law 13-36</cite>, October 7, 1999, law notification  46 DCR 8700).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 501(c) of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-302, July 25, 1996,  43 DCR 4181), § 501(c) of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-429, October 29, 1996,  43 DCR 6151), and § 501(c) of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-2, February 19, 1997,  44 DCR 1590).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) addition of section, see § 2 of the Taxicab Commission Emergency Amendment Act of 1999 (D.C. Act 13-93, June 4, 1999,  46 DCR 5340).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3 of the Taxicab Service Improvement Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-403, July 24, 2012,  59 DCR 9116).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see § 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effective Dates</heading>
      <annotation>Section 24(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97">D.C. Law 6-97</cite> provided that sections 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 20, 21, 22, and 23 shall take effect 1 year after March 25, 1986.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Hacker’s License Appeal Board abolished: Section 23(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97">D.C. Law 6-97</cite> provided that the Hacker’s License Appeal Board established by Commissioners’ Order 68-59, effective August 15, 1968, is abolished. Section 23(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97">D.C. Law 6-97</cite> provided that the Commission shall be the successor to the Board and any complaint, proceeding, or matter pending before the Board on the effective date of this section shall be a complaint, proceeding, or matter of the Commission. Section 24(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 6-97">D.C. Law 6-97</cite> provided that §§ 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 20, 21, 22, and 23 shall take effect 1 year after March 25, 1986.</text>
      <text>Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
      <text>Section 7007 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7. Therefore <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> became applicable on December 24, 2013.</text>
      <text>Section 7017 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5.</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite>: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-197">D.C. Law 20-197</cite> provided, in part, that §§ 1, 2, 3, and 4 of the act shall apply as of March 10, 2015.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
