<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-301.28</num>
  <heading>Loitering of public vehicles-for-hire.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No operator of a public vehicle-for-hire shall loiter around or in front of hotels, restaurants, theaters, or public buildings in the District. For the purposes of this section, the term “loitering” means the willful operation of a public vehicle-for-hire for the purpose of soliciting passengers by stopping the vehicle, or by driving at such a slow speed as may impede or block the normal and reasonable movement of traffic.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for a hotel, restaurant, or theater, or keeper or proprietor or agent acting for the keeper or proprietor, of a hotel, restaurant, or theater in the District to discriminate against a District licensed taxicab operator by excluding the operator from access to a hack stand or other location where taxicabs are regularly allowed to pick up passengers on the hotel premises; provided, that a taxicab or taxicab operator that is not in compliance with taxicab vehicle safety requirements or operator requirements may be denied a passenger and reported to the Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>It shall be unlawful for a hotel, restaurant, or theater, or keeper or proprietor or agent acting for the keeper or proprietor of a hotel, restaurant, or theater in the District to solicit, or offer to solicit passengers on behalf of a public vehicle-for-hire operator, company, or association if the resulting trip would violate this subchapter. This subsection shall not prohibit a hotel, restaurant, or theater from entering into a written contract to provide its customers with the services of public vehicles-for-hire on a pre-arranged basis, as long as these services are provided in a manner that complies with all laws, rules, and regulations applicable to public vehicles-for-hire in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Commission shall have authority to determine, by rule, appropriate fines and penalties for violations of subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-97" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-97, § 20i</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-184" type="History">as added Oct. 22, 2012, D.C. Law 19-184, § 2(s), 59 DCR 9431</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-270" type="History">Apr. 23, 2013, D.C. Law 19-270, § 2(h), 60 DCR 1717</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">2001 Ed., § <cite path="§50-328">50-328</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7, see § 7007 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see § 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) repeal of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5, see 7017 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 7001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle A of Title VII of the act may be cited as the “Subject to Appropriations Repealers Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 5 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite> provided that the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7007 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-184">D.C. Law 19-184</cite>, § 7.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Section 7017 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> repealed <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-270">D.C. Law 19-270</cite>, § 5.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
