<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-921.13</num>
  <heading>The District Department of Transportation Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the District Department of Transportation Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and which shall be used by the District Department of Transportation to pay for goods, services, property, capital improvements, or for any other permitted purpose as authorized by §§ <cite path="§50-921.02">50-921.02</cite>(f) and <cite path="§50-921.04">50-921.04</cite> and to pay into the Highway Trust Fund.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All revenue from the following shall be deposited into the Fund, beginning October 1, 2011:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Fines from the enforcement of truck safety and size, weight, and noise regulations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Advertisements on multispace parking meter receipts;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Repealed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Public inconvenience fees, described in 24 DCMR § 225.1(c);</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Fees related to car sharing after the first $270,000 in revenue per fiscal year.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Loading zone management program revenue, including:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The commercial permit parking pass revenue;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Commercial permit parking fees;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Other related citations and fines;</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Any other revenues, including grants or gifts, as may from time-to-time be dedicated to the Fund; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Matching funds from private nonprofit organizations for the 5310 Program pursuant to § <cite path="§50-921.02">50-921.02</cite>(f).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9e</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">as added Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 626(c), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 6052, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-234" type="History">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-234, § 2(b), 59 DCR 14772</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-241" type="History">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-241, § 2(b), 59 DCR 14794</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-921.04">50-921.04</cite> and § <cite path="§50-2635">50-2635</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite>, rewrote the section, which formerly read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) There is established as a nonlapsing fund the District Department of Transportation Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives (’Fund’), which shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and used to fund the cost of capital projects of the District Department of Transportation proposed by the Mayor and approved by act of the Council.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b) The Fund shall consist of revenues from fines derived from the enforcement of truck safety and size, weight, and noise regulations, and any revenues, grants, or gifts as may from time-to-time be dedicated to the Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(c) All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-234">D.C. Law 19-234</cite> repealed (b)(3), which read: “Advertisements on elements of the bikeshare system, including bicycles and stations”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-241">D.C. Law 19-241</cite> substituted “§§ <cite path="§50-921.02">50-921.02</cite>(f) and <cite path="§50-921.04">50-921.04</cite>” for “§ <cite path="§50-921.04">50-921.04</cite>” in (a); added (b)(8); and made related changes.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-208">D.C. Law 19-208</cite> amended this section as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">(1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase “section 5” and inserting the phrase “sections 3(f) and 5” in its place.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">(2) Subsection (b) is amended as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">(A) Paragraph (6)(C) is amended by striking the phrase “fines; and” and inserting the phrase “fines;” in its place.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">(B) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the phrase “Fund.” and inserting the phrase “Fund; and” in its place.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">(C) A new paragraph (8) is added to read as follows: “(8) Matching funds from private nonprofit organizations for the 5310 Program pursuant to section 3(f).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-208">D.C. Law 19-208</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (a) and (b), see § 2(b) of the District Department of Transportation Accessible Vehicles Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-465, October 4, 2012,  59 DCR 11764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(b) of the DDOT Accessible Vehicles Fund Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-7, January 31, 2013,  60 DCR 2809, 20 DCSTAT 456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 6051 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle F of title VI of the act may be cited as “Department of Transportation Enterprise Fund Amendment Act of 2011”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 629 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided: “Sec. 629. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of October 1, 2011; except, that sections 622 and 623(a)(2) shall apply as of the effective date of this act.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
