<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-921.04</num>
  <heading>Duties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The offices of the DDOT shall plan, program, operate, manage, control, and maintain systems, processes, and programs to meet transportation needs as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Infrastructure Project Management Administration shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Manage and implement transportation improvement plans and projects;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Manage and construct capital projects related to the design and installation of streets, alleys, curbs, gutters, bicycle lanes, sidewalks, streetscapes, and medians;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Conduct studies, review and approve construction materials utilization and ensure that the transportation system is maintained to the highest standards;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Administer the full range of processing required to execute construction contracts for transportation, from initial preparation of bid documents through final construction completion; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Plan, manage, and contract for all, or any part of, the design, engineering, construction, operation, and maintenance of any element of the Integrated Premium Transit System.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Transportation Policy and Planning Administration shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Develop and update the Internodal State Transportation Plan, corridor management plans and other traffic studies on a regular basis, focusing on the safe and efficient movement of people, goods, and information;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Conduct planning studies on the condition and quality of the District’s transportation system to locate areas where future investment is required;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Develop alternative methods of financing transportation projects and services to achieve financial self-sufficiency;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Develop streetscape standards;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Develop and implement transportation safety programs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Develop and maintain a performance monitoring system to measure the quality and effectiveness of transportation services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Develop and maintain the transportation elements of the Geographic Information System;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>Develop paratransit systems, water taxis, tour bus support services, light rail streetcar transit systems and other transportation services to provide for safe and efficient movement of persons throughout the city;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(I)</num>
        <text>Operate the District of Columbia School Transit Subsidy Program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(J)</num>
        <text>Prepare studies on mass transit needs of District residents, including rail and bus services, review and revise bus routes, review and revise the location of bus shelter locations, support WMATA Board members, and act as a liaison between WMATA and the District government;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(K)</num>
        <text>Develop policies and programs to encourage and provide for the safe use of bicycles for recreation and work-related travel, including planning, developing, operating, and regulating a Bike Sharing program, and administering the Bicycle Sharing Fund established by § <cite path="§50-921.14">50-921.14</cite> to fund a Bike Sharing program;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(L)</num>
        <text>Operate, maintain, and regulate the DC Circulator pursuant to subchapter II of this chapter;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(M)</num>
        <text>Develop and update the District’s various transportation improvement plans, consistent with federal and local requirements;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(N)</num>
        <text>Operate, maintain, and regulate the DC Streetcar; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(O)</num>
        <text>Implement managed lane policies, including lane pricing, vehicle eligibility, and access control; provided, that at least one lane of traffic on a street with managed lanes shall be free of charge; provided further, that the Department shall submit to the Council any policy created pursuant to this subparagraph for approval by act before implementation.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Traffic Services Administration shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Provide a safe transportation system by maintaining a high quality traffic control system, including traffic signals and street lights;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Incorporate transportation safety features in the development, design, and construction of pedestrian, bicycle, motor vehicle, and mass transportation facilities and programs;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Maintain the mechanical and electrical systems which support the transportation infrastructure;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>With the signed approval of the Director of the Department of Public Works:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Allocate and regulate on-street parking;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Develop a city-wide parking management program to balance the needs of parking in support of economic development; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Establish parking and curb regulations;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D-i)</num>
        <text>Install and maintain parking meters and other parking control devices and systems on public rights-of-way and other public spaces in the District; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Concurrent with any other agency’s authority to do so, enforce all violations of statutes, regulations, executive orders, or rules relating to motor vehicle parking offenses and enforce violations of statutes, regulations, and rules relating to the operation of a motor vehicle, except those violations contained in § <cite path="§50-2302.02">50-2302.02</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Rights-of-Way Management Administration shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Review, approve, and issue public space permit requests for occupancy, work within, or other use of the public space, including private use and utility work public space requests, and ensure that transportation services are maintained and that the infrastructure is restored after the occupancy, work within, or other use is complete;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Maintain official public space records;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Perform regular inspections of the transportation system infrastructure;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Perform routine repair and maintenance activities to maintain a high quality of transportation infrastructure;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Coordinate seasonal snow removal operation on major arterial in conjunction with the Department of Public Works;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>With the consent of the Chief Property Management Officer, acquire real property, by purchase or lease, grant or gift for use by DDOT, and dispose of real property through sale, lease, or other authorized method, and exercise other acquisition and property disposition authority delegated to the Mayor;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(G)</num>
        <text>Enter into agreements to allow the placement of advertisements on District property, under the control of DDOT, in public space and collect payments under the agreements, if:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The placement of the advertisement is not in violation of District or federal laws, regulations, or orders;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The following provision is included in the advertisement agreement:</text>
          <text>“If the Mayor or the Director of DDOT receives notice from the United States Secretary of Transportation that the future operation of the advertisement agreement may result in a reduction of the District’s share of federal highway funds pursuant to         , the advertiser or advertiser agency shall remove the advertisement within 30 days from the date of receipt of the notice by the District. Upon the expiration of the 30 days specified in this paragraph, if the advertiser or advertiser agency fails to cure the violation that resulted in the threatened reduction of highway funds, the Director of DDOT may terminate this agreement at no cost to the District.”;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The requirements of § <cite path="§1-303.22">1-303.22</cite> and 12A DCMR § 3107, pertaining to outdoor signs and other forms of exterior advertising in the District of Columbia, shall not apply; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>All proceeds collected from the advertising agreement shall be paid into the DDOT Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives, established under § <cite path="§50-921.13">50-921.13</cite>; provided, that proceeds related to advertisements on bicycles, equipment, or facilities used for the purposes of the Bicycle Sharing program shall be deposited into the Bicycle Sharing Fund established by § <cite path="§50-921.16">50-921.16</cite>; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(H)</num>
        <text>[Not funded].</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4A)</num>
      <text>Rights-of-Way Management Administration may enter into agreements to allow the private sponsorship of bicycles, equipment, and facilities used in the Bicycle Sharing program, the placement of a corporate logo, slogan, or other indicia on the bicycles or facilities, and on related websites and social media; provided, that that an agreement that would modify the name or design of any part of the Capital Bikeshare system, including equipment, or facilities, shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of passive review before execution. The agreement submitted to the Council shall include detailed information about a proposed name or design. All proceeds collected from a private sponsorship agreement shall be deposited into the Bicycle Sharing Fund established by § <cite path="§50-921.16">50-921.16</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Tree Management Administration shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Maintain a tree inventory system;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Perform routine tree maintenance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Review transportation related construction plans to ensure the provision of adequate rights-of-way for tree planting; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Plant, remove, and trim trees citywide.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“DC Streetcar” means a fixed guideway transit network offering rail passenger service operated by the District government or its agent.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Integrated Premium Transit System” means an integrated transit system composed of any or all of the DC Streetcar, bus service operated or managed by, or on behalf of, the District government consistent with the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact, and facilities including buildings, other structures, and parking areas appurtenant to the DC Streetcar and bus service.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 5, 49 DCR 3444</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 77(b), (c), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-225">Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-225, § 3(d), 53 DCR 10232</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-20">Sept. 18, 2007, D.C. Law 17-20, § 6032(b), 54 DCR 7052</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-248">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-248, § 2(b), 55 DCR 9203</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-223">Sept. 24, 2010, D.C. Law 18-223, § 6052(b), 57 DCR 6242</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-339">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-339, § 6(b), 58 DCR 618</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 6022, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 139, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-234">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-234, § 2(a), 59 DCR 14772</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-289">Apr. 27, 2013, D.C. Law 19-289, § 8, 60 DCR 2328</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, §§  6012, 6022, 6032(a), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-207">Mar. 11, 2015, D.C. Law 20-207, §  2(b), 61 DCR 12690</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§5-401.01">5-401.01</cite>, § <cite path="§50-921.06">50-921.06</cite>, and § <cite path="§50-921.16">50-921.16</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “DDOT” for “DOT”; and, in par. (4)(F), substituted “Chief Property Management Officer” for “Director of the Office of Property Management”.</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-225">D.C. Law 16-225</cite>, in par. (2)(J) deleted “and” at the end; in par. (2)(K), substituted “travel; and” for “travel;”; and added par. (2)(L).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-20">D.C. Law 17-20</cite>, in par. (3), deleted “and” from the end of subpar. (C), added “and” at the end of subpar. (D)(iii), and added subpar. (E).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-248">D.C. Law 17-248</cite>, rewrote par. (1)(D); in par. (2)(D), deleted “historic district” following “Develop”; in par. (2)(J), inserted “review and revise the location of bus shelter locations,”; in par. (2)(K), deleted “and” at the end; in par. (2)(L), substituted a semicolon for a period at the end; and added par. (2)(M).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-223">D.C. Law 18-223</cite>, in par. (4), deleted “and” from the end of subpar. (E), inserted “and” at the end of subpar. (F), and added subpar. (G).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-339">D.C. Law 18-339</cite>, in par. (2), substituted “light rail streetcar transit” for “light rail” in subpar. (H), deleted “and” from the end of subpar. (L), substituted “; and” for a period the end of subpar. (M), and added subpar. (N).</annotation>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> rewrote par. (4)(G), which formerly read:</annotation>
      <annotation>“(G) Enter into agreements to allow the placement of advertisements on parking meters, including the back of receipts printed out by multi-space parking meters, and may collect payments under the agreements.”</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> made a technical correction to <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-339">D.C. Law 18-339</cite> which did not affect this section as codified.</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-234">D.C. Law 19-234</cite> rewrote (2)(K).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite>, applicable only upon a contingency being met, would have rewritten (4)(G)(iii) to read as follows: “(iii) The requirements of §§ <cite path="§1-303.21">1-303.21</cite> and <cite path="§1-303.23">1-303.23</cite>, and rules issued pursuant to those sections, pertaining to outdoor signs and other forms of exterior advertising in the District of Columbia, shall not apply.”</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> designated the existing text as (a); added (a)(1)(E) and (a)(2)(O) and made related changes; substituted “maintain, and regulate” for “develop, and finance” in (a)(2)(L); substituted “maintain, and regulate” for “develop, regulate, and finance” in (a)(2)(N); added the proviso in a)(4)(G)(iv); added (a)(4A); and added (b).</annotation>
      <annotation>The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</cite> added (3)(D-i) and made related changes; rewrote (4)(A); and would have added (4)(H).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3(c) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-134">D.C. Law 16-134</cite>, June 16, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 5762).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-252">D.C. Law 16-252</cite>, March 8, 2007, law notification  54 DCR 3037).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Department of Transportation Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-159">D.C. Law 17-159</cite>, May 13, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 5893).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 2 of Capitol Hill District Protection Temporary Act of 2007 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-49">D.C. Law 17-49</cite>, November 24, 2007, law notification  55 DCR 8).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) amendment of (2)(K), see § 2(a) of the District Department of Transportation Bicycle Sharing Fund Temporary Amendment Act of 2012 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 19-198">D.C. Law 19-198</cite>, Dec. 11, 2012, 59 DCR 12083).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(c) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-321, March 23, 2006,  53 DCR 2557).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-564, December 19, 2006,</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3 of Department of Transportation and Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Vending Consolidation of Public Space and Licensing Authorities Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-564, December 19, 2006,  53 DCR 10264).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 3(d) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-3, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1439).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6032(b) of Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-74, July 25, 2007,  54 DCR 7549).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Capitol Hill Historic District Protection Emergency Act OF 2007 (D.C. Act 17-112, August 2, 2007,  54 DCR 8231).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Capitol Hill Historic District Protection Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-142, October 17, 2007,  54 DCR 10743).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of Department of Transportation Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-308, February 25, 2008,  55 DCR 2522).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 6012 of Fiscal Year 2010 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-187, August 26, 2009,  56 DCR 7374).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 6052(b) of Fiscal Year 2011 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-463, July 2, 2010,  57 DCR 6542).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 6062, 6063 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition of sections, see §§ 6062, 6063 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of District Department of Transportation Bicycle Sharing Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-424, July 27, 2012,  59 DCR 9375).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  6022, 6032 and 6042(a) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  6012, 6022 and 6032(a) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  6012, 6022 and 6032(a) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Short Title</heading>
      <annotation>Short title: Section 6021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that subtitle C of title VI of the act may be cited as “District Department of Transportation Advertisement Amendment Act of 2011”.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of Authority to Capitol Hill Historic District Protection Emergency Act of 2007, see Mayor’s Order 2007-185, August 9, 2007 ( 54 DCR 11621).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <text>Section 6062 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that on or before September 30, 2013, the District Department of Transportation shall prepare a policy compendium listing all of the agency’s policies and procedures that affect the management of the transportation network and public space; and that the District Department of Transportation shall make the policy compendium available online.</text>
      <text>Section 6063 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that on or before October 1, 2012, January 1, 2013, April 1, 2013, and July 1, 2013, the District Department of Transportation shall submit a report to the Council on the status of the policy compendium, the progress made in the preceding quarter, and the projected timeline for completion.</text>
      <text>Section 9 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> provided: “Any order, rule, or regulation in effect under a law replaced by this act shall remain in effect until repealed, amended, or superseded.”</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite>, § 8: Section 10 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> provided that sections 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and 8 of the act shall not apply until the Mayor’s issuance of a comprehensive final rulemaking governing signs on public space and private property pursuant to section 2 of the act. Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-289">D.C. Law 19-289</cite> rewrote §§ <cite path="§1-303.21">1-303.21</cite> and <cite path="§1-303.23">1-303.23</cite>, and repealed § <cite path="§1-303.22">1-303.22</cite>.</text>
      <text>Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</cite>: Section 12(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</cite> provided that §§ 2(a), 2(b)(1), 2(b)(2)(A), 2(b)(2)(B), 2(b)(2)(C), 2(c), 3, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and 11 shall apply as of March 11, 2015.</text>
      <text>Section 12(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-207">D.C. Law 20-207</cite> provided that § 2(b)(2)(D) of the act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer to the Budget Director of the Council in a certification published by the Council in the District of Columbia Register.</text>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
