<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-921.15</num>
  <heading>Sustainable Transportation Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Sustainable Transportation Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and be used by the District Department of Transportation on approved capital projects for bus-operating enhancements, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Unfunded recommendations in WMATA Bus Line Studies and WMATA Service Evaluations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Other investments determined by the Mayor to enhance bus transit operational efficiency and customer service within the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Fees collected for the parking of vehicles where meters or devices are installed shall be deposited into the Fund in accordance with § <cite path="§50-2603">50-2603</cite>(8)(B).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9g</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">as added Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6024(b), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 6034, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-2603">50-2603</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> substituted “§ <cite path="§50-2603">50-2603</cite>(8)(B)” for “§ <cite path="§50-2603">50-2603</cite>(8)(C)” in (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-212">D.C. Law 19-212</cite> added <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137">D.C. Law 14-137</cite>, § 9h, to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“Sec. 9h. Parking Meter Fund.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(a) For fiscal year 2013, there is established as a lapsing, special purpose revenue fund the Parking Meter Fund (‘Fund’). The Fund shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and used for the following purposes:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) To pay for the maintenance of parking meters in the District; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) To provide the local match for a Federal Highway Administration grant for performance parking.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(b) Notwithstanding section 9g and section 3(h) of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Parking Facility Act of 1942, approved February 16, 1942 (56 Stat. 91; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§50-2603">50-2603</cite>(8)), a total of $2.9 million in parking meter revenue shall be deposited into the Fund as of the effective date of this section.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-212">D.C. Law 19-212</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137">D.C. Law 14-137</cite>, § 9g, concerning the Parking Meter Fund, see § 2 of the District Department of Transportation Parking Meter Fund Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-476, October 9, 2012,  59 DCR 12101).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6034 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6034 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 6031 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle D of Title VI of the act may be cited as the “District Department of Transportation Parking Meter Revenue Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
