<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-921.20</num>
  <heading>Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Vision Zero Pedestrian and Bicycle Safety Fund (“Fund”), which shall be administered by the Director of DDOT in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>There shall be deposited in the Fund $500,000 per fiscal year from the fines generated from the automated traffic enforcement system, authorized by § <cite path="§50-2209.01">50-2209.01</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be used solely to enhance the safety and quality of pedestrian and bicycle transportation, including education, engineering, and enforcement efforts designed to calm traffic and provide safe routes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization in an approved budget and fiscal plan, any funds appropriated in the Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, §  9l</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">as added Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 6033(a), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 6033(a) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
