<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-904</num>
  <heading>Functions.</heading>
  <text>The primary function of the major organizational components of the DMV are to plan, program, operate, manage, control, and maintain systems, processes, and programs that serve to ensure the safe and efficient movement of people in the operation of motor vehicles within the District of Columbia. The following functional components are included within this framework:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Adjudication functions as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Administer the processes of collecting traffic fines and adjudicating disputes regarding traffic movement or parking movement in the public right-of-way;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Ensure that efficient information and payment processing services are provided to motorists who have been ticketed, booted, or towed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>To process all correspondence relating to contested traffic violations;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Maintain account for the ticket file;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Make determinations on violations which pertain to automobile insurance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(F)</num>
      <text>Make determinations on complaints filed against public vehicle operators; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(G)</num>
      <text>Make determinations on drivers’ permits, including suspensions and revocations;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Customer service functions as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Title and register new or used motor vehicles and trailers in the District and issue special tags and permits;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Coordinate the issuance of special tags and permits, and to enforce activities relating to automobile dealers and vehicle inspection facilities;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>License public vehicle operators;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Provide all services which pertain to the issuance of driver permits and licensing; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(E)</num>
      <text>Maintain and administer a traffic record system;</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Administrative service functions to provide department wide coordination of administrative services emphasizing human resources, technology and information support, procurement, and fiscal management support services; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>Take enforcement action, including the issuance of fines, for car dealers’ violations of Chapters 4 and 5 of Title 18, DCMR.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-175">Mar. 26, 1999, D.C. Law 12-175, § 1825, 45 DCR 7193</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-307">Apr. 8, 2005, D.C. Law 15-307, § 204, 52 DCR 1700</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 40-154.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-307">D.C. Law 15-307</cite>, deleted “and” at the end of par. (2)(E); substituted “: and” for a period at the end of par. (3); and added par. (4).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary addition of chapter, see note to § <cite path="§50-901">50-901</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90-day) addition of Chapter 1A, see notes following § <cite path="§50-901">50-901</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Application of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-175">D.C. Law 12-175</cite>: See Historical and Statutory Notes following § <cite path="§50-901">50-901</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
