<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-921.16</num>
  <heading>Bicycle Sharing Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a nonlapsing, special purpose revenue fund the Bicycle Sharing Fund (“Fund”). The fund shall be administered by the Director of the District Department of Transportation and used to pay for goods, services, property and for any other purpose under the Bike Sharing program established pursuant to §  50-921.04(2)(K).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>All revenue related to the Bike Sharing program, from whatever source derived, shall be deposited into the Fund as of March 19, 2013.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, including any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (a) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History" path="§9h">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 9f</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-234" type="History">as added Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-234, § 2(c), 59 DCR 14772</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-128" type="History">renumbered as §  9h, July 23, 2014, D.C. Law 20-128, § 2(b), 61 DCR 5722</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-234">D.C. Law 19-234</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-128">D.C. Law 20-128</cite> renumbered <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137">D.C. Law 14-137</cite>, § 9f, as added by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-234">D.C. Law 19-234</cite>, § 2(c), as <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137">D.C. Law 14-137</cite>, § 9h.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-198">D.C. Law 19-198</cite> repealed (b)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 5(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-198">D.C. Law 19-198</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-137">D.C. Law 14-137</cite>, § 9h, concerning the Parking Meter Fund, see § 2 of the District Department of Transportation Parking Meter Fund Establishment Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-2, January 29, 2013,  60 DCR 5400, 20 DCSTAT 1300).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(b) of District Department of Transportation Bicycle Sharing Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-424, July 27, 2012,  59 DCR 9375).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2(c) of District Department of Transportation Bicycle Sharing Fund EmergencyAmendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-424, July 27, 2012,  59 DCR 9375).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
