<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>50-921.02</num>
  <heading>Director.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The DDOT shall be headed by a Director. The Director shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to § <cite path="§1-523.01">1-523.01</cite>(a).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Director shall have authority over DDOT, its functions and personnel, including the power to re-delegate to employees authority as, in the judgment of the Director, is warranted in the interests of efficiency and sound administration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director may issue grants not to exceed $1 million per grant to achieve the District’s transportation goals, including safety objectives.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No later than December 31 of each year, the Mayor shall submit to the Council an annual report specifying for each grant awarded by the District Department of Transportation in the prior fiscal year the following information:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The name of the recipient;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The amount awarded;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The purpose for the grant awarded;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>A description of outcomes to be achieved with the funds of the grant; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>An evaluation of whether the identified outcomes have been achieved with the grant.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Director may issue sole source subgrants in excess of $1 million to the Union Station Redevelopment Corporation for the purpose of improving Union Station; provided, that the grants are federal grants and that the Union Station Redevelopment Corporation provides any necessary match.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director may enter into agreements with community-based organizations to support community-based transportation enhancement activities that are funded and approved by the Federal Highway Administration.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>An agreement made pursuant to this subsection shall constitute an agreement making or receiving grants-in-aid and shall be exempt from Chapter 3A of Title 2, in accordance with § <cite path="§2-351.05">2-351.05</cite>(c)(12).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Director shall submit to the Council on an annual basis a report detailing such grants and agreements.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director shall not spend directly from capital projects created in fiscal year 2012 or later that are funded through the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund established under § <cite path="§9-111.01">9-111.01</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Director may submit requests to the Office of Budget and Planning of the Office of the Chief Financial Officer (“OBP”) to allocate funds for the Related Projects, as submitted annually by DDOT through the approved Transportation Improvement Program as part of the budget request for each capital project created in fiscal year 2012 or later funded from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund. The Director, following allocation of funds by OBP to Related Projects, shall have the authority to obligate and spend the funds.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Director may submit requests to OBP to re-allocate funds from any Related Project to the applicable capital project created in Fiscal Year 2012 or later funded from the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund. The Director, following re-allocation of funds by OBP from a Related Project to its applicable capital project, shall have the authority to submit requests to OBP to allocate these funds to another Related Project.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director may:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>With respect to the program established pursuant to 49 U.S.C. § 5310 (the “5310 Program”):</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>Enter into agreements with nonprofit organizations to provide those nonprofit organizations vehicles to transport elderly residents and residents with disabilities;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>Provide an application for the 5310 Program each year, solicit applicants to apply, and administer a selection process to identify which eligible applicants may participate;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>Enter into agreements with the nonprofit organizations that are selected to receive vehicles to ensure they use the vehicles as prescribed by the 5310 Program guidelines and regulations enacted pursuant to this paragraph, including the requirement that the vehicle recipient deposit matching funds into the District Department of Transportation Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives; and</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iv)</num>
          <text>Enter into contracts with third parties for the procurement and maintenance of eligible vehicles to be used by the nonprofit organizations selected by the Director;</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Enter into an agreement with a developer, property owner, utility company, the federal government or other governmental entity, or other person or entity requiring payment for:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The costs of DDOT’s review of the proposed or existing project on private property or public space that may affect the transportation infrastructure or public space in the District or DDOT’s ability to manage and maintain the transportation infrastructure or public space in the District;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The implementation of transportation infrastructure or public improvements or mitigation measures to address the project’s impact on the transportation infrastructure or public space in the District or on DDOT’s ability to manage and maintain the transportation infrastructure or public space in the District; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>The cost of both review and the implementation of mitigation measures; and</text>
        </para>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Promulgate, amend, or repeal rules to implement the provisions of this subsection, pursuant to the Mayor’s authority under Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§  2-501 et seq.].</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A payment, improvement, and mitigation measure required under an agreement authorized by paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall be reasonably related to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The costs incurred by DDOT in reviewing the project;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The effects of the project on the transportation infrastructure or public space in the District; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The effects of the project on DDOT’s ability to manage and maintain the transportation infrastructure or public space in the District.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A payment made pursuant to an agreement authorized by paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, a payment required for the temporary use of public space or the use of the public right of way pursuant to the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act, approved October 17, 1968 (82 Stat. 1156; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§10-1101.01">10-1101.01</cite> et seq.), or Title VI of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 11-198">D.C. Law 11-198</cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§10-1141.01">10-1141.01</cite> et seq.).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Director may enter into agreements with jurisdictions in the Washington metropolitan area (“regional jurisdictions”) to plan, fund, design, construct, and otherwise carry out transportation projects.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>DDOT may receive funds from and disperse funds to regional jurisdictions for the purposes of planning, funding, designing, constructing, and otherwise carrying out the transportation projects.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>DDOT may take other appropriate actions to plan, fund, design, construct, and otherwise carry out the transportation projects, including performing work, including construction work, in regional jurisdictions.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 3, 49 DCR 3444</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 20(b), 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-354" type="History">Apr. 13, 2005, D.C. Law 15-354, § 77(b), 52 DCR 2638</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-248" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-248, § 2(a), 55 DCR 9203</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 11002, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 6024(a), 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 220, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-241" type="History">Mar. 19, 2013, D.C. Law 19-241, § 2(a), 59 DCR 14794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 6122, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-128" type="History">July 23, 2014, D.C. Law 20-128, §  2(a), 61 DCR 5722</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 8002, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 8022, 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§50-921.13">50-921.13</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite> validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-354">D.C. Law 15-354</cite> substituted “DDOT” for “DOT”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-248">D.C. Law 17-248</cite> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> added (c)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “shall be exempt from Chapter 3A of Title 2, in accordance with § <cite path="§2-351.05">2-351.05</cite>(c)(12)” for “shall be exempt from Unit A of Chapter 3 of Title 2, in accordance with § <cite path="§2-301.04">2-301.04</cite>(b)” in (d)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-241">D.C. Law 19-241</cite> added (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (g).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2014 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-128">D.C. Law 20-128</cite> rewrote (f).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added (e)(3).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “for the Related Projects, as submitted annually by DDOT through the approved Transportation Improvement Program as part of the budget request for each capital project” for “for the Related Projects of each capital project” in (e)(2).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Department of Transportation Establishment Temporary Amendment Act of 2008 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 17-159">D.C. Law 17-159</cite>, May 13, 2008, law notification  55 DCR 5893).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-166">D.C. Law 19-166</cite> added (c)(3) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Director may issue sole source subgrants in excess of $1 million to the Union Station Redevelopment Corporation for the purpose of improving Union Station; provided, that the grants are federal grants and that the Union Station Redevelopment Corporation provides any necessary match.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-166">D.C. Law 19-166</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-208">D.C. Law 19-208</cite> added subsection (f) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(f) The Director may enter into agreements with private nonprofit organizations to provide those nonprofit organizations vehicles to transport elderly residents and residents with disabilities pursuant to  49 U.S.C. § 5310 (the ‘5310 Program’). Furthermore, the Director shall have the authority to:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Provide an application for the 5310 Program each year, solicit applicants to apply, and administer a selection process to identify which eligible applicants may participate in the 5310 Program;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Enter into agreements with the nonprofit organizations that are selected to receive vehicles to ensure they use the vehicles as prescribed by the 5310 Program guidelines and regulations enacted pursuant to this subsection, including the requirement that the vehicle recipient deposit matching funds into the District Department of Transportation Enterprise Fund for Transportation Initiatives;</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(3) Enter into contracts with third parties for the procurement and maintenance of eligible vehicles to be used by the nonprofit organizations selected by the Director; and</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(4) Promulgate, amend, or repeal rules to implement the provisions of this subsection, pursuant to the Mayor’s authority under Title 1 of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-208">D.C. Law 19-208</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Transportation Infrastructure Mitigation Temporary Amendment Act of 2013 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-68">D.C. Law 20-68</cite>, February 22, 2014,  61 DCR 19).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2 and 3 of the Transportation Infrastructure Mitigation Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 20-112">D.C. Law 20-112</cite>, June 21, 2014,  61 DCR 4328).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of (f), see § 2(a) of the District Department of Transportation Accessible Vehicles Fund Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-465, October 4, 2012,  59 DCR 11764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Department of Transportation Establishment Emergency Amendment Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-308, February 25, 2008,  55 DCR 2522).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of District Department of Transportation Grant Authority Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-353, May 11, 2012,  59 DCR 5125).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of the District Department of Transportation Grant Authority Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-405, July 24, 2012,  59 DCR 9122).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the DDOT Accessible Vehicles Fund Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-7, January 31, 2013,  60 DCR 2809, 20 DCSTAT 456).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) of the Transportation Infrastructure Mitigation Emergency Amendment Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-198, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15327).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6122 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6122 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2(a) and 3 of the Transportation Infrastructure Mitigation Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-268, January 15, 2014,  61 DCR 785).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 and 3 of the Transportation Infrastructure Mitigation Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-298, March 14, 2014,  61 DCR 2566, 20 DCSTAT 3065).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§  2-4 of the Transportation Infrastructure Mitigation Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-351, June 17, 2014, 61 DCR 6328).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  8002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July 14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  8002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 10915, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §  8002 of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 8022 of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <text type="Short Title">Short title: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> provided that title XI of the act may be cited as “Department of Transportation Capital Budget Allocation Authority Act of 2011”.</text>
    <text type="Short Title">Section 6121 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle M of Title VI of the act may be cited as the “District Department of Transportation Jurisdiction Amendment Act of 2013”.</text>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 6123 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that § 6122 of the act shall apply as of June 15, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
