<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>50-921.34</num>
  <heading>Fares; structure; purpose.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Insofar as practicable, and consistent with the provision of adequate service at reasonable fares, the rates and fares and service shall be fixed by the Department, so as to result in revenues that shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Pay the operating expenses and provide for repairs, maintenance, and depreciation of the DC Circulator vehicles or other assets owned or controlled by the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Provide for payment of all principal and interest on outstanding revenue bonds; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide funds for any purpose the Department considers necessary and desirable to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Nothing in subsection (a) of this section shall prevent the Department from offering tickets at no cost or at discounted prices as part of the Department’s marketing of the DC Circulator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Beginning August 26, 2013, the Department shall not charge a DC Circulator fare to students on regular school days.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-137" type="History">May 21, 2002, D.C. Law 14-137, § 11d</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-225" type="History">as added Mar. 6, 2007, D.C. Law 16-225, § 3(e), 53 DCR 10232</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 10004, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Addition of Section">For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 3(d) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Temporary Amendment Act of 2006 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-134">D.C. Law 16-134</cite>, June 16, 2006, law notification  53 DCR 5762).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3(d) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-321, March 23, 2006,  53 DCR 2557).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 3(e) of District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2007 (D.C. Act 17-3, January 16, 2007,  54 DCR 1439).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 10004 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 10004 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 10001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Title X of the act may be cited as the “Revised Revenue Estimate Adjustment Allocation Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
