<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-101">
  <num type="law">2-101</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-08-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-101.pdf">D.C. Law 2-101</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 257</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-101 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-218, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 2, 1978 and May 16, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 15, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-207 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA August 23, 1978 D.C LAW 2-101 •Full Political Participation Act of 1978" Pursuant to section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbi a adoptec Bill No. 2-218 on first and second readings May 2, 1978, and May 16, 1978, r espectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on June 15, 1978, this legislation was assigned Act No 2-207, published in the July 14, 1978, edition of the o.c. Register, and transmitted t o both Houses of Congress for a 30-day revi ew, in accordance with Section 602(c) {l } of the Act The Counci l of the District of ,Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C Law 2-101 effective August lB, 1978 Chair~~A l-f TUCKER of the Council (Vol. 25, o c Register, 257 July 14, 1978) l!:orolled D.C. J.»I 2-101 1 THE (0J TL Jf T"E C! S T!&amp;lt;;CT JF CCLU 3 J t, ALQJST 18, 1978 To a~eno t.nc electi on and confl ict o f in t erest l•ws o f tn~ J i s tri c t o f Colu'!lt&amp;gt;i a an for ot'&amp;gt;er ~urµos .Js 3E IT F~ACT ED FV T~E COU~CI L OF r~r JIST~I CT OF COLU Th a t t ni s ac t may De cit e~ as the Full ~ol i ti cal ?ar ti cipation Act of 1?7 H Sec 2. Tnc Act en ti tl e 1 An Act to r e3u l ate tne e l e cti on of dol e 1ates re~ res un tir. y t nR C i s tr ic t of Co lumo i a to n3tional pol it ic al conventions a nd for otn• r p urposes 11 l l et s eJ l a s rn nrte i. i s furtrie r ir..en:1ed .is f o l lo s: {a Pa ragrapn 2) o f s ection (1 0 C. Code sec 1 110 1 (2 i s a mended to r e a d as f o lloh s 2 2 l e &amp;lt;;3 t ~s t o co:w ent i ons and conter enc es of ool i t:ical pa r t i e s i nc luoin le l&amp;lt ill €5 to no i nat c cdnOidJtcs f o r tne Pre s ioenct and ice Pr esiaency of tnc united S t ates P~OVI DEo Tn~t all electi~ns f or d e l•~ates to c on ven tions and conf e renc e of oolit ic a l parti es upon the r P.Ques t of tne s i 1 gt;a rty• snal l be -2- special elections al ready scheduled for other purposes b l Subsection Cc) of section 3 (O.c. Code. sec. l l1 03 (c is a mended to r ead as fol l o ws member ay be reappoint and if not reappointed the member sha ll serve unti l his successor has been appointed and qualif ies c) Subsection (c) of section 4 O.c. Code. sec l- ll04(c i s a mended to r ead as f o ll o ws c)(l) Each member of the Board excluding the Chairman, shall receive compensation at the rate of one hundred dollars (Sl00) for each e i gnt-hour period or t we lve dol l ars and fifty cent 12 50) per hour whichever prov ides less whil e ac tually in t he ser vice of the Board not to excee~ the sum of twelve thousand five hund r ed dol lars \ l 2 S00) per annum 121 Tne Cha i rman of the Buard snail recei ve compensation at t he rate o f one hundred dol l ars (Sl00) f or each eignt-hour period or twelve dollars and fifty cents Sl2 SO) per hour whichever prov i des less while actually in the service of the Board. not to e xceed the sum of twenty-Sik thuusand f i ve hundred dollars 26 SOO) per annum 1.nrolled Original -3 d) Secti on 5 10. c Code. sec l ll05) i s amended as follows 1) subsection (a O. t Code sec. l ll05(a i s amended as fol l o ws A) paragrapn 13 i s amended o y strik ing BJ paraq raph 14 i s r edesignated as par a g r aph 1 5 J a nd as foll o ws C) inserting a ne~ par agraph 14 to read 14) take reason~b le steps t o f aci lita te voting by bl ind, physic a lly handicapped and devel o p me ntally disabled person s Quali fied to vote under this Act a nd t o a u tho r iz e such persons t o c~st a oa ll ot with the assistdnce of a person of their own choosing and" i and (2) subsection (e) 10 c Code s ec 1-llOS (e i s ame nded Dy addin g i mmed iately follo wing contr ol of the Dir e c t or t he f o llowi ng clause and ma y not be r eassiqned without the conc urrence of the Directo r e J Section 7 10 c Code• sec l l l 0 7J i s a mendP.d a s follo ws: Enrolled Origioa1 -4 1) subsection (d) 10.c. Code. sec. l-llOl(d)l is amended by striking the last sentence thereof 2) a new subsection is added at the end thereof to read as follows h The Board shall cause a current copy of the list of qualified electors registered to vote to be placed in public buildings of the District of Columbia for a period of not less than fourteen (14) days preceding each election held under this Act as follows ll a city-wide list shall be placed in the main public library; and (Z) a ward list for the ward shall be placed in every branch library located within the respective ward f} Subsection (9) of section 9 (D.C. Code sec. l- 1109(9 is amended by striking the word "runoft 9) Subsection (e} of section 10 co.c. Code• sec. 1- lllO(e is amended by striking the phrase "the fourth Monday in January next fo llow ing the oate" and inserting in lieu thereof "noon of the thirtieth day after the Board of Elections and Ethics certifies the results hJ Subsection (b) of section 11 (o.c. Code. sec 1- llll(b is amended by striking the phrase "in violation of this Act" and inserting in lieu thereof "or the willful receipt of contributions in violation of the District of Enrolled Original -s- Columbi a Campaign F inance Refor m and Conflict of Int e rest Act 10.c Co de sec l-1121 et s eQ I i i Sect i on 14 D. c Code sec 1- 1114) is amended by s~ rik ing the phras e in violation of this Act" and inserting in l ieu the reof in vi o lati on of the Di stri c t of Co lumbia Campai g n Finance Reform and Conflict o f Interes t Act (D C. cooe sec 1- 1121 e t s eq J I Sec t ion 15 (O. C. Code sec l 1115) is amen oeo as f o llows Ill subsecti on a D. c Code, s ec l lllS( a )l I s amen d e d oy r e wording t he first sen tenc~ to read f ollo~s No per s on sh a ll be a c a ndida t e f u r mor r th an onr o ff ice on the Boa rd of Educ at ion o r th~ Counc il o r M3 yo r in any rl ec tion f or t nc me mbe rs o f t he Boar d of Educati o n or the c o uncil or ~dyor. and n o p e rson snall br a c and ida t e for more than one o lf icP on the Council or for the Ma yo r i n a n y p ri mar y e l ~c ti on a n d (2) subsecti o n (bl (D C. Code s ec l-lll5( b r s d mendod t o read as f o llows C b ot ~it hst~nd i n~ t nc p r o vi s i ons o f para9raµh Cal a person holding the office o f M~yor De l ega te Chai r man o r Memhc r o f the Council or me~b~r of the Board o f Ed u c ati o n s ha ll wh il e hol d i n g such of f ice be eliqibl o as a cand ida~e fo r any o ther of suc h Eorolled Original offices in a ny primary or general election Jn tne event that said person is elected In a general election to the office for which he or she is a candidate, that 1 person shall, within 24 hour s of tne date that the Soard of Elections ano Ethics certifies said pe r son s election. pursuant to subsection (a)(lOJ of section 5 of this Act (D. c Code• sec. l-l105( a l0 eithe r r es ign from the offi ce that person c urrently holds or shall decl ine t o accept the office f o r wh ich he or she was a candidate I n t he e vent tnat sa id pe rson elects to resi gn said res ignation shall be ef fectiv e not l ater than 24 hour s be fore the date upon which that person would assume the office to which he o r sne has been e lected Sec 3 The Dis trict of Col umoia Ca mpa ign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act appr o ved August 14 l974 (88 Stat 447; o.c. Code, s ec 1-1121 et seq a s amended is fur ther amended as fol l o ws a) Section 102 (o. c. Code. sec 1-1121 is amended as fol l o ws l) subsec tion (a O C. Code sec l -llZl(a is a mended by s triking the word "runoff ZI s ut&amp;gt;scc tion (f 0.C. Code• sec. L- 112l (f is amended as fol l o ws' Znrolled Original -7 A) parag raph (11 (O. c Code s ec l ll2l(f)(l is amended by inserting immed iately follow ing the phrase •dues )t loan• the clause •1 except a loan made in the regular c ourse of busine ss by a business engaged in the business of ~ak ing loans 8) parilgraph (4) 10 c Code sec 1- 1121 f 4 is amended b y i) inserting i mmediately follow i nq the phr a se compensat i on by i ndi vi du ills• the phrase including accounta nts and attorne ys ii) str i king the wo r d "or" immedi a tely f ollowing tne phras e •any c andidate f or of f ice Jn1 i ii) adding the f o llowing clauses at the enj thereof to read as f ollows F l se rvi ces of a n informat i onal o r pol ling nature and r e lated thereto des i g ned t o s e e k t he opinion(s) of vote rs c onc e rning the possibl e cand i dac y of qua lified e l e c tor s t or public o ffi ce pri o r t o su ch qua lifi ed electo r' s oecoming a candida t e as p r o v ide d in th is Ac t GJ the use of r eal or per sonal property and the c ost s of Enrolled Origina a- invitat ions food and beverages voluntarily provided by an individual to a candidate In render ing voluntary personal s ervi ces on the individual' s residential premises for r e lated activites or (H) the sal e of any food or beverage by a vendor for use in a candidate s campaign at a charge less than the norma l compdrabl e charge if sucn chd rye for use in a candidate s campai g n is at least P.Qua l to the cost of s uch food or bever~9e to the vendor; to the extent t ha t the provisions of (G) and (H) do n o t exceed 50 0 ~ach with respect to any candidate election 3) par agraph (4) of subsec tion (g c Code sec l -ll2l( gJ( 4 i s a mended by adding the following clause at the end thereof or the use of r ea l or personal prope rty and the cost of any food o r beverage voluntarily p r o vided by an Indiv i dual to a candidate in :tnrolled origi nal 9- rendering voluntary per sonal services on the individual's r es identi a l pre~ises for candidate related activity if the cu•ulative value o f such activities by s uch individual on behalf of any candidate do not e~ceed 5 500 with respect to any el ection and (4) subsection (h O.c. Code sec. l-112l(hl I i s amended by striking the word association b) Sec t ion 203 (O. c Code sec. 1-1133) is amendecl as f o I 1 ows l) subsec tion (a) {O. c. Code. sec l -ll33(a)I i s amended by Al st ri king the words national bank" and inserting in 1 ieu thereof tho phr dse one or more national banks 8) inserting the wor ds or depositories" i mmedi ately following the wo rd "depository" wherever it appears in the subsect ion; and (Cl insert i ng the words or accounts" immediately fo ll owing the word account and (ZJ subsection (I&amp;gt 0 C. Code sec 1-1133(1&amp;gt is amended by s triking the phrase mainta i ned at the campaiqn depository o f such pol itic a l comm itt ee or candidate" and inserting in l i eu thereof •or accounts maintained at a Enrolled Originai -10- campaign depository of such political committee or candidate c) Paragraph (91 of subsection (b) of section 204 (O.c. Code. sec. l-1134(b)(9 is amended by 1) inse rt ing the words •or banks" immediately following the word •bank and (Z) inserting the words •or depositori es• immed&amp;lt;ately following the word "depository• wherever it appears in the paragraph dl Subsection (b) of SP.Ction 205 (o .c. Code, sec. l- ll35(b i s amended by inserting the words •or depositories" immediately following the word "depos itory" wherever it dppears in the subsect ion e) Section 206 (O.C. Code, sec. 1-1136) is amended as follows l) suosection (a O.c. Code. sec. l-ll36(a is amended by striking the phrase •fifteenth and fifth days and inserting i n lieu thereof "ei ghth day and (2) subsection (d 0.C. Code, sec. 1-ll36(d is repeal ed f) Subsection (a) of section 208 (O.C. CodR, sec. l- ll38(a is amended by striking the clause taken before any officer authorized to administer oaths Enrolled Original -11 91 Section 211 10.c. Code, sec. 1-11~1) is a111ended to read as follows No provision of this Act shall be construed as creating li ability on the part of any candidate fof any financial obligation incurred by a politi cal com111ittee. For the purposes of tl'l is Act, and the Act to regulate the elec tion of d e legates representing the District of Colu111bia to national political conventions. and for other purposes. approved August lZt l9SS (69 Stat. 699; o.c. Code, sec. l-1101 et seQ act ions of an agent acting for a candidate shall be imputed to the candi date: PROVI DED, Howe ver, Th at the a c tions of s uch a gent may not be Imputed to the c and idate in tho presenc e of a prov isi on o f law r e quiring a wi llful ano knowing viol at ion of the Act s unl ess t he agenc y r e lationshi p to engage in suc h an act is shown by c lear and conv inc ing evidence h) Subsec tion c) of section 301 (D c Code sec 1- 1151 (c i s a men::ted by 1) st riking out the phr aso In any app r opri a t e c ase where the Boar d upon it s own motion or upon recommendation of the Director ma ke s a fi nding of an apparent v iolation of th is chapte r and inse rting in nro11ea original -12- lieu thereof the following "Where the Board, following the presentation by the Oirector of evidence constituting an apparent violation of this Act akes a finding of an apparent violation of this Act and (Z) adding the following sentence at the end of the subsection to read as follows The Director shall have no authority concerning the enforcement of provisions of the Act to regulate the election of delegates representing the District of Columbia to national political conventions, and tor other purpo~es (D.c. Code• sec. 1-1101 et seQ and recommendations of criminal or civil, or both• violations under that Act shall be presented by the General Counsel to the Board in accordance with the rules and regulations of general application adopted by the Board in accordance with the provisions of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act (O.c. Code• sec. 1-1501 et seq Upon the direction of the Board. the Director may b~ called upon to investigate allegations of violations of the elections laws in accord with the provisions of this subsection c,rolled Original 13 i) Section 3 02 (D. C. Code sec 1-1152) i s amended as f 01 l o s l) subsection (a D c Code sec 1-ll5Z(a is a 111ended by (A del e t ing and• at the end of paragraph 5 8) dele t ing at the end of paragraph (b) and i nserting in l i eu thereof and (C adding a new subsect i on to read a s fol lows tll to i nst itute or conduct on hi s or her o wn motion an informal hearing on alleged vi olations of the reporting requirements contained in this Act. Where the Direc t o r in his or her discretion. determi nes tha t such vi ol a tion has occur r e d the Dir e ctor ma y i s sue a n order to the o ff end inq party or parti e s t o ceas e a nd desi s t such violation s within th~ fiv e (5) day pe r i od immediate ly followin g t h e issuance of suc h order Shoul d the offendin~ party o r parti e s fail t o comply with sa i d orde r the Dir ector sha ll presen t evide nce of such fai lure to the Board fol lowin g the p r ese ntation of said evi o e n c e t o t h e boar d b y the Di r ector In an a d v e rsary proceeding and an o pen hearing the Boa rd may refer suc h matter to t h e United States Attorney f or the fol l o ws Enrolled Originai -lit- District of Col u•bia in accordance with t he provi•ions of section 10l(c) of this Act D. c Code• sec l-ll5l( c or ay disai ss the action and (Z) adding a new subsec tion c to r ead as Cl All i nvestigations of alleged vi olations of this Act shall be ade by the Director in his or her discretion in accordance with procedures of general applicability i ssued by the Director in accordance with the Distri ct of Columbia Administrat ive Procedure Act (D· C• Code sec l 1501 et seq All a ll egations of viol ations of this Act wh ic h shall be presented t o the Board in wr i ting. shall b e transmitted to t he Director without action by the Soard Jn a r e asonable time, the Direc t o r sha l l cause e vide nce concerning the alleqed violation of this Act to be presented to t he Boar d if he or she bel ieves that sufficient evidence exists const ituting an apparent viol~tion of this Act Following the p r esentation of such evi dence to the Soar o b y t he Di rector in an adversary p roceeding and lnrol l ed Or i glnai 15- an open hear i n g tne Board may refer s uch matter to the United States Attorney for the District of Columb ia in accordance ~i th the prov i sions of sect i on 30llcl of this Act 10 c Code sec l ll5l(c o r ~ay dismis s the action In n o case may the 6oard ref e r information c once rning an alleged vi o l a ti on o f t h is Ac t t o t h e Uni t ed States Attor ne y f o r t he Distr ic t o f Co lumbi a without t he p re senta t i on h~rein prov i ded b y the Director Shoul d the Director f a il t o p r e sent a matter o r a d vi s e the Board that insuffici~nt evidence e xi st s to present su c h a ma tt e r or that an addi t i on peri o d of time i s needed to inve sti gatu th~ matte r f u r ther wi t h i n ni nety 190 d a ys o f ot s rece i pt b y the Board or the Oi rec t o r, t ne Board may order the Direc tor t o p r ese nt tnn matter a s he r e i n p rovided. The pr o vi s i on s o f this subsecti o n s h a ll in no manner limit t n~ authority of the un i ted States Attor ne y f o r the Di s tri c t o f Co lumbia j Section 306 10 c Code sec 1-1156) is amend ed as follow s Drolled Original lb l subsection (b l 10.c. Code sec. l-115b(bll is aMended by designating paragraph 13 as •141• and inserting a new paragraph 3 to read as follows 3) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (Z) of this subsection. the Board •ay issue a schedule of fines for vi olations of this Act whi c h may be i~posed ministerially by the Di r ecto r. A c ivil penalty i~posed under the a uthority of t his paragraph may be rev iewed by the Board in accordance with the p rovisions of paragraph (Z The a ggregate s et of penalti es imposed under the authority of this paragraph ma y not exceed $50 and (Z) subsection (cl 10 c Code sec. l-ll5b( C i s amended by AJ strik ing the phr a se through it s Genera l Counsel B) inser t ing the following sentences immedi ately following the phrase "the Board has prima ry jurisdi c tion The Board sha l l publish a concise statement of eac h request f o r an advisory opi nion wi thout identifying t he pe rson seeking such :Enrol led Original -17- opini on in t he D i Ud ct_gLl2D!!l!E t9.i L within twenty (ZO) days of its receipt by the Board. Comments upon such requested opinions shall be received by the Board for a period of at l east fifteen (l5) days following publi cation i n the District of Columbia Re!l!.ll The Board ma y waive the advance notice and public commen t prov i sions foll o wi ng a f ind ing that the i ssuance of such advi so ry opini on constitutes a n emer gency necessary fo r the i mmed i a t e p r eser vat ion of the puol ic peace heal th safet y. welf dr e or rnor a Is and (Cl add ing the followi ng sentenc e at the end of the sub sec tion to read d S follows Wnen i ssued according t o r ules of the &amp;amp;oa r d an advisory opinion shall be deemed to b~ an o r der of the Board rev iewaOl e in t he Superior Court o f the Dis trict of Columbia by any inte r es ted per s on adve r sely affec t e d t hereb y kl Sec tion 401 (O.t. Code. sec l-llol) is amended as f o llows: Xo:rcille Ori"'i.nal -16 1) subsection (a) 10.c. Code. sec. 1-llbl(a is repealed 2) subsection (bl (0.C. Code• sec. l-116l(b is acended by striking the phrases •cother than an individual with respect to whom subsection (a) applies)"i other than such an individual and in the case of a runoff election. an additional S400 and and in the case of a runoff election• an additional $200"i and (3) subsection (c O.C. Code, sec. l-llbl(c is amended by A) striking the word "individual" and inserting in lieu thereof the word "person B) inserting immediately following "election" the phrase "for the Mayor. the Cnairman of the Counc il. each memher of the Council. and each member of the Board of Education (including primary. general. and special elections as appropr iate and (CJ strikinQ the figure •sz.ooon and inserting in lieu thereof "S4t000 1) Section 501 (O.c. Code• sec. 1-1171) is amended &amp;lt;is follows 1) subsection (a D.c. Code. sec. l-117l(a is amended by: Enrolled Original 19 A strikinq the phrase •to promulgate an iss uance within the Admin istrat ive I ssuance Syste eMcept indivi dual personnel ~atters and BJ striking the words "to unde rtake• and inserti ng i n lieu thereof the phase "to cause to be undertaken 2 subsect ion (b 0.C. Code sec. l-117l(b is a mended t o read as follows {b) The term compensation me ans any money or an exchange of val ue received reqa r a less of i ts for m. b y a person acti ny d S a lobby i!&amp;gt;t 3) s ubparagrap h of par agraph 2 of sub section f) { o. C. Code sec 1-1171(f)(2 E is a mc n-:iea Oy Inserting i mmedi a te ly following t ne wo r d s gener a l c ircu lati o n the p h rase or a public a tion whuse primary audienc e i s the orya nization s membe r s h ip 4) su::isec t i on h 88 Sta t 462; o. c. Cod e. s ec l-ll7l{h)I is amended b y str iki ng out "l-ll BZ(b 21(4 and i nserting "l-1182(0 l J" in lieu thereof S subs ec t i on i l 8 8 Stat 467 n. c. Code s e c l -ll7l(i i s amended by A) striking out GS-15 a nd i ns e rti ng GS-13" in lieu thereof; and Enrolled Original -zo BJ striking out •1-11BZ(O)(ZllA and inserting •t-ll82(b l)ft in lieu thereof; and amp adding new definitions thereto in the appropriate alphabeti cal sequence to read as follows The term 'registrant means a person who is required to register as a lobbyist unde r the provisions of section 502 of thi s Act (O. c Code, sec 1-1172 The term •expenditure means any money o r an exchange of value regardless of it s f orm {m ection 502 (o. c Code sec l-117 2) i s amended t o r ead as follo ws Except as provided in secti on 503 of this Act 10. c Code sec 1- 1173 a person shall re9ister with t he Di r e c t or pursuant t o sect i on 504 of this Act 10. c Code sec. 1-1174) if such person receive s compensation or expenos funds in an amount of S250 or mor e in any three consecutive c~ l endar month per i od for lobbying A pe rson who receives compensation from more than one source shall req i ster under this sect i on if such person receives a n a ggregate amount of SZSO or mo r e in an y three xnrolled Origina 21- consecutive calendar month per i od for lobby i ng n Section 503 fO.C. Code sec 1-1173) is amlE!nded by add i n g the fo llowi ng at the end t hereof to r e ad as f o llows d) a ny ent i ty specified n section 1 of title I of the oistrict of Columbia Income and franchise lax Act of lq47 a pproved July 16• 1947 (61 Stat. 334 o.c. Code sec 47-l554(dJJ no activities of whic h i nc lude l obbying the r esult of wh i ch shall i nnure to the f inancial gain or benefi t of the entity Any person who is exempt from registration under any provis i on of this sect ion, except a person exempt from r egistration under the provisions of subsection (a) of t nis section may be a registrant for otner purposes under this Act PROVIDED. Howe ver That no such act i vity engJged in by such pe r son shall constitute a confli c t of interest under the p rovi s i ons of title Vl of this. Act (O. c ode sec 1- 1 19 1 et seq Registrants have no obligation to r eport a cti vities in furtherance of exempt activiti es under this se ction in act ivity reports required under section 505 of this Act O. C. Code sec 1-11751 o) Paragraph E J of subsection (a) of sec tion 505 10.c Code sec l-ll7S(a)(E is ame nded by str iki ng the phr ase "and the nature of the communicat ion nrolled Original zz- {pl Section 506 O. C. Code, sec 1-1176) is amended as fol lows 1) s.ubs.ection {a O.c. Code, sec. l 1176(al) is a~ended by adding the followin g sentence at the end thereof This sect ion shall not be constr ued to restr ict in a ny manner contributions. authorized i n sections 401 and 4 02 o f this Act (O.c Cod e secs. 1-1161 and 1- 1162 and {Z) subsection (el (O. C. Code sec. l -ll76(e is amended by adding the following c l ause at the end the reat exceot as provi ded in section 5 03 of this Act (D· C· Co o e sec 1-1173 q Section 601 (O c Code sec J 1181) is ame naeCI as fo llows 1) subse c tion (b O c Cooe sec 1 ll!H{bl l is amenCled by add inq the following at the end tner eof Thi s subsection s hall not aff ec t a vote by a public off icial (lJ on an v matter which affec ts a class of per sons s uc h a class sha l l include no l ess thar1 fifty persons) of wh i ch such publ ic of ficial is d member if the financ i a l ga i n t o be rea lized is de mi ni mus; or ZJ on any matter relatinq to such publ i c o f fic i al s compensat ion as author i z e d by law; o r (3) regarding an y elections l a w. If an acti on i s taken by any department agency. boar d or commiss i on of the District of Columbia e xc e p t by the Counc il of tne Dist r ict -23- tnr~lled Origina~ of Columbia in vi olation or tn i s section such action may be set aside and declared void and of no effect upon a prope r order of a court of competent jurisdiction and 2) subsec tion (h i O. c Code. sec l -1 181(h is a ended by adding the follo.,ing clause bet een the ord capacity• and the period) at the end of the subsection or t o the appearance by a member of the Council (not the Chair man) licensed to practice l a w in the Distri ct of Co l umbia before any court or non-Di st rict of Co l umbi a regulato r y agency in any matte r wh ich does not af f ect his or her offici a l positi o n 3} paragrap h l of subsec ti on i D. C. Code sec l-l l 8l(i)(l is amended as foll o ws A) b y red~s i gnat i n D as El and inserting af ter it e m the follow ing clause DJ a member of the Zo11ing Commi ss ion or the Soard o f Zoninq Adj ustment anrt (8) b y aodi ng the f ollowi ng clause at the end thereof FJ and each member of a boa r d or commission who makes field dec is i ons as µrov1d e d i n paragraph {l) of subsection (bl of s~ct ion bO l (O t Code, sec. 1-1 182 b)(l)l Enrolled Original -24- {r) Section 602 (O.C. Code• sec. 1-1182) is amended as fol tows l) subsection (a O.c. Code. sec. 1-1182 (a is a.ended by striking all that follows the words •Reorganization Act and inserting the following in lieu thereof •the President and each ~e•ber of the Soard of Education. and the head of each independent and subordinate agency of the District of Columbia government• and each person paid from funds appropriated to the Office of the Mayor or to the Council of District of Columbia who occupies a position which is classified as a GS-13 or higher in the General Schedule under section 5332 of Title 5 of the United States Cod and the City Administrator, and the General Coun~el to the District of Columbia eoard of Elections and Ethics. and the Director of Campaign Finance of the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics, and the People's Counsel of the District of Columbia, and the Auditor of the District of Columbia nd each member of a board or commission who makes field decisions as provided in subsection (bl(ll of this section regardless of compensation. shall file annually, with the Board a report containing a full and complete statement of l) the name of each business entity (including sole proprietorships. partnerships and Enrolled Original -25- corporations t ransact i ng any bus i ness with the District of Col u mbi a gov e rnment (inc ludi n g any o f i t s agenc i e lt;lepart~ents b oar ds commiss i ons or educa t iona l bodies i n ~h ich such pe r son (or his o r her spouse i f propert y is j ointly titled A) has a benef i cial interest (including those held in such oe r son s o wn name in trust or in the name of a nom inee) exceed i ng in the aggr e gate s1. ooo: PROV I DED Howe ver if such interest consists of corpor a te stocks which a r e r eg istered and t rao cd upon a r ecogni zed n a tional exchange such a~gregate value must exceed S5000; o r B) earns inc ome for s er vi ces r ende red durinq a ca l endar year in excess of s1, ooo; o r Cl serves as a n officer d irecto r par t ner employee or in any other fiduciary capacity 12) any out s tanding i nd ividual li ab ility in e xcess of s1. ooo f or bor r o wing oy such per son or hi s or her spouse if such liability is JOint from a nyone other than a ~rolled Original -26- federal or state insured or regulated financial institution or a ~e~ber of such person•s immediate family J) all real property located in the District .9,f Columbia (and its actual location) in which such person or his or her spouse if such property is jointly titled• has an interest with a fair market value in excess of ss.ooo: PROVIDED. However, That this provision shall not apply to personal residences actually occupied by such person or his or her spouse 4) all professional or occupdtional licenses issued by the District of Columbia government held by such person 5) all gifts received in an agyregate value of SlOO in a calendar year by such person from any business entity (inc luding sole proprietorships. partnerships. and corporations) transacting any business with t~e District of Columbia government (including any of its agencies. departments• boards. commissions. or educational bodies and 61 an affidavit stating that the suhjP.ct candidate or off ice holder has not c~used title to property to be placed in another person or entity for purposes of avoiding the disclosure requirements of this subsection. Znrolled Original 27- For the purpose of this subsec tion. the words •immediate family• sha ll have the same meaning as in section 601 of this Ac t 0 C. Codee sec. 1-1181 The Board may by rul e. provide f o rms f or the s ubm ission of t he sta~e111ent requi r ed by this subsection in a ggregate cate9or ies. In format ion s u ppl ied pu rsuant t o thi s subsect ion shal l be modif ied by the fi l e r with in t h i r ty (30) day s of any changes t her e i n a nd fai l ure t o inform the Boa rd of su ch mod ifi cations i s deemed to be a will f ul violation of thi s filin g requi reme nt The aoar d ma y on a case b y cas e basi s p r o v ide for cert ain e xemptions to this fi l inq requ ir ement wh ich ar e deemeo t o he de minimu s b y the Boa rd 2 subsec tion (bJ (0. C. Cone s ec 1-l lBl(b is amended a s f ol l o ws A) parag raph (1) 10 c Code. sec l- ll82( b l i s repea led 8) para g r aph (2 D. c Code sec l- ll82( b 2) I i s amended b y i} s t rik ing the phr ase Confidential F inanci a l S tate ment" a nd inse rt ing i n lieu the r e of the ph rase Financial Statement as r equired by t h is s e ction i i i n subparagraph (Al addinq immediately f ollowing the word auditing the phras e o r af fecting the l eg i s l a tive process Enrolled Original -28 iii) in subparagraph (AJ striking the phrase •in paragraph (l) of this subsection• and inserting ln lieu thereof the phrase •in subsection (b) of this section iv) in subparagraph (A) striking the words •subsection, within• and inserting in lieu thereof the words •section,within v) in subparagraph (Al striking the word •paragraph" and inserting in lieu thereof the word (vi) striking out the entire subparagraph (8} vii) redesignating paragraph 2)(A as paragraph •111 and read as follows viii I adding a new paragraph 2 to 2) An individual or class of individuals may be eKempted from the filing requirements of subsection (a) of this section only upon a determination by the Soard that the duties of the individual or class of individuals do not involve decisions in areas specified in 'IJlrolled OrigiosL paragraph (1 of th •s subsection b and C) paragrapn (3 O.c. Code. sec. l ll82(b 3) l i s amended by str i king the phrase •confi~ntial Per sonal F inanc ial Disclosur e 5tate.,ent• and ins e rt ing In 1 ieu thereo f F inancial 5tate.,ent as r equ i r ed by this secti on and (3) subsection (d D Code sec l-ll8Z(d i s ame nded b y A) in serting 01 immed iate ly following Id and (B) by adding a n e w p aragraph IZ to read as f ol lows IZI Any r eport r equi r ed to be f i l ed with the Di rector fr om an empl oyee who is no longer c overed unde r t he provi sions of t his Act on September _l• 1978 sha ll be r e turne d to s uch employee or his or her r epr esentative on or befor e J anuary l• 1979 PROV IDED. However That s hou l d the Di rec tor cer tify that a ny r outine audit or a n i nvestigation concerning compliance wi th the provision~ of thi s Ac t is currently under way s uch reports shall not be re turned to suc h emp loyees except a s otherwise provided in thi s sec tion Enrolled Original -30 s) Section 701 (O.C. Code. sec. 1-1191) is amended Dy adding a new subsection to read as follows fl All actions of the Board or of the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia to enforce the provisions of this Act must be initiated within three (3) years of the actual occurrence of the alleged violation of the Act Sec. 4. Section 2 of the Act entitled "An Act to fix and regulate the salaries of teachers. school officers and other employees of the board of education of the District of Columbia approved June 20, 1906 (34 Stat. 316; o.c. Code sec. 31-10l(b)(3 is amended by striking the phrase including any runoff election Sec. 5. Should a court declare any provision of this act to be beyond the authority of the Council of the District of Columbia or unconstitutional in a 0 y part. such court shall declare such provision to De severed and of no effect. Sec. 6. This act shdll take effect as provided for acts of the Council in section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act: PRDVTOED. However. That the amendments effected Dy sections l(j)(2 3(a b C d e f 9 kl 1 m Enrolled Orig~nel -31 n o Pl Q and (s) of thi s act shall not become effective until January z, 1979 Ooei:et No: Bill No. 2 2.18 5-2.-78 0 VOlCE VOTE: Secz•DLJ"Y to th. Coundl ,x; aou. CAW. VOTE: t c I II I amp lt;•vfltCD C c•l 11.1"C I J 4 c.ot.1.-eui cM• il'.Jll I •n J a.T 1 1 l'UCKO. IX I MASON IX I I s A O'UI Ii'IO I A I I i:LA.R.D Ix MOORE. o. I x v;tISON X I I JIAJUl.Y Ix l MOO.RI, 1. IX WIN x I I Cl..\.'UCZ l Iv ltOLA..I\ 1 x I I ooco Iv I I S ACKlZ'lCNIX I I I I 'X-JN" C V.W 4 I lt. Y f•l V:a:daof '\..Al.l t-171.i .ltl Ameucied First lieadJ.ni Accion: l I VOICE VOTE: Sec:rea.ry to. the Co~c.U I I ROLL CALL VOTE: Cll'\&amp;amp;,llOlca n I I a f CJll' I A" f I I If c u 1 1 TUC i I I I 4 MASON I I I lfS?AIT JINO I I I i !UP..Cl'f I I I I MCORZ. o. I I I f'&amp;lt SON I I I i I Meo 1. I I· DIXON Secr·eta:y to die Council Fi.-1 Re lt;llnf rs..ru:r A&amp;lt;:tio s 1_6 7 8 J VOICE VOTE: Rolark, DMoore Clarke) ff ROLL CALL VOTE C..v CU C amp;A rC t I ¢.:kP&amp;lt;o I c 1 I C.'3"-c f ate I t TUCXZ I I I IW SON I I l I p \.U 11 IO I I I I I P..A_O y I I I 0 MOO.:U O. I I I I (WILSON I I I I I BNL Y I I I I ·a MOOl\£ 1. I I I I I ~W'!Nm. I I I I I cLA lt;c I I I I Q ROW r I I I I I I I DIXON t I I I j lt;e JN l I I I i I I I I I X'-Cad.ia v 1 z Ja H v f• t I Se ct'eta.ry to tb.e Cou:udl I a.ECOllll&amp;gt; OF 0.FFICli.A.L C OWlSIClr.L amp;C1!110:0 P.g• 2) Docket No: Bill No. 2-218 JUN 1 1978 1 &amp;amp; JUN 1978 Action of the M.avo:r provwd: Q Diu.ppravod; I I DhaJ ro¥ed U. pa.rt gt;R.o!erenco Docum u B qet Ac-ti o LI Rotunootd Wlthout Action b.ecu.tive S• c.ree&amp;amp;ry. 0. C cted without ~yor Slgna.1:1ne Socreta.ry to the Council Council :le-ena ccrr..e t; I I VOICE VOT Secreta.rr to tile Council L I ROLL C.U.L VOU ca""c MUt I I T I 11 v. I ic C:2v c1.1 E t I l'l•&amp;lt;r I I i covtt amp;i cA H I I I TtrC.U:R l l I l .i MASON I I a RDY I I I I MOORZ. D. l I I BA 1.RY I I I I II MOOIU J I CLA K I l I I .\ ROLA lt; I i DIXON I I I I II Si-'C!CZTON I I Z•1Ua1 el A. 3 U.-c: P:-csente d to the PTeaidetlt: Action o! the ?rct"ide nt: I I Reen&amp;amp;ct:z::1ent Approv~d LI M&amp;amp;y o:r1 1 Ve to So.s b.i:ie d Subt:"\ittec o the Coni'J'•SJ Scn&amp;amp;te Actton Resolution Number Zn.a.cte&amp;lt WitJi.o\ t Con ea:siona.l A--c:~on D. C. Liw No. Wectlve O&amp;amp;te I I ISP AU lD&amp;gt;"G I I I i I r awu.so~ l t I j I I lf1V1N I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I H. V-'f•.I V 7 Sec: r•ta. ry to the Council ru idet&amp;gt;t o! t:;e tr. S. See-reti.:y t o tbe Council Hou..s e Actioci Resolution. Number Cleric. oi :he Hou.sc Se cre~ry to ~e Cow:i.cU l S JUN 1978</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
