<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-107">
  <num type="law">2-107</num>
  <heading type="short">Criminal Justice Supervisory Board Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-09-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-107.pdf">D.C. Law 2-107</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1391</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-107, the “Criminal Justice Supervisory Board Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-211, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, and second readings on May 16, 1978, May 30, 1978, and June 13, 1978, respectively. There being no action by the Mayor, it was assigned Act No. 2-222 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTlUCT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. La.w 2.-107 Criminal Justice Supervisory Board Ac t of 1978 Pur suant to Section 412 oI the District oi Coluinbia Self- Coven:u:nent a.nd Cove=enta.l R eorgani ation Act, F t 93-198 the Act the Council o! the District o! ColLimbia adopted Bill No, 2-Zll, on first, a.mended fir st, and second readings May 16, 1978 May 30 1978 and Ju.ne 13, 1978, respectively. Following expiration of tb.e ten- day review period provided the Mayor pLlr~uant to Section 404 (el &amp;lt;?£ tb.e Ac t No 2-2.ZZ pL1blished in the August 11, 1978, edid.011 of the D. C. R egiste r and t::uurmitte d to both HoLlses o£ Congress for a 30- day review, in acco r dance with Section 6CZ (c 1) of the Act, The C oll?lcil of the Oist:-ict of Columbia le:eby gives notice t.!lat t!le 30-day Congressional review period has expi ed and, therefore, cite s the following legislation as D. C Law 2 107, ef!ective Se ptember 13, 1978, k~L-1 STE.RLIN'G UCKER Chairman of the Council (Vol. 2.5 No. 6, D. C. Regist t39t, August U, 1978 c o.c Law !N THE COU~C[ L OF THE O !ST~I CT OF COLUMS To astaolisn a criminal justice state planning agency for administering f ederal grant fun a s pursuant to tne o~ni ou s Cri~e Contr ol and Safe St r e ets Act of l06 and f o r oenar pu rposes. ae I T E~ACiEO 8Y THE COUNCIL OF r~e orSTRICT OF C0LUMatl. Tnat en is act may oa ci ted as t e r imina l Justice Sup~rvi sary ~oard Act of 1978 For tne ourooses of t ni s act a Board eans the Criminal Justice Supervisory Soar d establi s hed under secti on 4 0) of tnis act O Cri~e Cont rol Ac t eans th e Omniou~ Cri me Cont r ol ana SaFe Streets Ac t o f 1066 app roved June 19• 196 8 2 Stat 11 7 z u. s. c. 37 0 t c J?C• ne~ns tne J udi ci al Plann i ni Committee estaclisned pursuant to section Z03(C) of the Cri ne Control Act of 1976, aporovea Octooer 15 197 90 Stat 2407 z u.s.c. 372 1 Juvenil e Jus•ice •c t means tne Juve nile Just ice ana Oel inquency Pre ~en ~i on ~ct ?f 19 7 a oorovec S•otemoe r c 2- {e) RQCJPA• means tne Of f i ce of Cr i~i na l Justice P l a ns and Analysis establlsned pursuant to section~ of th i s act f Youtn• means a person wno nas not reacned· the age of twenty-one 21) years gJ •sen ior citizen~ means any cerson wno nas reached tne aqe of sixty {~0) years. Tne Counci l of tne Oist r ict of Columbia f inds and oec I ares tnift a) crime and delinquency are complex soci3l pnenomena requir ing t~e attention and efforts of the criminal justice sys tem local government and private citizens alike b l the establisnment of approoriate goals ob j ectives and sta ndards for tne reduct ion of crime and delinquency and for tne ad~inist ration of just ice must oe a priori ty concer n CJ the functions of tne cr i mi nal jus t i ca system must oe coordinated more efficiently and effect i vely d the full and effect ive use of resources affect i ng loca l cr i i nat justice syste~s requires t ne compl ete cooperat i on of local government agencies; and (e) training. rese~rcho ev a luation. tecnn ical ass is t ance and pu~lic ecucation ac~ i vities ~us~ be c iro l! ec. 0 igi.cal 3- enc ouraged and focused on the impr ovement of t h e criminal just ice system and the generation of ne ethods f o r the prevention a nd reduction of crime and delinque nc y Sec 4. Cr i minal Justice Suoervil2ry Soard. and Office of Cri ~l_dy,,seice P l ans anc: t.na l ys is j Membe~sh iQj Sta ff 1aJ There is nereoy estaolisne~ witni n tne Execut i ve Branen of ~he Ois tric~ of Col umoia ;overnment a Cr i minal Justice Supervisory Soard wn i c n Sha l l ser~e as the l aw enforcement and criminal just ice p lann i ng agency for tne Distri c t of Columoia in accordance wi t n the t e rms of tne C.ricne Co11tro1 Act Tnere is al so ner•by ~reated an Office of Crim i n Justice Plans and t.nalys i s wh i ch shall serve as the staff of t he Board o) Tne Cri minal Justice Supervisory Soaro snall consist of forty (40) memoers. as follows l J U1e Mayor i (2) ene C~airman of the Council of tne Oistr ict of Columoia 3) the Chi ef Judge of tne Oi str i ct of Col umoi a Court of Appeals 4) t ne Chief Judge of t he Supe ri or Court of t he Distr i ct of Co l umoia 5) the Corporat ion Counsel of tne O is~ rict of Columb i a: Cb the C~air~erson of ene Committee on tne Juoiciary of the Co~ncil of the District o f l Columola 7) the Executive Officer of the Oistrict of Columt&amp;gt;ia Courts 8) five (5) persons appointed by the Mayor I q I (10 ll 12 l 3) { l gt; l c l 5 I (lo 17 I l 81 (19 20) from a list of no less than fifteen (151 nominees suomittad oy the Chief Judge of th~ District of Columoia Court of Apoeals; the United States Attorney for the District of Columoia (if ne oesires to serve the Chief of tne Metroool itan Pol ice Department; the Director of the Department of ~uman ~esources; t he Oirector of the ~ayor s Office of 8u~get and ~anagement Systems; tne Director of the Off i ce of Youtn Advocacy; the Director of the ~istrict of Columbia Oeoar tment of Corrections; the Director of the Oistrict of Columoia Puolic Oefenoer ~ervice; tne Director of tne Oistrict of Columoia Sail Agency; the Chairperson of tne District of Columoia 3oaro of Parole; the Director of the vi strict of Columbia Municipal Planning Offi c e; the Chairperson of the Ois~rict of Columoia Commission on tne Status of ~o~en; the Chairperson of the s;a~e aovisory grou p of the Ci strict of Columoia es aol isneo pursuant to section 223 of tne Juvenile ·Justice -let c z l zz 23 l 5- four C4J memoers of tne state advisory g r oup of the District of Columbia established pursuant t o section 223 of t ne Juvenile Justice Act PROV! OEO That the four 4} memo4rs other tnan t ne Cha irp•rson of s uch state aav i sory group. shall be chosen o y a major.-i ty of t he memoers of such state adv isory g r oup and tnree (3) of tne ~our (4) chosen memoers shall not be employe•s of t he Ol str ic:t of Columb i a government; five (5) persons appointed by the Mayor: PRcvcDeo Tnat sucn oersons snall not oe employed by tne District of Col umbia gQve rnment• one (ll of wnom snall De a youtn ana e•o (ZJ of w~om s ha ll ~e sen ior cltiiens; four (4) p~rsons aopointed oy the Chairman of the Council of t he Distr ict of Columb ia w• th the consent of tne Council PROvIOE Tha t s uch person s shall no t oe e mployed by tne District of Columoia government. one (ll of whom shall oe a youth and one l J of hom s ha 1 1 be a s•nior c i tizen; ana {24) three (3) persons apooi n t.eo DY the Chairperson of t.he Commi ttee on t ne Judiciary of tne Council of the District of Columbia wich the cons ent of t.ne Com~it t.ee PROVIO£o Tnat sucn persons s nai l not. De emoloyed by t.he Oist.rlc t of Columoia government. one (l) o f wno m sr.al l be a yout.n a nd one (lJ of whom s nall oe a senior cit i zen Cl ~n alte~nate of a memoer of t h e aoare ma y oe des ignated by each member: P~ovtoeo. That suc h aes i9n at.l on shall oe in writi ng and wi th resoect t.o 3 member who serves on t he ao·ard oy virtue of an off i i:e in t.he governme nt. of t.he Oist~ict of Columbi a, an a lternate shall oe a r anking sooorainate of the memaer In th e event t r.at a non government member• apoointed oursuant to paragraphs (21) tnrougn 24) of section 4(b) of th i s ~t• i s aosent from three (ll consecutive meetings of the aoard or any of its committees or subcommittees. the Chairperson of the Soard snall reQues t tnat tne "ayo~ of tne Di str ict of Co l ~moia (nere inafter re ferred to as t~e avor l• tne Cna i rman of t ne Counc i l, the Cnairperson of the Comm i ttee on the Judi c iary of tne Council or tne state advisory group estaol ishea pursuant to section 223 of the Juvenile Justice Act as tne case may oe. rep l ace sucn a 0 po intea me moer d) Members ser ving pursuant to paragraphs (Zl) through (24) of section 4(0) sna l l serve for two (ZJ ~ear ter~s ano may!&amp;gt;&amp;lt reappointed for no more than one (l) aad i tional consecutive term ember s servin~ pursuant to paragrapn (SJ of secti o n 4(0) sna i l serve at tna ~leasu ra of the Cnief Juage of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals. The terms of all otner members snail oe concurr e nt with their s ervice i n t ne o f f i ce from ~nich t hey aer i ve ~he i r memoersnip e) Snould any memoer cease to ~e an officer o f tne unit or agency of government wni cn ne is aopointed to repr esent nis memoersnio on tne Crim i nal Justice Superv iso ry Board shall t e rm inat~ immeaiately ano a new -7- memoer shall be appointed in the same manner as his p redecessor to fill the unexpired term. vacancies occuring in meQbersnips created by items (8) and (Z2 tnrougn (24) of subsection Cb) of tnis section. except tnose oy the expiration of a term. snall be filled for tne Oal~nce of the unexpi reo ter m in t ne same ~anner as t ne origina l appointment within thirty (30) ctays of tne vacancy fl Tne ~ayor shal l appoint a chairpers o n of the Criminal Just i ce Suoervisory Soard vice-chairperson shall oe selected by tne Board from among its members c (9) A memoer of the Soar~ is not e nti t led to a s~lary for duties performed as a r.emoer of tne Soaro. Eacn memoer is entitleo to reimoursement For travel and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of official Soard duties n) The Mayor snatl appoint an executive airector of t~e Of Fice of Crimina l Justice Plans and ~nalvsis wno sna11 serve at tne pleasure of t~e ~ayor an~ wno snall oe paio sucn compensation as the Mayor may determine. The executive director may em?loy sucn oersonnel and contract for sucn consulting services. as may ~e necessary. to carry ouc tne our~oses of enis act and for wnicn sufficient appropriation l lrolled Oris~~a.J 8- Sec s a) The Criminal Justice Supervisory Soard shall meet at least once every ninety (90) days and at such otnei times designated by the chairperson or a majority of t~e 3oard D) 4 simple major i ty of tne memoersn i p shall constltut2 a auo~um for tne Cr i minal Just i ce Supervisory Board ano f.or its committees or subcommitte~s Cl [n its developing and administering an annual comprenensive criminal j ustice olan f~r t ne Ci strict of Columoi tne Soard snall establisn committees or subcommittees comori~ed of memcers of tne Board ana sucn other persons as t he Soard deems advisaole and feasible. The 3oaro snall also ~eterm ine th• cnairp~rson for eacn com~ittee. Tne committee structure of the 3oard snall i nclude but not be limiteo to 11 a committee on tne courts comprised of the JPC ano oesigneo to carry out t~e purposes of section 203 of tne Crime Control Act 2) a committee on juvenile justice c~mprlseo of the state adviso r y group of tne Oistrict of Columoia estaclisneo pursuan~ to section 223 of tne Juveni l e Jus~ice Act and oeslgned to develop tr.e juvenil~ justice component l:irollec or!gi:a.l 9- of the annual comprenensive criminal justice plan in ac~oraance with tne Juvenile Justice Act: and (3) an appeals committee design~d to consioer appeals from any action of tne Soard ~enying all o r part of any funds requeste~ in any s uogrant app li cation to conouct a pro ject f or wnicn fun ds are availaole d) Exceot for a committee on tne courts and a commicce~ on juvenile justice eacn co~mittee of the 8oaro s nail contain l } at least one (l memoe r from or aopo inted Dy tne Executive sranch of the Ois~rict of ·c Columoia government 2) at least one (ll memoer from or appoint~d oy tne Council of tne Di strict of Columoia; C3J at l east one (l) memoer from the District of Columoia courts: and J a suff icient number of members who are no t emoloyed b y t he Dis trict of Columoi.a government to comprise ~t l~ast one-third (l/31 of tne total memoersnip of tne committee or suocommittee n tne event tnat an execut i ve comm i ttee is est~olis ned by cne aoard such executive committee snail inclu~e in ies membership the same proportion of memoers represent ing tne judiciary and memoers representing tne juvenil e justice aovisory group as the total number of eac n s uc h cla~s of memoers bears to the cecal me moersni p of t he aoa ro c 10 e) Suoject to the provisions of paragrapns (l 2) and (J) of subsection (c) of th is sect i on. t he 3oaro snall ensure that• prior to the adop~ion by the Board of an annual comprehensive criminal justi ce plan. it shall have received and considered recommendations from at least one Cl) of i ts committees or su~committees witn resoect co what ought to oe tne contents of t~e plan concerning l) c~e admin i stration of justi ce 2) tne prevention of cri~e 3) detection of crime and apprenension of offenoers 4) prosecution ano o•fense; and (5) sencenci~g and correctional treatment of offenders. In adj ltion the Soard shall ensure that, prior to its making grant awards in accordance wi th an" approved annual comprehensive criminal justice plan. the Board sna11 nave received and cons idered recommenda t ions from at least one (ll of i ts committe e s or suocommittees i th respect to all potential suogrant award recipients wno Qualify in accordance with tne Soara•s rules and ~roceaures governinq suogrant award fl The Board snail promulgaie rules of procedure 94vernin9 its operations which comply witn ~ne Oistr ict of Columoia Adm in i strative Procedure Acc. approved October 21• 1q6e {82 Stat. 120 o .c. Code, sec 1-1501 et sec and 11- wi tn tne Advisory Neighoor~ood Commissions Act of 1975• e f fect i ve October to 1975 (O.c. Law t-Zll· Sec amp wers a Q_Qutie Tne Board snall a) advi$e and assist the ~ayor. the Oistrict of Columoia Courts and tne Council of the District of Columoia in develooing policies Jans programs and ouagets for improving the eooroination9 administration and effectiveness of the. criminal justice system in t~e Oi strict of Columoia OJ approve all components of tne annual comprehensive criminal justice clan preoared pursuant to the Crime Con~rol Act ano submit sucn plan to the Council of the District oF Columbia for its advisory review of the goals. priorities and policies conta ined therein prior to tne ultimate sub~iS$iQn of sucn plan to the Law Enforc~ment Assistance adminis t ra t ion U~ited States Oeoartment of Justice c) include in each annual comprehensi ve criminal justice plan a statement of the fiscal impact each component of s uch p lan would likely have if any. on tne fiscal budget of the District of Columbia for the next five (51 years OJ assure the participation of ci~izens community organizations and juven il e justi c e aovocates at a ll levels of t~e planning process l e) recommend 9oals. priorities and standards for the reduction of crime and tne improvement of tne administration of justice in tne District of Columbia: {fl recommend criminal justice legislation to the Mayor. the Council of the District of Columoia and tne Congress• wnere aopropriate g) ensure that tne annual judicial plan developed by tne JPC is imolemented to the extent that it ls in conformity with tne comprehensive plan .for the i~provement of law enforcement and criminal justice in accordance witn section 304(bl of the Crime Control Act h encourage local and regional comprehensive criminal justice planning efforts i) men i tor ·and e·va 1 uate programs and projects. funded in wnole or in part oy the District of Columbia government. aimed at reducing crime and delinquency and improving the administration of justice j) cooperate witn and render technical assistance to agencies and units of the Cistrict of Columoia government• and puolic or private agencies relating to the criminal justice system kl have the authority to collect from any Oistrict of Colum~ia governmental entity information. data• reoorts 13- statist i cs or sucn otner ma ter i al wn1cn is n ecessary to carr y out t n e functions of tne Office of Cr imi nal Just i c e ~1ans and Ana lysi s c onsistent with the Olstrict of Columoia Sel f-Govern~ent and Governmental ~eorganization Act: a n d perform such other duti es as may Oe necessary to c arr y out t ne pur poses of this a ct. Sec 7 Reoorts a) W i t~ in n i nety (90) Gays of the c l ose of e ach f i scal year. tne Cr i minal Justice Supervisory Boa r d s Mall s uomit a n annual r eport to the ~ayor and to tne Counci'l of the ·c Oistric t of Columoi a concerning its wor during tne preced ing fiscal year O} The OCJPA through the Soard may suomi t otner studi es evaluations. cr i me data anal~ses and r eports to the Mayor or t he Council of t ne Oistrict of Columbia as deemed appropriate or as reovested Oy t he ~ayor o r the Council. f n ere a re ne r eoy au~nori zeo to oe aporopriated s uch funds as may oe neces s ary for the aoministration of t n;s act In 4ddition. the Mayo r shall reor ogram and transfer t o the Of f i ce of Cri minal Justice Plans an naly~is. as c~nstituted b y th i s act. any and a ll ~roperty records and unex~ected val anc es of aporopriated f una s f~r t h e Office of l 011ea Orig!~a.l 14- Criminal Justice Plans and Ana lys is as created by Mayor's Orders 77-52 A and s. Mayor•s Orders 77-52, effective April l. 1977. 77-52A• effect,,ive Ariril 19• lq77, 77-52i\. effective May l7• 1977, ihis aet snall take effect pursuant. to t.ne provisions of section 602(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Self- Government. ano Governmental Reorganization Act i:oc.Mc Na: aIU. 2 Zll s s 16 s Adopted U~a nlmot s y (A s D Moor e rvC I 1 1 I I Pl c.Jll¥*Cht I 1 I t 1 I c:&amp;lt;Q::a, i J I I :I MASCN I \ :t?:l.l ° o I ii.I I I I i.&amp;lt;co lt;u I I 1 ON I I I 1 I I I I I 1 oc rt lt;l.u.~1 AC i•i: 5- 30- 78 {!j v cICZ vo~z, Acopted Unanimous ly (All Pre.sent ii -r t-:r~ r; fl-?J S S t&amp;lt;&amp;gt tl:i lt J_,I t r:.u..t. vo:z I MASON 1.&amp;gt;LCCU, 6. J If MCC1 J. I 1 l 6 13 78 Ado:ited tlnani.r.,ously Abs Barry f Moore la 71U-v, { f S•e&amp;lt;eca 1 f C;a;t;o.•C2 c c m c I I l ~c C!ci i f \ I ioc:l&amp;lt;e• Na SILL Z-Zll /{.t;t..U 7 i µ -s c e r_c_o C \ c 1 he11.eby c.e-t.ti I .tha.z Cou.nc.U S.i.Ll Z- 2 1 1 wa.4 p:i.e4 e.11zed .to .the Ma.If oil o Che O.i.4.t·t-lc.t: 06 co.e.1.1.mb.la. O l'l Ju.11e 21, ]978 (Utd lia..t .the Ma.qo.t l'le.i.t:hett. a.pp11.oved 110.t d..i.4a.pp11.oved .the b-ltl w..i..th..i.1t .the .te11 d.a.y pe.t..i.od 4pec.-l6.i.e.d i11 Sec.t.i.on 404(eJ 06 .the. 0.U.tll..i.c.C 06 Co l u.mbia. Stl6·Gove.11.11me.n.c a.nd Gove t nmen.tal. Reo1tga.11.lz!Ltion Ac.t, Pu.blic La.w 9J-19j 06 O~ctmbl!Jl 'l4, l'i73 A~c t a•!C1 Q M A lt;i S ate c c eJ1 olc neai t.a o t s \ Rous e i </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-901"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-902"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-903"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-904"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-905"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-906"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-907"/>
  </section>
</document>
