<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-109">
  <num type="law">2-109</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Commission for Women Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-09-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-109.pdf">D.C. Law 2-109</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1456</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-109, the “District of Columbia Commission for Women Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-236, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 30, 1978, and June 13, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 13, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-230 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. Law 2- 109 District of Columbia CotIUTlisaion for Women Act of 1978 Pursuant to Section 12 of the Dis trict o! Columbia Self- Government and Govenunental Reorganization :Ac t P L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District o! Colwnbia adopted Bill No. 2-236 on first Uld second readings May 30, 1978 and June 13 1978, respectively. Following the ll ignature of the Mayor on July 13, 1978, t.'lls legislation was ass i gned Act No. Z-230, published in the August 11, 1978, edition of the D. C. Register and tra.nsrnitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c l of the Act, The Council of the District o! Colu:mbia hereby g ives n o tice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period ha..s expir "d and, therefor e, cites the !ollowing legislation as D. C Law 2-109, effective Septernber 22 1978 l 1 AT~UCKER cr c the Council {Vol. 25, D. C. Register, 1'456, August 11, 1978 o. c. La 4 IS THE COU NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establisn the District of Columbia Co~mission for Women. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COU~CIL OF THE DISTRlCT OF COLUMBIA, That t n is act •av be cited as the District of Columbia Co•mission for women Act of 1978 Sec 2 State~ent of Purpose. It is the purpose of this act to support programs directad to a r d evaluating and proving tne status of omen in the District of Columbia by establishing tne Commiss i on for women. Sec 3. EstablisnMent of the Commission a) There is nereby establi shed i n the District of ColUMbia a ComMlssion for Women {herei nafte r r eferred to as the •com~ission The CoMmission snail be composed o f twenty-oni (tlJ ae•bers appointed b y tne Mayor of the District of Colu• bia (hereinafter referred to as the •Mayor wi th the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia (hereinafter referred to as the council from among tne resioents of the District of Colulllt&amp;gt;ia with e~perience in the areas of publi c affairs and i nrolled Origioal -2- issues of particular interest and concern to women. represent~tive by 9eo9raphic area and reflective by race and age of the population of the District of Columbia. The Co1mission shall be the successor to the Commission on tne Status of women established by Organization Order No. 38, Commissioner's Order No. 73-94a~ effective April 24• 1973 (hereinafter referred to as the •commission on the Status of (bl Memoers of the Commission shall be appointed to serve terms of three (3) years and shall serve until their successors are appointed. The present members of the Commission on the Status of women shall be members of the Commission established by this act f~r the remainder of their current terms. A member of the Commission may be reappointed but may serve no more tnan two IZ) consecutiv~ full ter~s. Tenure on the Commission on the Status of women shall count toward the consecutive two (2) full term limit on the Commission C) Whenever a vacancy occurs on the Commission. the ~ayor. with the advice and consent of the Council, shall, within ninety {90) working days of such vacancy• appoint a successor to fill the unexpired portion of the term nroll ed Or!ginal -3 d) The Mayor shall designate from among the members appo inte~ to the Commission, the chairperson who shall serve in that capac ity at the pleasure of the Mayor e) All •e•bers of the Commission shall serve wi thout compensation: EXCEPT. That expenses incurred by the Commission as a whole or by its ind ivi dual membe r s whe n duly authorized snall become an obl i gation against appr op riated District of Columbia funds designated for that purpose fl The Mayor av remove, after notice and hearinq. any ember of the Co•mission for neg lect o f duty• incompetence. ni sconduct or •al feasance in off ice. Sec 4. Powers of the Commission a) The Commission shall conduct studies. rev iew progress, develop, r ecommend and undertake action and i nit iate and conduct p r ograms In ar eas i nc l uding but not l imited to. the following 1) e limination of disc rimination based on se• and eli mi nation of sex role s tereotyping and bias 2) public and private employnaent practices. includinq •atters pertaining to hours, wages ana wor ki ng conditions 3) education 4 1 equality of rights and responsib il ities of en ana °nen under the law Zrlrolled Orig!~al 5) new and expanded services for women to facilitate their opt•mal functioning as homemakers. wage-earners and ~citizens. including ~ental and physical health care. and the iaprovement of facilities for child care and youth development bl The Commission is authorized to apply for and receive grants to fund its program activities in accordance with procedures relating to grants management cl The Commission may accept private gifts and donations to carry out the purposes of tnis act d) The Co~mission shall stiMulate and encourage study and review of the status of wo~en and may act as a clearinghouse for activities in the Oist rict of Columbia. Sec. 5. Administrat ion a) The Co~mission shall appoint an executive director wno shall be the chief administrative officer of the Commission. The executive director shall report regularly to the Commission on staff activities. The executive director shall receive annual rate of compensation fixed in accordance with chapter Sl of Title 5 of the United States Code bl Additional staff service for the Commission shall be supplied in accordance with positions and funding approved in the Oistrict of Columoia budget 5 C) The Commission is autho rize d to estaDlish rules and procedure6 for the conduct of its Dusiness including the ,election of officers other than the chairperson. as it deems necessary d Tne Com• ission shall submit to the Mayo r annual reports of its activ ities and the work carried on under it s di rection Sec 6. Repealer and Continuation Organizat ion Or der ~o. 38• commissioner•s Order ~o. 73- 94a• effective April 24• 1973• is hereDy repealed and the Commission on the Status of Women establ ished pursuant to that Or d er is aoolished All personnel. property and records of and unexp ended balances of appropriations and other mone y availaol e to tne Commission on tne Status of Women are transferred to the Commisson establ ished pu rsuant to this ac t Sec 1 Effective Oate fhis act shall take effect as provided for acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 602(c) {l) of the District of Col u•bla Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act Doclco: No: BUI Z-236 JUN 1\ A o Ybv or: I I A IJ7I ~i I I 01.sap;i~o•ed Q DiJa.pproved iA p~=t Ae!e::e:i.ce Oocu \e~t B tset .AJo:o Ex.acu ive s u.t.a y o. c i c:tad wiQou.t tay or' s Sis~t gt;n S• c e&amp;amp y lo le Co=dl LI vo1c von I I ilO.t.I. C.U von c c 111 I l I 4 cau ci u I ir I I a lt;I c ooei c I •Tt 1 t ~UC I I I I I I.SON I I I I qS?A lii..D:.Xc; I I I E I I I 1 q MCO gt I I I I 'w~o~ I I I .3.A l.·y I I I I MCO.RZ I I I I I I I I I c I I I I a ~oi \ I I I I I I I I I I C!XOiS I I I I S.'4:ZCZ q I l I I I I I I :z t 7•.t L v fa J:Y Action t ~e e,i4er l L I :R mtnt A;&amp;gt gt;r11Ved LJ 'M&amp;amp;yr Vee&amp;lt;&amp;gt; s sta.i=ed amp;Ei t'iJ' Seo::ecu-y co tho Cow:cil 11 e Acc!oa 11..u oluticm Nwr.ber u Dowt No: Bill 2- 236 l'!z•t llar.di.:C Ac:ien: May 30, 19 78 171 voxcz van Adopted Unanimously (All Present 4 µ S;cata y to :ha Cou l I I I.OU. CAl VOTE C itcL i t f t I a.II c•1i1 f I I u Uw.•cn u 1 •TY 1 1 1 Ti;C:X:U. r I I I i MASON I I I I Si'AO c; J I J l I AAllY l I I I I lo&amp;lt;COl'.£. D. I I I I 1\U.SON I I I I I .11.4..L'lY r I I l ccoiu I I I I WIN I I I i c~ J I I I OU lt I I I I I I I l)J:tcz.&amp;lt; l I I I 5 AC:&amp;lt;!Z lNI I I I ,j I I I I I J Or4ke 1 &amp;gt 1 t. T V •cat I I I VOIC:C VOTZ: If llOU c..\!;i. VOTI a l •f"t' l l 4 -It I •Y'T I i j amp L U••C I I l I I a T°:lC-A a I I I I I MASO!&amp;lt; I I l I AtJLZCi(j I I I I I A.ul.:l 't I I I I J ~ccaz o. I I I P't.l..SCN I I A.U~ I I I I f l.&amp;lt;COU I I 1 l IV l':Z..i. I J I I c n I I i I lOU e I I l .l I l l t I tlet~N t I I I I £ r I I I I I I I I I 1 1. y_y I 1'lzlal A•a 11.q or ~1 Acti June 13, 1978 [Jj YQICJ; VOT:I Adopted Unanimously (2 Abs Barry, T. Moore /iiiHr~'1 I I aou c..u.L &amp;lt;on u J I J 1 -4 I a TtTC:la3. I I I I !MASON I I I I ;iSP At Ol lC I I I H A q J 'r I I I l 4Mooaz. o. I I I ~\VU.SON I I I I I U I l I I \ WCOA l r I l s z I l I I I CU3 v I I I I 3 I I I I 4 I I I l DCC ON I I I I l S.-C N f I I l I I I r a gt I tt r 7 11..C.:4" I</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-701"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-702"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-703"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§3-704"/>
  </section>
</document>
