<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-114">
  <num type="law">2-114</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Consumer Transmission of Money Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-10-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-114.pdf">D.C. Law 2-114</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1985</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-114, the “District of Columbia Consumer Transmission of Money Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-210, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 13, 1978 and June 27, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 21, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-242 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA QTtCE D. C. La.w 2-114 "District of Col umbia. Consumer Traosmis sion of Money A&amp;lt;:t of 1978" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Colurnoia Sel Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. P L 93- 198 the Act the Council of the District of C.&amp;gt;lurr.b ia adopted Bill No. 2-2 10, on first and second readL~s June 13, 1978 and J11ne 27, l97a, respecti ely. Following t.'le signature of t.i..e Mayor on July 21 1978, chis legislation wa.s as signed Ac t Na. 2-242, publhhed i:l th.e August 25. 1978, edition of the D. C. Register VoL 25, page 1985) and transmitted to Congress fo= a JO-day r eview, in acco rdance with Section 602 {c l of the Act ie Cou:tcil of the Oist=ict of Columbia e reby gives notice t lat the 30 day Congressional Review Pe riod has expired, a nc, therefore, cites the iollowi!lg legisla tion as D C Law 2-114, effective October 5, 1978 1 ev J STERLL'\i T-C:CKER Chairman oi t.'i e CoU:&amp;gt;cil Dates Caur..ted During the 30-0av Congressional Review Period: Ai GUST 7 8, 9, 10, U, 14, 15, t6, 17 SEPTE..vlBER 6 7, 8, 11, l2 13, 14, 15, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 25, 26, 2 7, 28, 29 OCTO.BER 2 I J, 4 Ldw 2-114 £~ THE COUNC IL J F THE DISTRICT ~F CQLUMSfA Jctooer 4 1978 To pr ovi de for the licensin9 by the District of Columb ia of t he ous iness of selling issui ng or j el i verinq che c ks 1rdfts and money oraers as a service o r f o r 3 fee o r otner cons ioer d tion in tne Distri c t of Columbia a nd for other ourpose s BE I T ENACTEJ 3Y THE C JU~Cll CF THE o rs T~ l CT OF :OLU~6[A Tna t thi s act nay be cited as the Dis trict o f Columoi a :onsumer Trans"1 ission of ~oney Act of 1976 OEF!N tTI JNS Sec. z. For the purpos e of tn is 3c t a I t r.e ter11 ned&amp;lt means a ny c eel l r aft 1oney orje r pe rsona l money or~er o r otne r i nstrument for t he t r ansmissi on or payment of money otne r than a traveler s c.hec!&amp;lt b) tne term de l i ver• means to transfer pos sessi on of a neck to tnep first person no in ~ayment for same maKes or ourport s t~ na~e a remittance ~f or against the f ace anoun t thereof ~ne tner or not the de l i veror a lso ch a rges a f ee in oaoi t ion to t he face a 'lloOJnt and het'ler or no t the deli•1aror signs tn e check lrolled Or!gi:ial z (c) the term li censee" means a person duly l icensed b y the Mayor unoer th i s act d) t he term "Hayor" means t he Mayor of t he District of Colu~bia or his designee e) the term •person• means any indivi dual, partnership association, joint stock associati on t rust or corpora t ion but does not inc lude t he United States government the government of tne District o f Columoia or the united States Postal Servi ce fl tne term persona l money order means any instrument fo r the transmission or pa yme nt of money wn i cn Is signed by the pur chaser or r emi tter whether or not he appoints tne seller of the money o r der as his agent for the receipt t rans~ission or handling of money and whether or not such instrument is also si gn·ed by some othe r person in addition to tne purchaser or remitter 9) t he term setl me ans t o s e ll to issue or to de l I ver a check. Enrolled or:g:na! 3 LICE~SE RE QU !R:C Sec J o Person e~cept t~ ase specificJlly e•emDted in sec ti on of t~ i s ~c t or anents of a I ·c n see dS pro e section 11 of t ni s act snall en~a;e in th~ ousi nes s of selling cnec ~s 35 a s~r vi ce o r for a fee or o c n~r cc,nsi1~ ration in t11e :Ji tr i ct of Columoi a i thou c navi n 9 f ir s: Jot a in ed al icense unde r c"e provisions a f tni s acc chis ac may c ontinue to engag~ tna re in ithovt a 1 icenSd inti 1 tna ~avor 'ia acte&amp;lt;l upon hi a.ipl icati gt;n for~ s i~t y u) c~ys a fter t h e effect e of er. is act ist ri c t o f :c 1~~ci a or dutnor~z~d t~ JO Ous lnes s •n t,u J is tr•ct o f ~o l u~o i a ana c ne ~nlte1 ~t t~s F&amp;lt;.1s t a l Ser •i ca in l r eceiv oney 1t any of cnel r re s~~C•l•e o ffi c es o r ~g~ncies f or i mmedi;ite cr i nsmissi o n ll y te l e r ih 4 JAL fFl:ATC:JNS Sec S. To qualify fJr a 1 icense under cnis Jct dn Jo~ I ic3nt ~u st ~eet t he followi n~ r ecu oremen ts d The applicdnt mu st nave d net ftortn Jf dt led st Jn~ iundrej tnousanc do llars {!100 00D l coTI~ut ed ~c cora ing t enerdl ly ~cc ep t~d accoun t ing orinci les n) Tne fin ar1c d re scons i o i l i t t. Fi nanc i I c on&amp;lt;J i c, 011 1na iusi ness exper1enca uf t ne 30ulicdn~ mus t ~e such ~s to r~3son ~o' y arrant t hie Ct! l i af th 1t apo~ icant s ousi r.tts s J i t l oe C)njuc t~a ho nes t ly ~na c a re f ul11 ne e en t aeemeG i dv1sJ019 oy the ya yor os set f o r t1 in s~ction S of tn i s iC t Ai o L I C .I CO: J Sec a) cacr aop li c~t ion fur a lic ~n und~r t~is tct s all le :n:3 Ce. in r~ l c.i n9 dn!l un r o~tn t o t!"lc v1 v gt;r in c~n ful 1 n nn Ju s ines s ~aar ess of l} the p r o;&amp;gt; r ietor if tn~ 3:1.&amp;gt;l i cJn t i s &amp;lt;ln Z) e ~cn ~e~Da r. if t ne duplic~nt i i 1 o Art nersn i a &amp;gt;f' assoc l d ti Jn C3l e acn t rust.9e or ot~•er of f 1cur if the aoo l i C&amp;lt;l n t. i 5 a t r u s t gt;r £ olled Original' 5 { t,e corpo r ation and eden offic~r ~nd direc~vr tr:~reof if tnP. apµlicJnt is a co rpor'3tion r cu rv1,~r F r ATc\lE'ffS \,\JG Ju Sec 7, {a} Each application for a 1 ic~ns~ shall b~ ilccompdn i eel gt;y an investi91tion Fe e of t ~o hun1red fifty ooll drs (t2SJ) wh icn sh a! I not o~ suO ject co r~fund Out ~nic if th t license i s q ranteC sna ll cons c l~ute t~e li cense fe~ fo r th~ first license yedr or o•rt t nereof 2) f indnci1l sc a tene nts redSOndbl y Sd tisfacto r y t o in sur anc e co~o3ny aut~cr~zed to do J~in a ss tM e J1 s trtc~ 1 s5a c~c1 acn ap~ l icant ~hall ann~a ll y fl I~ a ~1n il ~r \ icen s~ Fo r y calenaar y~ar in t n nounts p ro~ i~e un~aro cnecks for the pr avio~ s y~a r not o ve r fifty tnausand dollars 5J OOJ tne oono snall oe fifty tnaus ~nd :Joi I r sc .occ 1. Fo r d li censee t i lt r;i t o t• 1 out stdnd i n~ dn1 un~aio ctiec~s fo r t he )r ~v o ous yea r in e xCe$s of f i fty thousano doll a rs (S S 000) ou t l es s t hdn e vency- fi •1e housanci &amp;lt;!ol l a r s s7S COC J ttie gt;oni; snail oe seve~ty- fi~e thousana ctol la rs i7S, QJC J. ca r a 1 i cens~w Ai~h average t o td l ou tstJna i ng and unp i cndc~ s f o r t he ~rev iou s lic tnse year i n e•c~ss of s~ v~n c y- F ivm cho usdnd ~c l l a r s (S7 S a~O J the cond s"1ll ~e one ~un~rea ous 3n1 ~clL1rs (Sl 00 0 0.J The Do n d 5n 3ll O•l i n 3 fo r :n sati s f.ictc r y .t 1 I IC) s -3 a of c ac Jt s i n t~e Oistr1ct lf Co1.J-n gt;ia Suer cn~mselv~s ~rirtq su it o i r~ctly on the Oona e r t~D tar r J tiC•I Counsel ~ay or i ng s uit tne reon in e~a l f of sucn t n e princ ioal sum o f ne oon ExCE? T, f h ,lt tne 5~ r c t1 sha l 1 have tn e 7 3r i s i tn r asoect t o obligat ions f t he aooli cant oucstanain Jn or orior co the da y c~a t such oana i s canc el~a Enrolled o nal (bl In li eu of a cor pora t e su ret y ~enc or ~ones or of Jnv portion of t ne pr i ncipal t hereo f as r equi r eq !l y suos ~c ti on (a 4) o f t~i s secti on, cne appl i can t ~o y J~~Js i t i:n e ~Jyor o r ith such Danks o r t ru st cgojp~nie s o r nacian~l n•s In :ne J istr ic t o f :o l ~moid S SJC~ 1001ic3n t n~y 1esi~n~t and t~e PJy~r r ~µp r~ve i n t~rds t ­ ~e3rin1 s:~c ~s o r ~cn~s notes Je :Jent~ r !S o r u t,er 'lOl i 1..i: i ins o F t h e ii tej St.,t&amp;lt S or any aqenc; o r i st rurn e nt~li t y t~ereo f. o r 1uardnt~~c by ~nd Unit State s Jr tMe Discr1 c c ~f Co1J~~i3 i n an a~~r~q~ t mount dse pon princip~J a~ou~ t r m~r ket vJlua i~rev~r is 1c~er Of l"I J t: 1 ~S S tt l. f'l t: he a r"c un t Of 1~ f" o lt;;U i re~ coroor Jt StJ r t.\t ocnc or DOrt ion tne r~o f T~4 5~c~ricidS s~all t aosite~ As mant i Jnflc aoa ve dMd ~e 'd t o secu r ne Sd·ne u3l1~1c ions JS •Oul~ cne sur~ t y Dond b u t cne u a~ o s i t o r sna i l De ~n~itled to r ~c i e ol 1 int~r est et nJ d i vi ~enu s t r t!{)n ~r:tJ !a h:.511 :iriva t ~e r i~ht i t h t n e d po r oval of cne yo r ta suosc i ic~ o t ne r securities f o r tno se depos ite d o t1Tt'-JG Q L[ C S Ci l 'IV~S f \Tl 1;1 S s c 3 d Jpon t.~e f i li n :i uf an .1cp l i c..it i o n i n J ue 8 tne ltor Sl"&amp;gt;al I issue t o tlie a upl i can a 1 cense to en ~a:;e in c~e selling of cnecks in cnt J 1scric: of Columbia unles s t Me ~ayor finos tn~c t~e cualification s p r~scrrbad ty 5uosactian of t~is S•c ti on a~a 1 secti on 5 of cnis ~ct ~ave not oaen ~et JI f h financi'll res~onsi:i i lity conditions d ll d ~us i ne s s e eri enc e of tne a ppli cant or I icens2e must Sue n as t o r r a" t t l"&amp;gt;e belief chat tr• apclic~nt's c~s inas s ~ill be con juc te~ nonescly and ca r e fully Tne ~ayor m1y in.,cs t i lt nd consiae r t ne qu &amp;lt;1 lificat ions gt; f tne a;,µli lnt o re s crooed bv section 7(JJ(4J of t ne act as follow JO sett•n~ Forth t~a l ocations dt nich n~ sells cnec~s t ne Distric t of Colum gt;id d S of Jdriu r y 1 April l July ~n ·I J ctooe r l o f e &amp;lt;1cn year tne reoart t o r e acn s~c~ date is Ju~ o~,or ~e for e t he fift e unth (15 Y tner t•r 9 !tlrolled origioal amount exhausted in whole or part or if the surety on the bond shall have notif ied the ~ayor of its intention to cancel the bond he shall by written or der require the filing of a new or supplemental bond or the deposit of new or addi ti ona l securities in order to secure compliance with th i s act Such orde r i s to be complied with within th i rty (30) days followinq service thereof upon tne 1 icansee ANNUAL LIC E~SE FEE Sec. 10. Eacn 1 icensee snail pay to tne ~ayor annually on the date determined by the Mayor, a 1 icense fee of two hundred fifty do llars S250J AGENr Sec ll A licensee may conduct n •S ousiness at one (l) or mo r e loc ations withi n the Di str ict of Columbia and through or o y means of such agents as t he li cens ee may from t ime to time des ignate or aopo int. No license under this act snail be required of any agent of a I ice nsee LIA81LITY OF LICENSEES Sec l Z. Each licensee sha ll be liable f o r the payment of all checks whi ch he se lls in the Jistrict of Columbia in whatever form and wheth P.r di rectly o r tnrough an aqent as the maker or d r a wer thereof according to the laws governing neqot i ~ble instruments in t he O i ~trict of Columbia I icensee #hO sells a cneck• wh e ther directly or throug h an agent• bolled Orfg!z:a,l' l ·J sndll n ev~r~~eless h~ve th~ sa:ne 1 s h v 1 t r esi c t. ti e r~t o as if ~e hdd siqne1 n Sdrne 3s tne jr3~e r thereof JISCLJSU~E CF ~ESP1~S!~iL!fY Sec 13 Eve ry c1ec~ sold by a licensee d ir~ctly or tnrouq~ 1n agent s~arr ~eJr t~e na~a uf tne lfc~nsea &amp;gt;e i lo 1 1 cens ~eor hi J.?n r sn 'lll cn..J r e a f~Q for t~e face a~ount tn9 r~o f or fifty cent s s 0 5 hi cnever is gt;la t 1on of 3ny pro~ls idn of this ac t ll :is tr1ct o f Columbia A~ministrJtiv roc eour c t appr ove j Jc t ooer lZ l 968 2 Stat lZO~ i o.c. Coce sec l -15 1 Sec 17 A~y P~rson ~no Yiallces dny provision of ni s ace s hal l ~e gu ilty o f a m is ~emeano r. shall Da fi ned not ~ore tnan one cno~sand ~ollars (ll 1DOC or i~pr i soned fo r ~ot ~or e tn ~n one (LJ yed r• o r ~Jtn r as acuc ions sndl l oe Sec l The pro visi o ns of t nls ~cc dr e s everab le Jnu •f i I le 1al inv ,11 id unconsti t ution.;1 or on.;p:&amp;gt;l i CJ01'1' to ~n• Jerson or ci rc unstances s uch no 11inq s1all no~ a FFnc t or s~c ci ons or oarts of the act o r cn~ir op~lic 1on ~o otner ~erscn~ or ci rcu~s tancas l e ·J is) \t i voa i nt:a:i t tnat th i s dct au 1 1v gt;ef?n ~J tiOot L! i f ~rovi sion se~ t enc c1 ~use s~ctiQn o r par t ndo no~ b~e~ i~clJd~d ~orein a nd if t ne per son o: circu~s~anc ~s to ~n •cn 12 E"'FECTI E D~ TE Sec l This ~cc snail take effdct jS proviC~d For acts of the Council of the Jistrict of Culumtia i11 section gt;:J2(cJ(lJ of t'1e Distric t of ColumbiJ Self- Gvv'!rnment Jn:l ~cvernment~l R~org~nization Act Cocket ~o: Bill Z-210 rt:st ltu4i 4 \.c:i.oe June 13, 1978 J]9 VCICZ v::TZ: Adopted Unanimosl~ Barry u c.J' S•c:ei:a:y die Co~ LJ lCI.1. C.u.L. VO I YClCZ 'IOTZ occ.:N l I MASON cc i M.GC.3'.Z 1 Adopted Unanimously (labs) Dixon I a J l 1 JUb 1978 -L I e l.?c i o J.c oc I f :tC L C.U.L 'fOTZ j l JUl i97B</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
