<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-12">
  <num type="law">2-12</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-06-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-12.pdf">D.C. Law 2-12</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 1442</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-12 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-87, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 22, 1977 and April 5, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 26, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-33 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>.I&amp;gt;istrict of Columbia Register 1 9 AUG 1'81 ACTIONS OF THE CITY COUNCI L D: C. LAWS COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE July 13, 1977 D.C LAW 2-12 "Volunteers Services Act of 1977" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-87 on first and second readings March 22, 1977, and April 5, 1977, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on April 26, 1977, this legislati on was assigned Act No. 2-33, published in the May 13, 1977, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislati on as D. C. Law 2-12, effective June 28, 1977. STERLING Chairman (Vol. 23, D.C. Register, 8985, May 13, 1977) 1442 lcK of the Council (\ District of Co lumbia Register 1 3 MAY 1'!17 NI ACT 2-33 Ill THE COUl1CIL OF TIIE DIS'.i.'P.IC OF COLm.mIA April 26, 1977 To provide for the use of vo luntee r s by the District of ColuF.~ia gove r nncnt BE I I:lll'&amp;gt;.C'I'ED BY THE COUIJCIL OF TEE DIS RICT OF COI..U!iBil\ That this ac t may be cited as the "Volunteers Services Act of 1977 Sec 2. It shal l be the ?Olicy of the District of Colur.lbia gover nr,1e nt to utilize volunteer citizens in as r,1a.ny govcrnnental programs as is practicable to serve the interests of the conmunity. llo vo lunteer person shall be used to fill any position or perforn any service which is currently be ing perforned by an er'.lp l oyee of the District of Colllr'.\bia government Sec. 3. The 11ayor is directed to promul gate r egulations governing the use of vo lunteers by agencies lt;lepartr.ents conuniss ions, and instrUJ entalities of t he District of Colur.bia: PROVIDED, That the District or Colunbia Board of Education and the Council of the District of Colunbia May pronulgate regulations governing their respective use of volunteers 8885 District of Columbia Register 1 3 MAY 19n Sec. 4 a) Volunteer citizens may not assist governmental programs until regulations have been properly pror.mlgate&amp;lt;l under the authority of thi~ act. Ho volunteer may be placed in any position lil:ely to constitute a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest in violation of the 2rovisions of chapter 29 of the act entitled "An Act to revise, codify, and enact into positive law i'itle 18 of the United. States Code, entitleC Crimes and Crirainal Proced lrc alJproved June 25, 1948 62 Stat. 710 or title VI of the District of Colur!bia Car.:pai gn Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act, approved l'.ugus t 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 4G5; D.C Coc!c, sec. 1-1131 et seq b) Persons engaged as volunteers by the District of Col'l.lr.lbia government as authorized !Jy this section shall not be eligible for benefits provided to e:r:tployees of the District of Colurr.bia governr;1ent under c!1apters 81, 33, 85, 87 and .89 of the act entitled "l'm Act to enact title 5, United States Code Government Or0anization and Employees codifying the general and pernanent laws relating to the organization of the Government of the United States and to its civilian officers and employees approved Septer.1ber 6, 1966 80 Stat. 531 c) All volunteers shall be considered employees of the District of Columbia governnent for the purposes of the 8986 District of Columbia Register 1 3 MAY 1977 District of Columbia r:r.1ployee !Ion-Liability Act approved July 14, 1960 (74 Stat. 519; D.C. Code, sec. 1-921 et seq d) The District of Columbia shall be liatle to third parties for tortious injury caused by volunteers under its supervision and control. Sec. 5. No provision of t his act shall be deernecl to apply to volunteers in the offices of t!1e Uni t ed States Marshal or the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia. Sec. 6 a) The provisions of the act entitled "An Act making appropriations to supply &amp;lt;leficiencies i n the appropriations for the fiscal y.ear ending LTune thirtieth, eighteen hundred and ninety eight, and for prior years, and for other purposes approved July 7, 1398 (30 Stat. 666; D.C. Code, sec. 1-215) prohibiting volunteer services to the District of Columbia government are hereby repealed b) The provisions relating to.the acceptance of voluntary aid by child caring institutions in the act entitled "An Act making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and eleven, and for other purposes approved nay 13, 1910 (36 Stat. 409; D.C. Code, sec. 3- 119) are repealed. 8987 District of Columbia Register 1 S MAY 1977 (c) Section 3 (b) of the act enti tled "An Act to authorize the District of Colurmia governfilent to establish an Office of Civil Defense and for other purposes approved August 11, 1950 (64 Stat. 439; D.C. Code, sec 6- 1203(b is araended by strikinCJ the words "volunteer and other" and "volunteers a!'ld d) The provisions of the act entitled "An Act Daking appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the nistrict of Colu.'llbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and eighteen, and for other purposes approved Ilarch 3, 1917 (39 Stat. 1019; D.C Code, sec. 8-132 concerning the use of volunteers for playgrounds are repealed e) Section 2 of the act entitled "An Act to regulate the use of public school buildings and grounds in the District of Columbia approved Barch 4, 1915 (38 Stat. 1190; D.C. Code, sec. 31-802) is repealed f) The provisions of the act entitled "An Act making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the governnent of the District of Colurabia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and eleven, and for other purposes approved nay 1 1910 36 Stat. 409; D.C. Code, sec. 32-1006) relating to the acceptance of voluntary medical services are repealed. 8988 District of Columbia Register 1 S MAY 1977 (g) The provisions of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act of 1952, approved August 3, 1951 (G5 Stat. 161; D.C. Code, sections 32-327--32-329) relating to the use of volunteers by the Health uepartment are repeale&amp;lt;l h) Section 22 of the Distr ict of Columbia Public Assistance Act of 19G2 approved October 15, 1962 (78 Stat. 919; D.C. Code, sec. 3-221) is repealed i) Paragraph (6) of subsection (a) of section 302 of the District of Columbia Canpaign Finance Reforn and Conflict of Interest Act, approved nugust 14, 1974 {88 Stat. 455; D.C. Code, sec. l-1152(a 6 is amended· to read as follows 6) to accept gifts j) Section 1 (7) of the act entitled "l~n Act to regulate the election of delegates representing the District of Colurabia to national political conventions, and for other purposes approved l'mgust 12, 1?55 {69 Stat. 700; D.C. Code, sec. l-1105{f is repealed k) Any provision of any la\·l affecting· the use of volunteers by the District of Columbia government is repealed insofar as .it is inconsistent with this act. Sec. 7. Persons who are serving as volunteers for the District of Columbia government as provided for by law before the effective date of this act shall not be affected 8989 D1str1ot of Columbia Register_ 1 3 MAY 'f&amp;lt;!T7 by the provisions of subsection (a) of section 4 of this act until thirty days after the regulations mandated by section 3 of this act are adopted. Sec. 8. For the purposes of this act a) The term "employee" means a person who is paid hy the District of Colunbia governnent from grant or appropriated funds for his or her services b) The term "volunteer" means a person who donates his or her services to a specific program or departr.1ent of the District of Colunbia governnent, by his or her free choice and without payment for the services rendered. The reimbursement of the actual expenditures by a volunteer on behalf of the District. of Colunbia goverruaent shall not make that person an employee of the District of Colurabia for t he purposes of this section c) The term "agenci es, departments, commissions and instrur:tentalities of the District of Colwnbia" means all governmental instrunentalities and bodies of the District of Coluinbia government, except the Superior Court of the District o f Columbia and the District of Columbia Court of Appeals. Sec. 9. This act shall become effective according to the provisions of section 602(c) of the District of Colunbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. 89SO</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-319.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-319.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-319.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-319.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§1-319.05"/>
  </section>
</document>
