<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-121">
  <num type="law">2-121</num>
  <heading type="short">Housing Discontinuance Regulation Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-10-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-121.pdf">D.C. Law 2-121</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1542</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-121, the “Housing Discontinuance Regulation Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-333, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Urban Development. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, and second readings on June 13, 1978, June 27, 1978, and July 11, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 2, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-251 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> i o I I 5Z?T~~t2 c 7 ­ iC c c 11 1 c 1 r r i 1.a 'l r gt J 1 u L I gt; I a a i I ~7 1 S 1 lt J f J w 0 t 1 I 01 J u II, Cl gt r \I Q J u 7 gt; I 1 L' \U j 7 l;I I ul 8 OI 0 u ll' c Vl ;J gt I c ru .t 11 c Gt 0 0 1 J n u :1 r \I t .l { l l_I IJ lt n 0 1 w T r f ll r f7 z gt J UJ O I :t r t,1 ro gt a r al j t:l lU m 0 u u ;r \I IU '1J c I u c Uf 11 1" tO LI ;J r Gt n: r \ 01 &amp;gt v L Vl 0 1 I t L. 111 0 \I ll \ lt ll' E r J I ll on t: 1\1 N II I \J N v fV r t- VP lt n u c n u u i r 'll I- ll I vt UI n u 0 19 o c u gt L 0 0 0 s 01 J; 0 n 0 0 c 0 J l.I ill c v J n 0 v O n \ r I q• r l c gt c O• r c °' r 'I 1 It gt f) t: t I r. f I ru n \J l c &amp;lt r. r \ I r 11 c v t c n L; c u 0 e n v l.I 1 l ;J r c f 0 0 c r IJ r J: u u r I t1' \ c c n 'O u l r c (l r c (l v 0 oJ c •u J a c c \ 0 J r. \ II l: I t ti lt u 0 n C I\ r l 0 0 r c f fl gt; o 0 r gt; 0 J r c l I v c l II \ v :J J II Tl Ill :1 r 0 r r. v :J 1 \J QI r l r 1 r c I Q c r \. 0 ti c r c ll ti l I f 0 t \ c 01 QI gt r 0 c •I r L \ c rr \" I I u I gt; r c 0 u r. O• O 0 r J r l 0 L r u r v r 0 lt;II r gt n u 1 gt; QI n r 0 c { } J u 0 c i gt c 0 c u c lt;I' r r n L 0 lt 0 c \ o&amp;gt; c Ill &amp;lt;T&amp;gt; 0 u 0 t J lt;&amp;gt; Ln c J v c c QI {; O r: \I gt; t t {1 t tl 0 I ­ \j v n1 O c J 0 &amp;lt l r; o I "J :r {) 0 f: 0 -j c u 0 0 c 11 r \, 0 •L c t J u c 0 v c t c 0 u u QI I I\ n u v r I u U\ c 0 C J OJ r c \ QI u c 1 0 L C 0 n f lt;r c h 0 QI di r fl I) u &amp;lt;11 c Ii u r. \I OL 0 u lt;J r: 0 Vl 11 c u c c 0 c n 1.1' r c 17 Ill u u 0 c 0 U \ \ 1 di c lt;r c L r: \1 c O u 0 0 0 n v. o 0 0 17 c r l\O L c y v c c c 0 ru u u c o t: m L c (J 0 0 gt u L r. VI I 0 lt v 0 c 0 u L (I 0 c I tJ L c 1 t \ lt \. I I o I \ v c :J lt 1 r: 1 lt II' II U gt 1 t J lt \I u v 0 t u lt 0 c u qo gt c j fl L c: 0 fJ L Tl 0 Qt r u I l 1JI lt;&amp;gt u ll I I 11• r J 0 0 n J &amp;lt;I n u r ro u c J :J c c u c 0 u v tJ c E u c 0 tr• r. u QI r 01 .r. I n IJ I \ u H t J u 0 o J l 1 I T. UI « .I I "I •11 I rtl n 11 1 \ I I I I r \ J \) t 0 0 u c QI u r. u J n 0 m c Q v 0 \I 01 c v t QI c QI r VI r r. 0 o= Cl' \1 0 oii u c VI u r 0 0 0 c 0 r 1 n \) 0 r 1 I gt OJI c 0 QI c n T l tlJ :J c t I I t c n u c t r II t \Jt u t tl 0 Q,l l f(l LJ t c 0 Ill c r 01 I I c u 0 c 0 0 gt c QI 0 0 c I c \) I v r y c \ 0 u v c c 0 11 u 0 f' Ii n \ u \ c J 0 J: QI 1 0 n r.&amp;gt 0 «l I U\ TJ u QI c E u c µ c c 1 I r c \I 0 11 lt;i II \I t I u r \I gt 1 l i E 0 L Of gt c 0 u c gt c ill 0 c 1; n 0 lt;J c f c 0 J c c 0 v I f \I L II c \ I I) I: v c f I fl 0 r U 1: II I J c c: 0 \I 0 F \I Q c l c l'1 :J r Cl I n c n VI c n u I c t,o II l &amp;gt;O r. 0 t 0 li I I 0 r 0 u c v r 0 N 0 c v r r t1 r gt; Ill lt O• c r. u &amp;lt t r t1 r n n 0 l QI r n c IV v c r c 0 l c J 0 r c 0 [ l 0 n ti O c QI t v r: u :J 0 N J r: 0 v V1 t• t ri tn \I 0 0 r- c 0 v u L 0 c t ti c 0 v 0 :J 0 01 Ill c r U c 0 0 V1 t n -0 V gt; n u ll v r J ti c u L 1 J ti 0 &amp;lt r 0 di II 0 \ r tr gt ll o• u ¢ Ot Vt t: t ni to {J 0 E ll't llJ J ti 0 ft r: u tU "\ l r: 0 r. \ J ru c 0 u 0 J ill u t J 0 c r) 11 C IO v r- 111 c 0 &amp;lt f QI t t tJ ti e.-J 0 u \I Ill 0 c t,_J { \1 0 l r 0 Ill r c r r. \ r. 0 &amp;lt n c \ i t1 c u c 0 &amp;lt;J v 1'J \ r n QI c Ill E v r: v \ J (} c 0 v V1 0 c L 0 u v n 0 c 0 i \1 &amp;lt;JI c 0 u 0 0 c 0 v lt 0 f tl r \ gt c \ c \1 c I I J c n &amp;lt;J f P c 0 v l v v :J 0 e v v 0 \ l J c lJ &amp;lt m r 0 I 0 v I v c I' c 0 t r 3 0 &amp;lt 0 lt;I&amp;gt 0 I} \ u \1 &amp;gt; 11 \I L r v I r 0 11 t I ti r J ll l t o •n Olf&amp;lt 3 of J I l o t::a..a::i c.sl tz s 3.t r lt \ J I c z 1 1 I 1 3 c JUL l SIS I I p c.c liG I I I 1 i 11.:f t </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
