<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-120">
  <num type="law">2-120</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-10-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-120.pdf">D.C. Law 2-120</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1519</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-120 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-304, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 27, 1978, and July 11, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 2, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-250 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COtiNCI L OF THE Dr5TR!C OF COLU~lo~A &amp;gt;.TOTIC J, C. Law 2-120 "Standar c Va luation anci Nonio te i tur e Arnencimc nt Ac t o! 1978 Pursua nt to Section .nz oi t!le Dis t,-ic: oi Col u m bia Self Gove nme !ll a nd Gover meotal Reorga:ri z ation ct L 0 3 -1 S the :\c the CouncH oi the Dist ict oi Coll!rr gt;ia a dopted Bill \'r 2 JC on iir t and second :eading s J une 27, 1978 acd Ju ly ll, 1978, r espe cC ely was a sgigr. eC. Act o 2 2 30, publi.si::ec L t!l e Auqust ll, 19 S a i on of tne O. C a e gister Vul. 2 5 page 15191 a:-ic tran~rr::tted l gt; Ccngr e"s on Augus t 14, 1978 for a 30- day r c•tie le accordance with Section ~02 (c l oi the Act. T'ne Cou:ic il of t.'ic Dist r ict oi Co!u.rcbi neuby ves :ict ice that th e 30-day C or:grc s sional R e vie•.o. i'&amp;gt;er!oc i.5 expi r ed anc L'i c r efor e, c ite s the followin g legi sl a tion a s C C w l 1:?0, c;'fectivc O ctober 13 1973 \ TLRU 1rr.;cKER. c air:nar 1 the Cou ncil Dates Cou:itec gt;a in~ the 30- 0 av Congr es sional I\e,·le Pl?.ri gt;d A UGUST 14 15, l b, 17 S PTE~l.BER o, 7, S, U 12 3 14 15, l 10, 2 Z Zi&amp;gt 2 7, 2 :3, 2 9 OCT03ER 2, 3 t, 5 10 11, 12 0 C. LAol IN THE COUNC IL J F THE DISTRICT OF COL~MSI 4 To a~eno C~aoter V Of t he Li fe In sur~nce ACt approve o June 19. 1934 (48 Sta t 1151&amp;gt o. c. Code s~c 35-701 et s.ia to u~oat e the s tan da rd v a luati on and nan f orf ei ture laws and to ajo~t a s t a nda r d nonfor fe i ture l a~ f o r indi v idual oefe rrec a nnuities SE IT E~•CTED SY THE COU~CIL OF THE OfST~ ICT OF ~OL SIA That tnis act ~a y b e cited a s t ne stano arc Va luatio, and ~on for• e iture Am endme nts Ac t o r 1978 Sec 2 Tne fif th p a ragraon o f s ec t ion I (b) of Chac ter v of t he L i fe rns u r anc e Act aopro vej June 19 1934 (4 8 S t .n 11 57 i c Co d e• s e c 35 -7 01 (bJJ i'&amp;gt; ame nded to r ead a s f o l lows Exc Qp t as other wise pro vide d in paragr aph 2 of subs ecti o n C f or g roup annu ity a ,c p ure enao~mc~ t con tract t he l e qdl mi ni~um sta noard f o r tn~ v al u 3ti on o f 3nnui t ies issued on and afte r Ja~uary I, 1~35 sna il be Mc: l i ntoc k s Table o f Mo rcal ity A~ong nn ui tants i tn inter e st a~ 4 ~er ce~tum per annum ut a~nulties de ferrec in s u rance sh a l 1 ~e valued on tne sama oa si s a s t nat useo in 2 computing the consioe rdtion o r Dremiu~ tneref o r or upon ~ny hiqner stanoar d dt tne opt ion or t he compa ny Sec 3 Subsect i o n (Cl of sect ion 1 o f Chapte r v of the li fe lnsur dnce ACtr d poroved June 1 9 1 9 34 t ll Stat 1157 O. C Code, sac 35- 701 (c)} 15 ~men&amp;lt;J eo oy a} aod 1ng i~meoia tely afte r cne wo rus the stanoor~ non~or fei ture l a on t he first o ar 3qr anh t ner eo f t ne fol l owi ng ne~ wor ds e ~cepc dS otner s e p roviaed in p&amp;lt;trag rapn 1 2 1 of thi 5 s uosec tion for 9 r o up annuity ano oure en~owmen~ con tract$ issue~ prior t o such o~erati ve ~a~e b) s t ri ki ng tne ~O rd Tne" in par raoh (1 a no inser t i ng in 1 ieu tnereo f t !ie fo l l o in 9 ne w oros s o t na rw ise p r c v ioed in pa ragr aoh (ll of cn15 subs ection th l:t 11 CJ s t ri k ing t he wo r ds •reserve va l udti on metnoo &amp;lt;Jet1ned i n paragr aon 2 1 3 5 per c en tu i nt arest in p~ragr apn (1 J dnct 1n s er tinq i n lieu t~ereof the fo ll ~winq new "Oro s reserve valuation ~ethods a efinen on pa r aqraon s (3) and (4) of ~h is s uhsec tion and i n sect i o n 20 5 pP.r cen t um Jn t •H est oer ann um. o r in t ne case gt;t po l i cies and c ontracts o t her than annuit y and pure endowment contrac ts issued on o r fter cne P. ffec tiv~ oate of the Standa r d Valuat ion ano Nonfor fe•t~re Fi 3 •nenc~encs E~Rr gency •c c ot li78 5 ~e r centum ~nte r est oer annu s uopar J9 r 3pr t:1e fo llo~in g 11ow ~o res: any cat ~qor y of ch pol 1c1 es 1ssu ~d on fe~a le ris ~s a11 ne pa raqr apn to r eaJ as fol l o~s Zl rne ~ininum s c~nJar~ for :ne valuat•o~ o f 31 1 dl I annuiti e s ~n~ pur~ endow~ents ?u rc~ as on o r uf t r sucn o')erri t i v&amp;lt Oat&amp;lt;&amp;gt; un•je r .Jr'.lup Jnn 1t;y t:l.l pure va lv;iti on metnoos Jehnec on Jra r.,i rs (JJ d gt;f tn~s suns@c t ion an~ the f o l l o~in o l es ana fnte r ~st r aces 4 i) For indiv1 oual sin9 le ore~ium i~medi a te a nnu i t y c o n t racts• exc lud ing an y oi saoi l ity ano acc i a ental de ath nene f i ts i n suc h c ont racts tne 19 71 Indivi dual Annui ty ~ortd l ity T4o l e or any moo 1f i cat ion o f t nis t a ol e aporovea by the Supe rintende nt and 7. 5 per centum inter ~st pe r an nu 1' t i i J Fo r in di v ioual annu i t y ano our enoowment contr~cts otner tna n sinql e premium i~meoi ate a nnu i ty contra cts• e xc l ud 1nq an y olsab il ity and acci dental d•at~ Dene f 1t s in sucn c unt r3ctS t he 1971 Ind iv i d ua l Annui t y ~ortal i ~v Tao l e o r an y ~odi f ica t •on of t h•s t aole approved o y the Super inte ndent a nd 5 S e r centum inter2 st per annum for sing le pr emium deferred a nnu ity and pu re e ndo wment contracts ano 4 S oer c ent u~ i nterest pe r annum for a ll otnar such inni vijual an nuity ann pu r e endowment c o n t rac t s i ii) For al I annui~i es a no p ur e endowmen~s pu r c hased undo r gro up annui ty ana pur enao~m~n t con tracts• exc lud in~ dn y oisdoi li~ y 4nO acc •dan t a l ce~ th benefits ourcnased unoe r s ucn contrac ts t~e 1971 Group Annu i ty ~orta l 1ty Ta ol e o r an y moo ificat1 o n of tn1 s ~aole app r oved o v t~e 5 Supe ri n teno ent and 7 5 per centJm nteres t oe r annum Atter t ne ef fective date o f t ne Standar o Va luat i on ~no ~onforfeitur e Amand~ents Emergenc y Act o f 197 8 anv compa ny mav f i l e w• tn t he Superint e ndent a wr itten no t i ce of 1ts e lecti o n to comply witn t he orovlsion s o t thi par ag rapn a ft e r a speci fie d oa te oe fo r n Janu ~r y 191q wnicn s nal l ~e tne o per a tive d~te of t nis pa raqraon for s ucn company, u rovi oeo a company may el ect a oi ffer en t o pe r a tive oate fo r i n oivi oual annuity and pur e endowment contrac t s from tnat lec ceo for g r ouD annuity a na oure enoownent cor• tr dC t s If a comoany m~ke s no Suen e l ecti on the ooerat1ve date of th is o aragr don f o r such c ompan y snail De J a nu ary t 1979 h) str i k i ng t ne word "Res e rves• in par aq r a pn l a s reoesi qnated and insert i nq in I i eu t ne reof the fol l owi n g new ~or o s Exceot a s otherwise o rov1 deo in oaragr ap n (41 o f (i str i n~ t he wor ds i l a nnui t y ano pure endo•~en t contrac ts• in tne l a st s e ntence o f par ag raon (l rlS reaes ignated and inserting in lieu t~ereof tne fol l o win q i 1 g r o u p annu i ty and p ure enao men t contract s purchased un~er a ret i rement plan o r plan of oe f e rrea co~pensat ion es t 3o l isned or ~ai n t a ined o y an emp loye r nrolled c~iginal b (including d partnership or sole oroprietorsnip or by an e mployee o r qan i z ati on or by bot n ot~er than a plan providing i nd ividual retire ment accounts or indivi d ual r etirement annu iti es uocer section 408 o f :ne I n ternal Revenue Code of 1954 (BA St a t 959 lb u. s c. 4Cdl as now Or her~d fter am~nded j) insertin g immediate ly af ter tna wora s iv) a ll other oenef i tS e xc eot life insurance ~nd enoowment oenefi t s in I ife insuranc e poli cies" in t ne l ast sentenc e of oara; r3pn (3 as reo e s1gnated t ne followinq new Or os a nd benef its orovideo b v all otner •nnui ty and nu r e an~owment contracts J striking t ne woros paragraon CZJ in tne last sen tence o f parag r aph (31• as reaesi qnated, ano insertinq in ieu tnereo f t he f ollowing new wo ros par agraph (3 11 aooinq immediate ly aft e r o a ragra pn (3 as resaesi d tea t ne follo wi ng ne. o araqraon 4 ta reao as f o llows 4) r ni s paragraph snall a pply to all annuity ano pur e e ndowment contr acts eKcep t tnose gr oup annuity 3n d oure endowment con tracts for wnic n r eserves are to oe cal cu lated by a met noo consistent •i th t ne p r inci p les o f parag r3ph (3) of th is subsect ion 7 aeserves dCcor ding t the Comm •s sioners Jnnu1 t v r eserve method for benefits under annu ity o r pure endowment contracts e ~c ludin~ any d isab il ity and acci oent a l oeath oen ef its in sucn contrac ts sna il ~e t~e greatest of the respect•ve exc e sses of t ne u resent values t tne date of valuat ion. of tne futura gua ranteeo oenefi ts. incluainq guaranteed nonforteit~r c oenefits orov ioeo for oy suc n con tracts at tne end of each resoective contract yea r. ov r tne oresent va lue t the o~te of valuat ion ot any tuture va luati on co~sid~r dt ions o~r·v~d from future g ross cons ide rdti on reg~ir~d by t ne terms of sucn con tr ~ct tnd t become pa yable o rior to tne eno of sucn resoecti ve contract ye a r Tne future guaranteed oenefits snail be dete rmined by using the morta lity tdole. 1f any. and the interest rate or rates s oec if ieO rn such contracts for T&amp;gt;ia val uJtion consider )t1ons are ~t portions of tne r es oecc1v ros s cons icerati ons dDnl ied unaer the te rms of sue~ contrac ts to deternine nonforfeiture v~'ues m) striMing the wor os •oar dgrapn 2 in pa r aqr~pn S a s r edesignateO and inser ting r n I i P.u tnereo f tha follo wing par~graoh (31 of th is suo s ection ano sec tion ZO ilnc f 0 l l O wS Rq ser ves for an v categor y of ~ol i c ies contracts o~ benefi ts as esta~ l i sne d by toe Superi n t e nden t. may oe calcwl a ted at tne ootion of the comoa ny according to any stdnaaros ~n icn oroouce 3r eater aggr ~g ate reserv e s for sucn cate 3o ry toan t oose calculat e a accor 11n9 to t oe m ini ~um stdnoar a herein ~ro viaed. Out toe rate or rates o f inter e st used for po lic ies and con tracts. othe r than annuity and oure endowment contracts• shall not be o i qher t nan t he corr e spo nding rate o r rat e s of interest us ea i n calcul~t ng ~ny nonforfeitur e benefit s pr oviaeo fo r tnerein Sec 4 Suos e ction (b) of secti on 3 of Cn~pter v o f the Life I nsu rance Act dPorove~ June 19, 1934 (4U Stat llS d o. c. Code sec 35-703) is amen d&amp;lt d Oy s trilcing the woros •sec~ion sc and inserting 1n l ieu tner~of "secti o n ~d Sec 5 T~e ninth par ag raoh of sec tion 5 o f C na~ter v of tne L ife Insurance ~ct pproveo June 19 1 19 34 (48 Stat 1 1 o l; D. c. C:&amp;gt;ae sec 35-7 gt;5 l is amend e&amp;lt;.1 oy a) inse rti nq immea i 3te ly after t ne oros Si xth A or ovislon" th~ fol lowing new words spec ifying t he ooti ons avail40 le 1n t he event of c essation of payment o f consi der a t i o ns unoP. r the cont roct In the cas e of contr acts issueo on or aft er t ne OO• r t t i ve d a t e of sec ion 5c t ne st dn ~a r a f o l l owin n o r es Fo r c ~nt r~cts 5s u r 1 o r to t~e 5 C 6 Tne t i t le o f sect on 5b of Cha~ t&amp;lt;i!r t t n e if e l r f r ~rc o ct l 3t Z 5 t.;lt Sec 7 Tne f ir t sente n co o f th• tif t n µd r aq r aoh o f suosecti on (di o f s ec t •o n 5b o f ~hdP t e r v o f t ne Li fe h i e r tioq i mmed ia t ely af ter o r a s 11 gt d l 1- u o non f or t ei J&amp;lt be!'lef 1t. s t h~ f o l f J w•n c nP o r .is 1 t•i r. I C:1 r ~te of i n t e re 5t sna l I no t e xcee~ 3. 5 ~e r cont u m ce r ~11n u i ce~t ~nat r ate o f ter es t not e xcee31nq 5 S p e r c ~ntu~ pe r ·Jnru 11 1'a y oe u sed fo r :J 0 1• C 2: S i ssu on or fr.er t 4! LO e ffect ive da t e o f tne Stanoard va luation and Nonf or f eitu re Amendments Emergency Act of 1978 ano (C) srr1~ing the word tnree• anj insert1nq •n I ieu t ne reof the followi ng new ~oro si x Sec B. Tne f ir st sentenc e of tne si x th pdragrapn or s uosection (O) of sec t i on Sb of Chapter V of the lif e ln$u rance Act aop rovect J&amp;lt;;ne l'I Jq3&amp;lt {o 2 Stat 32 o c Co::se sec 35-7050 10 is amenoe-:i oy a) str iK ing t he words not e Kceeaing ] 5 per centvm per .J nnum 0 an&amp;lt;J (b) inserting immedia tely 1fter t:1e &amp;gt;&amp;lt; Oros i;i 1r.t-oo non forfeiture oene f its tne foll owing ne or ds nicn race o f inter es t sna11 not exceeu 3 5 per centum per annum e Kcept t~at a rate of inte rest not ex cceoin~ S. 5 pe r cent.um per annu~ may be used for policies issued on or a f te r the effective date of the Stanaara Valuation and Nonf orfe ture Amendments Energency Act of 1976: P rov•~ed Tna~ f o r any categor y of inou s tr1al insurance issueo on femal e ri s kr aOJusted premiums ano o resent val ues mdy oe ca l cul 3ted accor ding to an age not ~ore t~an si x y~ar s younger tnan tne actual age of the 1nsurea Sec 9 Cnapcer v ~f the Life Insurdnca Ac t app r o ved June 19 1934 8 Stat 1156; o. c. Coae sec 35-70Sc) i ar;iended oy: l l a) redes1 q nat ing sec ti on 5c (oZ S tat 34: o.c Cooe sec 35-T05c) a s sect ion 5d; ano J dddin9 immediately after secti on 50 the f o ll owing new sec t ion 5c to reao as fol lows SEC. 5c STAllLJA,{l) NONFQRF F. T TuRe LA F;)R INOIV!OUAL DEFERRE D AN NUITI ES l a t This s ection s nall not aooly &amp;amp;O any reinsurance g roup ~nnuity ou r cnaseo under d r et irement p l an or pl~n of de fe rred compensat ion estaol i sned o r main t ained Oy an emcloye r (includ i ng plan p r ovi~ ing 1nd i 11i aua l r et or emen~ account s of i nnividua l ret i rement annuities under sec tion 408 of t ne lnternai Reven~e Cone f 1954 1aa Stat QS9 26 u. s.c. 40B as no~ or hereafter amendeo prerniu deposit f und va ri a:i le cont r i!Ct• im:ne :ji~t annui~y any deferred annuity contract after annuity p ~y~ents nave commenced or rever s1~nary a nnuity nor to any cont r act ~h1ch s~all De deliv ereo outside the Oist rict of Columo ia tn r ouqh a n ag ent o r oth er r~pr esen t~ tive nf the compa ny issuing the cont r act 1 E lea' O s;;i..Q TO J 12 bl In tne case of coritr cts issuea on or after the operative date of tnis section as defined in suosection (k no contract of annuity. exceot as state&amp;lt;J in suosec ti on (a sn&amp;lt;.111 oe oe 1 i vered or issued for delivery i~ the District of Columoia unless it contains in substance tne fol lowing provistons• or corresoonaing provisions wnicn t t~e ooinion of the Superintannent are at ledSt as favorable to the contract holder l) That upon cessation of rayment of consiaarations unoar a contrdct, the company will qrant a oaid-up annuity oenP.fit on Jan 5tipulatec in the contract of ~ucn value as is specified in sul:lsectoons (d} e f lt;Jl• and i 2) If a contract oroviaes for a lumo sum settlement at maturity• or at ~ny ot~er t~~e. that uoon surrence~ of the contrdCt at or prior to the co" wencement ot any annuitv ~ayments• the company will pay in li eu of any paid-up annuity ~enefit a casn surrenaer benefit of sucn amount as is specifieo in suosections (d e 9}. ana (i The company shall reserve ~ne rignt to defer tne payment of sucn casn surrender oenefit for a period of si• montns after demand therefor with S\Jrrender of the contr&amp;lt;1ct 13) A statement ot tne mortality t•ble• if any, anj interest r3tas used in calculating any ~inimu~ paid-up annuity• casn surrenoer or deatn oenefits tnat are guaranteed under the contract togetner witn sufficient information to aetermine tne amounts of suer. Denef its 14 orief and general statement of tne method to De usea in calculat ing any paid-uo annuity casn surrender or deatr. benefits tnat may ne availaole under tne contrac: and an exolanation of the manner in which such oenefits are altered bv tne existence of any additional amounts credited ~Y tne company to the contract• any inaeotecness to th e co~pany on tne c~ntract or any prior withdrawals from or par ti al surrenders of t ie c:&amp;gt;ntract otwithstana1nq the requirements of this section. dny defer r ed annuity contrdct ~ay provide tnat if no considP.rations have oeen receive~ unaer a contract for a period of t~o full years and tne portion of the p&amp;lt;1id-up annuity benefit dt maturity on t:-ie plan sctpulatea in Enrollee 0:-1.0 l"ll l 't tne contract arising from consiaerations ~aid prior to sucn period woula De less than twenty dollars montnly. tne comoany may at its option termi~ate sucn contract Dy payment in cash of the then oresent value of such portion of tne paia-uo annuity Denefit calculated on the oasis of tne mortality taole. if any, ano interest rate soecif ied in the contract for determining tne oa 1a- uo annuity oanefit• an&amp;lt;l ly sucn pdvmenc s:i;ill cie rel ievea of any furtner obligation un&amp;lt;ler sucn contract c) The minimum values as specifiad in subsections (d f q an&amp;lt;l (i) of :1nv paid-up annuity, cash sorrenaer or aeatn oenetits available under an annuity contract snal I be oased uoon minimum nonforfeiture amounts dS oefinea in tnis subsection l) With resoect to contracts orovidinq for flexihle considerations. tne minimum nonforfeiture amount at any time at or prior to tne commencement of any annuity payments shall be equal to an accumulation uo to sucn time at a rate of interest of 3 oer centum per annu~ of percent1qes of tne net consiaerdt1ons (as nereindfter aefinej) paio prior to S•Jch time. decreased oy t~e sum of: 15 i) any prior witnorawals from or partial surrender of tne contract accumulated at a rate of interest of 3 per centum per annum; and ii) the arraunt of any indeotec:ness to tne company on t'le contract, incluoin interest due ana accruea; dnO increased oy any existing additional amounts credited oy tne comoany to the contract The net considerations for a given contrdCt year used to aefine tne ~inimum nonfor•~iture amount sha• l oe an dmount not 1ess tn~n zero ?nj snal l be equal to tt&amp;gt;e correspon&amp;lt;J i ng gross cons ioerations credited to tne contract during tnat contract year less an annual contract cnarge of thirty aol lars and less a collection charge of one dollar an~ twenty-five cents per consioeration creaited to tne contract auring tnat contract year. Tne percentaqes of net consiaerations snail be 65 per centum of the net consideration for tne first contract year and 67 5 oer ~entum ot tne net consiaerations for tne second and later contract years otwithstanding tne ~revisions of the preceding 5entence tne perce~tdge shdll ~e 65 per lb centum of the portion of the total net consideration tor any renewal contract year which exceeds by not nore than t~o times tne su~ of those portions of tne net considerations on all prior contract years for which the percentage was 65 per centum 2) With resaect to contracts providing for fixed sc~eduled considerations. minimum nonforfeiture amounts snal I ~e calculated on the assumption that considerations are paid annual I y in aovance and sr.al I ie def 1 nea ~s for contracts with fle~iole cons1derat1ons whicn are paid annually wit.n t~o e~ceptions i) The portion of thP. net consideration for the first contract year to oe accumulated shall be tne su~ of 65 per centum of the ne~ cnn~ijerat1on for the first contract vear plus 22.5 percentum of the e~ccss of the net consideration for ~ne first c~ntract year over the lesser of the not consioer~tions for the second and tnird cor1t.ract years ii J The annual contract charge shall be the lesser of thirty collars or E::rclled c l l 7 10 uer centum of t~ e gross annual consideration 3 itn res~ect to contracts providing for a single consioeration. minimum nontorteiture amounts shall oe oefinea as for contracts with flexiol~ consioerations e~cept that tne uercer•tdqe of n~t con&amp;amp;ineration used to determine the minimum nonforfeiture amounc snail be equal to 90 per centum ano the net consideration snall oe tne 9ross consideration less a contract cnarqe o~ saventv-five rtollars 1) Any p;iid-up annuity benefit avai lat&amp;gt;le under a contract snall oe sJcn tnat its present value on the date annuity payments are to commence is dt least eoual to the minimum nonforfeitura amo:int on tnat date. S 1JCh gt;reserit val u~ sn;Jl I t:e computed using tne nor ta Ii ty t&amp;lt;!Ol if ~nv• on&amp;lt;l t!"le interest rate s~ecified in cr.e ~ontract for oetermininq tne minimum paio-uo annuity nenefits guaranteed in tne contract ceJ For contracts wni cri Drovide cash surrender Denefits. such cash surrenocr benefits available prior to maturity snail not oe less t!"lan tne present value as of the date of surrender of tnat portion of the maturity value of tne paid-uo annuity benefit which would be provided u:1aer tne contract at matJrity arising from consideration~ paid prior to the time of c~sn surrenoer reaucea Dy tne amount appr~priate to reflect any prior witndrawals from or partial SJrrenders of tne contract, such present value oeing calculatec on tne basis of an interest rate not more than one percent n i gher than the interest rate specified in t~e contract far accumulating tne net consiaerations to determine sucn ~aturity value. decreased by the amount of any 1naeDteaness to tne company on the contract• inc l uding interest due and accrued. and increased by any eKiSting additional amounts credited Dy tne company to the contract. In no event Shall any c~sn surren~er benefit De loss th3h t~e minimum nonforfeiture amount at that time. Tne aeath benefit under such contracts shal l be at least equal tn the casn surrender bonef it f J Fnr contracts wnicn dO not provide cash surrender ~enef its. tne present value of any ~ain- uo annuity benefit available as a nonforfeiture op~ion at any time prior to 'lldturity snail not be 19 less th~n the present value of thdt portion of tne maturity value ot tne paio-uo annuity benefit provided under tne contract arising from considerations paid prior to the time tne c~ntr~ct is surrendered in excnanqe for or cnanqed to a deferred paia-uo annuity. sucn oresent value De1nq calculated for the perioa p r io r to the ~aturity date 0n tne basis of the interest rate scecif ieu 1n tne contract for accumulating tnc net considerations to det~rmine sue~ maturity value~ and increased by any existing additional amounts cre~ited by tne company to c~e contract. For contracts ~nicn ao not provide any jeacn nenefits prior to the commencement of any annuity oayments• such oresent values snall be calculated on the oasis of such interest rate ana tne mortality table s~eclfiec 1n the contr~ct fvr det~rrn,ning the ~aturity value of tne paid-up annuity oenefit. nowever. in no event snall tne present value of tne paid-up annuity benefit be less tnan the minimum nonforfeiture amount ~t tne time. ul91 For the ptJrpose of deter~ining tne benefits =alculated under subsections and (f in tne case of annuity contracts unje r whicn ~n 20 election may be made to nave dnnuity ~ayments commence at optional maturity oates the ~aturity oate shal I be deemed to be the latest date for wnicn election snail De permitted by the contract. but shal l not be deemed to ~e lat~r than tne onniversary of the contract next following tne annuitant's seventieth o irt~oay or the tenth anniversary of the con tract h icnever is later h) Any contract wh icn ooes not provide casn surrender benefits or does not provide death benefits at least eoual to the minimum nonforfeiture amount irior to tne commencement oi any annuity iayments snal 1 'nc 1 uoe a s t.;itement in a prominent place in tne contract that sucn bene•its are not provided i) Any paid-up annuity. casn surrender or death oenefits 3vailable at any time. other tnan on tne contract anniversary unoer any contract w1tn fixed scheduleo consijerations snail De calculatec wi tn allo~ance for the laose of time ano the payment of any scneouleo considerations beyond the beginn i ng of the contract year in which cessation of payment of con&amp;amp;iderations under the contract occurs. Zl j) For any contract whicn provioes ithin the same contract oy rider or supplemental contrdCt provision ootn annuity benefits Jna life insur3nce t.&amp;gt;enefits tn3t are in ex~ess uf the greater of casn surrenoer t.&amp;gt;enuf its or a return of ttie g ros s consiaerations ~ith interest• tne m1nirnum nontorfeit~re oenefits shall be equal to the sum of the rnir.imurn nonforfeiture oenefits for the dnnuity portion ano the minimum nonforfeiture benefits. if dhY for the 1 ife insurdnce ~ortion computed as if e~cn portion were a separate contract ot -itns tana1nq tne provisions of suoseccions (U e)o (f and aooitional t&amp;gt;enefits (1) in the event of total and ~ermanent d i s ab i 1 i t y 2 as reversionary annuity or deferred reversionary annuity benefits; or (3J as other ool icy oenetits acloi tiona l to Ii fe in!.urc1nce. enoowment and annuity oenefits ond cDnsi derations for all such aoaitional benefits• snail be disregaroed in ascertaining tne minimum nonforfeiture amounts+ paic-uu dnnuity• Cdsn surrender and oeatn benefits tnat m~y te required by this section. Tne inclusion of such aocitiono l gt nt?.fits sr.31 1 not oe required i n any ~aia-up 2Z oen~fit s l1nl ~ss suc h ajo1tiona l uRr1ef1 ts 7 1.\ 5apdr~t e l y ~ou l d r eauire mini~um nonforfe tu r e amounts pald- uD a nnuity c1s~ surren~er ano oea~n ienefits lt;} Afcar t ne effect i ve ~atn of t he Std nn~ra 7. JI: Act cf I '1 73 rn ·f comp.Jr. y r1;,y file wi tr. tne 7 3B compl y th tne provisio1is ~t ~h is seccion ~tter 7 19 aft~r sue fect i v e JUt t r t ;i e f 1 l 1 n 'J t 7 o witn espect to c.Jnnu1 ty c.ont r dc t~ tner t.!ntter 1ss ue!J ~Y sucn compan y If a co~pany md• es no sucn Amend~encs Emer gency Act of 1~7 Se c I i Sec t io n 2C of (h;,o r.er of t'1 e L 1· l nsu r .rnce Ac t. approv l Jun~ 19 1934 41 t;,t 1I70 i C gt;&amp;lt;ll s c 3S -72l) is &amp;lt;inld nnec t.:l re.Jd gt;s fol l:&amp;gt;ws 23 sec 20 WHEN ACTUAL P REMI U~ FOR LIFE POL ICY IS LESS THA~ VALUATI ON NET PREM!U Jf i n any con tract year tne g r oss o re~ium cha r ged by 3ny I ife insurance company on any ~ol o cy o r contract S l ess than the valuat ion ne t or e mium fo r t ne pol i cy o r cont r ac t ca lculated oy tne method useo in ca l c ulating t he r eserve thereon but using the ~inimum va l uation stanaaros o f ~o r ta l i ty and rate of interest tne ~i nimum r eserve r cGu i reo fo r such po li c y or con tract sha l l be t~e great~r of eitne r t ne reserve calcu l a ted accordinq t o the mortali t y t ao le rate of inte r e st and method ~ctua l l y used for such po l icy o r contract or the reserve ca 1cu 13ted by th e •ne t n no ac tually useo f o r sucn pol icy o r con t r~ct nut usin q t~e m i n um stanaaros of mor t ality ano r ate of in t e r es t dna r eo l a cing t he valua tion net p r emium by the actua l q r oss prem ium in each contract year for h ocn the val uation net r erni~rn exc~eas tne actu31 g ros s o remium Sec l t T~is act snail t ~ke e ffect ~s pr ov t OeO fo r acts of t he Counc i l of t ne District o f Columoia on sec ti on 60Z(cJ(l) o f tne Dis tr ict of olumoia Sel f-Government and Governmental Ra orgdn iLat i on ac t ioek.c :O:c: Bill \o. 2 304 3 c A n: June 27, 1978 (Xl VO:C V07Z: I 4~ l lt;M 1 L i r CA c I CC July !l, 1973 ore vo:-z, Adopt~d t:na.nirr.nus ly (labsl arcv </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
