<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-128">
  <num type="law">2-128</num>
  <heading type="short">Employment Opportunities Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-128.pdf">D.C. Law 2-128</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 2236</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-128, the “Employment Opportunities Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-151, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 11, 1978, and July 25, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 17, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-263 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>r \ COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOT ICE D. C. LAW 2-128 "Employrrent Opportunities Act of 1978" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governnental Reorganization Act, P. t. 93-19 8 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-151 on first and _second readings, July 11, 1978 and July 25, 1978 respectively. Follcwing the signature of the Mayor on August 17, 1978, this legislation was ass i~ed Act 2-263, published in the September 8, 1978, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 25 page 223 6) and transmitted to Congress on January 18, 1.979 for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c l of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired, and, therefore, cites the follcwing legislation as D.C. Law 2-128, effective March 3, 1979. G f ARRI NG'I'~IXO'*N Olairman of the Coun il Dates Counted Durina the 30-dav Congressional aeview Period: January 18, 19, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 29, 30, 31 February 1, 2, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 13, 14, 15, 16, 20, 21 22, 23, 26, 27, 28 March l, 2 11 O.C. LAW 2 12 8 't~t£ MA~ 0 3 1979 AN ACT 2-263 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA AUGUST 17, 1978 To create employment opportunities for blind and other severely handicapped individuals by assuring a market for products and services provided by them. and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED SY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act ~ay be cited as the "Employment Opportunities Act of 1978 The purpos~ of this act is to further the pol icy of the District of Columbia to encourage and assist blind and other severely handicapped individuals to achieve maximum oersonal independence through useful and productive gainful employ~ent by assuring an expanded and constant market for blind and other severely handicapped products and services thereby enhancing their dignity and capacity for self- support. Further~ it is the purpose of this act to create employment opportunities for blind and other severely handicapoed tndividuals ~hich enhance training. eva l uati on. 3djust~ent and open ~arket employment for t hose persons #ho become sufficiently capaole \ f 2 ~olled Original cor the purposes of this act a) The term ~bl ind" refers to an individual or class of individuals whose central visual acuity does not exceed 20/200 in tne better eye with correcting lenses or whose visual acuity. if better than 201200~ is accompanied b~ a 1 imit to the field of vision in the better eye to such a degree that its widest diameter subtends an angle of no greater than twenty (20) degrees b) The term •direct labor• includes all work required_ for preparation. processing and packing but not supervision~ administration. inspection and shipping c) The term •qualified nonprofit agency for the bl ind and other severely handicapped" means an agency l) organized under the laws of the United States or of the District of Columbia operated in the interest of blind individuals and other s2verely handicapped and the net income of which does not ensure. in •hole or in part. to the benefit of any shareholder or other individual 2) which complies ~ith any applicaole. occ~pational he·a1 th and safety standard required by the 1 aws of the Unita&amp;lt;:l States ~r of the District of Columoia; and Enrolled Original 3 (3) which in the manufacture of products and i n the provision of service (whether or not the products or services are procured under this act) during the fiscal year employs blind and other severely handicapped individuals for not less than seventy-five per centum (75 of the person-hours of direct labor r~quired for the ~anufacture or provision of the products or services d) The term •severely handicapped• means any person (other tha~ a blind person as. heretofore defined ho i s so severely incapacitated by any physical or mental disability that he or she cannot engage in normal competitive employ~ent because of such ~is~bil ity. Sec. 4. Establishment of a Committee for Purchase of a) There is hereby created a Committee for Purchase of Products and Services of the Blind and Other Severely Handicapoed (hereinafter referred to as the "Committee"} to be appointed by the ~ayor of the District of Columbia (hereinafter referred to as the ayor The Committee shall be composed of t~o (2) private citizens conversant with the problems incident to the employment of the bl ind and otner severely handicapped9 two (2) citizens \ I Enrolled Original 4 representing individuals who are handicapped consumers employed in qua1 ified nonprofit agencies for the bl ind and other severely handicapped• two (2) citizens representing the general public and a representative of .each of the following agencies: Directors of the Department of General Services. the Office of Budget and Management Systems 3nd the Department of Human Resources. The members of the Co~mittee shall be appointed by the Mayor for a term of four years and shall not serve beyond the expiration of their term: EXCEPT~ That of tne six (o) private citizen members first appointed• two (2) shall be appointed for a term of two (Z) years. two (2) shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years and two (2) shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years, as designated by the Mayor at the time of apoointment. The members of the Committee shall designate one (l) of their number to be chairperson b) Any private citizen member, apoointed under subse&amp;lt;:tion (a) of this act to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for •hich his or her predecessor •as appointed. shall be appoin~ed only for the re~ainder of sucn term c embers of the Committee shall serve witnout compensation other than reimbursement for axpenses actually incurred in connection with the work of the Committee. Enrol led Or i ginal 5 d) Sub j ect to such ru1es as may be adopted by tne Committee, the Mayor may appoint and fix the pay of any personnel which the Committee determines is necessary to ass i st it in carrying out its duties and po~ers under this act. {e) The Committee ITTay secure directly from any agency of the District of Columbia government (hereinafter referred to as "Oistrict government information ~hich the Committee deems necessary to carry out this act. Upon request of the chairperson of the Committee, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Committee f) The Committee shall, not later than ninety (90) days following the close of eacn fiscal year, transmit to the Mayor and to the Council of the District of Columbia (hereinafter referred to as the "Council a report which sha l l include 1) the names of the Committee members serving in the preceding fiscal year 2) the dates of Committee meetings in that year 3) a description of its activities under this act in that year a list of contracts awarded under this act and tne recipients thereof; and (5) any recommendations for changes in tnis act ~hich it determines are necessary. Sec. 5. Duties and Powers of the Committee a) The duties of the Committee shal l be as fo l lows: \ \ i J I \ I J Enrolled Original 6 (l) to determine the prica of all products manufactured and services provided by the bl ind and other severely handicapped and offered for sale to the various agencies of the District government by any qualified nonprofit agency for the blind and other severely handicapped. The price shall be set to recover the cost of raw 11ateri·als for the workshops, labor. overhead and delivery costs. but shall not include profit Z) to revise such prices from time to time in accordance with changing cost factors; and (3) to make such rules and regulations regarding specificatians. ti~e of delivery~ authori~ation of a central nonprofit agency to facilitate ~he distribution of orders among agencies for the blind and other severely handic3pped 3nd other relevant matters of procedure as shall be necess~ry to carry out the purposes of this act b) The Committee shall establish and puol ish a list of products produced by any qualified nonprofit agency for the Olind and other severely handicapped and the services provided by any such agency ~hie~ the Committee determines 3re suitable for procurement by agencies of the District government pursuant to this act. This procurement 1 ist and revisions thereof shall be distributad to all purchasing officers of the Qistrict government. 7 (a) If any agency of the Di strict government intends to procure any product or service on the procurement 1 ist. t hat agency shall. in accordance with rules and regulations not contrary to ~he procurement laws and rules and regulations of the District of Columbia and of the Committee. procure such product or service. at the price established by the Committee. from a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind and other severely handicapped if the product or service is available ~ithin the period required by that agency and if the product meets the minimum quality standards requir~d by the agency: PROVIOEO That this act shall not apply in any cases where products or_ services are a a i 1 able for procurement from any agency of the District government and procurement therefrom is required under the provisions of any law in effect on the date of enactTient of this act. These procurement actions shall not abrogate any existing contractual agreements for goods or services but shall only 3pply after the termination of existing contractual agreements b) In furthering the purposes of this act and in contributing to the economy of the District 9overnment. it is the i ntent of t~e Council that there be close cooperati on Enrolled Original r 8 oetween- the Committee and any agency of the District government from ~hich procurement of products or services is required under the provisions of any law in effect on the date of enactment of this act. The Committee and any such agency of the District government are authorized to enter into such contractual agreements. cooperative working relationships or other arrangements as may be determined to oe necessary for effective coordination and efficient realization of the objectives of this act and any other law requiring procurement of products or services from any agency of the District government. Sec. 1. Effective Date This act shall take ~ffect as provided for acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 60Z(c)(l) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act Oac lt;ec Na: BILL 2 -151 .rt::st u.di:g Ac cn: JULY 11, 1978 CJ. vorcz voTZ: BY MAJORITY 2abs BARRY, HARDY i I I I I J I I T 1 1JI jJ/'4/ J ·Sec:ec:a. r r ea i::e C.:iu l Q R.OU C.A VOTZ: CAUltCI lt 1111 •c• I c 4.a 'P I I J \1.-c:&amp;amp C c• I I r I f. v. J i u.c::i c ecJ1t t •P't 1 l a I TUC:-c I I I !I MASON I I I I 11 s u~D;C 1 I I I i I I I I ii MCOR1 o. 1 I I I :I r scN I 1 I I I 3.4 U I I I il ~ol{CC I I I ii lf f'!Z3. I I I I I C U \Z I I I I I OI \ I I I I :t I I I I 1 .o:crc~ I I I I :I c 1 I r I :j I I I I I J 411 r::U GU ft 7 ot• A. 3 1 lsRU T lt;et t.11 I 0 VO!Cl on il~ON 11-0.CO 0. ii MCC I ii ADOPTED tJNANIMOU5;.Y ALL PRES c:;f s rn 111 1Jf_u;AA Sec;et:i-1 e ~u ci lt au c::a LA c 1 1 ll c c i r1e 1 lt lt;l 9•c 1 1 c:c I M cr 3 {c amp 7'4C \ I \ J Docket No BILL 2-151 Pl"esen:ed to t:le Ma.yor: AUG 14 1979 Secretary tQ' che CoWlcil ActiotYoi t~e ~a.·1or 1 7 AUG 1978 ~pproved: I I Ois•?proved LJ Disapproved in part Rete:-enc:e Ooc:u:nent Budget Ac:d.o:u LI Retur ed With.out Action c:utive Sec:reta:y, D. C E iacted without M.a.yor1 s Sig atu Secretary to he C.;uncil Council Re-,nac l.ent: I I VOICE von I I ROLL CAl..L von c:11u"cn amp;Jo•CJll I I v. j ii c:u,.c:1 lt ecit I AT'C I I I a.:I cou,.c:i Oo•Cl'I I I J j TUCAZ-°' I I j I JI ~L.\.SON I I I I llS?A.CJ'l..DL.'iG I I I I H.Ut.DY I I I I II MOO!U D. I I f I 11,~i.I..SCN I I I I 3.A tY I I I I ii MOOR.i I I I I !jW!NTZ.3. I I I I c t.A Cl..te I I I I ~ROLA I I I I I I I I I ·ocroN I I I I II s c lt;I.Z-:ON I I I I 11 I I I I X 11111111:111• 701• A a f•l c Scaeta.ry eo he Cou.r:.cil P-ruented to the P eside.e.t: Sec:rei:a.ry :o e c~u:ic:il Ac:tioc o esider.i LI Reen.a.c:tment ApprQ'V111d o Submitted ~o the Congress: SEP s 1979 Resolution N1i l; e Senate A.&amp;lt cn House Ac i.oi:i Resolution Nu.r be Cle:k of ~e House j D. C. U.w No. E ec:ive Ca.ee</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-301"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-302"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-303"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-304"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-305"/>
  </section>
</document>
