<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-130">
  <num type="law">2-130</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Renters and Homeowners Tax Reduction Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-130.pdf">D.C. Law 2-130</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 2517</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-130, the “District of Columbia Renters and Homeowners Tax Reduction Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-318, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 27, 1978 and July 25, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 30, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-268 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF TBE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 2-130 •oistrict of Col1IJ11bia Renters and Homeowners Tax Reduction Act of 1978• Pursuant to Section 41 2 of the District of Columbia Self- Joverment and Governnental Reorganization Act, P. L 93- 198 the Act t he Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No 2-318, on first and second r eadings June 27 1978 and July 25 1978 respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor o n August 30, 1978, this legislation was assigned Act No. 2-268, publish ed in the September 22, 197 8, edition of the D.C. Register Vol. 25, page 2517) and trallSlllitted t o Congress on January 18, 1979 fo r a 30- day review, in accordance with Section 602 cl (1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives no t ice that t he 30- day Congre ssional Review Period has expired, and, t herefo r e, ci tes the following legi s lation a s o.c. Law 2-130 effective March 3, 1979. \ t AR.RINGTO \ D{ON Oia i rnan of t he C uncil Dates Counted Du r i ng the 30- day Congressional Review Per iod: Janua i:y 18, 19, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 29 30 31 February l, 2, S, 6 7, 8, 9, 13 14, 15, 16, 20 21, 22, 23 26 27 28 March l, 2 Znrolled Or1gioal W 130 MAR \I 1!79 AN ACT To 2-268 JN THE COUNCIL OF THE OISTRICT OF COLU"BIA increase tne sin9le-fa111ily resi dential real property t•x ption; to classify rea l property in t he Oistr ict of Colul9llla for purposes of establishing real property tax r ates; to provide an e1tpanded property tax credit for certain renters and homeowners i n t he District of Colu•bla o and for other pu r poses BE IT ENACTED BY THE COU ~C IL OF THE DlST~ICT OF COLU ~B IA. That this act •ay be cited as the oistrict of Columbia Renters and Homeowners Tax Reduction Act of l97e Sec z. For the purposes of this act a) Tne term condominium• means the ownership of a single d •e lling unit In a horizontal property regime b T~a ta r coope rative nousing association ean s a n associat ion wnetner Incor porated or unincorporated orga nized for the pu r pose of own i ng and operating residential real p r ope rty in the District of Columb ia tne shareho lders or aeabers of which. Dy r eason of tneir o wne rsni p of a stoc k or IH•bershi p certificate. a propr ietary l ease or other evidence of memoersn ip are entitl ed to occupy a d welling un i t pursuan t to the terms of a proprietar y lease or occupancy agreenent z cJ The term dwelling unit• means any room or group of roo~s for~ing a single unit which is used or intended to be used for l ivi n g, sleeping and the preparation and eating of eals and which is located witnin a building which is who lly or partially used or intended to b e used for living and sleeping by human occupants d) The ters •nor i z on tal property regime• s nal l have the aning g iven that term by s ec ti on 5-903 of the o.c Code el The term •non-transient• means occupancy of a dwelling unit or units by any per son(SI for a period of more than five (5) consecutive days during any one stay in su ch unit(S f) The term •s ingle fa~ily resi d ential property mea ns real prope~ty i~proved by a dwelling unit nicn is used excl us ive ly for non-transient residential purposes and wh i ch contains not more than one Ill dwelli ng unit whether as a row. d etached or semi-detached structure• or as a single condo~inium unit wl tnin a horizontal property regime. Sec. 3 The Oistrict of Columbia Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved Septenber 3 1974 (9 8 Stat l OS l; o. c. Cod e 47-621 et seQ•I is amended as follows a Sect i on ~12 (O. c Code. s ec 7-63Zl is a~ended t o r ead a s fo 11 gt;ws 3 The Council. after public nearing. snall by .ct estaolisn each year. within twenty days after the receipt of the Mayor•s recom~endation under section ~13e rates of taxation by class as set forth in section ~7- 632a of the o.c. Code which, excapt as provided In section ~31 shall be applied. during the tax year. to th• assessed value of all real prooerty subject to t axation. The Council• acting by resolution ay extend the time for setting the r ates of taxation. I f the Council does extend the tiee for setting tne rates of taxation of real p r operty it ~ust establish tnose rates for the year. If the Council does not estaolisn the rates of taxation of real property 1111itt1in twenty days and ooes not extend the time for sett ing tne rat es tne rates of taxation o f real pr~perty submitted by the ~ayor pursuant t o section ~13 shall be the rates of taxation of real property bl Section ~13 (O.c. Code. sec 7-6331 is a~ended to reao as follows 1a1 By July 1 of each year the ~ayor shall calculate and submit to the Counc i l proposed real property tax rates f o r the tax year: PROVIDED. fnat for the tax year beg inning Jul y 1. 1978 and for eacn tax year tnereafter tne Mayor s hall c alculate and submit to Znrclled Original the Council proposed real property tax ~ates to be •PPli~d to the classes of real property set forth in section •7-632a(b The Mayor snail infor• the Council of his or her certification of the assessment roll pursuant to section ~l-6~6( g The ~ayor •ay extend the period for sub•itting such recc endation bl At the ti~e t he Maydr sub~its to t he Counci l the p roposed real property tax rates u nder subsect i on t•I of this section• he or she s na il also suomit the followin cp •tll The total aggregate assessed value of taxable real property for the year preceding t ne tax yea r for which the rates are oeing recommended. listing fo r t a x years oegi nn i ng on or after July 1 1978 the val ue s of sucn propert ies ~v class as set f o r th in secti on ~7-632a(b 1 21 The esti•ated total aqgregate assessed value of taxable real property for the tax yea r for whi ch the property tax rates are oei ng recommanded listing• for tax years beg inning on o r after July 1, 1978 the va lues of sucn p r operties oy class a s set f orth i n section ~7-632a(b) and ind icati ng separ a te l y for each class tne estimated value• if any at tr ibutao l e to new construct ion; ltii-011ed Original 5 J) For real property tax years beginning July t. 1978 and succeeding tax years. the real 4 property tax rates (rounded to the nearest penny) calculated to yield .in the tax year th~ sa~e amount of revenue (exclusive of the revenue attributable to ne• construction) as was raised by that tax at the rate or rates applicable during the preceding tax year. plus a percentage of such revenue equal to the percentage change between the consu~er price index for the first calendar year preceding the tax year and the consumer price index for the second calendar year preceding the tax year. The consu~er price index referred to in th~ preceding sentence snail be the annual average Washington• o.c all items consumer price index. for all urban consumers• as published by the Bureau of Laoor Statistics of the u.s. Depart~ent of Labor c) The rates of taxation for real property submitted by the Mayor pursuant to subsection (b)(3l shall become the real property tax rates applicaole during t:te tax year for which tney are submitted unless the Council acts to set diffarent rates pursuant to section 47-632 I l:zirollod Original -6 di On or before February 1 of each year• t"'9 yor snail est i •ate as closely as possiole the rates of ta••tlon for real property to oe calculated in 5ubsectlon (b)(3J of this section and shall so infor111 the Council cl Sect I on 26( i O.c. Cod sec. 4T-61ob( ill is Sec. 4. Section 303(aJ of Tne Revenue Act of 1976 (O.c. Law 1-TO; o. c. Code• sec. lt7-b32a(al) Is a111ended as follows a) Subsection (a) is a111ended t o read as follows I The Council snall estaolisn different categories of real property for ourposes of setting the rates of t a •ation thereon bl Subsection (DI is redesignated as subsection (dl and the following new suosections (DI a nd (cl a r e inserted in lieu t hereo f to read as follo•s b) For t he property ta• yea r beginning July 1. 1978 and end ing on June 30. 197 9 the following cateqo ries of real property ar! estaolisned for real property tax purposes. including tne setting of rates of taaati on aoplicable to e acn cate9o ry c11 Class One Pr~perty Class One prooerty shall oe coMprised of single family residential property Earolled Original -1- and real property, owned by a cooperative housing •ssociation and operated for residential purposes c21 Class Two Property Class Two prope~y shall be comprised of all real property which is not Class One property cc&amp;gt; The Mayor aay require an owner of real property to submit inforaation that the Mayor bel ieves will assist in determin i ng tne cl a ssifications under subsection (D) of this s ection. The Mayor may prescriDe the t i111e a nd manner for submitting t his information Sec. 5 Secti on l01(c) of the Ren tal H9using •ct of 1977 10.c Law Z- 54 is a111ended to reaa as follows cc) Tenants receiving r enta l supple~n~s under this title s na il also be eligible to r ecei ve a tax credit under tne provisions of section 8 of t he District of Co l umbia Income a nd Francnise Tax Act of 1947 (O Code• s ec. 47-15679 P~OVIDEO, HOkEV ER t That said tenants are otherwise eligible unaer tne provisi ons of said Act to rec eive such tax credit Sec. 6 Section 8 of title Vt o f the District of Columbia Income and Franchise Tax Act of 1947, approve~ July 16 1947 (88 Stat. 1060; o c Code. sec 4 7- l S&amp;amp;7g is a~ended as follows a) Subsection (a) i s a :11ena ea to read as fol lows r I lcl'olled Original -a I) For purposes of providing relief to certain District of Colu.c&amp;gt;i• r•sidents wno own their c princlp•l plac• of residence •nd who reside in the sane. an incone tax c red it shall be •11owed to the eligible clai•ant eQua1 to the amount by which all or a portion of real property taxes the taxpa yer pays on nis or her principal place of residence for tne taxanle year. exceeds a percentage (as deter•in•d under subsection (a)(Z) of this section) of his or ner nousehold g ross inco•e for that year. District of Columoia residents who rent their principal place of residence. wno r~side in the sane and who are eligible cl•imants under tn.J provisions of this section. shall oe all o wed an income tax cred it equal to the amount by which rent paid constituting prooerty taxes. deeme d for tne purposes of tnis subsect ion to be l S~ of r ent on his or her principal place of res ide nce for t he taxable year ex ceeds a pe rcentge (as deternined under subsection (al(ZI of this sect ion of his or her household g ross income for that year and which e•ceeds the amount of any rental supplement payments• received by t he c laimant pur suant to the provisi ons of Title III of t ne Rental Housing Act of 19770 duri ng tnat yea r 4 4 l:arolled Original 31, 1977. the percentage required under parag raph (1) o f this subsection to be determine d for claimants other percentage specified i n the follo~ing table If House'1o1 d itllL.lnco so 12.999 •sr.ooo 19 999 •s1s ooo 120 000 -10- J:nrolled Original rax Credit f!l li: 95l of prope rty tax• exceeding l.Sl of nouse'1old i nc:o- 7St of property tax• exc eeding 2. oz of household in co- 75l of property tax exc eed ing 2.5~ of house'1old inco111e 75t of property tax~ ex=eeding 3.oz of household income 75% of property tax• exceeding 3.5% of housenold income 75~ of p r operty tax• e xceeding oz of nouse hold inc:ooie o r r ent paid constituting p r operty tax (15% of r ent 1( 3 1 For taxable years ginn ing after Dece~ber 31. 1977• th• percentage required under oaragrapn (11 to be deter•lned for elderly. Ol i nd o r disabled claimants shall oe tne percentage spec:ifiea in tne followin g taole If nousehold gross inco•e is: Jlai.olled Ori~!n~l -11- The credit snail equal the a..ount of property taxes paid or rent paid constituting property taxes (l5l of rent) which is in excess of the follo~ing percentage of househo l d g r oss income under Sit,999 •ss.ooo to s9,999 •s10,ooo to s1~.999 •s1s.ooo to s2 0.ooo 1.ox le5l z.ox z.si a tl All eligible claimants who rent their principal place of residence no resi de in the same and who receive rental supole~ents u nder the provisions of Title III of t he Rental Housing Act of 1977• snail, when co•puting their inco•e tax credit pursuant to this section• deduct from the a•ount of said credit tne total a•ount of rental supple•ents received during tne taxable year. The amount of credit whi ch is in excess of an y rental supplements received shall constitute tne eligible cla imant's total income tax credit under this Jl:lnoolled Original -1z- section. If the a111&amp;lt;&amp;gt;unt of rental suppleMtnts received exceeds the ainount of credit cal culated under th·is section• then the eligible clai•ant•s ~redit shall equal zero b) Subsection (b)(l)(A) is aaended by deleting the phrase •cnot including relief or credit granted under this section and inserting in lieu thereof the following cnot including relief or credit granted under this section or any rental supple.ent provided under authority of Title Ill of the Rental Housing Act of 1~77 cl Subsection (D)(7 as adde~ oy o.c. Law z-~s. sec b is amend,ed to reacr as follows 7)(A) the term •disabled claimant• ineans a c la imant unaol e t o e ngage in an y g ainful activity by reason of a ~edically determinable physical or menta l impa i n1e nt wni ch can be expected t:&amp;gt; result in deatn or wnicn nas lasted or can De e•pected to last for a continuous period of not less than twelve (12) months. Certification of such phys ical or ~ental iinpairment shall be attested to by a licensed pnysican selected by the c lai•ant at his or her own e•pense. Suen c laims and certification shal l be submitted in such for and in sucn ~anner and at such time as tne Mayor shall pres c ribe olled Original -13- In tne event that the Mayor shall determin• that clal• mad• under the provisions of this 4 sul&amp;gt;Section is unsubst.antiated by available evidence• the Nayar eay requir• the clai•ant t o be exaained by a licensed pnysl cian cnosen oy tne "ayor at the expens• of the District of Co lu..cia govern~ent d) Subsection (b)(S) is amended by deleting t he words •or on behalf of• in the first sentence andt in the thir d sentence by ins•rtin9 tne phrase •renta l suoplements obtained under tne p rov isi ons of Title III of the Rental Housing Act of 1977• i~madiately prior to tne phrase advance rental payments for another period e) The first sentence of subsect ion (e) is amended to r ead a!I follows Beginning with calendar year 1977 and f or eac h succeeding calendar year. if a claimant o wns and occupies his or ner no~e in the Di s trict on December 31 of any sucn year p r operty taxes accrued means real property taxes (exclusive of s pecia l assessments. interest on a delinquency in payM!nt of tax. and penalties and services c na r ges) as reflected on the District r e a l estate tax bill or dinarily sent out in Sept e moer of sucn year: PROVIDED. HOWEVER. That any amount of real property tax defer r ed under tne ltirolled Original -14- provisions of sections 47-655 or 47-656 sh•ll oe of deter•in ing tne credit allowable under this section Sec. 7. The Residential Prooerty Tax Relief Act of 1977• effective February 28. 1978 10.c. La• Z-4S is amended as follows a) Section 2 Is amended by rltdesignating current suosecti ons (11 and (2) as (a) and (bl• respectively b l Section 3 is amended as follows l) Suosactlon (b) is amen~ed by deleting the phrase •six thousand dollars (16t000 and inserting in lieu thereof the phrase •ni ne thousand dollars (59 ,000 Z) Subsection (C)(l I is ended by deleting tne onrase •and for each ta• year thereafter 3) Suosections (cl(Z) and (c)(3) are r edesignated as (c)(3) and (c l r espect ive ly, a nd a new suosection (Cl (21 is added to read as fol lows Z) For t he purpose of co•puting taxes on real p r operty In the District of Colu•Dia for the ta• year commencing July l, 1918 and for each year thereafter. the Mayor shall deduct from the estimated •arket value of residential real property owned by a cooper ative hous ing association ana occupied by tne Zllrolled Orig~al 15- M!•bers of such association the amount of eighteen SMrcent (18 of the estimated •arket value of said property; PROVIDED1 HOWEVER, That the deduction •ay not exceed the al90unt of nine thousand dollars {S91000) 9ultiplied by the nu11lber of d•elli ng units n ich are t he princ ipal place of residence of .11esoers of s uch as soc i at ion cl Sec tion b Is amended by redesignating subsec tions (11 Z) and (3) as (a O) and (Cl• r espectively Sec. s. The Hayor shall publish in the Di stri c t of Columbia Register and local newspapers the tax assess~ent s for each year and that tax rate (rounded to nearest penny) which will bring in the same amount of real estate tax revenues in the upcoming tax year as was produced from the r eal estate tax in the i~mediately preceding rea l estate tax year. excluding new construction. Sec. 9 This act shall take effect as provided for acts of t ne Council of the District of Col u mbia in section 60Z{ c ll of t he District of Colu•bia Self-Gov e rnment and Governmental Reorganization Act.</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
