<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-149">
  <num type="law">2-149</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-149.pdf">D.C. Law 2-149</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 7035</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-149 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-372, which was referred to the Committee on Transportation and Environmental Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 28, 1978 and December 12, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-338 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNC I L Of THE DISTRICT OE' CO!.OMBIA NOTICE D. C LAW 2 14 9 "Surveyor User Charges Act of 1978" Purs uant to Section 412 of t he Distr ict of Columbia Self- Govermrent and Governmental Reo r gani zation Ac t, P L 93- 198 the Act the Council of the Distric t of Columbia adopted Sill io 2- 37 2, on first and second re adings rovember 28 197 8 and Decer.i- ber .l 2 1978 respectively f ollowing the signature of the Mayor on December 29 1978, thi s legi s la tion was ass i.gn ea Act No 2-338, publ i s hed in the January 26 1979 ed itio~ of tile D. c. Register Vo l 25 p age 7035) and transmi tt ed to Cong~ess on January 18 1979 Eo r a 30- day· review in accordance with Sectior. 602 (c)(l) of t he Act he Coun::il of the Distr ict o f Co lumbia t.ereby gives notice that the JO- day Congress ion al Review E'e riod has expil::i?d an&amp;lt;l thOrP.Eo re cites the folle&amp;lt 1ng l egislat ion as D. C. Law 2-149 effect ive March 3, 1979. Dates Counted Dur ing the 30- day Congressional Review Period January Feb r ua ry March 18 19, 22 23 24 25 26 29 30, 31 1 2, 5 6 7 8 9 13 14 15, 16, 20 21 22 23 26 27 28 1, 2 D.C. lAW 2 14 9 1 MAR 0 3 197g 2-338 I~ THE CC UNC IL JF THE DISTRICT JF CJL UMBl 1978 i o 0111 c.n c c r o author i ze the Mayor to revi s e the schedu la o f fee s cur r ently char ~ed for s e rvices r ende red Dy tne Surveyor of the District of Columbi a and to estaol isn fees for ne~ services; to provide that certain ser vices ba pr:&amp;gt;vided by applicants for survey s under tne ~irect i on of the Off i ce of t he Surve yor: t o provi de for t he re f unding of f ees paid f o r servi ces no~ r endered Dy the Offi ce o f tne Su rveyor; anj for utner pur poses BE lT ENACTED 8Y THE cou~CIL OF THE otsrqr:r OF COLUMBIA. Tha t thi s act ~ay oe c itad a s the •S ur ve yo r J se r Cnaryas Act of 1978 Sec z. Section 1593 of the Act e ntitled •Ar Act to Establisn a Code of La for the District of Colu~b ia iipp r ovad 'Hlrch 3 190 1 (31 Sta t l42b; o c Cod e, sec l- 1&amp;gt;2 q) is aine ndP.d to read as fol l o s iec 1593 a) The 11ayor of the Di stric t of Columb i a i s ner eD y authorized to revise as r~cess~ry tha sc~edule of fees to be charged for servi ~as rendered by the Sur veyor o f the District of Columoi Such fees shal I De established by the Mayo r in sucn ilmount s as in his judgt1ent ill be co&amp;lt;nmens urate with the 1:o st to the Dist rict o f Columbia f or p rov iding the servi 1:es rende r ed by tne Qff ic a of the Surveyor Jo t i ce of an·1 revi sion 2 of the sch~dJl e of fees shal l oe pJOlisheu in ac~o r oance ith t~e pr ovi sions of the Dis tri ct of Col umoia ~anini s trative Procedure Act an j in addition s1all oe filej ith t he Counci l of the Ji$trict of Co lumb ia t le3st thirty (30) days prior to t he ir effective date Th 2 s c"le:lule of fees eS tdl'l l ishe&amp;lt;1 b y th l gt;yor sh dl I ie jVdil a~ l e f o r inspect ion i n t he ic e or tne Surve y r b l Jf tne Offi c e of tne 5Jrvevor is unao l e to conplete and record any su rvey wit~ in ninet y t 90) jJy~ af ter ritten request fo r tne s urv y i s fi le t,e Surv eyor sha11 not ify the applic Ant for the surv~ y of the sstina ted aace when the surve y will oe oerformed a no su~n app l ica,t Y at h i s e1ectl on eit ner reaffir m ni~ r e1uest fo r th fflce of tne Surv e yor to perforn the survey or ~itnar~w hi s r eques t f o r t~e su rvey ~nd re~u est in wri ting a fJl I refur1d &amp;lt;&amp;gt; f the t oes pai~ t o tne Sur vuyor ny aoplicant includin; dn appl icant wno nas su~sect i nn m~y emp loy a t his ~x~e nse a req istereo la~d surv9 yo r t:&amp;gt; perform th su rva y. Sue r e9 1 sten~o l ~nJ su rvo ynr emo loyea pu r sua nt to thi s suosact ion shgll oe rf:i rn tne surv ay under t ne d ir ec tion of an1 i n accorcJ i11c&amp;lt;i wit, prnced.ires &amp;lt gt;St~hl iShe&amp;lt;.1 t&amp;gt;y the S&amp;lt;&amp;gt;r v:i y:ir 3- fhis subsect io" shall not aooly to dny d~par tmenr ag1ncy of th~ governTient of t he Oist ri :t of Co lumbi a c) F~r the pu rpos es of t ~is secti on a regi stered land surveyor sha ll mean 3ny oe rson or fi rm approved and per~itted bv the Office of the Surveyjr to reo a re ~nd certify surve ys ~nd suna ivision olJts in t ne Ji st ri=t of :o l umo i;i includin3 nu t not li ;nite tJ to reqi s t e raa c ivil e "gineers T"e Su rveyor is a~cnor i£ej to est3b l isn and enfo r ce scanoa r ,s ana operJ~ i 11q ;i r.&amp;gt;c ed11ri?S fo r t ie perform.:ince at su rv&amp;lt;~v s l&amp;gt;Y r eq iste r e:1 land s urveyo rs unaer subse ction (bl of tnis s e= t io·1. Tne Su rv~yor is fu rther autnor izan to estaol i sn ~nd •aonta in a list of appr oveo r e 1i&amp;amp;tered l anJ surveyor s ~ho ma y oe u til ired ~y aoplic~n ts fo r surv3ys pu rs~ ant co suo~ ecti on (b) of t~is s tion lt; c: I ru l e 1n:1 re~u l ~tions as may he essary to C3 rry ou t the Ju rp~ses o f tn is s ic ti on Sec J Tnis ~c t Sh311 take ef f ect as provi d in sect ion ~02 (c) o f the Dis tric t of Colu~Dia Se lf-Governnent 3n j Go ver nTient~l Raor qanila tion ~ct I:od:e o No: Sill 2-3 72 November 2 8, 1978 1~ voic c7 i c t J'I ~l l y I l .a I T C I f j I 11 1~CN I I I I ii S?Atr.J..Or:NC j I I 1 I I I I I ~A'.CO l. I I I I lt V SON I I I I I 3 j I I I l cco I I I ii W!N t Ao J I I I I t 3.0L\ 1 c c c t t J-.f i.t c c r i rit l 1 1 t c c O 1 l r l 1 1C 3~0 t is t:r c;c Ii tee D. 1- jW l'TZ 31 dcil l e=g i \c:LJa: Decembe r l2, 1978 voici: vO Ado ted Unanimoual I I ~OLL CAl..L von 1 IL 1 1 1 =w c l T i cu t 1 1 I C ° 3 I I j C SC:'I I I I i }3 \C I I f I p.coc o. I I j~:u sc I ccltct No: Bill 2 372 9!8l T T:i a t ec-:e f tQ t c cc cil L I s re 41c i gt;a 2~e!.e~e icc ~O&amp;lt e t St c fi Ac:i gt;~J UY o! t c ~Oi:J&amp;lt c: oi {~&amp;gt r 2 9 JE~ 1978 E e 1 ivc: Sc c::t y U C 2..c:.cC 'Nit l.eut }.U.yo s S ia.t Sc Qry e Co il I c cr ll"llt T j 1 ii c t i 6'ftl I 0:;\11&amp;lt;o&amp;lt;I I I o.'l 1 I ii L.t..S O i s 1..D.i s~ce n.c an soh le Nu-~c </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
