<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-16">
  <num type="law">2-16</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-09-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-16.pdf">D.C. Law 2-16</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3336</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-16 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-77, which was referred to the Committee on Advisory Neighborhood Commissions. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 17, 1977 and May 31, 1977, respectively. Enacted without signature by the Mayor on June 22, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-49 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE October 4, 1977 D.C. Law 2-16 11Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1977 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act PL 93-198) the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-77 on first and second readings May 17, 1977 and 1· t f f t i f ¥Y·HY I L i r t May 31, 1977, respectively. Following expiration of the ten-day period provided the Mayor, in which no action was taken, pursuant to Section 404(e) of the Act, this legislation was assigned Act No. 2-49, published in the July 8, 1977, edition of the D.C. Register and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore cites the following legislation as o.c. Law 2-16, effective Septe~~er 20 uck1 f the Council (Vol. 24, D.C. Register, 223, July 8, 1977 t t F i i r F L\ OH r f ft O.C. LAW 2-16 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF CJLU~8IA September zo, 1977 To provide for the appointment of individuals to fill vacancies on Advisory Neighborhood Com~issions. BE IT ENACTED SY THE COUNCIL O~ THE DISTRICT OF COLUMEIAt That this act may be cited as the "Advisory ~eighborhood Commissions Act of 1977 Sec. 2. The Advisory Neighborhood Counci l s Act of 1975, ef~ective October 10, 1975 (O.C. Law 1-21) is amended as follows a) Section Z is renumbered subsection 2(a) and a new subsection 2(b) is added to read as follows b) Oef initions. For the purposes of this act l) The term •removal' means the process by which the qualified electors of the District of Colu~bia may call for a vote of an Advisory Neighborhood Commission to remove or retain one of it members prior to the expiration of his or her term r -2 2) Tb.e terQ 'appoint~e?lt ~r:cedu:e' ceans the process by ~hich a vacancy on an Ad~isotr ~eighborhood Co~:issioc ~ay be filled b) Sect ion 8 is alilended as f cllo 'JS 1} subsection (c) is amenC.ed to read as f ollO'JS {c) No oe~ber i:lay represent a Siegle Meober District Eor ior&amp;lt than t"'o (2 onsecutive ter:s, e:.ccept that the portion of a ter~ served by a ~e~~e= as the result of a S?ecial elec~io: er as the result cf ac arpoint~ent to office s~a.ll not be considered in coi:q:uti11 he tilo {2 consecutivP. ter~s 2) subsection (d} is a:i~na.ee to read as fol.lows d} (1) liueaever any vacancy ia office due to deach, r~signation, failure to continue t~e sualifications for office under secticn 6 (a) of this act, e= re1:1oval exists wichin an Advisory Neighborhood Co~mi~sion 1 such vacancy shall te filled pursuant to subparagrap 5) of this subsection (d 2) Withi.n sixty (60) days c! the date that the Boa.rd of Elections and Zth.i s declai:es 1 pu lica tion in the District cf Colu~oia aeqister, t!at s~ch a vacancy exists, tbe Gffice of the Advisory ~eigh~c=~cod Coo~ission 3- w~arein the vacancy exi~ts shall fill s~c~ vacancy by the appointment procedure of paragraph 8 (d) {5) of this act 3) Said individual shall :ie~t the GUalifications set teeth in section 6 (a) of t~is act 4) Said individual sba.ll fill sucb. vacancy uotil a successor has been certified and svcrn in pursuant to s.:ction 8 of this act. 11 (5 a thin five (5) wor~ir.g days (excluding Sdturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays) a!ter the date that the ~oacd declar~s such vacanc7 br ~ublicaticn in the District of Colu:bia aegiste t~e Boar: shall cake available p~titions fct t~e ?Urpose o! cctaiJing the signat u:es of tegisteted electors withic the res?ective Single ~e~ter Oistric iithin thirty (30) days indi1iduals intacested in filling such vacancy shall su=~it a petition to the aoa:d contaicing the sig~atures cf thirty-five (35) of the ragistared electors •ithin the Single ~e~~er District. The aoard after a. ten (iO) day challe!lge period sna.l.l transuiit a list cf the na~es of i.i:div:.duals qualifying for appoint:ent to the respective Adviscr7 seigh=crhood Coo~ission he Advisory Neigbborbood Co:mission shall appoint, after a public ~ea.ri!lg and any cthe= ef!orts designed t~ elicit the preierence of the vc~e=s of the af!ected Single ~e~ber District, by ~ajcr~ty vote o f the i~olled Origi:al 4- r~maining b~rs, an incividual froc the said list to fill the v~cancy at its next regular Qeeting 3) A nev subsection (f) is added to reaa as follows f 1) Any mecber of an Ad viscry Neighborhood Co~:iissioo •ho resigns from the Single ~e::i.ber District E=oc •hich he or she is elected shall sub~it a copy oi the lett:r o: resigna~ion to (A) the Board of Elections and Etbics 3) the Central ~dvisory Heighbcrhood Com~issions Office. a {C) t~e Chairperson of t~e Qember•s Advisory N~i;hborhood ~o~~issioo. The District of Colu~~ia Soard of !lcctio~s and ~tnics shall then dEclare the vacancy ~s p~escribed in sec~icn 8(d) of this act 2 hen a vacanc7 occurs on aD Advisory Nei;h~or~ood Commission and no letter of resig~atio~ is su.bci t ted as required by su~ pa raqra ph 1) of this section the respec~ive Advisory ~eighborhood Cciaission snall petit~on t~e Dist=ic~ cf Colu:bia Board of Elections and £th.ics, by a resolution si~:e 1 the Chairman and the Secretary of the Advisory N~igtborhood Comcissioc, to d~ci~re the vacaricy. T~o resolution, accompanied by ~inut2s oi tAe e~i at VAicb ~he resolution ~as adopted and a li.st of t~ose attendi.:g t~e :i-aeting, shall te sent to A} ll 0 ed Ori 1 -C lt;Wf;9 -5- tJ~ Oi~trict o; Colu~bia coard of Elections a~d Ethics and (9) th~ Central Advisoty 3~ighborbood CcmQissioQS Office 3 A) Any qualified electcr ay itllin a ten (10 day ~eriod, challenge the validity of t!ie rasolution filed under su~section (2) of this section, by a ~rittcn state~ent duly sig:ed by tle challenget, filed with tee District of Colu~bia Soard of Elections and Ethics and S?ccityi:ig coacisalv the allegitl defects in said resolution. A copy of th~ challeng!d state~ent shall be sent by t!ie Oist;ict of Colu a Soard of Elections a~d ~thics to the Cbair?e:son of the petitioning Advisory !leigh:cr~ood COQ:Jission a) Th.e District of Colui!tbia Soard of Elections ar.d Ethics shall receive evidence in support of and in O?position to the challenge and shall deter~i~e the validity of the challenge~ resolution tot ccre t~an t~irty (3 0) days after the c~alle~ge has been file ithin three (3 days aft~r the a~nounce~eat of the deter:inatioc of the District of Coluwbia Seard of Electiocs and Etbics ~ith res?ect to the validity o! the resoluticn either t~e cha l ler.qer or the aftected Single ~ember Di!trict Coom i ssioner may apply to t~e District cf Ccluotia Court of A ~peals for a revie~ of t~e reasonableness of such deter:iina t i er rollee -6 {C be District of Cclu~bia court of Appeals shall expedit~ consiceration of the deter:ination. The decision of sue~ Court shall be final and not appecala!)l e D) If the resolution is found to be valid, then !ha District of Colu~bia aoard of Elections and Ethics shall d~cla=e the vaca~cy as prescribed in sectioc B(d) of this act 4) A nev subsection (g) is added to cead ~s f ollo·•s: 11 (q 1 \~y eober of an Advisory Neig~~orhcod Co:~ission :ay be re~oved ty the registered electors of the Single ~eober District !rom vhich he or she ~as elected ne~ever a petition deQandinq his or her removal signed by ten (10) percent of tbe registered electors, thereof, is filed with the Board. The nucber of reqist~r~d electors whic~ is used for cocputinq tbi~ requireQent s.:iall .te acc.jr:iing to the la.test cfficial count of registered electo~s by the Board vhich was issued thirty (30) or more days prior to subcission of the signatures for the particular recall petition. The Board, after a ten (10) day ehalleng e=iod 1 shail certify and for•a~d the petition to t~e respective Advisory ~eighborhood Co==ission vhich shall d~cide, by a majcrity vote, tc re:cve or retain the 7 e~b~r to ~hich the petition refers. suco action sball be expresse~ i~ th~ forQ cf a resolution of the respective ~dvisory Neigh~othood Comiission signed by the Chair:an aod the Secretary. Sai~ cesolution, accompanied by ;inutes of tne ;eeting at •iiic!l the resolution was adopted and a .list of those attendinq the meeting at ~hich the resolution was acoptcd, shall ba sent to A) the Seard of Elections aad E: t b.i:s and (3) the Ad ·1iso ry ~h!igh gt;orb.ocd Cco::iission o: f ice ne aoard o lections and Etb.ics, attet a ten (10} day chdlleng~ perioc shall t~en declare the vacancy as pr~scrib~d i~ section S(d) of this act 2) A 1:1e:.ber of an Advis·ory Neigllborhood Coo~issior. i~y not be re:ov~d •ithin the fi:st six (6 ont~s nor last six (5) QOnths cf his or her ter~ of of.:ice no itllin six (6) months after an attem?ted re!llo 7 al procadur~ has be~n deter~ined in his or her favor Sac. 3. This act shall take effect as provided for acts of the Council of t:e District of Colu:cia in section 602(c) of the District of Colu~bi'a s l e f-Govero~ent and Govern ntal Reorqanization Act DocketNo 2 7_7 i:st Ruei:g Ac c 5/17 /77 [i VOlCI: VOTI Adouted unaniQjly -LI ROI..L CAU. VOTZ: co CJ c c• I I •AT t I 1 c C••t Ti I a i w~C:\ lt cc Tt 1 r j j VC?.Z I I I I iA.SON I I I q S t n l I l F u:JY I I I I ii ~oo z. i I I I I ·1 ON I I I I t u I 3.r t~ I I I I !l ~{00 Z. J. I I I I U w I I I CLJ Z I I I ~ROI I I l I II I I I I I oz:cc~ I I I j ~I s c rc:-q I I I I I I I x Z:ic.ic amp;J I A. 3 u r le: Vi I A::1endec :n:s: R.e•&amp;amp;g Ac ic I I VCICZ VOT Sec etu·y tc Coi::c l If ROLL CA L VOTZ: TUC:-cr J M.ASON I s c D C I ii cc I iJ 7 SCN I .3.A MCO P' I· j 3. I I er oz u I ii I I Dr:tON s c c I I q I. I GI J f 1 5/31/77 VOICI: VOT Adopted Unanimously If R.OU. CALL VOT c:IU•C1 C~•C.11 I C I r i 1 c=w C:l C••C• I t I \ Ca amp CJt i .re i i 1 I TUC I I I I 'I ~t SON i I I I i-3 r_'\ I I I I H i gt JY I I I I a tcc:u I I I I :1 s 1 I I I I 3 I I I I ~I CC Z I I i :j°.'1 i I I I I CT gt I I I j CLJ I i I I I I I I ·I !lr:tCN I I I I !I s c I I i I .1 I I I I I x c s•&amp;amp ra 4 I 2-77 Docl:et No I hereby certify that Council Bill 2-77 was presented to the ~layor of the District of Columbia on June 6 1 1977 and that the Mayor neither approved nor disapproved the bill within the ten day period specified in Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, Public Law 93-198 of December 24, 1973. LI VOIC VOT Sec::eta o h e C.:i il I I ~O l. CAL.I. VC-:Z I f I c u,.c t u:;11 I i: I I" I v. I c c l-11:11 I I I c:~1.1,.c I u i I I AS;N I I I I 1lS?Ai: L.l i C I i 1 I f r DY I I I I ij MCO Z D. I I f I i v SCX I i i I I l I I I M co z I I I I 'l r i -r I I I I I 3 Y I I CLJ KZ I I I j I 0 r\ K i I I I I l I P resented to t.~e P:es i ce:.t: Action o! t e P:-es i e e LI Reena.c e.:t A;&amp;gt;?rOYeli If M:Lyor' s Veto S1J.st:a.i:.ed Se!\&amp;amp;te .Ac:tion Resolution Nu iDer Secr e:a y o! t:e Se:a.t~ D. C. u w (\o. E ec ivi: O:.i.t c Sec::e y to i.e C 1.1 c:il P:-esiC:e oi t.i. S. Ho~.se A.c:t:on R.eso b ti c IJ e Cle:k o l e H'c:us e</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
