<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-2">
  <num type="law">2-2</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-09-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-2.pdf">D.C. Law 2-2</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3341</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE June 17, 1977 D. C LAW 2- 2 Closing of the Public Alley Syst em in Square 551 Act of 1977 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act the Counc i l of the District of Columbia adopt ed Bi ll No 2- 66 on firs t and second readings March 8, 1977 and March 22, 1977, respectively Following the signature of the Mayor on April 4, 1977 this legisla t ion was assigned Act No 2-21 publ i shed in t he ~pril 22, 1977 1 edition of t he O.C Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30- cay review, in accordance with Section 602(c)(l) of the Act. The Council o f the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, tberefore, cites the following legislation as c Law 2-2 effective June 11, 1977 1 f/ I 1 I t;t::L -L-·f hiRLING ~KE; Chairman o~ the Council Vol 23 c Rcgi ster ,8193 April 22 1977 O. C. LAW 2-2 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA June 11 1977 To order the c l osing of the pub li c a lley sy s tem i n Squar e 551 bounded by Florida Avenue lst o, 3rd and R Street s N. W S O. 74- 152 BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DI STRICT OF COLUMBIA, Tha t thi s act may be c i tod as the Closing of t he Publ ic Alley System in Square 551 Act of 1977 Sec 2 The Counc il of the Di s t ri ct of Columbia finds that a) A publi c heari ng was held on November 9 1976 conce r ning the proposed c losi ng of the pub li c a lley s ystem in Square 551, bounded by Flo rida Avenue 1s t Q, 3 rd and R S treets N. w. as s hown on a plat o n f il e in the Office of the Surve yor o f t he Di stri c t of Columbia (S. o. 74-157 and (b) The Counci l of the Dis tri c t of Co l umbia ha v i ng consi de r ed the pr o~o sed c l os ing is of t he op ini on t hat the public a lley areas refer red to i n s ubsection (a) should be c losed Sec 3 No twithstandi ng the p rovisions o f The Street Re~djustment Act o f the Distr ict o f Columbi a appro ve d December 15 1932 (47 St at 747; o. c. Code SPC 7-401 et Ollod Orieina1 seq as amended by, the Emergency st::eet and Alley Closing Act of 1976, effective December 29 1976 (Act 1-104 the public alley areas as shown on the plat filed in the office of the surveyor of the District of Columbia (S. o. 74-152) are hereby ordered closed, PROVIDED that sa·id order is subject to the condition that the Mount Sinai Baptist Church located on Lot 230 in Square 551 shall be frovided with continued utility service, including water sewer electrical gas and telephone services without any unreasonable interruption, and PROVIDED further that the District of Columbia reserves a 10 foot vide easement over the entire 110 foot long by 10 foot vide east-vest public alley located in the southwestern quadrant cf Square 551 and abutting on Lots 230, 826 828, 870 87 1, 905 906, and 907. Pursuant to such easemen no buildings er ether structures may be located vithin. the 10 foot vide easea:ent and the existing right-of-way of the east-west public alley shall not be physically closed to pedestrian and vehicular traffic without the prior approval of the chairman cf the Board of Trustees of Mount Sinai Baptist Church or a~y subsequent owner or trustee of Lot 230 Said ease~ent shall automatically terminate upon the occurrence of any of the following events ll:orolled Original 3 (a) the sale or transfer to or acquisition by the Department of Housing and Community Development of the 110 foot long by 5 foot vide porthern half of the east-vest public alley area to be closed b) the sale or transfer to the .tlcunt Sinai Baptist Church or any subsequent ovner cf Lot 230 of the 110 foot long by 5 foot vide southern half o~.tbe east-vest public alley area to be cl~sed c) the demolition of the e xisting structure l ocated on Lot 230 in Square 551 or (d) the receipt by the Surveycr of the District of Columbia of a written document signed by the Chairman of the Board of Trustees of the Mount Sinai Baptist Church or any subsequent ovner or t rustee of Lot 230 in Square 551 and stating that the r eservation of said easement is DO longer necessary Sec. 4. The Surve yor of the District of Columbia shall record the easement provided for in section 3 of this act on t he ~ppropriate plat on file in the Office of the Surveyor of the District of Columbia (S. o 74-152 Sec. 5. Immediately after the effective date of this act, the surveyor of the District of Co lum bia shall cause a public notice of this order concerning the closing of the public alley area to be given by advertiseoent and shall ollOd Or iginal 4 serve a copy of the order on each property cwner abutting the public alley areas to be closed in accordance with the procedures set forth in s ection 4 of The Street Readjustment Act of the District of Columbia approved Decembe r 15, 1932 (4 7 Stat. 749 D.C Code, sec 7- 404 Sec. 6. If no objection, in writing is made by any inte rested party withi n t hirty (30) days ,after the s ervice of the order referred to in s ection s of this act, the surveyor of the District of Columbia shall record in his office the order a.nd appropriate plat or plats. Sec. 7 The Sec retary to the Council of tbe District of Columbia s hall t r ans mit a true a nd accurate ccpy of t hi s act, upon its effective da te, to the surveyor of the District of ~olumbi a \ sec. 8. This act s halJ. t ake effect at the end of the period pr ovided for Congressional re view of acts of the council of the District of COlumbia in s ection 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reo~ganiz a tion let Dockot for the Oilf 2 6_6 Con;:J1:rcd in Council Fi~t Vote 3/_S 7_7 RECORD OF COUNCIL VOTE ec;uuc:1~ M C ntA AYC HAY H.V u. I COUHCH. MCMOCM I AYC I HAY N,V, A.O. couucu. M(MnC:n AH N.V. A I TUCY.ER I I HOBSON I I SPAULDING HARDY MOORE, D. I I WILSON BARRY I II MOORE, J. I jWINTER I CLARKE I I ROLARK II I I I DlXON i &amp;amp;-I.A.CKIEIDN I X-locilcal Vote E i,oen l. V~Not Voti:ig IX /VOICE VOTE: l O Ir f n-.11) 1101.rtN.!A 3/8/77' Adopted unanimously Secretary of the Council date vote result Final Vote m Council 3/22/77 R 'EC 0 RD OF COUNCIL VOTE I c:ouNc1~ Mt~1e:cR I amp;.YE c4Y H.v.1 A.a. O eotJNCH 4~!oo!aCR I t I NAT I s.v. I s. l~ couNca M£ O£t:t I AY-£ j NAY i N.v. f j TUCKER ·I I I I llHOBSQN I I I iiSPAULDL'iG I I I I HARDY I I I I II M00RE, D I I NILSON I I I I BARRY I l 1 I ii MOORE, J. I I I I j!W1 {TER I I I I CLARKE I I I I II ROL1 RK T- I 1 f I I I I I DIXON I I I I II SACKLETCN I r I I I I I I I X-lJlc!iCG Vote 3 bse:it N. V.-No! Vot g /X/VO!CE VOTE 3/22/77 AdoEted unanimously (date vote result} Presented to the Mayor MAR 2 4 1977 Mayor's Ac:ion c 4APR W1 Approved Disapproved En~ctcd without Moyor's Si~n~turn 1-ai!l1tb.a lt Secretary o i the Ccur.ci l Secretary of the Coundl l!4zl Mayor's Signarurel Secretory of the Council I I i I I I .</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
