<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-32">
  <num type="law">2-32</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-10-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-32.pdf">D.C. Law 2-32</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3725</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-32 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-107, which was referred to the Committee on Employment and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first and second readings on June 28, 1977, July 12, 1977 and July 26, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 17, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-78 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• 17 COUNCIL OF THE DJSTRICT OJ: c OLUMBlA. I NOTICE Nocember 3, 1977 D. C. LAW 2-32 "Diauict al Col\IJ!lbia Depo•itory kt of 1977 Pur•u.ant to Section 412 of the Di•trict of Colwnbia SeU- Government and Qovenunental Reorganization Act PL 93-198) the A.ct, the Council of the Dhtriet of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-107 on first, Amended first, and •econd readings June 28, 1977, July 1.2, 1977, and July Z6, 1977, respectively. FollowiJlg the i gnatw'e of the Mayor on Augu.st 17, 1977, thi1 legillation wa1 a1ai gned Ac:t No, 2-78, pabli1hed in the September 16, 1977, edition o! the D. C. Regiater and tran1mitted to botb ~ou of Congress !or a 30- day review, iA accordance with Section 602 (c)(l} of the Act. The Cowu:il of the Di•trict of Columbia hereby 1iive1 notice that the 30-day Coqresaiou.al review period has ezpired and, tbere fore, cit.a the foll~ leghl&amp;amp;tion aa D. C. I.Aw 2-32, eHective October 26, 1977. the Council (Vol. 24, D. C. Register, 2036, September 16, 1977) o.c LAW IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBI A OCTOBER 26• 1977 To select private financial institutions to be depositories for Distr i ct funds; to maxlmi le earnings on public f unds in a manner to bene fit District cit izens who trad itionally have not had access to conventional credit a nd t o stimulate the economy of the Dist r ict BE IT ENACTED BY THE COU~CIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU ~e!A, Tha t t his act may oe cited as t he Distri ct of Col umbia De posi tory Act of 1977 Sec. 2 Def initions For the purposes of this act a dverage demand depos i t balance" means the daily ave r 3ge. computed monthly• of the Dis tri ct s demand depos i ts ~ith a depository b} Board of Appeals and Rev ie means t he board estab li shed under Organizational Order Number 11z. dated Au 1ust 11 1955 C com~unity credit union eans a financial institution chartered and insured by the National Credit Union Administrat ion and serving des ignated geog raphi cal areas •ithin the Distr ict d} council means the Council of the Di strict o f ~o l umbia Drolled Or1aiiia1· 2 (e default or insolvency• aea ns either: I 1) tlae inability or fail11re of a designated de posi tocy to repay an r public de posit upon de1aod or at aatarity; or (2) t he acknovledgeaent by a designated depository of such inability or failure to repay; er (J) the issuance of an order fro• the apftopriate regulatory ageacy advis iag a stipulated regulatory aqency to arrange for the s uperv ision of the portfclic cf a depository •hicb falls under subsection (e 1) or (e) 12 fl "deaand deposit" aeans public funds exclusi ve of any savi ngs deposit 1 vhich are held by a designated depository subject to 11i thd ra val upon de aa nd by the Distric t or upon a cbec~ or warrant of the District g District• aeans the District of Ccluabia govern•eot or any a qE:DCJ, bo.a.rd coaaissioo, iastitutica coaa ittee office, officer or instraaentalitJ thereof; or, if required by the context, U.e ord oistrict eans t he geographical area of tile Di•trict of Co laabia. Chl •eligibl e depository" aeaas any co a11ercial bank, savings and loan association, or credit unicn vbicb is ins11red b y t11e Pederal gover11 aeat pur suant to chapter 16 of t itle 12 of the United States Code (64 Stat. 873) and vhos e aain office is lcx:ated in the District. Enrolled Origin.al 3 (i eaploy•ent practices eans the r•cord of e•pl~f•eot of •inority persons and •oaen defined by tbe !qnal ployaeat Opportunity let of 19i2 (86 stat. 103 j fillllncial serri.ces ans those setYices noraally perforaed by a deaand depository in connection with the reteatioa of deaand deposits, inclading but not liaited to check payaeot, check cleariag, the reconciliation of accounts, check printing, the collection and transfer of taxes and fees, 11.iqht depository ser•ices and such other serYices as •ar be necessary for the efficient utilization of public funds. {k installaent credit" aeans any perscnal loan of eight thousand dollars 8,000) or less, aade to an indiYidual District resident and payable in install1ents for tbe purchase of consaaer durables or ser•ices or for personal expenses (excluding ~o i1proweaents, hoae rehabilitatioa, personal lines of credit, and student loans 1 interest diYidend rate bid" leans tbe interest offered to be paid on a sa•inqs deposit bf ao eligible depository coapnted froa the dar of d•po•it to the day of withdrawal of such deposit and subject to appropriate federal requireaents Drolled Orig1Dal 4 loan ori9ioation ean s the place•ent and extension of credit directly t o a borr.o •er n llayor• Mans the 11aror of tbe District of Colu•bia established under section 421 (a) of tbe District of Colu bia Self-GoYerannt and Go•ern•eo.tal aeorgaDizaticn Act, a ppro•ed Dece abe r 24, 1973 (87 Stat 789 c .c. Code, sec. 1- 16 1 (a or the !la yor 1 s desi9nee o eoderately-priced bousinq lean" eeaos aoy loan to 1) a prospectiYe owner-occupant fer the purchase of a building containing one (1) to fcor (4) residential nnits in the District selling at or belcv cne hundred and twenty percent (1201) cf the eedian s alE price for s uch housing sold in the District, accordiog to tbe latest data aYailable fro• the llaycr for aa entire calEodar year; or (2) a prospective owner-occu pant cf r eal property io the Di~trict for tbe construction cf a buildi ng contaioio9 one (1) to four (4) residential units in the District lliaq at or below one hundred and t11enty percent (1201) of t eedian sale price for socb bcosing sold in t~e Distri~t, aa:ordinq t o tile latest data a•ailatle fr o• the 1ayor for an eA~ire calendar year; oc (3) ao owner of real propettf in the Dist r ict f o r tae rehabilitation of a buildin9 contaioin9 one (1) to f o ur 5 (4) residential units in a loan a•ount not ezceedin q twenty thousand dollars 20,000 p oderately-priced 1olti-fa1ily hoo=:in9 loan" aeans any loan for either l) the purchase er construction cf a boildinq containing fi •e (5) or ore residential units in the District sold at a per unit •alue at or belcv one hundred and tventy percent (120l) of the 1edian sal~ price for all 1ulti-fasily units sold in the District acccrdinq to the latest data a•ailable fro• the !ayor for an entire calendar year or (2) the rehabilitation of a building conta ining fi•e or aore residential un its in the District in a loan aaount not to ezceed fifteen thousand dcllars 15,000) per unit q Clbliqa tions of aqen.cies of the Oni ted States" aeans iustru1ents is.sued by agencies of the Onited States 9o•ern1ent and not directly bf the Oaited Statee Treasury r obliqatious of the District" aeaus obligations issued bf the District pursuant to section~ 461. Q71, Q72, and 490 of the District of Coluabia Self-Gc•ernaent and Gc•ernaeutal Reorganization Act, appro•ed DEcEaber 24, 1913 (87 Stat. 804, 806 and 809; D.C. Code, secs. 47-241, 47-247, 47-248, and 47-254 zlrolle4 Ori11Aa1 6 (s obligation of tile Dnited States govern•ent" ae ans aa instruaent of the Dnited States futlic debt that is issaed bf the Dnited States Treasur7 and fully backed by the Daited States qovernaent, inclgdinq United StatEs Treasury Bills, United States ~reasury lotes. and United States Trea s ury Bonds t Office of the Dis trict of Co lullbia laditor" aeans that office as established unde&amp;lt;r section llSS of the District of Calu•bia Self-Governaent and Goyern•ental 9eorgani zation l et, approved Dece•ber 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 803 o.c. Code sec. u7-120J uJ public funds eans all •onies belcngi r.q to or under the contro l of the District, including tat not lieit ~d to the federal payeent, federal grants, taxe fees, spec i al assesseeats. all other eonies received froe the federal governaent and eonies paid to or received by a court agency or instru•entality of the District, or fro• any other soarce: PROYIDBD, BOUEY!R, That before Octoter 1, 1978 the ter pablic fonds• do~ oot ill lude peosioo funds held by tbe District and: PBO~D!D, POBTR!P, That notbinq in this act shall be coostrued to require the reinfest•ent of securities owned by a pension fund on Se~te•ber 30, 1978 and: PROVID!D, FOBTB!i, Tbat the ter public fund does l!!nrolled Origiual 7 11.ot include tbe pension funds for the public !chool teacher s of t be nistrict T repurchase aqree•ents eans the sale or purchase of securities subject to tbe condition tbat, after a stated period of tiae, the oriqinal seller i ll buy bacK such securities at an agreed price plus interest at an agreed r ate v sari.oqs deposit" 1eans any public funds vh.icb are held by a depository and upon which a diTid•nd or i ntere st is paid. The ter saTings deposit" includes, inter alia, those instruaents ccaaonly known as tiae certificates of depos it tiae deposits share deposi ts, share certific ate accounts, open accounts, and saYings depcsits X s •all busines~ loan" aeans a lean tc a busines s whose principle place ot business is in tbe District 1) tor secured loans not to ezceed a total of f i e ~nndr~ tbonsutd dollars (SS00,000) during tbe Fre•ious calendar 7ear; or (2) for a loan guaranteed by the United States S•all Business ldainistrati on y stodent loan" aeans any loan tc a tli!ti:ict resident enrolled part-tiae or foll-ti1e in an institution of higb~r­ education to pro•ide for tbe costs dir~ctlr l'•lated to the resident's education. l depository s participation i n a Enrolled Origi:lal. 8 studeat loaa poolinq arraage11ent shall be credited to the depository accordiaq to its pro rata share in the pool. Sec. 3. {nvest•ent of Public Pynds {a) The !ayor shall i avest or deposit all FUblic funds received vbich are not required to be disbursed i aaediatelr. The investaeats or deposits shall have the loaqest aa turities possible under the circu•stance&amp;amp JPCVIO!D, That the period the aayor aay bold aa iavestaeat in an obliqation of the Onited States qovern•ent o r its ageacies and/or in repurchase aqree aeats shall aot erceed ninety-one (91) days PROVIDED, l'URTH?B, That to the •a•i ua erteot practicable the !ayor shall iavest public funds i.11 sa vings deposits b) Public funds aay be invested in obligations of tbe United States qovernaent or its agencies directly or throuqb repurchase agreements or depo sited in eligible depositories in accordance with this act. sec. 4. Sel1ctjon .21-Q!tl!Qsitori!UJ_J!~A!Sstaea l!­ (a} Sbort-ter• deposits and iaves t•ents short-ter• deposit or aa iavest•ent cf ninety-one (91 dars or less shall be made on the basis of tbe bi9best i oterest rate yield available at tbat tiat for a siailar i oYestaeot peraitted aoder tbis act and ia a aanner hroll&amp;amp;4 Original 9 co nsistent with liquidity and s afety. To tbe a t i 1 u1 e i t ent possib le, consistent witb the highest interEst ratE yield and the inten t of this legislation, the Rayer s hall atilite the eYaloatioo criteria in secti on S (a) cf this act t o sel ect fina ncial institutions for short-ter inYest aents b) Teri deposits All ter1 deposits e t ceedinq ninetr-cne (91) days shall be placed with depositories in the following 1a11Der 11 !qual a1ounts, not in e xcess ct cne bondred thousand dollars 100 000 shall tE offered to be deposited in eacb co111 unity credit unic n at rates o f interest equal t o eac h credit union s current share deposit interest r ate: PROYID!C, HO iEV ER That the a scuot on defOSit in any single co 11nnity credit 11nion a t any ti•E pursuant to tbis subsection shall not exceed one hundred thousand dollars Sl 00 000 Deposits 1ade pursuant te this s11bsection 1ay be aaintained in the cc11unity credit union after their oriqinal 1aturitJ regar dless ot whether any other Distric t funds are placed t!Htrein fo r t eca deposit 2) Of any re1aioin9 fuads aYailatle for ter1 deposit, not less th aa one-thi rd (1 /3) of the total a 1ouat of eac h solicitation f or the placeaeat c f tEr• depe~its SQall be set aside for the two (2) highest ran~iag sa•iaqs and loan associatio11s and tbe two (2) bi9best raokicq lnrolled Original 10 coa•ercial banks, based on the criteria in section S(a) of tais act, vhich bid oD the solicitation 3) Tke taror shall solicit interest rate bids not less tban three (J) veeks before the dead1ine for tbe submission of the bids. The &amp;amp;ayor shall set forth the term of the proposed deposit, the ai ni•u• acceptable rate o! interest for deposits placed io oon-coa•uoitJ credit unions and sawinqs and loan associations, and the aini aua acceptable rate of interest for depos its placed in co••erc ia l banks. fij) I depository shall subait interest dividend rate bids settin9 f crth the ainiaua and aasiaua a acunt of deposits i t ill accept. In addition, deposi tories shall sub•it in the f or• regni.red by the !ayor inforaation necessary for ranking bidders in accordance vitb the c riteria in section 5(a) of this act 5) The District shall deposit ooe-fcurth (1/Q) of the foods set-aside pursuant to para9raFb (2} in each of the two (2) hi9best ranting sawings and lean a2!0ciation s and each of tbe two (2) highest ranking cc•rercial bank based oa the criteria iA section 5 (a) of thi! act, sub•ittioq ao interes~ di• ideod rate hid equal to or greater than tbe District' s applicable •iaiaua acceptatle bid: PBOYID!D, ROl!VER, That the deposit shall aot be in esce of tbe l!!nrolled Original 11 •axi •u ollllt bid by tJae depo•itory. X•terest on deposits of funds set-aside porsullllt to paragraph (2) sllali be at the applicable lli.ni•n• acceptable interest rate regardless of the depositorr•s interest diYideod rate bid 6) fhe funds not set-aside end a•J f~nds set- aside pui:suant to paragraph (2) of this sabsection (b) bat not deposited pursoant to section 4(b 5) ahall be placed in the deposit ories slll&amp;gt;lli.tting interest. diYidend rate bids equal to or greater than tile applicable aioi acceptable rates of interest so as to yiel d the •asi•U• retara to the District: PBOVID!D, BOl!V!B, That no depository i1creasio9 its score less tllan two (2) percenta.qe points ill each eategor:y i n section 5(a of this act for each c ai eodar year after 1977 shall be e ligible tor &amp;amp;DJ deposit. tbE depcaitories recei Ying funds set-aside pa.rsuant to paragraph f2 sbal l be considered f or non-set-aside deposits at their interes t diYidend rate bid for aaouots bJ •bich their MZi•ua bid exceeds depo•its •ade parsaant to paragraph (5) of this subsectio11 (bl 1) Ia tlle e•eot that two (2) bid• are identical, tbe institati.011 raaked bi9heat parsaa•t to tbe ci:iteria in section S(a) of this act •hall be 9iwea ptecedeaee for tbe rd c) De•&amp;amp;Dd deposits Bil.rolled Original 12 (1) The eayor shall pro•ulgate a list of financia l ser•ices required to be perforaed bJ de aand dEposit ories in connection itla the retention of deposits Tlae 8ayor shall conduct public hearings concerning vbich of the financial services shall be set-aside for award only t o t he highest ranking co ercial banks based. on the e.,aluati cn criteria in section 5 (a) of this act. lfter the putlic hearing and prior to the solicitation of any bid for placing demand deposits, the eayor shall deteraine which financial services s hall be set-aside. The set-aside shall prcvide that one- third (1/3) of the public funds be deposited on an annual basis pursuant to set-aside contracts 2) Not later than Dece• ber 1, 1911, unl ess an earlier date is set ty the Bayor, and at inter.,al s of not longer than eYery three (3) years therEaftEr, each co••ercia! bank desiring to bid for the placeaent o f de•and deposits slaall s@ait the inf ormation in tlae fcra r equired by the Bayor, Decessary for ranking the perfcr•ance of eoaaeccial baaks in accordance Mith the evalua tion criteria ia sec~ioD S(a) of this act. The Bayor shall gi•e notice in tae Qistrict of Coluabia Regi~!J: o f the cank in9 of all coaaercial banks subaitti119 i 11Cor•aticn prier to aolicitinq bids for placing de•and deposits. 13 (3) lll coaaercial bank depositori~s aar be ran~~d in the first ranking by the ayor pursuant to section 1 c 2) of this act 4) Not less than two (2) aonths prier to the deadline for the subaission of bids for the placeaent of d~•and deposits, the ayor shall solicit bids tor the performance of those financial services set-aside pursuant to section 4(c 1) of this act fro• the tvc (2) ceaaercial banks ranked highest pursuant to sectico 4 (c) 121 of this act and shall solicit bids fro• all coa•ercial tank depositories for the reaaining financial services. the solicitation shall reguest bids to provide financial services for three (J) years 5) The bids subaitted shall stat~ the cost to the District in teras of beth the payaent fer financial services and the aaintenance of coapensating balance The bid solicitation aar require bids on either single financial services or groups of financial services 6) The award of the financial services set-aside pursuant to section 4(c 1) of t.bis act and of those not set-aside shall be aade basEd on the lcvest eoEt to the District: PROVIDED, BOiEVER, That the cest to the District of specific financial ser~ices vithin the s•t-aEide portion shall not ezceed one hundred and seYenty-five percent (175 Enrolled Original 14 of the cost to the District of identified financial r•ices awar~ed oa aon-set-asid• bids rec•i••d in tile sa solicitation and: PBOYil&amp;gt;IO. P08%BIR, Taat the sayor sball select not le than tllree (3) d Dd depositories for the Distri ct and •ball deposit flUlds •itll those depositories according to the following tiaetable l) tbe first deposit witbia cne bundred and eightf (180) days after tbe effectiwe date cf this act B) the second deposit vitlli.n tvo hundred and se•eaty (270) days after the effecti•e date of this act; aad (C) the tbiJ;d deposit within three haudred and sizty (360) days after tae •ffecti date of tais act. Of the abo•e aentioned depositories at least one of the first two (2) shall be a depcsitcry with a set- asid• pursuant to section 4(c)(1) of this act 7) l o award to a coaaercial baDk aaf be de unless that bant•s aluation score pursuant to section 5(a) of this act has increased by fiYe (5) percentage points in eaca e•alaatioa category for each three (3) year period aft81 ti. fii"•t ra11kin9 8 Ia the e•uat that t•o 121 bids are identical tk• depository ranked bigbest pursuant to section 5(a) of tkis act shall be gi••n preoedeaee for tbe a•ara Bl:ll'olled Original 15 (d) Hotvithstaodin9 any other pro9iSioo of this section, oo depository shall be required to e%cEEd a score of fifty percent (SOS) iu each of the eTaluaticn criteria in section 5(a) of this act. sec. S. ETaluation_frite,ia a) The ranking of depositories shall be aade based on the aTerage of the three (3) follovin9 catE9ories 1) two (2) year loan originaticn for qualifying loans, as defined in subsection (b) of this section, e%pressed as a percentage of total loans originated 2) outstanding loans to an individual District resident or a business whose priaary place ct business is in the District expressed as a percentage cf tctal deposits at the end of the preTious calendar year; and {3) eaploy•ent practices e%pressin9 the aTerage nnaber of ainority persons a~d woaen in 1ana9eaent le•el positions and on the board of directors as a FErcentage of tile total n~ber of such positions and toard seats, respectiTel7, for an eligible depository during the previous calendar year bl Qualifyinq loans shall be cot~rised cf 1) all •oderately-priced housing leans; lnl'olled 01-iginal. 16 (2) all aoderately-priced housing loans on houses priced at or below eighty percent (801 of the aedian sales price for those houses iD the District 3) all student lous 4) all s aall business loans 5) all installaent credit leans 6) all aoderately-priced au lti-falilJ hcu::ing loans 7) all o bligations of tbe District 8) all eliqible rehabilitaticn leans for a ter• of teo (10) years or long er 9) all eligi~le aortgaqe lcacs fer oderately- priced ho using or olti-faa ily units for a ter• of twenty- fi'le (25) years or loDqer; and 10) all eligible nall business leans f or fi•e (5) years or longer. Sec. 6. Liaitation OD Q~~gi Eatlic lands OD D9posit. ro~withstaDdiDg any other pro•ision of tbis act, Do depository shall at •DJ ti ba'le OD d•FO•it public funds in an aaoont ezceeding th• lesser of (1 D aacaDt equal to t wenty-fi•e percent (251) o! tbe total assEts, eKclasi•e of public fuods, of socb depository, or (2) an aaouot equal to nrolled Original 17 twenty-five percent (25 of the total ~ublic funds of the District on/or available for deposit duting the fiscal year sec. 7 ollateral Required Opon Oetosit ~f Public f'und s a) wo collateral shall be required tor any depcsit t o the extent that the defosit is fully insured ty an agenc y of the United States govern•ent, but if requited the collateral shall be received by tbe ~ayor at the close at tbe b~siness day on •b ich the deposit is made b amp;ny public funds on deposit in excess of the amount i nsured by an agency of the Federal govern•ent shall be fully secured by 1) obligations issued and fully insured or guaranteed by the Onited States or any Onited States govern aen~ agency and obligations of 9o•ern1ent sponsored corporations vbicb under Sfecific statute 1af te accepted as security for public funds at 1arket value at par value, whiche ver is lover. at tbe close of business co the day previous to their placeeent as collateral 2) obligatioos insured or 9uacantEed bf an aqenc1 of the United states governaeat or a District agency at a value equal to the aeovnt of the insurance e r qoaraotee la:rolled or1g1Dal 18 PROfIDEI&amp;gt That iusvred aortgages sball te secured b7 property located iu taE District c ach eligible depository shall sobait with its bid the financial iltforaation and reports the !a7or detErmiues are necessary to e•alaate the condition of each eligible depository: PRO VlD!t, That no e ligitlE depcsitory shall be required to suba i t infor•atio n ~nd reports not aa de public under Federal re gulati cus. DepositoriES s hall ke ef current the i nformation required to be subaitted undet th is subsection and shall iaaedi ately no t ifl the Mayer of any change which causes deposi t s to exceed the liai tat ion in section 6 of this act d) No depository shall be enti tled to the r e t urn o f colla teral except apon the repayaent of the public fund s on deposit with such depository: PROVID!t, BOIEV!B, That any depos itor! 11a7, with the appro •al of tbe fta7or, s ubstitute different and acceptable collateral of the tn:e s pecified in subsection (b) of this sec t ion e) Opoa the insol•enc7 or default cf atJ depositorJ, the Di~trict shall be entitled t o s aeh cf the collateral as 1 be necessarJ to recover all pnblic fund• on deposit wi th such depositorJ, aet of such public funds as aa7 be ful l y insured bJ an aqencJ of the Federal qo•ernaent. Bach depository shall, at the ti9e of the deFcsit of collateral Enrolled Or1g1na1 19 deliYer to the eayor a power of attorney authori zing hi or her to transfer any securities or any part thereof for tbe purpose of reparin9 any deposit •adE under this act f) 1othing in t his section shall be cc11strued as liai.tinq any right of the District to sbare in any distribution of tae assets of any depositor1 to the extent that the public funds co deposit at the tiae of tb e depository's default or iasol•eacy exceed the net proc eeds of the collateral. Sec. 8 f ubl ic p isclosyre a) All bids and information suba itted ty eligibl~ de positories to tbe 8ayor pursuant to this act shall also be subaitted to the Office of the District of Coloabia Auditor b) lll such bids and infor•ation shall be a•ailable f or public inspection and reproduction durirg regular working boors at the offices of the !ayor and the District of Colnabia auditor c) lithia ten (10) days after tbe last day of eac h ealead~r aooth and whenever requested by th ayor or the District of coluabia luditor, eacb depcsitory receiYioq public funds sball sabait to tbe ftayor and to the Office of the District of ColU•bia Auditor a written leFOtt, ander oatb, indicatioq Drolled Or1giaal 20 l) tbe total aaoant of pablic fnnds beld by it at t be close of business on t he last banking day in the on th 2) the a •erilge daily balance for the 1ontb of illl public funds held bJ it during the 1c11tb l) il detailed schedule of pledged ccllateral at its •alue for the purpose of collateral at th e clcse of business on the last banking da y in the 1onth; and (14) any other infoniation that aay be reguired by the eayor wit h respect to public funds d) The !ayor shall quarterly report tc tbe Council conc erning which depcsitories hold public funds, tbe a mounts of public funds and the interest dividend rate bid for each indi •idual depository e} The !ayor shall ha e a•ailatle for FUblic inspection t he free balances and s bort- ter a in estaentl! at tbe close of busi ness on tbe pr e ious day f} The Bayor shall identify in•est ae ats of pension fund asse t s. See 9. Ter1 i oatioa of pepositori!.§ a } lay deposi t ory •hicb aisrep rese ots e ny aa t etial i Dforea tioo required tc be subaitted pur sua nt to this act sbalL be tera ina ted as a depository by tbe !ayor and shall 21 be ineligible as a depcsitorr for public funds for a period of not less than t•o (2) rears bl ADJ de•and depository which is unable t o provide fioancial services pursuant to its couttaet or bid s hall be t eraina t ed or refused a contract as a deaa.nd depository by the !layer c) The ~ayor shall, prior to ter•inatiuq or r e fusinq a contract pursuant t o this sectioA, provide the affect.ed depository and the Office of the District ct Colu•bia Auditor with the follovin9 written iofctaatioo 1) the proposed date of the teraiuaticn or refusal 2) the specifi c r eason to r the teraioati cn or refusal 3) the riqbt of the affec ted depcsitorr tc appeal the propo~ed terainaticn or refusal to the Eoard of Appeals and Bevie• within one (1 eek of recei~t bl that depository of the notice to ter•ioate or the refusal d) The Bayor 1ay, upon a written dEter1ioation that the interests of the District require the i11ediate vitbdrava l of p11blic funds, withdraw the public funds iaaediatelJ after a proper notice is sob•itted to the afi«cted depository aod the Office of the District of Coluatia Auditor. JCnrolle4 Ol'ig!nai' 22 (e amp;fter recei•in9 notice of a vitbdraval under s ubsection (d) of this section, the af tected depository is entitled to a hearinq by the Board of Appeals a nd Be ie withi n three (3) days following the receipt of such notice (exclasi• e of Satordays, Sund ays and bclidays and of any coat inuance(s) which •aY be requested bJ s ach depcsitory lny notice of an i ed iate withdrawal shall state clearly t be eight of t he affected depository tc ba•E a t earing by the Soard of Appeals and Re• iew vitbio tbcee (3) business days following the receipt of such notice f) The District o f colu• bia Aud itor aay i a tet•ene as an independent party to the dispute, in any bear ing before the Boa r d of Appeals and Review ccncerning any dispute between the l'layor and a depositor y. Sec. io. Poyers of the aa ror and tb~!tt!£S S Cola•bia luditor a) T~e aayor ud the District of Col u1hia auditor are authorized to 1 aka u1d l!llfo r ce re911l a t ie11 nectssary and pcoper to the fqll asad co•plete pecfocaance cf bis or her respectiYe functions undec this act 2) i nspect and reprodllce all i afcr•at io 11 and docuaeuts i n the posses sion o f a depositor} necessa ry t o BD~olled O?-iginal 23 dete.r::aine coa pliance vitb. and to t:be eoforceaent: of th.ill act a nd (3) perfor• such duties and respoositilities as af be required by this act b) The Dist:rict of Columbia auditor shall be directl y· accountable to the council, thtouqh its Co••itt:ee on E• plo7 aent and Econoaic Developaent fer t he fUtpo~e of: reportinq on t he iapleaentation of this act: tPCVICED That the District o f Colu1bia a udi tor shall fCeFatE and submit to the Council an annual report on the District depository activities i.ncludin9 the ran.king of each institution subaittinq bids for the deposit of putlic toad Sec. 11. Staff a} The Office of the District of Cclu a tia Auditor i s authorized tvo (2) positions to carrf cot th• purposes of this act, toqeth er vitb the necessary supporting facilities b) The coaaitt:ee en E•Floyaent and Eccnoaic Oe~elopment is authorized two (2) staff positions f or the purFoses of coordi~ating tbe i•pleaeQtation of tbi~ act with the Offic~ of the District of colo• bia auditor and cf aa~u•iDq tbe responsibilities specified in t his act. Sec 12. Effecti•e Date. 24 This act shall ta~e effect as prowided to~ acts of the Council in section 602 (CJ 1) of tbe District ct Col uabia Self-GoTeraaeat. aad GoTeruaeatal Reorqa11i%atic11 l et DocllatNo:~2 l_0_7~ Ftr.t a."41q A.eel Tune 28, 1977 ct v01a VOTE• 0 aou. c.u.L. von C c I t J I •11 1 amp;'1' \ 1 Tt1CXZA MA.SON I I s gt un~ING I j t I a.utDY .KOOIU J I WU.SON 1 I I !1..UU MOOIU 1. I ~n I I C:.t..U U: I ltOI..All lt; I I I DrtON i'ACX.U c lt;1 I z-t=t•n y W.Y-.Ha Y l Am•nd-4 Fbo1I R cilq .AcdOla• Tuly 12 1 1977 (E VOlC vcrn Adopted Unanc y (all present liit dWJtt 1 LI llOU. C:ALL VOT u 1 t 1 tc:h.#11 1 n: 1 1 1 nrcx I I I I fMASON I I pAtiUJQiG I I I I I ~¥ I l j I oo&amp;amp;s g, I I I I ltLSON I I I I I A.AlUl.Y I I l I P,o(OOJU I. I I· I n \ I j I I I ex aicz I I I I I llOL.A U I I t I I I I l:lCCCN I I I I IS'Ao;:I t I 1 I l I I tto A t y T I s.cz to cba C c!l n-1 R.adbt or Ema~aqo A&amp;lt;:liola: July 26, 1977 fZj VCXC:I: VO'l'J:a Adopted Unantmol%t!Present) LJ llOU C.A.t.1. VOTJ u l•f"C' t l J 1 I 1 1 C t •rc 1 1 TU'C:la:1l I I I I IMJ..SON I I I I p;&amp;gt; A.ti UlL lt;:G I I I I I KAJUlT I I I IMOOIU C. I I I I IWU.SON I I 1 I I !AJU&amp;gt;.T I I I I MOOJU 1. I I I I l'lr'CNT%1 I I I I I C~B!a: I I I I I llOu.A!&amp;gt I I I I I I I I 1 I CtXOM I I I 1s lt;e:X.U:"M'f I I I I I I I t X-d' d I I \ It I a.cco11LD o r orFICJ:.a.l. coanic:u u:no3 &amp;lt z1 Ooc&amp;amp;.tNo 2 1_0~7 4ej=a.w, ttc n Jlr Hmttd to Ill• Mayor: AUG 3 1977 Actlo11 of lb.e Uyor amp \pprOftd: 0 Dt.fLpp•ned: Q Dl1approTtd IA Lrt 9Jt.atert11c• l BwiJ•t Ac 0 c:i 0-&amp;lt;tl S.cntary c&amp;lt;i tllt C:o uc!l btcutl Seereta.:y, D lt Enacted wtthco.&amp;amp; Mayor 1 SISU&amp;amp;lllU Secrttary to :he COWlcU Caspdl R1ee.&amp;amp;s me11t: It VOIC:t von 0 aou VOTE: 1'1N• en I YI 1 &amp;amp;.If 1 ta'l,.CP 1 l 1 1 ~11 COl!ffl 9 1 n 1 f T v I I I .I MA.SO N I H AJUlY I I I MOOIU o. I 8.AARY I I MOOIU I. I C t..UUa I I l I l.O t..A..11..K f OOCON I I I I Sl~l'=lN I :a A. L Actt.on of th• Pruidf t: LI .a °" Apprw•d 0 W&amp;amp;ya•a V•to S111t&amp;amp;Uaed SoYmttt•d c..rnu s_&amp;amp;_7 l_7_7 .s A.ctiaa ol11ti er S.crotary ol Che S.-te Ellacted Wllhou.t Co11puaioul Acrioll: f I I •t I I 1s~AUI.OLN&amp;lt I I I l f lwtLSOl'&amp;lt; I l I I I ,W?Nn:.a I r I I I i I I I I I I I 1 f Secucary to Ill• C cil Prt1idt11t ol Ill• u. s fM 0,Wr S.cHa.ry to Ill• CO\Uldl K•ae Acl!.011 1.e•olC- Nllmbert Cluk ol tile KG&amp;lt;au I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
