<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-45" flag="true">
  <num type="law">2-45</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1978-02-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-45.pdf">D.C. Law 2-45</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3614</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-45, the “Residential Property Tax Relief Act of 1977,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-127, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, and second readings on June 28, 1977, July 26, 1977 and September 13, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 2, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-96 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE D1STR1CT OF COLU}.1.BL~ NOTICE March 13, 1977 D. C. Law 2-45 "Residential PToperty Tax Relief Act 0£ 1977" Pursuant to Se ction 412 o! the District o! Columbia S e ll- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council o! the Di strict of Columbia adopte d Blll No. 2 tz 7 on first, amended first, and second readings June 28, 1977, July 2 6, 19i7, and September 13, 1977, r espective ly. Following the signature o! the ~yor on November 2, 1977, this legislation was assigned Act No. 2-96, publish ed in the fovember ll, 1977, edition o! the D. C Register and tran smitted to both Hou ses of Congress !or a 30-da y review, in a.ccorda.nc~ with Section 602 (c l) of the Act. The Council of the District o! Columbia h ereby gives notice that the 30-day Coo.are• s ion.al Review P eriod ha• expired and, therefore, cite• th.a followiq legillation a.11 D. C. Law 2 ·45, effective February 28, 1978 j Jl.j STERLING TUlK.E:R ChairmAn of ch' Council (Vol. Z4, D. C. Regi.st er, 3614 Nov e m ber ll, 1977) u LAW IN THE U~CIL ~F THE DI S T~ICT ~F COLU~B IA FEBRU AR1 2 6• 1978 To esta blish a property tax exemption f o r s i ng le-fdmil y r e si1ent i a l •no coope rative ly-owned property in the District o f Col vmo i a a nd to provi de add itional circui t or ~aker relief to homeowners and renters in the Ci str ict of C?lvmbid ~no are over 62 year s of a ge. o li nd or d i saoled 8E I T E~•CTEO BY THE COUNCIL OF THE ~IsTqicT CF COLUMBIA, Th3t t ni s act ~ay oe cit ad a s the "Residential Prop e rty Tax Rel i ef Ac t of 1977 Sec 2. Definitions For the pu r poses o f tnis act l The ter m "s in~ le-fam i l y r e s idential orope rty" means r~al p r ooe rt y impr ov~d by a dwelling wnich is us ed ~xc lusi ve ly for non-transi a nt reside ntial ouroose s and wh l c n c on ta ins not more than one (l) dwelling unit whether dS a row detached or semi-detached structure or as a si nq le condominium unit 1 Z l ne. tera In a declared prooerty reg i me cooperat ive housing assoc iation• means an 1ssoc i ation, whef,ner incorporated or unincorporated• or an ized for the pur pose of owning and operating resi oential real p roperty in the District of Cc&amp;gt;lumoii the s hareho l der s or members of wh icn. by reason of their 'wnersni~ of a stock or memoer~hip certif icate a Ellrolled Origi:e~ proprietary lease or other evidence of memDership. are entitled to occ~py a dwelling uni t pursuant to tha terms of a proprietary lease or occupancy agreement. Sec. J Singl e-Family Res iden~ial and Cooperative Property Tax Exemption a) For the purpose of computing taxes on real property in the District of Co lumbia for the tax year beginning July l• 1977 and ending June 30t 1978• notwithstanding the p r ovisi ons of sect ion 421 of th e ~orstrict of ColumDia Real Property Tax Rev ision Act of 1974 approved SeptemDer 3, 1974 (88 Stat. 1053; o c Cod sec. 47-641 t here shall be deducted from the estimated market value of a s ingl e-family residential propert y the amount of six thousand dollars s6.000 ROVIOcO. HOWEVER That such deduction Shal l not exceed th• esti mat ed market value o f that property D For the purpose o f computing taxes on real property in the Di strict of Colu•Oia f or the tax year beginning July l• 1978 and for each tax year thereafter• notwithstanding the provisions of section 42.l of tne •oistrict of Colu•bia Real Property T Revision Act of 1974 approv~ Septfflber 3. 1974 98 St•t• 10,3; o.c. Cod sec 7-6~1 th•r• sh•ll be deducted fro• the esti•eted rket value o f si n9l e- l' a 111 i l y resi dential property wh ich is th• princ ipal place of r es ide nce of its owner •nd l'ro• tne esti111ated 111arket value Znrolled Orig~ 3 of a residential property with five (5) o r fewer dwelling units whi~h inc l udes the principal place of residence of its o~n•r th• amount of six thousand dollars (S6 oOOOJ PROVIDED• HOWEVER Tha t such deduction s hall not exceed t he est imated market value of th• property. To determine th• owner's pr.incipal place or residence. the ~ayor shall devise a form f or an affidavit and mail it to th• owner along with the noti ce of assessme nt requ ired _under secti on 4Z5 of the "D istrict of Columb i a Real Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 approlfe d Se ptembe r J 1974 (S8 Stat. 1055 o.c. Code sec 47-645 In order to obtain the deduct ion p r ovided under this subsect ion (b the owner shall compl ete the affidavit and r eturn it to the Mayo r within s ixty (60) days o f the date such affidavit form was mailed to the owner. The Mayor may verify the contents o f the affidavit. The Mayor may gra n t a reasonabl e ext e nsion of time. not to exceQ&amp;lt;I six t y (60) days• f or Pil ing the a ffi davit· whenever in his o r her judgftent good cau se e xi sts therefor C)(l) For th• purpose of computing taxes on real property In District of Columbia for the t;ax year commencing Jyly 1, 1977 and for each tax year tn•r••ft•r• the Mayor shall deduct fro• the estimated market value of r•sldential re•l property owne d by a cooperative hous ing assoc iation and occupied by th embers of such association I the amount of twelve perce~t (12 of the es ti mated ~arket va l ue of aid property: PRO•IIOED• HOWEVER That the deduction may not exceed the a1110unt of six t housand dollars (16,000) multiplied by the number of dwelling units which are the principal place of res idence of memt&amp;gt;.rs of such association ZJ In order to obtain the deduction provi ded under this subsection (c) and to determine the principal ?l aca of res idence of members of cooperative housing associations, each member shall, at such times and in such manner as the Mayor shall prescribet complete and return the form of affidavit provided for under subsect ion (b) of this section J The Mayor may require the officers or managers of each cooperative housing association to distribute the a ffidavit forms to its members and to coll.ct the completed affidavits from such members for return to th• Mayor. Such o fficers or managers shall supply s uch other in format ion as 3 Hot•lthst d ing th• provisions of subsection (c)(l of thts .sectiOft :a. for th• tax year commencing J~ly 1 l• 19T1 onty. C bills relat ing to residential real property OMned by cooperative housing associations shall not reflect th• deduction fro• estimated market value pr~vided for in said s ubsect ion (c)(l Such tax bills s~•ll b• paid Enrolled Ori s i nt.he full amount shown ~hereon at 'the times provided f or in sa id subsecti on (c)(l The amount of the deduction shall be deter~i ned by th• Mayor at the earliest p racticable ti me after receipt of the required affidavits and snail be r efunded to the owners o f such property, such refunds to b• made from current real property tax revenues d) In relat i on to property tax bills r~quired to be paid on September L5, 1977 and on ~arch 31, lq 7a by owner s of property eligible for the exemption provided in s u~sec cion a) of th i s sect ion 3 1) The Mayor shall indicate on eac~ tax bill, to t h e extent feasible. th• fact and a~ount of the exemption and snail enclose with such tax bills a notice which incl udes at l east the following information 4) the amount of the deduction 8) tne name of this act and the date on which it was enact.ltd by the Counc il of the District of ColulllOia and (t) the exact amount by which the deduction has red11eed the property owner•s tax bill ZJ Atty -rtg•g• lender. including but not 1 imited to a savin9s and loan association, a coaMercia1 bank. and a Mortgage banker which receives such a property tax bill and pays i t on behalf of the owner of the p roperty in question 6 shall fo r~a rd t o sa id prop e r t y owner no t later t han fou r 4 mont n s a fter t he da te on which t n e property tax payment i s du e A} a copy of said property tax bill; and csr a c opy of th• no~ice required by subsect ion d l) of this section 3 e) In relation to property tax bills required to be pa id after ~arch 31, 1978 the information specified in p aragraphs (d l)(A} and (d l C) o f this sect ion 3 s hal l be incl ude d on the face of each tax bill Notning in this subs~ction (e) shall diminish th• duty o f th• Mayor to Include an explanation o f the exemption provided in s ubsection (a) of th i s secti on 3 on a .notice of assessment. a s required by section 4Z5 (9) of the Di str ict of Columbia Real Property Tax Revis ion Act of 1974 approved September 3, 1974 (88 Sta t. 10551 o.c. Cod sec. 47-645(9} Sec. 4. Expans ion o f Circuit Breaker Proper ty Tax Relief for Homeowners and Renters in th• Oistrict of Columeia wno Are Over 62 Years of Ag amp;lind or Oisabled. Secti on of Title Vt of the •o i str l ct of Colu•b i a rncoiae and Franchise fax Act of 1947 approved July 16• t947 (88 Stat. 1060; o.c. Cod sec. 47-l567g(a)(ZJJ is a~ended as follows a) Subsection a ZJ is amende d to read as fo llows l!:arollad Or!gi:'la.l 7 Z Al Ef.fective ror taxable .years beginning after December J l 1?7~ and ending before January 1 1976 the percentage required under paragraph (l) of this s ubsection (a) to be determined for claimants other than e lderly blind or disabl e d claimants shall be the perc•ntage specified in the follow ing table: PROVtOEO, HOWEVER. That the credit shall not exceed three hundred and twenty dollars (S320) and: PROVtOEO· FURTHER, That for tax years beginning on and after January l• 1977 th• percentage r~quired under para~raph (l) or this s ubs ection (a) fo r elderly, blind, o r disabled clai~ants shall be the percentage s pecified in paragraph (Z)(Cl of this subsection Non-Elderly Circuit Sreaker "After December 31 97 and Prior to Janua ry i, 1978 f household gross i ncome is The pe rcentage of the first under s3,ooo S'-00 or real property tax paid o r the rent constituting the real property tax which shall constitute tJ'I• credit i s: 80 pe r. centu111 of th• tax in e xcess. of 2 per c:entu• or gross i ncom 70 per centu• of th• tax ln excess of 3 per centu• of gross i ncoaie. 60 pe r c e ntu111 o f tJ'I tax in excess of 4- per c:ent.u111 or gt"OSS inco111a. 8 3 Ef f e c:ti e for tax ,years be ginning after Oecember 31 1977, the percentage reqoirec under paragraph {l) of this subsec t ion (a) to be determined f o r claimants other than el de rly blind. or disabled c:lalmants shall be the p ercentage s pec i fied in the following table: PROVtoeo, HOWEVER That the credit shall not e xceed four hundred dollars (S400J After Oecember Jl, 1977 I f household gross income is Under SJ QOO "S5 ooo to s o 999 "S7,000 to 11~0 The percentage of t ne real property tax paid or rent con- stituti ng the real property tax which s hall const itute t he credit i s: 95 per c e n t um of the tax in excess of 2 per centum o f gross income. 90 per centum of the tax i n excess of 3 per cen t um of g r o ss inco me. e5 per centum of the tax in exc..ss of 4 per centum o.f gross income 80 per centu• of the tax in e xcess of 4 per centu• or g r oss i nc:o.e. 4anuar y l• 1977 th• percentage required unde r paragraph (l) of thi s subsecti o n a to be d etermined t o r e lderly, blind or disabled c: l a i~ants s nall be t he percentage spec i f i ed in the followi ng tabl e PROVIDED, HOWEYER t nrolled Orig J.4.l That the cr•dit shall not exceed seven hundred and fifty dol"lars s750 Elderly. Blind. or Oisabled Circuit Breaker If household gross inco•a is Under s1p,999 "SS, 000 to 59,999 "s to .ooo to s11p, 999 "Sl5o000 to szo.OOO The credit shall equal the amount of property taxes paid or rent constituting the property taxes wnich Is in excess of th• following percentage of household gross income: 1.oi L.5~ 2.oi Z.5i b) Subsection (b)(5)(Al is redesignated as subsection (b)(8) and new subsections (b 5 b 6 and (b){7) are added to read as follows 5 The term •elderly claimant' means a claimant who is sixty-two (62) years of ag• o r ol der during any. I tax year o r part thereat beqinn ing after December 31. 1976 and who, together with his or her spouse, if any. provides f ifty percent (50 or more of th• household gross inco or the household of which he or sh• is a part. whose central visual .cuity does not exceed 20/200 in the better eye wltn correcting lenses or whose visual acuity is greater than 20/200 but i s accompanie~ by a li~itation in the field of vision such that the widest 10 diameter of the visual field subtends an angle no gr eater than t enty 20) degrees. ft(7) The term •disabled clai~ant• means a claimant unable to engage in any suostantial gainful acti vity by reason of a medically determinable physical or mental impai r~ent which can be expected to result in death or has lasted or can be expected to last for a continuous peri od of not less than twelve lZJ months Ois~bled persons filing claims under this act shall submit proof of d isabil ity in such for~ and manner as t he Mayor shall by rule and regulation prescribe. Proof that a claimant is e ligibl e to receive disability benefits under the federal Social Security Act shall constitute proof of disability for the purposes of this act. A disaoled person not covered under the federal Social Security Act shall be exam ine d by a physician designated by the Mayor and the person•s status as a disabled cla i mant snall be united St•t•s Social Security Administration. The cost of this fnatlon shall be borne by the claimant Sec. 5 llure to Provide Information Requested 8y The Section 422 of the •District of Columoia Real Property Tax Revision Act or 1974 approved SepteBber 3 197 80 ll S~at. LO S o.c. Code. sec. 47-6421 is amende d by adding a new suosect ion d to read as follows s:m-ollec o:-i.gi d)(ll The Mayor ~ay require an owner of real property ~o submit such information relating to the income or economic benefits derived fro• such property as in th• Mayor's judgment will assist in t he determinati on of the esti mated market value required under this title. If an owner of real property in the District of Columbia fails to s ubmit sue information wi thin the time and in the form prescribed• there shall be added to the real property tax levied upon the property in .question for th• next ensuing tax year the amount of ten percentum 10 of sa id tax: PROVtOEO, That when such information is provided after sa i d time and it is shown that the failure to provide it was due to reasonable cause and was not due to willful neglect• no such addition shall be made to the tax Z) t.11 i nformation sub•ittad by a property owner to tne Mayor regarding income or economic benefits derived from real property in tt'le Oistrict of Columbia shall be a&amp;lt;:corded th conf'lden~lality as that applied to District or Co1umbi• lnco ta• returns under section ·4(a) of Title v of the •District of' Col~mbla lnco and Franchise Tax Act of' 1947 proved July \6, \9~7 (bl St•t• 342; o.c. Cod sec. 47-l564e and any violation o f such 12 confident i ality shall be pun i s hable as provided i n subsection {e) of said sect ion 4 Sec 6. Report to th• Council of the Oistrict of Columbia on Assessment Change s for th• Highest-Assessed Properties. No t later than April lst of each year the Mayor shall submit a report to the Counc i l of the Olstrict of Columbia witn t he follo~i ng i nformation: {l) th• assessment chan ges. if any. made on th• t hirty (30) taxable commercial and multi-fam i ly residential proper ties which had the highest assessments in t h• District of Columbia for the previous property tax year 2} an explanation for each such assessment change reported under subsection (a) of this section 6; and (3) th• changes in the assessment of each of the thirty (30) properties referred to in subsection (a) of th~s section 6 over trie previous four (4) property tax years. Sec. 7. M•yor to ~ther and Re9ort Information Relating Pr-opercles a) On or before the date the Mayor transmits to the Counc il of t he Oistrict of Columbia a recom~ended property tax rate for th• property tax year beg i nning on July l 13 19 78 tne ~ayor sn ail repo r t the f ollowi ng i n formation t o t he Council of th• Oi strict o f Columo i a lJ the number of un it5 i n each res ide ntial rea l p r operty o ne d by a cooperative hous ing associat ion in the Oistrict o f Col umbia and occupied by th• members of said assoc ia t ion ZJ the es timated market val ue of each said res ident i al property for the two (2) most rece nt assessment s; and (3 a recomcnendat i on for a real property tax as s essment exe mption that would be applied t o each in~i v i~ual unit in said property b Tne Mayor s hall report t o th~ Council of the Ci str ict of Columbi a each year on or before the date the ~ayor s u bmits a budget to this C.ounc i l as required under sect ion 2 of the District of Co1urnt&amp;gt;ia Self-Government and Governmenta l Reorganization Act approved Oe&amp;lt;:ember 24, 1973 7 Stat. 798; D.C Cod sec 7-221 the number of properties th• Mayor e.xpects to be benefited by the deduct;ons provfd~ In section 3 of this.act, according to the type o propercy, for the fisca1 year to which said budget applies and th• a~unt of revenue which the District o' Colu•bia wil 1 forego ~cause of sai d deductions 14 Sec. a. Counc il of t~e Ois~r i ct of Col u mb i a to ~ev i ew Single-Family Reside ntial and Cooperat ive Property Tax Ex emptions Annual ly. Th• Counc i l of the Di strict of Columbia shall rev i ew b y July l st of e ach year t he resi de ntial and cooperative property tax r~l ief provided under section 3 of this a ct and shall adjust the rel i ef whenever in its v iew s uch adjust me nt i s necessary to reduce excessi ve resi dential and cooperat ive p roperty tax burdens and to maintain equity among and between the owners of different clas s es of real property. Sec. 9 Authorizat i on to Establish Regulations. The Mayor i s author i zed to deve lop the necessary forms a nd procedures and to establish regulat i ons necessary to carry out th• provision s o f this act. Sec. 10 Provis i on of Existing Law Re peal e d S~ti on 430 of the •oistr i ct of Col umbia Real Property Tax Revision "4:t of 1974 approve&amp;lt September 3, 197 88 Stat. 10 Q~C· Cod sec 7-650 author i zing the Counci l of t h e District of Columbi a to establi sh property tax exeaptions of up to thr thousand dollars (53,000) for row• d etached. or se~i-detached dwellings. i s hereby repealed. Sec. ll. Severability. Th• provis i ons of this act are severable, and i t any 15 ille;al inv ali d. unconst i tut ional or inap p licabl e to any per s on o r ci rcumstances. such ho ld ing sha ll no t affect or i ~p a ir any of the rema i ning provisions, sentences clauses. sect i ons or parts of th• a ct or th9ir appl icat i on to other persons or circumstances. Sec. lZ. Effective Cate a) This act shall app ly to the property tax year beginning on July 1, 1977 and to each property tax year tner~after bl This act shall take effect as prov ided for acts of the Council o f the District of Columbia i n section 602(c)(l) of t he Di strict of Columb i a Salf-C?v•rnment and Governmental Re organization Act app r o ved December 24t 1 973 (87 Stat 814; o.c. Coda sec. l-l47(cJ(lll i Oocluit ~o• Z-127 cli=c ~t!.CUU rune 28 t !977 a;j VCICZ VOTZ LJ I.OU. CAU. VC-:Z 1 o1 f r 1 i 1 J 1 TU~ I I I I f W..SON I I I I I s Ati IQ:C I I I I A.UJJ J I I I i.co~ D I I I I I V.U.SCN I 1 I t 3~ f J I I lt;OCl 1. I I I J t W?Nn:!l I I I I a..u i I I I 5 :itO~&amp;gt;c I I I I I I I I I Oi::t=N I I I I 1.C:U i I I I I d I I I I T I rt v Ji l x T f•t 4:rrded J1 iit LtM!b1 ~OIU Tu1y 26 1977 Adotlted Unanimously (all present} \.f ;J Lf-c.u.hJ.k ta Co==rll CJ llOt c.u von Tulv IZ, 1977 t 1 1 a i f l 1 t l V I a..I Tt?C c I l&amp;lt; I I I M.A$ot I X I I I pMrt v I X I I I I vi I I "4Cos.:i 0 I Y I I F ftUON I I X I I YI I I :W.CCli Ix I I· I 'W1 TP-3. 1 I I I X I C:t i'a I Xl I I I s.ct A i 3: I X I l I J I 1 I I I CctQI" I XI I I A .9 A i x t 1 .II. I I I I I l I I J J X.T~17 I Sa a amp;17' m t!I crr=dl n.i z a Z S-r September 13 1977 t'VC lt I I I I ~M.A.SON t I I I jS.r .\.U l Ji lt;;f I I I I I !LU!T I I I I l~COll O. I I I I CN I I I I I !IA7..1T I I I I I .WQQU I I I I I I 1 I I ct i1iza I I I I S.Qt a I I I I I I I I l I llXCl:f I I I I f 5r!I lt q I I I I I I I I I I t IL Y J• T.-it I s.cn c c</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
