<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-54">
  <num type="law">2-54</num>
  <heading type="short">Rental Housing Act of 1977</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1978-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-54.pdf">D.C. Law 2-54</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 5334</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-54, the “Rental Housing Act of 1977,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-152, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 15, 1977, and November 29, 1977, respectively. There being no action by the Mayor, it was assigned Act No. 2-118 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> 7 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE April 6 1978 D. C. Law 2- 54 "Rental Housing Act of 1977" Pursuant to Section 412 of the Distric t of Columbia Self- Gover:u:nent and Governmental R eorganization Act PL 93-198) the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-152 on firs t and s e cond r eadings November 15, 1977 and November 2 9, 1977, respec tively. Following expiration oi the ten- day review period provided the :May o:r pursuant to Section 4 04 (e of the Ac t, dcr~ng which no action was aken, this legislation was a ssi gned Act No. 2 118 published in the DecembeT 30, 1977, edition of the D. C. Registe r a nc tra nsmitted to b oth Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in acco r cia. nce with S ection oCZ (c l) of the Act The Co=c:il of the Dis tr ic t of Coiurnbia nereby gives notice that the 30-day Congr e ssi onal review ?eriod !i.as e;-cpi=ed a nd, t!1ereiore cites t!te follo ing l egi s la tion a s D. C. if'w 2 4, cf!eo;tive Mai-ch 16 978 r I J i.&amp;lt 7CKER Chairr.:an of ~e Coundl (Vol. 2 4, D. C. R egister 334, December 30 1977 1 C L AW 2-54 I TM F CCU~C IL n F Tn( OIS T ~JC T ~F CJLJM5 1~ To provi •le r &amp;lt l 1~ci!t1on 1ss 1$ tancch st'lh;liv! rc,;1 ·iential re t s pro v i~e eviction control nd f o r GtnP r gt;uruo s e £:I T Et:ACT~ O l Y T'1E CflU'iC.IL CF 14G O l ST.tTC T Cf t OL ll;t Tt°&amp;gt;·Jt r.n i s ~cc '71.:JY b e c i t ed d s t h e en T.&amp;lt;t l -t o u s inc; Act of l 7 7 A 1 TITLE I- 102 TITLE I I 20 1 202 203 204 205 20 6 207 2oe 209 2 10 2 11 21 2 213 2 14 215 216 2- l ASLE Of CONTENTS DEFI N.l TIONS Definitions RENT S TAElLJZAT.lON P ROG &amp;amp;AM Cootin uation cf Rental Ac ccmmcda ticns Commis s ion; Qualifica tions Duti es of the comeission Rental Accommcdations Of fic e Duties of Re.nt Ad ;uin1st r a t or Re9istrat i.on a.nd coverage Be nt Cailing Adjus tments in t be Rent Ce iling Qualifica t ions for Incr eases Atcve the Bas e lient Rent ceiling Cpoo Ter minat ion of Exemption 11od f or 11e 11 ly- Co ver eo ile ntal Units Capi~al Impro vement s services and Facilities Haraship Pet i t i on vacant Ac commodations Adjustment ercced or e Secur ity Deposit Judici.a l Review TITLE III. 3£STAL SUPfLEMENT PilCG RAM 3 01 30 2 3 03 304 JOS 3 06 TI TLE IV 01 1'ITLE V. 501 502 f ligibi li ty l!e otal Supple ~en t Gra ats Administration Cont i nu ed Eligibi lity Ter~inaticn o f Eligi~i lit y Ta x Exca:pticn RE VEll UE Annual ~e nt al Onit Fee EVIC I CtlS All tll:;T AL.lATOB C'IIGl! rvictions Re tal iator y Action 1 0 l c4_eu ·r ~sina 3 rITLE vr SAL OF REN AL liO USING 601 Sa le of Sius le- fdl ily Hcusing AcCC ilia:o&amp;lt;lation~ 60 2 Sa le of hous ing Accommod a t io n Ccmpcis ed of lwo or More Uai t~ 60 3 Conversion o f a lio us ing Acco ~1cdat io n t o a coop~cative 604 Con ve r s i on of a Housiny Acco lt;dat io n tc Another Us e 605 Am endments to the Cond o~iaium Ac t of 19 76 IITLZ V11. SO&amp;amp;STANTIAL REli ABILITATI ON CF ECOSI NG ACCO M~ODATIONS X3 CM WB ICll A TENANT WAS EVIC4EO 70 1 A;&amp;gt;plicabili':y of Ero vi s ioas 702 Pe~itior or Adjust~ent in ~ent Ceili ng ue to Su cstantia l nebabilitation 703 Crit er ia f o r Appr o vin g Petiticrs 704 Amoun t of A&amp;lt;l j ~st~e nt in Re Dt Ceiling tor Substa.ctial aeha bilitaticr. 703 ~otice cf Intent to Subst a nt i a lly R~ha.bil itate 706 Notice t o 7acate for Subs t antial P.e ha. i:il it a tion 707 Tenant s aignt t o Se-~eu t TI~L£ VII I. RELCCATION ASSI STANCE FO F 'IINAhT S DIS PLACED Y SDSSTANTI A.L SEHA EILI'l'ATION Oli 0£ ~011 'I IOK 801 Notice of Right ~o Re l ocat i o3 Assis i:a nc-c E::rolleC, Orit el 80 2 l!igibil! t y BE~ui rements for ~elcc~tion Assista nce 803 9~ loc~t ic 11 AS&amp;amp;ista nc e Pa ym E ot~ 804 P loca t ion Advi sory Services 8GS. Tenant Ho t \.ir,e TIT:.E .rx. 901 902 &amp;lt;}03 9C.U 905 906 SCELL i\ lEC !JS l?e nalti es Sc verabilit y S P r se &amp;lt;len::e Se vice J::f fE c ti V Q Oat€ 'l' e r:n inat ion l::nrollua Origi nal -4- T.lT LZ I DEl"IllITIONS Sec 102. Qef initior.s. For the puq;:oses cf this act a) The t erm base rent means th at rer.t legally c~arqed or char; eable cu October JI 1577 fer the re nt.a l unit whic h shall be th e sum of rent c oarged on February 1, 1973 a nd all rent i ncrease s a uthori zed tcr that r ental unit b y prior re~t c on trol la vs or any adQinistrative decision issuec th ereunde r, or any rent increases authcrized by a court o f co~?e~ent jo ristliction The terlll "cap ital improve tuect" mears an i:u pro vement or r e nova tion o~her tha n ordina ry repait ceplace2e~t or ~ain~ enance the use of hich continues teycnd tbe t ~elve {12) month period beginning o n t h e date cf completion of such capital improve111eot c The ter 111 "Co m11.ission oeans thE Rent al Accoomodatious Comoission a s ccntinued ~y title II of this ac I The teem "Counci l neans tne Co uncil of the Oi srrict of Coluooia a£ establis~ed by section 401 of the "Dis t i:ict of Columbia Self-Go vernme nt and Gcv ~rnmental aeor:;anizatioo Ac t amp;fproV lo!d l)ece11l:er ~ll 19i3 (87 Stat. 785; o.c. Code sec 1-141 f;firoi1ec Original 5 e Th&amp;lt terc 11 0 c. 1.av 1-33 weans the 11 rist tict o f Columbia Renta l Accommcdations Act of 197511 as a~ended f) The terDI "housi ng accoc:nodation" means any s tructure or build ing in the Cist rict cf cclu~ tia cont ain ing on e (1) or more c~ntal units and the la n d afpur t enent th e r ;i 'to. s uch t e r:n s hall net include any hot el, motel, o r oth~ t structure, inc l uding any room therein used pr.imarily for transient occupancy and in which at least sixty ~ercent (60 ot ~he rooms devoted to living gua rt ets f e r tenant s or quests ace use~ £or transient occu pancy Fer t he pur poses of this act a c antal uni t shall be due med to t e us ed f o r transi er.t occupanc y if the la ndlcx d he reof i s sub j ect to and ;ia ys the sal e s tax i nq:osed hy sect i c n 47- 26 01 14 a 3) of t he Distric~ of Col~mbia code lt;:J The term Houtinq Re g ulations a:eans t h e lftCst recent ed ition of the F.oosing P.eg ulaticns cf the Cistrict o f Colu mbia a s establish•d b y tbe Commius i c ne1 1 s Cr der dated Augus t 11 1955 (C O O- 55- 1S03 h) The term i nit ia l l e asi ng pe ricd" mean s t ~at period for vhic b the iirst ter.ant cf a renta l unit rents soc!i rental unit. for rent al unit s desctiheo in sectic n 205(a 2) o f this act the first tenant i s the tenant v ho cent s such re ntal unit i mruediately fcl lc vin g the issuance of the certi ficate of cccopancy_ For units d£scri t ec in 6- sect ion 209 of this ac t, t he fics t tena nt i~ the tenant who rents s uch r e ntal unit i~me&amp;lt;iiately ait er t he date it i s first oft~red tor r en t as a r enta l u~it ~hich is no t otherwise e~e~ pt f rore this ac t i) The term landl.ord o e ans an c 11ner l essor, suhl.essor assignee, a ny age nt thereof e r any ct ber perso n receiving or e ntit led to receive rents ct benefits for the use or occupancy of any renta l un it within a hc usiag acco moodation ~ithin the District of Cclumtia j) The ter managenent ee means the a~ount paid tc a managin g agent and any µre ra ta sa laries cf cff- s ite admi nistrative personnel paid by the l.andlcrd: PROVIDED That the duties of sacb personnel. are c cane cted vitb the opecati on ot the housi og acco2~cdatian k) The torm 1a rket value means t he ~os t recently assessed va l ne o f tbe housi ng accommodation a~ de ter~ ined by the Ma yor f oe real. pro fer t y t a x purfose 1 he t t r :t aia ximum possible ceotal i nco:iie" aeans t~e s u~ of the cants ~cc all re ntal. un i ts in t he housing accommodation whether occu?iec o r net co~fUted over A base gt;er:iod of the coose.:utive twel ve (1 scntl1 io;:rediately precading th~ da te of any fil ing re guit ed ct percitted under tilis act En v 7 o rhe t er m "l'laycr" mca us the ottice cf th e Ma yor of the District of Co lumbia as e~tab l ished und&amp;lt;r sectio n 421 of t.he Dist r i ct of ColU l:ia Self Go vec-nme nt and Go vernment al Reorgdnization .l.:t dFp;:ov"1 D~cemter 24, 19i3 (57 Stat 789 D. C. c ode sec. 1-161 n he t er :t "Office" mea ns the iienta .l Acco1uoda tions Office as ~ro vid ~d i n section 20 3 (a) cf this act. [o) The t er 11 o perating expenses means the expenses re~uired for the operation of a housing acccmmodat~on fo e- c b e consec~tive t~elve (12 ontb pericd imaediately p r eceding the dat.e o f its use in any cc~fUtaticn tequir e d by a ny provision of t his act, includinq tut net li~ i ted to ex~enses foe salaries cf on-sit.a ~erso r. cel, SU~flies pain tioq main tenance and repairs util ities rofessional te~s on- site offices, and insura nce p) The taro other inco~e vhich is derived frc~ the housi ng accommodac ion" means any i nccme, cthec thao qcoss rents which a landlord e arns beca us e c f his er her ov nersh~p of a housicg acco~~odation itcluding but no t limitef to fees c cmmissions i11come f r c m vending machines, lncome fr om l~un dry facilities and inccme fr cm packing and r ecreation a l facili ties The t.erl!I pe rson" me ans ar. indivi d ual, ccq:c ra~icn, ra rtn crship 4 Ssoci~ ticn joint ven t urt busine~s enti ty, ot 8- dO crganized group ot in ci v duals and their r es fecti ve successors and assigcees r) The term "proi;erty taxeli mea &amp;amp;s r.e aa.cunt levied b y the go vern me nt of t he District of Cc l umtia fer real property t a x on a housing accommoda tion dur i n g a tax ye a r s) The terQ "related fa c ility reaos acy facility f urnis hi nq o r eguip mert made available to a t e nant t y a ia ndlord the use o f which is authorized by the payment of the rent charged tor a r en tal unit includirg any use o= a kitch en, batil laundry facilit y, parking facil i ty and t he c ommon use of any co mmcn room, yard ot e t her ccmmcn area t) Tba term "rel at ed se rvices means ervices provided by a landlord or required by la or by the terms o f a rent a l agreement to he provided h y la ndlcr d to a tenan t i n connec t ion 11 i ~h t he use and occ u paccy of a renta l unit, including r e pairs, decorati ng and mainte nance, the Frovision o f lig'1t heat ho~ and cold water, a i r-condi t ioning, tele phone ansverillq and elevatoc se r v ices acitoria l s ecvices a nd t he remo val c f trash and re fu e u) The t .izm "re nt" means t!l e e nt i r e a!r.c unt cf money, money s worth enefi bonus or gratuity de ~anded re c eived or char qed by a landlcrd as a corditicn of occupa ncy o• use of a r e ntal unit, its r €late d ser vi ces a nd its r elated facilities 9 v J':1c ter:n "rent ce i ling neans tha t ancunt defin ed in or c =rrnted under section 2'.l 6 of t!i.i s act { w) The tern "re tal unit" neans a~y ?art o: a housing ilccommoda ti on as def i 1ed in sec ti on 10 2 of this act \·!hic!:l is r ante d or of:ercd f or r e:it for resie ential occupancy a nc inc ludes a ny apartment, eff i ciency a pa rtnent, roon, sinq lc- farnily house t:.he land appurtena nt there t o and suite of rooms or duplex x The term "subst antial rehabilitation" ncans =Y iir.prove1:1en t t o or renovation of a housing accCr.11:1od.:i tion for Hhi ch 1 the building permit was cranted on o r after rebruary 1, 1973; and (2) the total expenditure f.or the improver.ie t or rc.~ova ti on cqua ls o r exceeds fifty perccn t 50 of the r.tarke t value of the housing acccr.imoda tier. ueforc s uch rehabilitatio n y) The t e rr.&amp;gt tenant" includes a tenant, subtenant, le s see, sublcssee or o t her person entitled to the ?Ossession occ~pancy or the benefits thereof, of any rental u~it owned ty anot.;er person z e teP uncol ectec! r er.t" r..e ans the anount of rent (s) o.nd ct 1er c:iarge5 d•.Je for at leust thirty 30) d ays cu no t rccci 'led f roo t c i.n!:s at t.'le t irr.e a r.y stntencn t f or:n or petition is filec pi r suant to t!ii s act 10 1111 The teri:i "v acancy loss lleans the aa:cunt of ren·t not collecta ble du e t o vacaot units in a hcuEin9 acco~modatioo Mo amount sball be includ ed ttere in for units occ upie d by a landlor d or his or ~er em ~lcyees or o t ber vi se oot offered for rent b he term s ul:staotial violatic.o eans the presence of any ho using conC.itioo the existence of vhicb, violates the Oistrict cf Columbia Bousins 5egulations or any ot her sta tute or requlatioo :ela tive to the conditio n of :esidential premises a nd ~ay endanger c: materially iD?&amp;amp;ir the heal t h ani safety cf any tenant or ferscn cccupyin9 the property I.I!LE II 4ENT STA5IllZdTION eKCGci AH Sec 20 1. Concipuaticn of c omais si cn Qlalificat ions a) The District cf Colum bia llen t a l Accommcdati ons Co1111ission iereioa! ter refe rro.id t o as tb e "Ccu,ission as established under s ec tion 101 (a of o. c. La v 1- 33 is c ont inuef and shall be comFoSed o f oi nf (9) oembe rs appoin ted by the ~ayer by a nd vith the advi ce acd consent of the Co unci l eobers appointea to th e Coramis ~icn ~nder this act sha ll each serve a t vo (2) year t ern ThtEE (3 e llbers ct the Co~mission shal l represe nt the ioteres t s of -11- landlords, ar.d each of the thr ee (3) shall te a l a ndlord of a t least one 1 o usi &amp;amp;g accommodat ion lcca te d in the Dis t rict of Co lumbia Three (3) 11e!lbers of the Ccmmission s~all be ~er.ants wr.o stall r epresen t t he io te ~ests cf tenants, a nd thr ee (3) members of the Ccmmissicn shall be neither landlord s r.or tenants All of the 1temb1:rs o f the Commission sha l l be residents of th e District o f Co lumbia and sha.11 be ~embers of no sore than cn e (1) ethe r Dis trict o f Columbia Board o~ Ccmmission b) Individua ls serving or. the Co~aissio en the ef fective dat e of t his act shall remain in cffice unti l tb ei r successors a r e duly sworn into cffice. r. e mb crs of the Co ~missior. pres ently s ervin9 shall te eligitle for reappcint!l?ent Cl ~he Mayor shall b~ve the authcrity t c temo ve any :member from the Co mmission who fails tc maintain the qualification of a member or vbo fa ils to attend se ve nty pe rcent (70 of the regularly scheduled Cc2mi ssicn mee tings nel:i within any si x (6 month period d) An'{ oe mber v hc holds no o t he r salaried ;iul:lic posi tion shall receive compensation at the rat e o t fift y ~c llars 50 00) fo r each day s uch me:i:ter is en ;aged in the actual pei:fc rmai::ce o f duties ves t ed in the Coitmission: PROVID~o Tha t no oe~bEr shal l receive ~ere t han five Eorol :ed Original 12- thou sa nd and fouc hundred dcl lars 5 CC. 00) under tbi subsection i n &amp;lt;1 ny one (1) calendar yeai e Five (5) mei:.bet's of the Co1tmi&amp;amp;sion shall constitute a quo ru~ f o r t he pui:pc2e o f transactin~ bu &amp;amp;iness fROVI DED Th at o ne of the fi ve (5) members is a landlci:d o ne (1) is a tenant and one (1) is neither a ter.aot nor a landlcra The Co mmission is au thorized to celegate tc any panel of thr ee 3) or more :n embers any appellate functic o ~bich it may itself e~ercise PROV I DED Tha~ said ~anelE are constituted vith one (1) tenant one (1) landlord, a::d cnP 1) v t.o is ne ither a tenant nor a landlord f) The Co:nmission shall choose annually, fro!D among its membe rs bo are ~eitner t enants ncr lanclcrds a C~ai rperson and Vice Cha ir perscn The Ccmmissic n may choose from its ~emb ers hip s uch ct ~er officers as it deems nece SSll ry Sec 202 QutiP.2 cf~_s;o:nC1issi a he Coa:missi or. s ha ll 1 gt;roflulqate a11end and rooscinc rules and proce dures f or ~he admini s tration of tbi2 act and (2) decide olHeal :s tircuq bt tc i t frcm decisions of t he Ben t Administrator b he co~missico a c d tne aeot ~d ai ni~ra tor shal l coll ect and report data oo the ef fec t s that t~ e pro visions Enrolled Or 1 13- of t~1 s act have o n the price guantity and quality of reGt~l housing in the tistrict o f Cclumxia c T"-e Commission, lo' ith the assistance of the Re ntal hcco mmodations off ice, shall re port tc the Cou ncil annuall y on tbe fiscal ye ar basis util ized by the gcvern~ent of th e Dist rict of Columbia cot late r t han Ncvemter 15 of each year This report shall cove r rhe precedi ng t wel ve 12) months except that the r efort to h e fil e d Novembe r 15 1978 will cover the pe r iod f om r.arch 21 1577 1he first report shall incl ude any chaoses in opera ting costs cccurrinq du r ing the period from tne last repcrt, and any kno wn co urt mandated futu re rent increa ses Th e annual report s ha ll inclnde t~e number of har ds hip pe titicrE filed and the number of hardsh i p petitions granted lbis infcr ~ation sha.11 be broken dovn by ward anc s hall i ndicate vbether the affected housinq acco 11odat1or.s are sinsle-fa cily (comprisi~g one rental unit flat (coat-risin fou r or less r nn-.ci l units or multi-family (comfrising fo-ur or lll Or e ren t al units rurther t he te pcrt shall i nclude findi nq s with respect to, but net liai t ed to, taJes f €es a nd permits wa ter and se v €c s~rv ice charge heatin q oi l; elPctricit y atural gas; building mair.teoance ccntract ed ser vices inc luding parts and suppl ies poyroll costs re!'air costs; i:lsuranci management fees and g;onera l ~oile~ Original 14- aciministrative costs To th~ ex tent pcssi~le the report shall als o adciress the quactity guality and p :ice cf the ren~al housing s tock in the District cf Colu~tia and any effect the provisions cf this act may have ~a 3 thereon as demon s trated by statistical e vidence f ladings inc luded in th e Commissi on s report sha.l.l be based in part en testimony presented by both la ndlords and tenants gi ven at fUblic hearings Such othe r documentat i on and analysis as may te required tc support the Commission s findi ngs shall also be included d Jase on the tindirgs made by the Coa:missicn for th e r eport reguired by subse~tion (c) cf this secticn the Co~mi ssion shall as a part of such refcrt, make the determina tion authori z€d by section 20f (b) cf this act and ma y tllake reccmmendations to t he Council for legislati •1e ac~ioo e 1) The Commission may hold such hearings s it and act at s uch times and ~laces within the District o f Colu~bia admini s ter such oat.hs and r €quire ty s ucpoena or other wise the attendance and tes~imcny cf such ~itnesses aod the prod uction of s uch books, records, ccrteSFCndence emorar.d a pa~~rs and docum~nts as the Commissicn m2y deen advisable in carrying cut i ts fUGcticns under this act Enrcl \ 15 2) I o tne case of contu il\acy er ref usal tc obey a suht:oeoa issued un~er sect oo 202 (e 1) cf this act by an y person who resides is f o uud or t ransacts bu:siness •itb. i o the District of Co lumbia t he Supe rior Court cf the District of Col unbi a at the wc i tt ec r equest of the Co~mission s hal l :ia ve jurisdiction t o issue t he per son a o o rilec requir ing the pe r son to appe a r before t oe co2miss:oo t~ e re tc produce e vide nce if so ordered or t here to gi ve tes t i:iony touching upon the :tatter un C.e r in1uir y A ~y f a il ure of the person to obey an y or der o f the ~uperio.c: Court cf the Distr ict of Columbia ~ay he pun ished by t ha t court as ccnt€ropt th ereof Upon the writte n req uE-s t of the Cl:airpe .c:so o of t he' Co~~issio n, each departm ent or entity cf the gov e r nmen t of the Oistric~ of Col ombia is authori zed tc f urnis h cirec t l y t o th e coo111is s ion such assistance a nd info i::o:a tion as 111ay be aecessary fo= the CoEmission to effectivel y c arty out t hi s ac t. Sec. 2 03. gental ~cco m mod~tiQ ns ~ific a here i s hereby cont.inue d as an agency o f t h e go ve rnment of ~he Distric t of Colombia, wittin the xec uti ve Office of the ~ayor a Re n tal Acco mm odation s Cf fice which s hall have as i ts he ad a 3en t ~dministr ator t c be e~ poin ted uy be :1a 7or 16 b) The ~ent ~d ministrator shall FCssess expecience of a technical na ture i n landl ord- tena nt affairs er i n a fie ld directly r elated thereto s hall be a rE Side ot of the District o f Columbia and shall be e ntitled to recei ve a nnual compensat ion (payable io resular installments at the r a te o f 9rade 15 of the General schedule under s ecti on 53 32 of t i t l e S o: the United Stat es Code. Sec. 204. Qut ies cf the Rent AdministJ.At.£ amp aJ The Rent Administrator shall. carc7 out accordin g t o rules and procedures es t al:l lished by the com mission under s ection 202 (aJ (1) of thi s act t he rent s tal:iliza t ion program establ.ished under ti tle I of t his act an d s hall perfo:m s uch o ther duties a s may be necessary ap propria te and c onsistent with the provisions of this act l&amp;gt;J The Rent Administ r ator er his er ho;r designee s hall have jurisdiction o ver those co mplaints and ?e tit icns arisinq under: title s II, v, VJ: and VI~ of tbis act which ma y be disposec of through ad ~inistrative f roceedi ngs c) The aent Administrator Slall etofc~e an an~oal bud9et and c£conmend such sta!f as vi l l ena t;e the ot=ice and the Co~ci$sion to carry o ut the aF ~ropriate provisions of this a c t d 1) The !lent Adnin i st.rator may E[Jlplcy wi th such fund~ as ~ay be av a ilatle to tr.e Sent Administ rator s uc h E~rollea ih~t.i:i 17- pe r s on ne l a nd consul ta nts incl udiug beari rg e xaminers a nd l e ga l couns el as are necessary t o carry out the pro visions ot this a ct 2) In accordanc e 11.it h the re9ul&amp;lt;1.ti cns Fromulga ted by t be c o mmission, t he gent Ad~inistca~cr y delGgat e au th ority to those e mployees a p?ainted in ccn formi ty wi th section 20 4 (d 1) of this act Such au thorit y may include but is not limited to hearing adminis t rative ~eti tions filed or initi at ed under this ac issuing these decisions and render.illg final or de rs on an} petition heard by the e mi:loyee e) The ~e~t Administra t o r shall ass i st and provide staff support to the Ccmoission in tb e ~refa ration cf t he annual report required by s ection 202(c) of this act i) Tbe Rent Ad 111 i nistrac.o= o i his e r b€ i: designee shall at t~nd al l oeetings o f the Co ~missio n, and ~hall ma ke av ailable to the co mm i ssion s uch boo ks re pcrt s and da t a collP.cted 3nd wr.ateve r sta!f support t he Ccx~ission ~ay r e guirr. in order to e ffectivel y ca rry c ut its duties under tais act g 1) Tile ent Ad1tinisti:a tor shall hav1 the po lle r to hold bearioi;s si"t a cd act il 't those ti ~es a.nd laces wi thin toe District of coluobia, ad~inist~r cat hs and require by sub?oena or o thetwise the attendance anc te sti~cny of 18- w i tc esse~ and the prcd uct i oo of boo ks recc tcs correS?ocde~ce e~oraoda paFe~s a nd dccurents as the Rent Ad ~inistrator ma y dee~ nec essary in car r yin 9 c ut his or her functiocs under this act 2) In the case of contuma cy o r refusa l to obey a subpoe na i ssued under section 204 (g 1) of this ac t by any person who resid~s is f ou nd, or transacts tusiness within the Distr ict of Colu mbia, the Superior c curt cf t he District of Columbia at t he writte n r equest ot the Sent Adlllin istrator, s hall have jurisdiction to i ss ne tc suc h person an orf.er requ i ring such pecs cn tc an:ear before t he aent Ad ai nist rator, there t o Froduce ev icence if s c crdered, or there t o give testi :no11y touching upon tl: e mat ter under inquiry. Any fa ilure cf s uch person t c cbey a~y crder of the s~perior c cu rt of the District ct cclu~kia ~ay te ?Unished by that c ourt a s ccn tempt ther ecf n) Upon the wr i t te n request of t he Rent Ad111inistra t or eac~ depar t~en t o r ent ity cf th~ go ver n ~ent of the vistr ict o f Columbia is authorized tc f urDish directly to tbe Re nt Aa lllinistra tor s~ch assist~ nce a nd intcr~atico as may he ne cessar y to e ffectively discharge the fur.cticc e~ ui=e~ under this act i rhe F.e nt Adminis trator shall i:u!:ili~ h wi t hin sixt lt 6 0) days after the e ffective dat.e cf this ect a bookle t or -1'1- othe r suc h written material describ ing tenan t and landlo r ds r ights obliqations and frccecuce s fUrsuant to tbis act This ma t erial shdll be dis trituted t hrough t he Di $trict o f Colum bia licrari e s and othet Di~trict of colu~bia offices in which the public ha~ f[equ e nt c ontact and at th e office of any community orga r.izati c n vhich re quest s t o dist ri bu te such z a te r:ia l Sec. 20 5. Regis t ratio n and CoverA.Q.h (a) Section 205 (d) through sectio c 21€ (e xcept section 21 5) of t his act s hal l apply tc each rental uni t i n t he Dis trict of Columbia exce~t 1) any rental unit in any fed era lly er District ovned housing accommodation; or in any housin acco mmodation with resp ect to vhio b the cortgage or rer.t i s fed erally or District s ubsidized e xcept uni Ls subs i di zed p ur ~uant t o title IIl o f this act 2) any .re ntal un t in a hou:;i ng ac c c.m ocda tion for vbi ch the i ni Lial certificate of cccu~ancy va s issued after Pa br uary 2 1973 but such e xclusion s hall t a e ffect i ve only d ucing tae le nqth of the in i tial leas ir.9 ?Er icd er f or the firs t year o f tena ncy v hich~ver is s hcrter 3) any re ntal .i r.i t in ar.y ne wly-cc lls tructed housicg a cco~P.odation f or vticb the bui lding ~er mit was i ssued on o r after January 1, 1976: r F.CVI DED HO \i EV EP That 20- t his exemption shall net apply to any bcusing accommodat:on t h e cous truction of vhicb reguir ec th€ de~clitico of a ny housing accommodation s ubject t o this a c t unless the number of ne vly-ccns truct ed rental units e xceeds tbe numter of de molis hed rental un i ts 4) an y r e ntal uoi t in an y housing accommodation of four (ql or £e ver u nit s including an1 aq~regate of f our units whether within the same s truct ure or not Eovro o That A) suc h housing acccmmcdaticn is o wned by no t more than fo ur (4) natura l persons B) none of s ucb o wners has an in terest either direct l y or ind irectl y i n any ethe r rental unit in t h e Distric t of Columbia and (CJ the owner(s) of such hcusi119 accommoda tion shal l fi le wi th the Rent AdmiDis trator a claim of exempt ion s t a t e ment vhicn shall con s ist cf an oath o r aifi=oation ~y such cw ~er( s) of the valid claim to the e xemption he claim cf e xeaption state1.ent s hall a ls o coutai n tbe sign atures of e~cb persco ha virg an interest (di r ec t o r indirect) i n t he housing acccm mcda~icn. Any change in the ovnershir of the exemFte d bocsin9 accom~oda tion o r chan ge ~o the owoer s in•e re st in any ctber bousin; accompodation which voul~ invalida te the exemption 21- c l a i m must be re Eo r ted iu wcit ing to t he Rent Admioistrator within thiny (30) day s of sucb chaoge 5) an y iiousinq accommcda ticn •hi c h bas been continuo usly vacan t and not sub ject tc a renta l agreement f or a period o f at least six (6) mont hs f ECVI!:l!D That January 1 1977 falls within such six (6) i.cnth period and t hat such hous ing accommooation h~s net bee u tented or offered for rent s1oce t he beginning cf the x eguired vacanc y pe r iod of at l east six (6) months a nc PROVI t:ro PUl!THE!l That upon re-rental such boa.sing accommcda tion is in s ubstantial compl i ance vit b the Rousi n g Segulations when offered for r e nt b) Prior to the e xecu t ion of a l ease er ether •ent al agreement after t he effecti ve date of this act a prospective t enant of a ny unit ei empted une er ~ect icn 205 (a o f this act shall r eceive a notice i n riting ad v is ing him o ec tha t rent incr eases fo r the accc mmodatico are not •e9ulatP.d by tbe ~ent Stabi liza t ion Prcgra c This act s hall not api::ly to th&amp;lt;a fcll c vinc; cental 11n i t s 1) any rental unit in a1: esta!:li bmeot vbich bas as its primary purpose t he pr o viding cf dia~ncetic care a nd trea t ment of dis ea ses inclucing but net lim ited to Enrolled Original hospi tals convalescent hemes nursing heme s and persona l care homes 2) a o y dorm itory of an ins t.i tuticn of higher educa tion or of a pri vate boar ding s cbccl in vbich rooms a r e provided fo r students d ithin not core than ninety (SC} da ys follc~ing the etfective date of this act each landlc cd cf acy rental unit not e ~e3pte1 by this act snall f ile wi th t hE Fent Administ:i:ator, ou a f orm ap Froved by the &amp;amp;ent Administrator a ne 11 r e&amp;lt;;istr ation Std.te ment for each bcusitg accoma&amp;gt;odation in tne Dis trict of Colum bia fo r which he or she i~ recei ving r~nt o r is entitled to receive rent Ibe 1egistration fo rm shall contain, b ut not be licited to: { l) fo r each accommocation regui:i:i ng a l:ousing business license the date (s and numbet {s) of tha t h ous in9 business licen~e aod tbe certif ica~es cf occuFancy here reGuir ed by l a i ssuec by the qovern1ePt cf the Distric t of Columbia and a copy o f each lic e nse a nd c~rtificata 2) fo r each accoamodatior. ne t :tEc;uired to obta i n a ho using business licanse the inf c cma tict cc ntaina~ the rein anc the da~e aod ao~b2r of the ce:r~ ificates cf occ~pancy issu ed by the go ver nze nt ct the tis t:ict cf Co lum b ia a nd i3 CD?:f c f eaca certificatE; Eurcl r a l V..I -u ci 23 3) th e base rent .t or each rental unit in the accommodation the relatbd services included a n d th e r e lated fa cili ties and cha rg~s therefo r 4) t he oumb€r 0 £ b~drooms ic the bcusing accomcioda tion 5) a list of any outstandinc; viclaticns of t he housing code applicabl G to such accommcdati cn er a n a ttidavit that there are no kno wn oute t andin9 violations 6) the rate o f t et urn for the hcusins acco~;noda tion a nd the computations made by the l an dlord t o ar r i ve at such race of r e turn by ap~licati cn of t he f ormula J:&amp;gt;rov i ded iH sectio n 2 1 2 o f this act 11) An amended r egistrati on stat e a:ent s h a ll h e f iled by each r egis tra nt under this .lav li ithin thirty (30) days of a ny eve u t vhich c hanges o r s ub stantially af fe cts the re nts services facilities o r he o vnershiF c t mana gemen t o f any re ntal un it in a register~d housing acccmmc dation: PRCVID30 That no such a2ended registrat ion s tatement shall be ~egui~ed f or a chan ge in r e nt pu tsuar. t t c &amp;amp;ection 206 of tnis ac t f) Each registra t i on sta t e ment fi led under t his section s ha l l be a vail ab le for Ublic irspect ic o a t the ~ffice d e acb landlcrd snall Xeep a dupl icat e cf the registration s tatement posted i n a public place on the p r emises of the housiag accommodation tc which s uch r ec; i strati oa sta teme nt applies PROVI tED Ih at each landlord ~ay, in lieu cf posti ng in e8Ch housin g Qccommodation co~prised of a single r e ntal cnit, mail to eacJ tenant of such ho using accommodaticn a duplicate of the registrati on sta te111en t g) Each r e qist. ra t i on statement filed under this s ection which meets the Jrinimum require ~ent£ established by t~is act and by the rules oi procedure cf the Commission shall be a zsig ned registration number h) Bach certificate of occupancy a nd each housing bu s iness license issued to auy landlord in t he District of Coluobia aftec the e ffectiv e date at this act s ball contain th e registration numbel of the bousin9 accGemcdation to which sucn certifica t e or lice .use applies. sec 206 fill.Lf lilinE a} xcept to the extent p~ovided in se.ctico 206 (b) of this act no landiord of any re ntal un it subject to this act $ay charge or coll ~ct rent t or s uch rectal unit in ey..cess of t :e a~ounc compu ted bf adding to tbe base ren t no ore tban one o) of the follo wir1g pecc~n tages, whicheve r is ipplicable 25 1} t11 0 perc ent (27 if the rent ccvers the cost of no fuel or ut i lities 2) se ven percent (7 if the rent co vers t he cost of heat and hot vator 3) eight percent (8 if the c ent co vers the cost of beat, hot water a nd general pUC fOS€ elec tricity, but aoes not cover air-conditioning and oth~r ccoking f uel 4) nioe percent (9'.l if the rent covers the cost of eat hot water, gene ral purpose electricity, and other cookin~ fuel but doe s no~ cover air-ccnditicning or (SJ t e n perc ent (103 if the rent covers the cost of heat hot water general purpose electricity, ct~er cooking fuel aad air- ccnditionins b) The Com ~ission i s authorized by this section to determine at the time it makes tne annual repcrt fUrsuant to section 20 2{c} whether there shall be adjustment cf gene r al applicability in the r en ceiling s QS~a clishe d ~Y s&amp;amp;ctioo 2u6(a of this act If t~e Co~mission aetecmines tha t such ad just~ents ace vai::raoted the Coaaissicn shall alsc 3etermine che ma oner i&amp;amp; kbic~ such ad;ustmeot s a re to be made and the percentage amount of tbe adj ust~ent: EROVIO ED, Tha• the perceata~e coes oct exceed t he rate cf c~anqe in t~e Consuitei Fri ce Index i n the re c e ·3iog tvelve (12} ~ont~s Jn ~akicg this determi~ati c n the commission shall Juu'olled or:ginal 26- cons ider the operatinq c ost ratic wbjcb i ccm Euted b y di vidi ng th e a vera ge OFer a t i n g e xpenses of all ho using accomooda tion s by th e a ve ra ;e rental inccme o f all ho using accommodations The Ccmmission may us e th e landl crd r e gistration s t a temen ts filed under section 2 05(d) c f this act and sec tion 202 of the aen ta 1 Accc.a&amp;gt;cdat icns Ac t of 1 975 (D.C. Coile 5 ec. 45-1 6 42 in ascertai ni ng this ratio The Commissio n ma y u se scientifically based r a n do sa mples io ascertaining t his ~atic The Commissic n oay c ontract with a private agency or ot he r govern ment age ccy t c ascertain this r a t i o. I f su ch a dete t minatio n is mad a l a nd lord ~a y im ple ment this a d;ustment in t h e tent c eili ng for a r e ntal u n i t covei:ea oy title II o f this ac t cnl y after t welve (12) consecuti ve c aJ.e ndai: mcnths ha ve ela pse d since the effectiv e date of an adju$t~en t in t he ren t c eili og f er t ha t r ental unit pe rmitted b y sec t ion 206(a of tbis act c) At the l andlord s eJ.ection in l ieu of a n y a&amp;lt;i justme n t au-c.ho riza d t y subsection s (a ao&amp;lt;l f l of s ection 206 oi this ac the r ent ceiling for a a acco2mcd a t ion may be adjustF.e -c.hrouqh a ha rd~hip pe titic r. pur ~uao t t c sec ticn 212 of this act suca a petition shal l be clearly ident ified a s an election in lieu o f t h E q e teral adjust~ents a uthori zed by s ubsec tions (a) a nd (b) cf secticn 20 6 o f this act Th~ Rent Ad min i stratcr shal l acccr d ac EXfe dited -27- review process f or s uch pet iti o ns a nd sha ll i ssue and publi sh a f i nal d0&amp;lt;cis icn within ninety (90) days after the ~etition bas been filed ln tne ca se of any petiti on fi l e d u nde r this s ubsection as t o whic h a fina l decision r.a s not been rendered by the P. Ent Admi nistrat c r o• his des iqnee a t th e e nd of ni ne ty (90 days fro m t he date cf fili ng thereof (and as to bich the lan d l ord is n ot in defaul t in complying with any info r:nation reguest lllade under s ecticn 214 (c) of t his a ct the r e n t cei l ing adj ustment n ;gueste d i n tbe peti:io n may be conditionally implemented ty the landlord a t th e e nd of s uch nine ty (90 day pe r iod such conditi o nal rent ceiling ad i ustme nt s h a ll be subject t c subseg uent modif ication by the final decision of the Sen~ Administrator oi; bis des igo e e OD tbe petitio n: l' llOVID ED, llC WE VEP Tha t if a hea ring bas been he ld oc t be petiticn the Fent Adaiinisti;ator or his des1 9oee s hall by cr dEr serve d upon th e pai: t i es a t least ten (lOJ days prior t c th e e xpiration of s uch nine ty (90) da ys gaj(e a prc vis icoal finding a s t o th e i;ent c e iling adius t meo t just ified by the e titi on a nd i f he does so the l a ndlord ma y i mplemer. t coly tbe a mo unt o f tn e =ent ceilinq adjustment authori zed by t he s aid order if any. Except to t h e e x t en t. JlOd i fied he.re i n the a il justD?e n t procedur es ot section 21~ ot th is act s hall aF~ly t o any adiustl'lent Ellrolled Original -28 d) If on the ef £€cti ve da te of ttis ac t t ~e r€~t being charged xceeds t~ a allowable rent cei ling t hat rent s ha ll be red uced t o the allo wable rent ceilios eifectivE the nezt date that tbe =ent is due: PROVIDEC hat th is subsec tion shdll not apply to any rent adlllinis tra t ive1 y apfr o ved under D. C. Law 1-JJ as e nded, or a ny rent i ncrease authorize d by a co urt o f competent jurisdict ion be landl crd shall notify the t e nant in writing of any decrease r equ ired pu rsuant to this act p=ior to t he effective d ate cf the decr ease e) A t e nant may challenge a rent adjustire nt implemented p ursuant tc s ubsections (a and (t) of section 206 oi t his dct by filin; a pet itior. with t be Rent Ad ministrator u~de= section 2 1q of th i• act sec. 207 A diust~€nts in_the Req~_fei]inE; 7he r ent ceiling Ecr a particular tental ucit cc~futed .according to the ?COCP.dures Spec ified in secticn 206 ma y be i ncreased or decrettsed as the case ~ay t e a) a cco rding to section 2 10 cf this act tc ailov fo r tbe cost cf capita l ioprovclents b) according to Eect~cn 2 11 ot this act t o allc v fo r any increa se or decrea se cf r lated serviceE n6 facilities c) according to an1 fina l ord er cf bard~bip adjust ~ent per~i tted under s ectioE 21 2 (c) of thiE act; or amp;lrclled r 1 o \ol 2 &amp;lt u) according to section 21 of this act as t c re i:;u!t o: a voluntary vacancy Sec 203 Oucl.ifications for Incr e ases Arovo the ~asc Rent a l o twithstanding any provision o f t.'1is act, the rent for iny rental unit slull lot l::e i ncre.:isec al.love the base rent unl ess (A) the r ental unit an&amp;lt;l the comoon c lements are L'"l su hst.:intial cor:tpliance with t."le ilous inq Pogulations ROv~DF.D, That such noncor.iplia~co is not the resu lt o: tenant ne&amp;lt;J lect e r misconduct. Evicence cf s uch su sta n t i al cncompl iance shall be lini tad t o housing code vio la ti on no ice( s) iss ;iee l:y ti1e Distri ct of Colur.ibi;,i Department of ous ing and Cor.vnur:ity Dcvelo?r:ient and suc h ot.'1er off s c f ~roof as t.'1e Ccr:imission may deem a cceptable through i ts rule- making p r ocedures B) t."le !1ous ina accor:unod.:ition is re9istered i r. accorda nce wit.1'1 section 205 e cf t."l is act C) t."le lenclord of such housing acco1TT.1odation is ?ropcr ly licensed gt; ursua nt t o the llou si g r&amp;gt;.egu!a tions i f such regulations require his or her licensi ng D) t!1e r.iana ger c: s-.1ch accor::moeation, when ot e t."ia!"l the owner is p r operly reg istcred pursua~t to the P.cusin&amp;lt Reg ulations i f s uch rcg;;lat:.ons r esu ire his or her rec:ristration El noti &amp;lt;:t! cf ;ouch incrca se com?Ees with sec tions 20 g ind 904 o: t."lis ~ct 30 2) Where tbe Hant Administra tcr finds tbat thece have been e xcessive and frclonged violations c f the Housing Re gu l a tions affectinq the bea lth, s afety and s ecurity of the tenants or the ha bitability o f the bousiog accc ~modation i n wnich such tenants r eside and that the landlord ha s failed to co rrect such v~olatioo s the Sent Adainistrator may r oll baci. the cents fer t he affected rental units to an amount which sball not be less tba n the February 1, 1573 tase r e nt ;or such renta l units until such time as the violation s ha ve been abated b A housing acccmmodation a nd e ach of the rental uni ts ther ein shall be deemed t o be in substantial complianc e with the Housing Regulation s ll if fo.x: fU r poses of the all j ust11ents llade in the rent ceil.inq in section 206 of this act all substantial violations cited a t thE tioe of the last inspection o f the housi ng accommodati on Frier to the effectiVE date of the increase by the De ?a rt~ent of Housi ng acd Ccmmcnity De v~lopmen t were abated witbin a fortJ i ve (US) day period tollo ving t he i $suance of the citaticn( s er that time g r anted by the Denart~ent c f Hous ing and Coms unit y Develop~ent and the D~part~ent of Hou si ng and Community Develofment has ce rtified tbe a~ateoe nt or the c wner or the J 1- t e nant has cectified tbe abate ment ao d has FreEen tcd evi~e nce to substantia t e such certification and (2) if fo e i urposes of the fil in g c f petitions fo r ad j us tments in t he rent ceiling as •re Ecri~ ed in sect ion 2 14 of th is a ct the bc using accommcda tion and each of the re ntal units t hecein have been i nspecte d at th e r equest of eac h l andl ord by t he Department of Housj og a nd Communi ty Devel op110 nt ll ithin the t hir ty (30) dayE iomediately precedin g the fi li ng o f a petition for adjust ment c) If se venty pe rcent (70 ot t he t 1;oants of a ho usin g a ccommodat ion sign an ag ree~ent fi led with the Sent Adminis tra t or tc h~ ve the r ent ce i lin g fer each ren tal un it i n t he housin g accommod~tion adj usted by a specifie~ percentage the oent Aemin i strator s hall im ~ed iately c ertify tb.e Rent Administrat or •s a;iproval o f the iocr ea oe. The ag reeme nt sha ll i nclude the signature cf e a ch tenan t the number o! eac h tenant rental uni t o r afa r tm ent, a nd a s ta teme nt t hat the agi= eement 11 i th the lan:ilc.rd was e nter ed i nto volun ta= i.l.y 11 thout any form cf cce.rc icn cn the pa r t of the landlcrc of t~e housing accompodat icn d) A t enant of a housing acco m~cdaticn who aftei= receipt of no l~ss thac fiv 5 G.a ys Hit t ei; notice that t~e landlc rd d es ir~s an i ns pect ion of tbe t 6nn nt o r e ntal unit for t be ;iurpos e of det~r miain~ whether the housinq OM 32 ccommodatioo is i n substant ial c O~Fliaoce wit h the Rous i ng negul a~ior.s ef uses vithou t geed cause t o ad mit o r cause t o be adm i t ted a n employee oi t~e Depa: tm e nt cf Ecasir.g a nd ~omounity Develo pment tor t he purpose cf ic~pecting the tenar.t s rental us i t er who r efuses without good cause to admi t or to cause to be aamitted t be laodlct d er the landlord s e mployee or con tractor f or t he FUrrcse of abating a oy viol ati on of the Housing negulatio o~ cited by t he Depa r tment of Housing and community DevelOF~en t hall waive tt.e r igb~ to cha l lenge t he val idi ~y oi the FrCfCSed djustme nt fo r r eason s t 4at tbe r e n tal unit occo pied by such tenant is not in substantial comp l iance with the Ho us ing lie&amp;lt;;ulations e o tbinq i n th is section shall te ccn ~t toed t o limit o abrogate a tenant s right to ini t i ate acy law f ul action to co rrect any viola ticn i n the t P.na n t s rental uni t or in t~e housing accommodation in vhicb that ren t al onit is loca t ed f lotwi t hstandi r.g a ny other prc visicc of this act io re nt s hall be adjus t ed under this act fer any r ental uni t ith respect to vbich there is a valid vritte n lease or rec ta l agre~1eot establisning the r e nt fe r su c h re ntal unit fo r the t erm of s uch writte n lease or re ntal a g ree~ent. En~olled Orig inal -33 g oy not ice of an adjust~en t pursuar.t to section 206 of this act shall contain tr.e registraticn oumter required by section 205(d) of this act a stateme nt cf the current rent, the increased rent, and the utilitie&amp;amp; ccvered by the rent vbich justify the adjustment or other justification foe the rent increase h) No adjustments in rent u~der this act may be implemented unless and until a full one hundred and eighty (180 ays have elapsed s ince any prier adjustment. Sec. 209. Rent Ceiling upon Terminat i9.JLQf Exemption and For Newly-Covered F.ental Units a) The rent ceiling for any rental ur.it in a housing accommodation exempted cy section 205 cf this act irom the provisions of sections 205(d) throuqh secticn 216 (except section 215) of this act upon the expiraticr. er termination of such exe~ption shall be the ~ent charged during the last six (5) consecuti ve months of the exe~ftion, increased by no more than five percent (53) of the rent charged during the last six (6) consecutive mor.ths of the exe~~tion. The increase may be effected ocly i n accoidance with the procedures specified ir sections 2C9(g) anc 904 of this act b) A s~ructure or building, incl uding the land appuctenajt thereto hich is lccated i~ the ~i £~rict of Colu~hia in which one (1) er more rental unit~ as defined in E.t:rolled Origiu~l 34- section 102(v) of this act is established after the eff~ctive date of this act, shall be thereafter defined as a housing accommodation for the purFOSes of this act. If any rental unit in such a housing accommodatio£ is not ctherwise exempted by one (1) of the frovisions cf section 205 of this act, the rent ceiling for the initial leasing Feriod or the first year of tenancy, whiche ver is shctter, shall be determined by the landlord and is deemed tc be the equivalent of ~aking the comfutations Sfecified in section 2C6(a) of this act. Sec. 210. Capital I:nprovements a) on a petition by the landlcrd, a rent adjustcent to provide for the cost of capital improve~ents, a~ortized over the useful life of such improvements er acccrding to Internal Revenue Service 9 uidel ines and afFlied en an equal basis to those rental units within the housing accommodation whicn benefit t ro~ s uch an improvement, shall be approved by the Rent Adminis trator: PROVIDED, lhat 1) {A) the i~proveC1ent would frotect, or enhance the health, safety or security ot the tenant or the habitability of the housing accommedaticn; er o) the i:npr cvement ill effect a saving in the use of energy by the hcusing accommcdaticn er is ictended to com?lY •ith a~plicable environC1ental frctectic~ regulations JS- PROVIDED That any savings en energy are passed on to the tenants; and (2 l) the a~ortized cost will net increase rents (aside from any increases otherwise prcvidec f er in this title) for a unit b~rnefittinq from the impr cven,ent in e xcess of ten percent (103) of the rent charged before the comrletion of the imprcvement; or (B) the P.er:t Administrator is satisfied based on the Rent Administrator's review and/or hearing c f a petitic~ tiled under this sect icn and such other i nfcraaticn or survey of the affected tenants as the Fent Administrator may reg~ire that t he interests cf t he affected tenants are being protect.ed. I&amp;lt; finding that the af f ected tenants desire the capital iaprovement and have agreed tc the rent adiustment req ui red to finance the ca pital improveuent ~ay be avidence that the interests of the t~nants are being p r otected b) Plans, contracts, specificat icns and i:ermits relating tc s uch capital improvements shall be retained for one (1) year by the landlord or his or her fesignated agent tor such i spection ~Y atfected tenants as such tenants may regu~st at the l andl ord s pl ace o f business in the ~istrict of Col umbia d·J.ring working hours. lf the landlcr:'i does net have a place of business in ~he District of cclumtia, the pla~s co~tracts specifications and fermit s rela ting to the Enrolled Ori£inal -36- ca pl tal im pro vement s s hall be made available u0cn regues t by tb c affected tenants at the Reota l Accc~modations Office c) Action by the Sent Administra tcr en a rent adjustme nt pursuant to this section shall t e ta ke n within sixty (60) days of recei pt ot plan s fer th e capital impro vemen t a pproved b y the appropriate District of Columbia agency or a7eocies. Sec 21 l ServicgS and raciJ.ities l f the :ent Ad~i nistra tor determines that t he r elated services or rela ted facilities supflied by a landlcrd fer a housing accommodat ion or tor an y reots4 unit tbereiD are subs taut ially incr eased or decreased t.he Een t administrator may increase o r decrease the ren t ceilirq as afplicable so as to proportionally reflect the va lu e cf the cha nge in services or facilities Sec 212. s~dshit P~titio n. {a) ilb ere an election :ia s been ma de pursuant tc section 206(c) of this act to seek a r ent a cjus taen t t hrough a hardship petition, the Ren t Ad ~in istratc r s hall, a fter review o~ the figures and co~putati cns set f o rth in the ~andlord's peti tion, lillow such adciit i cnal increase s in rent as would generate no ere than a n eight ~ercent (6 rate of return cooputed accoraing to sec t ion 212(b) of this act 37 b) In dct.ei::nining t.he r ate of retu r n for each housing accommodat.ion the fo llowing formula ccmputed ever a base pe riod of the cons&amp;amp;eutive t we lve (1:&amp;lt llCnths i11!lrediately receding t oe filinq of a petition und er t his act shall l:e use&amp;lt to 1) obtain t he net income by ~ub ttacting fr om the s um of maximu m possible r ental income bich can be derived cr am a housing acco mmo dation and the ia 1 imu~ amcunt of all a t.he r income which can be d erived fro~ t he housing acco mmodation ~h&amp;amp; fo llcving A) the operati n g e x penses: PBOVI DEC That th e follo wing items s hall not be allo wed as o perating expenses iJ me mbersnip fees in organiza t icns ~stal::lished to inf luence l eqislaticn and i:egulaticns i i) contributions to lobbying effor~s iii) contributions fer legal fees in tile pi:osecution of cla.ss action cases iv) political co t:!tribui:ions t o ca ndidc t.es for of.f ice v) mcrtgage pt: incipal a nd inte cest pay111ents vi) maintenance e x pen s es l o= waich the ndlcrd has been reimburs ed ty any securi~y 5apos i t insurance settlement judg mect fer jamaqes a g reed u pon gt;aym e n ts or an y other method vii) attcrney s fees char9ed foi ervices ccnnected vith ccut:!seling oi: li t i gation relate t o act ions ro ug bt. by the gov ernment cf tbe Dist i:ict o f :ol~nbi~ due to the landlord s i:epe a ted failu re t o comply 38- witb. applicable Ho usi ng liegulations as ~videuced by housing code •1 iolation notices issued by the De i;artn.eut cf Housi ng and Cc~munity Development; and {viii) any expenses for vhich tAe tenant hos la wfully paid direct ly B) the i:ianagement fee here applicable of no more than six perce nt (6 i of tbe maximut renta l income of the hou sing accom~odatior. unless an additicnal amount is appro ved by the Rent Adrainistrator pursuant tc section 212 gt 1 B l of t his act i) if in the comi;u taticn of a r a t e of r:turo, a landlord see ks to deduct a ma&amp;amp;agement fee io ex.cess of six pe rcent (65 of the maxiitu m i:cs.Eible rental income the landlor~ shall first file with the Rent Ad !tlnistr ator a petiticn t o a:low the e xcess to be deducted. T~e petition shall contain such infor matico as th e Sent Ad~inistra~or may reguire, includi ng but net l imited to the name cf ~he pa yee only sc muc h ox th€ e xcess o ver s ix percent (67 o the ma x.i;nu1:1 possible rental income as is a;:provP.d iy the Rent Administrator sha~l c e dEducted ii) i f the Rent Ad •ini~trato r deter mine s hasec on the petition and such ether information as the Rect hd~inistra tor may require ttat the e xcess or part thereof is reasonable, the P.ent Adzini ~trator may -39- permit the same ~xcess or sc ~uch of the excess as is reasonable C) proi:;erty taxes DJ depreciation expenses (ccmEuted on a straight line basis) of no more than twc percent {2i) of the assessed value of the ~uilding as deter~ined ty the ~ayor; no depreciation may te d educted f~r the value cf land El vacancy losses fer the bcusing accommodation; and {F) unccllected rents 2) divide the net income by the narket value of the housing acco~modation tc determine the rate of return C) If after any increase 11hich itay be authorized pursuant to this act, the landlord can sho w a negative cash flow for a particular housing accommodation after con5iceration of debt service, the Rent Administratcr, upcn a petition filed by the landlord, may allow such additional increase~ in rant as will provide a one-guarter of one percer.t (1/43) cash flew based on the Baximum fOSsible ren::a i ir.ccme fo r the housing acccromc:iation: flWVIDED, Tbat in the consideration of such petitico(s the Rent ~d~inistrator shall coosider the de~ree of hardship which the requ~sted increase will place upon the tenants of the housing acccmrooda t ion rolled Original 40- Sec. 2 13 1 acant ~ccommodatiQll a) Not1;i th s1:andi og subsection (b) of section 208 of this act vben a t enan t vacates a rental onit en hi s or her o wn i nit~ative or as a resul.t of a no t ice t c ~acate for a ny o f t!ie follov inq ca.uses 1) nonpayment of rent 12) violation of an obligation cf his or b€r tenancy; or (3) use of the accommoda tion fer an illegal pUrfcse or purposes as jetermined by a court cf coa1petent j urisdicticn tbGn, the r~nt c eiling may at the electi on c! the landlord e adj usted to either (Al the rent ceiling which wculd otherwise be applicable to such rental unit ander this act pl.us three percent (3 thereof, or (E t!Je rent ceil ing cf a s uostantially identical rental unit in the same housing accom 110C.a tio:i: PROVIDED That no increase under this sectio n shall he permitted unl.ess the hcusicg accommodation has been registe red under section 205 (b) o f this act b) For the purpose s of this secticn, rent al. units s hall e C.efined t o be "substantially identi.cal" vhere they contain essen~ielly the same squar e f cota g e, esse nt ially the SH•e floor plan compa rable ac:enities ard e&amp;lt ipment, compa rable lo cacio ns with respec t tc e Xfcsute and height (if e~ pos ure and heigh t have previousl y been factors in the amount of rent cbarqed and are in CO~Farable physical cond ition Olled O» i ci 41 a) The Rent Administrator or bis er her desigoee shall consider ad justments allo•ed by secticns 210, 211 and 212 of this act, or a challenge to a section 206 adjustment, upon a petition filed with him or her by the landlcrd er tenant of such rental unit. such petition shall ce filed with the aeot Administrator on a form provided cy the Bent Administratcr containing such infcrmaticn as the Rent Administrator or the ccmmission may reguire he Eent Administrator or his or her designee shall issue a decision and an order approving or denying, in vhcle or in part, each ~etitions within one hundred and twenty (120) days after such petition is filed 1tith the Rent ildministrator. Such time cay be eztended only by written agreement between the landlord and tenant of such rental un it b) Upon receipt of such petition, the Rent adlllinistrator or his or her designee shall not ify the non- petitioni~g pa~ty (landlord or tenaPt) cy certified ~ail or any o~her fer~ of service which assures delivery cf such ?eti,ion ancr of t he right of either party tc make, within titt~e n (15) days after tbe receiFt of ~uch notice, a w ri~ten request for a bearing on the fetiticn. If a hearing is ti~ely requested by either party, nctice of the time and place of ~he hearing shall be furnished the parties by certifiad mail or an y ctber torm of service v hich ass ures d e liver y at least f ift een 15) da ys befcre t h e co~mence ment of s uch bea ring. s uch notice shall i nfcrm eac h of the parties of hi s or her right t o r e tai n legal ccunse l to r epresent bi~ or her at the hear i ng c lt;:acb landlord of any rent al unit i; j t h respect to vhich a pe tit ion is filed or ini tia t ed ooder t his s ection shall submit to ~be Be nt Administrato r e r the ~ent Ad min i stra tor' s des ign ee with in f iftee n 15) da ys a f t e r demand theref or is made an i niormaticn s tat e ment en a f or m a?proved b y the ie nt Ad minist ra t o r ccn t ain ing the info r ma tion t he Ren~ Adm i nistrator er t he co m~ission ma y r11quire d The Ren t Admi nistr a tor or bi s er hEr desi goee may consolidate petitions and bearings r elating tc rental units in t h e same housing a c co mmcda t ion e Jhe Re~t AdDioistrator or bis er h•t designee may i thout holding a hear i ng re f use tc adjus t t be r e n t ce iling for any renta~ uait and may ~ismiss any pe titi on f or adjus t ment i f a i inal ceci s i on bas been a de en a petit ion tiled under t his sect icn e r under secticc 212 of O. C. Lav 1- 33 =o r adjustment as tc the same rent al uni t s vithi n the six b) mon ths immedia ~e ly precediag t he fili ng o f t he pendinq pe t 1 ti on llJ f) All gt;etitions filo&amp;gt;d u.nde.r this secticn, all heacings held r e l a ting therato a nd al l apfeal&amp;amp; ta ke n from decisions of the A~nt Administrator or llis er her des i~nee, shall ~e con~idered and held according tc the Frovisions of lhls section ao d to the "Dist•ict o f Ccloml::ia Administ t"ative Pt"ocedure Act" 10 c Cede, sec. 1- 150 1 et seq I n the c ase oi any direct irreconcilab l e conflict b~tw een the p rovisions of t his section and the Di&amp;amp;trict cf Coluob ia Ad oin ist ra t ve Procedu re Act the "Di&amp;amp;trict cf Col umbia Ad iti nistra tive Proce dure Act" shall afply 9 gt;ecisio ns of the aent AdministratCI er his or her designee shall be made oc the record relatiDg tc any petition filed with hi~ or her. An a~~eal from any dec ision of th~ lent Ad mi ni s trator or bis or hEc desi9ree may be ta ken by the aggrieved party t o t he Cc ~mis&amp;amp;ico vitb i n ten (1 0) days afte r the decision of the Rent Ad~ini strator or his or h~r desig nee or the Commiss ion may rev iew a decision of the Rent dministrator er the Re nt Addnistr ato.r s desi qnee on i~s c wn in itiat ive te Cc~mission m4 Y reverse ia whole or in part ar.y oecisio n of the eent Admin i s trator or t he aen Adoini$ttator •s dasignee wbjcn it f i Dd s to be acbitracy, capricious an abuse of discret i on, not in acco•cance wi th the previsions of this act c• uns ufportec by s ubstant ial e iaence i~ t he ceccrd cf t he ~roce~dic~ s Enrolled Original -44- before the Bent ~d~ini stra tcr or his or her designee or it may affirm io hole or in part, t he cent Administrator's or his or her designee s decision The Cc,miss i cn s hall issue a decision with respec t to an appeal vithin thirty (30) days a fter such a n appeal vas filed b) No increase it r~nt alloved under this act shall be i mpleoented unless the tenant concerned has heen 9i ve n v ritten notice pursuant to section 904 cf this act i A copy of any decision made by the Rent Ad ministrator o r bis or ber desiq nee er by the Comzission unde r this section shall be mailed b y certi fied mail or any other form of service vbich assures delivery to the parties to such decision jJ The aent Administrator and here aprlicable, the Commission, s hall accord priority to a landlord hardshi~ petition co vering a housing accommcdaticn fer vhic h the federal qoverllJ!le~t is Entitled t o afp r cve rent increases v here processing of such a petition bas not bequo v itbin the thirty (30) days i~mediately fcllo~ing the fili ng of the petition. Processing of s ue~ petition(s) shall begin no iater ~han five (5) days af rec receip t ~y the Eeot Administra tor o f vritt en reGuests fcom the landlord and fro m the federal n&amp;lt ency El ollc;;i Origf.~al Sec. 215. Security Deposit. Ne ferson shall de:nand or receive a security deposit for any rental unit where no security deposit was deman ded or received fer scch rental unit upon the effective date of this act. sec. 2 16. Judicial aevie w. Any ferscn or class of persons aggrieved by a decision of the commissicn, er by any fail'.He on the: part of ti e commissico er Bent Administrator to act within any time cer tain mandated by this act, may seek judicial review ot such decisicn er an order ccmpelling such decision by filing a fetiticn for review in tbe District of Columbia ccurt of Appeals. The Commission or the Rent Administrator may co&amp;amp;mence a civil action to enforce any rule or decision issued by them. TITLE III RENTAL SUPFLE~ENT PRCfFAM Sec. 301. I;liqibility a) The rentaJ ~Ufple:nent provided by this title shall be available tc any tenan t of a ren~al uuit in the District of Columbia 1) who is a bona fide reside&amp;amp;t cf a rental unit in t~e Dist=ict of Columbia pursuant tc regGlaticns promulgated by the Mayer, or the ~ayc r's desi~nee Enrollee Orig!nal 46 2 whose c uti: eut annual inccre (co mbined vi t h t he i nc om&amp;amp; o f all other pe t s cns residin9 in such tental unit does not e xc eed the e ligibi l ity inc ome limi ts es t ablis hed by the District o f Columb ia fo r persons e ligit l e t c recei ve h o using a ssistance pa y rents pursuant tc sec tic n 51 7 of the Condominium Act o f 1 976 '1 L.C. t av i- e9 { 31 wb.ose re nt (det e r mi ne d vi th cut regai:d f o r tbe r e ntal assistanc e pro vided herein) and utilitie s (utili ties f o r the pu r pose of t his sec t i on s hall i nclude heating fuel wa ter a ua sewer, gene ral purpos e electricity a nd ccokiog fuel to the extent paid by s uch tenant) EJCee d thirty-five pe rce nt 35 o f the ccabined gr css inccme cf all pers ons r e s i ding in s uch r enta l unit; a nd 4 whose to tal asse ts (c oml: ined with the a s sets o i al l oth e r ?er s ons resid i n9 i n such rent al uni t e xclud ing cash s urre nd er valu e in an y life insurance policy n an a moun t o i t went y-five thousand dc l lar :s 25 ,0 00.00) or l e ss personal c lotbi ng, a ut omo bi l e f n toitur e aod f urni shings d o 3ot exceed ten thousan d doll~ rs (510, 0 00- 00 i n value b No t !liths tan di r g any o ther r c vi sic n in this section, no tena nt sha l l be e lig i ble t c recei ve r e ntal s uppl e ments here unde r if a ny person re siain~ in t~e r e ntal uni t 47 1) is rece1 vi u9 monetary asaistance ei ther &amp;lt;li=ec tly or iud irectly und er the Aid tc Families with Dependent Childr e n P:i;:o gram (42 G. S. C. A. sec EOO et seg as a oe nded Aid t o the Elicd a nd Aid to the Totally and Permanently Disabled (Q2 u s c .A. sec. 131e et seq as aaended or such other public assi stance progra ms as may be S?eci fied by the ay or PROVID~D KC WEVEB That a tenant receiving benefits under t he Social Security fi cg i a Old Age surviv ors and Oisa.tilit y Income (42 o. s.c. s ec. 402-3 1 as amended s hall not by reason of the receip t cf such benefits be deeced ineli gible under this para graph or (2) is ceceivi ng mo netary ai:sistance under provis ions of the "Condom1n1um Act of 1976 t.C. Law 1-89 or (J) is r esid ing in a publicly e r FC i •ately o wned r ental unit administared operated maintained, or subsidize d in vhole or in Fart by an instrumentality o r agency oi the go vernment of the Dis t rict of Ccl umtia o r federal 9ov ernment: EF.O VlOED, f.C ii EVE5 That a tenant who r es ides in a si&amp;amp;~le-fa ~ily rencal acccm~odati c n financed under tbu federally in ~ured p rograas c f t he P&amp;lt;deral Honsinq ao~inistrat1o n (Chapt• r 37, Ti t le 39 u.s C as am ended shall not by re~son of such residence t e deemed ineligi~le under thi s title E::iroll.oC. vi i.giual -48- {c) No tenant receiviu; rental SUf flements under this title shall claim a ta .I credit under the prev isions of section 8 of the "District of Columbia lncc~e and Franchise Tax Act of 1947 D.C. Code, s&amp;lt;ic. 47-1567g as amended, for rent paid during the period fo r which such tenant received assistance here under d) Notvithstandirg any other prcvisict cf this act, no tenant shall be initially eligible to receive rental supplements hereunder if the rent being paid exceeds tne fo ll.owing amounts: Number of Non-Elderly or Non-aandicapped Persons F.en t Being Paid Residing in Unit Fer l!onth 1 170 2 2 {)5 3 307 4 340 374 6 llC9 -49- for Senior Citizens or HandicaFped, Number of Persons Residin9 in Unit 1 2 3 4-6 3Ci 301 307 E~rolied Or1gioaJ. same as non-elderly tal:le above. No person shall be deemed ineligible tc continue to receive renta~ supple~ents under this title beca~se a rent adjustment authorized pursuant to this act after the time the initial rent supplement was granted causes the rent paid per month to exceed the maximum allowable amount as set in this subsection. However, in computing the a1tcunt of the rent supplenent, that fart of the rent whic}. exceeds the maximum amount allowable under this sul:section shall net be considerec i~ the computation of the rental supflement Lhese limits shall be revised annually l:y the t1ay01: to reflect che average annual inc rease in rental hcusing costs iu the District of Cclumbia e) For the ;iurpcse of this title the ter1t "grcss income shall mean all items considered inccme for District of Columbia or federal ta~ purposes, acd all ether ~onies or pay~er.ts received by any individual residiDg in the rental E=rolled Original so- unit i ncl udinq b ut not limi t ed t o s ccial s Ecurity benefits unemplo y r;iP.n t ben efits vork aa D' s co2pellsa t i oo s ta~ e ben e fit s alimony an d chi ld s upport ensions retirement benefits annuities monetary gi fts in excess of t ilra e hundred dollars 3 00 .00) and such ot her su ms as tbe Ma yor or the aa yor s designee s hall frc1 t i~e tc ti~e deter:iiir:e Sec 302 ental supplement Gr an a) The l!l a yor is bere y authorized to ma ke rental supplement g rants available on a yearly basis t o e ligible r enters ic acco r dance vith the r ovisions of this tit le. Tbe amount cf such yearl y rent a l s up?lement grant s hall be det ermined by s uc tracting thirty- fi ve per cent (3Si) of t he comb i ned grc ss inccme of a ll pe rso ns resi di nq in such r e ntal unit frc m the jea rly rent due on that unit FRO VID~D HO PEV£ R, Tha t in DC CaEe shall s uch gran t el(ceed fi f teeo percent 1 5 cf t be gros s a nnual rent b) On or before the t ventieth 0th) day of eac!i mo nth p reced~~q t3e month in which r en t on t he r e ntal unit is due t he ~ayor shall. iorwarc one-twelfth 1/12) c f uch r e ntal s uppie l:leo t gr an t (ren tal supple ment. pay1teot) directly to t he e ligible r ent e r at the address o f the unit indi ca ted on the ce nte r' s a pplication term. En.t-o11ed Orig:.oal 51 c) Each re n ~al s uppleme n t ~aymen t shall be in t he f orm of a chec k d r a wn agai nst the depcsit ories c f t he Di strict of Columbia a r.d shall b e Fa yable jointly tc the ap plica nt and (as indi ca ted o n the applicat ion f orm) t he l andlord or de signee e ntitled to receive re ntal pay ment E f or the applican t s uni t d) Zach rental suppleme n t payme n t check s hall be dra wn i n s uch a manner as to bec o me void fo rt y-five (45 da ys after i ts issuance Sec 303 e&amp;lt;lministra tion a] The !l ayo r shall administer t he 2ental =u~plenent Pr ogram e stablished by t his t. itle b) The ttayor sha l l have the autbcrit y a nd po wer to pcomulqate amend rescind and enfocce s uch rules, r egulations and proc edur es for the administra t ion cf t h i s t i tle as are consiste n t with the prcvisicn s ot this title cl Ap9lication fer a r enta l supi:le ment g ran t shall be s ubmitted to the ~ayor and s hall be on a t e r m a s designated by t he ~a yoc. S uch form shal l conform insc far a s poss ibl e to ferns used by the federal gove r ntren t for its r ental azsistance programs he applica nt s bal l e xec ute suc h fo rm under oa th or affirmation as to the trut h cf the matters co ntai ned the r e i n. Addi ticnal ve r i fica tion proced ur~s ~ay be reyu:.red as are necessary to ensure that the iofo~mati oo 52- contai ned i n s uch form s i z accura te, incl udin g b ut not liaited to cei:tified copies of t a..x returns of ell those residi ng in the un it s t a t eme nts of net wcrth of al l those r e siding in the unit copi es of leases rent r eceipts or can~elled checks and vei:ification of tenef its free t he s oci a l sec urity Administration d) T!:te nayor shall r e Yiew the a pi;licaticn a nd detar~ine in a timely fashion the e l igibilit y of t he a~plicant Tbe applican t s hall be no t i f i ed in writing of a pi;roval or disappr oval o f tbe applicat icn s t ating the reaso ns f or a ny fi ndings of ineligibili t y. {e Action on all applicat ions filed under this t itle any hearings held relating thereto, acd all a~~eals t aken fr om deci sions of the ~a yor shall be ccnsidered an d held according to t he rules and regulati ons esta tl i s bed under this titl e a nd the District of Columbia Ad t ini s tcative Pr:ocei.l ur:e Act D. C. Cede, sec 1-150 1 et s eq In th e case of a ny dicect and i r:reconcilable ccnflict bet ween such rul es anc the "D istr:ict o f Colum.bia Admi ni strati ve Proced ure Act t~e pr:ovisions ot the "Distric t cf Col~mtia Ad ltinis•=ati ve Procedure Act" s:ia ll 9cvei::n f) To t be e xtent practical all inf o.rma ticn provided hy dn applicant shall t e c on! idential a nd s hal l not he w Enrolled OriGinal 53- disclosed in s uch a form as to identit y thE ren t s ub s idy grant applicant sec 304 ontinut:d Eligibili ty a) sii ty (60) cays prior to tbe e xpira tion of any rental suppl ement authorized under section 302 of this act the departmeot shall ?Jotif y, in writing, the t e nant receiv i ng r e ntal sUFfl e~ent tha t the rental supplement gr an t is about to exri re and that t he tenant if eligible and desiring to contin ue to receive rental supple~ent must r ea?ply vithin thirt7 (30 days upon recei?t of such notice The ~enant shall rea Fply by e xecuting under oath o r affir matio n a state~ent ci continued eligibility on a form approved by the ~ayor and submitti ng sa me to the ~ayor- Exce pt as other vise Frc vided io this section the pro visions ot section 303 cf this act shall apply to the p4ocessin9 of stateme nt5 cf ccttinued e ligibility under this section Unless the Mayer dete rmines that such person is not eliyible fo e a rental s upplement granc such assistance shall cont i nue fe r t he succeeding t velve (12) oont hs pro videc the t enan t cont inues t o be aligibla therefor. Sec 305 er minatiQ] of iligitili.i:i a) I f at any time a t enant receiv ing rental s upp leme nts hereunde r fa ils co sa tisfy the reg uire~ents of section ~01 relating to condi~ions of e llqibility te sball im~ediate)J co ti fy io 5 4 citin g the Mayer of his ineliqi~i lit y EEnt a! s upple~ent shall t e rminate on the ne x t day therea fter upon v hich rent i due b) If at any t ime the ~ayor deter~ines that a tenan t receiving r ental sup ~lements is n e t or has c eased t o be, eligi bl e therefor, he e~a ~l so no t ify the t en ant and landlord i o writ i ng SEtting torth the reason s for such ueter ~ination Ren tal s upplement pay~ents shall terminate on the ne xt day ~he r e nt is due occ urring at least thi r ty (JOJ cay s after the da te zuc~ notice is giv en unlees vitbin 1fteeo (1 5) c;iys a fter the receipt cf s uch notice th e tenant submits to t be ~ayor a ~rit ten sta teme nt under oat h or affirmation and ~ncl~dir.g any availatle su~portinq uocuments assertinq his reasons for al l egitg contitued eligibilit y \iithin thirty (30) da ys fo llc;ii nc; t he recei pt o f $UCh s tatemeut anc oocu:ner.t s the ~ayer shall make tbe final deter~i oation of such tenant' s el igibility f o r continuec r~ceipt of r€ntdl scpp lemeot Sec 306 Iax..J;X§!ropt i2.r a hl l aionie r e ceived by a ny tenan t through r e ntal s upplement grants und er t his act are hereby exe~pt f~om income ~ax es pa yabl€ pur~uant to t he "Di s trict o Colu:n!:ii'l Income and Franchise 'Iax ;\ct of l9 47 as a:nended, ef ~ective July 16, 1947 61 Stat. 331 e t seq 55- TlTl.E lV R.i:VESlJE sec. 40 1. Annual Re:ital Unit fee. Each landlord reguirad to register under this act shall F•Y a fee of two iollars 2. 00) fo• each renta ui:it iI a bcusing accommodation registered by the landlcrd. 1he fee shall be paid annually to the gcvern~ent of the ristrict cf Columbia at the time the landlord applies for his or her business licecse or a renewal thereof; or in the case cf a housing accommodatio~ f o r which oc such license is required, at such time and in suet anne r as the Com;i:issicn inay de t ermine such fees shall te deposited in a timely manner in such depository or depositories designated by the government of the District of Columbia for such purFcses. T!TLE V EV.ICTICtlS i&amp;gt;ND RETAlIATOiiY !CTlO~ Sec. 501. Evictions a) llo tenant shall be evicted frcir a rental unit for any reasou other than non-payment of r€nt ur.leEs be or she bas been served ~i~h a writt&amp;amp;n notice tc vacate w~ic h meets the re~uirements of this act. Notice cf all evictions other ~ban for ncn-payment of rent shall te S€cV€d u~cn beth t~e tenant and the P.en~ Admitistratot. Er.~oll~c Origi~al 5&amp;amp b) No t eClan t sha ll l:e e victe d fr ee a r e nta l unit, no itbstanding the e xpira tion o f h i s er her leas e er renta l agreece nt, so l o nq a s he o r sh e continues tc Fay the rent to which the landlord is enti tled for s uc h i:e ntal un it un l es s 1) the i:enant is violatinq an o bligation of hi s or her tenancy a nd f~i l.s tc co r rect s uch v i cla t ioo vithin thir~y (30) days after r ec eiv i ng notic e therec f fro m th e landlor d 2) a co urt cf competent uriEdicticn has de ter~ined that the te nant has perf ormed an i llegal a c t ithi n s uc h rental un i t or housiug accca moc a tion 3) the land l ord see ks in geed fait h t o reco ver possession of su c h r e ntal unit foe his or b e e imme diate and persona l u se and o ccupanc y as 11 d ve llin g Q) t he land l ord ha s i n 9000 fait h c ontracted i n riting t o s ell t he re ntal uni t er the bousinq accommodatio n i n wh ich suc h r e ntal unit i s located f or the im~ediate and personal use of and occ updnc y by aocth~r pe rscn, sc long as at the time t he ov ner ci te.ts the r ental unit ct bousinq accommodatio n f o r sa le the landlord bas sc n c ti fie d t he i oan t c wri ting and extende d to tr.e t e nac t an OFpcrtun ity to ?urctase a s pro vided in t itle VIII cf th is a ct PfW\i I DC: D, That s uch re nt al unit is not beir.g ccnve rted to a condo minium o r a ccope ra ti ve 57 Tbe l a ndlord se e ks in g e ed faith to recover po ssession of t~ e r e ntal un i t A) for the i mmedi ate FOrfos E o f making alte rations o r r eno va tio ns t o the rental unit which can not s a f e ly or r e asonably be acconplished vhile the rent al unit i s occupie1 s o long a s the pla ns fo r s uch alterations ha ve been filed vit h th e Re nt Admin i s trator and apFroved by t he Bent Ad mi n i s trat or a n d such plans d e mcrst r ate that the proposed alte rations o r r enovations c annot !afel y or r~ason~bly be accomplished while the unit is cccupi ed; o r (E) for tbe in0ediat~ purfcse c f demolis h ing the bousiog accom.:noda tion i n vbicb such rental uoit i s l oc?1 t ed and c e p!.ac i n g it v i t h ne" cons t ructio n: F!iO'rIDED. Th a t a co py ot the bui lding permit for such n e w construction has ueen f iled with the Rent Ad mini s tra tcr and ffiOV IDED FURTH ER Tha t tbe r e q u iremen ts c f titl e VIII cf t his a c t ha ve been complied wit h; er (C J fo r the i mme d i ate i:uq:ose c f su bstantially re habili ta~in9 the nous in' accommcdation PllOVI DEt rba t t he r equire!l! E: nts of t i t l e VI II ba ve bee n cu~plied ~it o r (DJ fo r the i 111 mediate puq:ose o f discont in uing the hou s i ng use and occu ~accy o f ucb r e ntal uni t PP.CVT DED, That prior t o recove ricg pcssessioo fro 3 j Oll~d Original -58- th e tenao t (s tbe l anclord s hall file, with the Rent Adtti.nist r a t or, a fully executed a ffidavjt s e t ti ng f orth t he follo wing 1 t hat the landlc.rd wi l l not canse the r en tal unit or the hc usi cg accommodation whi che ver is applicat le to te sub;ta~tiall y reha bi l i tated 2) tha t the laodl c.rd will not Flac e the r ental unit or the bcus inq accommodation whichever i s app licatle, i nto use and occu?ancy a s a rent al acco~mcd ation f or a c ontinuo us t wel ve 1:&amp;lt ll&amp;gt; Cnth period beg inning from the da te t~at such nse i s ciscontinued pursuant tc t his s e c tion c l (1) In a oy case irnere a l a ndlord seeks to recover p.ossessi on of a rent al unit under subsecti cns (b 3 b q b 5 A b 5 S) or (b 5 C cf secti on 50 1 of tnis act, be or s he sb.all firs t notify t be t e oa11 t ill 11r iting at least nine t y (90) days prior theretc of bis or ber inte~t T. o recover possessi on of s ucb r e otal ~nit 2) In any case where t he l a oclcr d see ks to recover p osse s s ion of a renta l uni t purs uant to s ection 501 (b 5 C) of this ~ct fo e purposes cf s l:l:l£ tan tial 59- r e habilita tion, such nctic e s hall be in acccr dance with section 705 o f t his act 3) Io any case ere a lan&amp;lt lcrd ~eeks to r ecover possession of a rent al unit or housing acccr.m cda ticn t o convert such rental unit or housing acccmmcdaticn to a condominium, or cooperat ive, or to an o ther use nct ice s hal l be gi ven accorcinq to the provisions ct secti o n 208(b) o f the "Condominium Act o f 1976 o. c. La w 1-8 9 effec t i ve Macch 27, 1977, or sec tions b 03 and 604 o f th is act especti v e1y {4) ftirty 0) days notice s hall te provided in al l o ther cases 5) The notice reguired shall cottain a state111er.t de t ail i ng the r e as ons fo r the e victio n a nd if t he hou s ing accoonoda t ion is r equired t o be regis t ered ty thi s act, a state~ent tha~ the housing accomQodaticn is registered vith th e Corom i ssio n and t he re~ist raticn auml::er c f the accozmoda t ion d) t;o landlord s hall de :unc. or :cec.i i ve rent fo r any rental ~nit which he or s ne nas r epcsses s ed under sections 501 (b {3l or 501 {l { 5 0) of this act. dur ing th t welve (12 ont h peri od begin ni nq o n the date he er she rEcovered possessio~ of such rental unit No per son wbc bas purchased a rental uni~ which ~as been re possessed by a la ndlord unuer E.nrc l le :i O.t· i S i.oe:&amp;lt;l 60- s ectio n 50 1 (b 4) of this act s ha l l de ma nd er rec ei ve r e n t for s uch r en t al unit during t he t welve {12 cnth peri od beginning on the dat e en v hich s uch la ndlord r eco ver ed such r e nta l uni t e) I n the case ot a ny r e nt a l uni t vbicb bas been re pos sess e d by a landlcr d under s ectio n 50 1 {b) {5 A) of this a ct t be t e na nt f r om whom t be la ndlcrd repcssessed s uch unit s hall bave an ab so lute r ig ht to re- ren t su c h oni t i~mediately u pon completion of t he r eno va ticn o r a lter a tion Where the renova tions er al tera tio ns are nece ssar y t o b ri ng the uni t in t o s ubs tant ial c omplia nc e wi t h the Ho us ing Regulation s t he t e niln t ma y re- rent a t the sa ~e rent a nd under t he same obligations as vere in effec t a t t he ti me he o r s he va s dispo ssesse d: PROV I DED, Th a t such r e no vat ions or alterations ve r e not mace necessary b y t he ne~ligent o r malicious conduct. o f such t enan t f) Te na nts displaced by act ions ~nder s Gct i cn 501 i 5) of thi s act shal l be e nti t led to t eceiv e reloca tio~ assis tance as se t for th in title VllI of t his act f&amp;amp;OV ID!D That the tenants meet t be eligibi lity c riteria of tbat title Sec 502. ae t alia.:t.12r v Action a Ne l a ndlor:'I s ha ll t ake any re~a lia tory act i o n agains t any tena nt vho exercises a n y ris ~t confe rred ~p en him or her by thi s a c t Y any r uJ.e Eurolled O.·ig~n!.l -6 i or o r der issued pursua Et Lb eretc o r by any ether pro vis ions of la w. Retalia:.ory action otay uicluce any action or proceeding not other wise ~er~itted by la w which see ks to recover possession of a r ental unit action v t,ich vculd increase rent decrease services increase the obliqation of a tenant or constit ute u ndue o r unavoidable i ncon ve nience, violate the privacy o f the tenant harass, re 6uce the qu ality oc quanti ty of s e rvice a n d an y r efusal tc honor a lease or rental aqreement er any frcvisicn cf a lease or ~ental a greement refusal tu rene v a lease er rental agreement, termination of a tenancy without c ause a nd any ethe r for~ of t hreat or coercion b) In determining v h e tber a n acticn tal&amp;lt;e n by a lanelord against a tenant i s retaliatory acticc t he trier ui fact shall ta11.e into consideration v be tb er 11itbin the six (6) month s preceding such landlcrd acti cn the tenact 1) has made a witnessed ora l er n itte n request to t~€ landlord t o makE refairs vh ich at € nec e~!ar y to bring tne housi n; acco~~oda tion or the rental unit into compliance with the Housinq ~egulaticns 2) contacted app ropriate officials cf the go vernment ot the Dist ~ict o t Colum ~ia e i the r crall y in the p r esence of a witness er in vr iting ccnc~rnin g e xisting violation~ of the Hous ing &amp;amp;egula t ions in the rental unit be -6 2- or sh e occupies or perta in~n9 t o the hcusin g acccmmcdation in v hich s uch rental unit i s located er r efot t ed to s uc h offic ials s uspected vic l ations •hich if ccnf ir med vould r e nde r such =enta.J. unit or hou si ng accc~todat ion in non- compliance vitb the Hous ing Re9ul ation s 3) l egally vitbheld a ll or part cf bis o r her r e nt, afte r havioq qive o a reasonable nctice to the l a ndl.o r d eit her orally i n the presence cf a wi t ness or in wri t i ng of a violation of the Ho using Fegula tions 4) organi zed, been a meml::er c:t, er bee n involved in any lawful activit ies per~aioing t o a tenant orqan iza ticn 5) ma de an Effort t o s ecure er edc rce any of his or he r r ig hts un der his o r her l e ase or contract with the landlord or 6 J br ought l egal a ct ion aga inst th e landlord TITLE VI SALE OF RE~TAL HCU SlSG Sec. 601 a le of~ingle- Fa mily csi~g_.Asco~mod~tio ns a) Any owne r oi. a housing accc1ucda ticn ccrq:rised of a singl e r e ntal un i t may sel suc h housing a cco~modation to a purchaser but on l y after s uch ovne r ha s given the t enan t of such hou s ing acco~modatiun aa OFFOC~ u~ity t c FU ~cbase suc h -63- housing a cco mmodation at a price vbich represe nt s a bona fide offe r of sale A wri tten offer shall te qi veo t o the tenant by the landlord. The offe r to purchase the bousin g accommod~tion shall include but not be linited t o the asking price f or the housing accommodation and a sta tement oi the tena nt' s right to purchase the bcusing accc~modatico under the pro visions of section 60 1 of this a ct The ten ant shal l be affcrded at least forty-five (Q5) days in vhich to make a contract vitb the landlord for the purchase of t he accom~odation at a mutually agreeable f t i ce and under ~utually agreeable ter ms b) The tenan t shall also have the right o f f irst refusal duri nq ~he fifteen (15) days a fter the landlord has received a valid sales contract or o ther written cffer t o purchase from a prospective purchaser c If the housing accommodation is net &amp;amp;old d uring the $ix (61 months i:11med iately f ollowing t he original otte r to the tenant under subse ction (a) of th~s s ecticn and i s still being offe red for sale t he landlord s hall ttake a not her to the tenant in t he same manner as tie f irst offer as :11ade. sec. 60 al~ Housing Accomm cg~ tiscs Ccmerise.9 Q_t I~o or ~ore Rental un i t2 I I -6u- A landlord of a housing accommodaticn ccmfri se1 of t vo 2) o r more rente l units may sell it tc a fUichaser bu t only afte= the landlord has done the follo viog a) in the case ot a housin g accoaecdaticn coc prised of fo uc (4) rental units er less, given tbe current t e nants jointly or severally an opportunity to fUrchaEe the housi ng accommoda tion at 11 price vhicb r eprese nts a bcna fide offer of sale A v=itten notice cf intent tc sell shall be given to the tenants b y the .landlord Tbe no tice shall i nclude but not ~e limit ed t o the asking price for the hous ing accom modation and a statement cf the tenant righ t to pur chase the housing acco~modation under the fro vi s i o ns of tnis section The t enants shall be a ffccded at least fo rty- fi ve (ll5) days in vhich t o c ontract v itb the landlo r d for the rcha se of tae housing accommoda tico at a mutually agreeable pric~ and under mutually agreeable term s At the e xpiration of t~ e fo rty-five (45) day i:eriod, the landlord s hall provide an a dditional fifteen (1 5) day ;erioa during vh i cb any oae of tbe c urrent t enants ~ay ccotrac~ vi tb t he lanjlord for t he purchase of the acco cdatioo at a mutually agreea ble price a nd uader mutually aqreeable terms o r (b) io the case of a housin g acco ~icdaticn co~prised of :nore t!lan four (4) rental units, and vhich ba~ an o r ganization of tenantE with t~e leqal capacit~ t o bold ceal t;.nro 11 ea Cr.L:;inal -65- estate who have previcusly i:idicated an interest in purc~asing the housing accommodation, given the tenants an o~portunity to purchas€ the housing acccmmcdatico at a price which represents a bona fide offer cf sale. A 1;ritten notice of intent to sell shaJ.1 be given to the tenants by the landlord. The notice shall include, but cct be limited to the asking price fer the housing acccm~cdatico and a statement of the tenants right to purchase t he housing accommodation under t.he provisions cf secticn 602 of this act The tenants shall be afforded at least fort y- five (45) days in which to contract with the landlcrd fer the purchase of the housing acccmmodation at a mutually agreeable price and under mutually agreeable terms. sec. 603. Conversion of a Housin.!Ll£.£.£!J!!£datign to a Cooperative a) Every ter.ant of a housing accca·mcdation vhich the landlord seeks to convert from a rental ta1is tc a cooperative shall be nctified in writing of the landlord's intc~t to convert the housing acccmmodaticn tc a cooperative not less than one hundred and tventy {120) daJS bcfore the conversion thereof. The landlord shall alsc ~ake to each tenant of the housing accommodation a tcna fine cffer of sale of the rental unit which such tenant ccc~Fies. The offer shall incl ude, but not be limited to, the asking price r MM Enrollee Or!ginal 66- tor the r ental unit 3nd a state ment of the tenant s righ t to purchase the rental unit uncer the Frc vi s iccs of sect io n 603 o i this act. The tena nt st.all be afforded not l ess than sill.ty (60) days i n vbich t o contract vith t he lan dl ord tor the ?D rchase of tbe ur.i t at a mu tual ly agreeatle price aod unde r mutually agreeable terms b lo t e nant s hall be ser ved with a nctice to vacate until ni ne t y (90) days after the tenant received no tice of the ov ner's in t e nt to conv ert and prier to t he e xpiration of t he s ixty (fiO) day pe r:iod r equired undoH subsection (a of this section oc recei pt of the t ena nt s wr:it ten re jection of the bona fide of fer o f .sale o f the rental unit whiche ver OCCU I:'S fi r st c) Yot!lioq i n this s ection shall l:e ccnstrued to permit th e conversion cf rental uni t s tc ccoperative uni t s where o thecwi$e ?COhibited by law. Sec. 604. Coq ve r s ion of d :iousin.9 Accc1rn1 cda ti.i Another Use a) Every tenant of a bousing accc~mcdaticn which t he ~and~ord saaks t~ ccnvert from a r ent a l t a£is t o a use ot~ec tJlao fer &amp;amp;en-tra nsie nt reside nti a l ccc1q:aocy ball !le notif i ed in wr itinq cf the landlord s intent to convect the housi ng accom~odation not l ess tha n cne hundred and t we ncy (1 20) days llefore t he conversion therecf 67 b lo tenant of &amp;lt;I hoGsing accom;iicdaticn vhicb the landlord seeks to convert to a use oth€r than fer non- tcansient residen~ial ccc ufa11cy shall te served with a notice to vacate until ninety (90) days aft&amp;amp;r the t&amp;amp;nant received notice cf the l anclord's intert tc ccnvert c) Ncthing in section 604 cf this act sba.11 be construed to per ~it the coGversion of a ho~siag acco~modation as defined by section 102 (f) cf this act to a use other than for non-transient residectial occupancy if the conversi on is othervise prohibited by lav. Sec. 605. Amendments to the Condf~1niE of 1976. Item (i) of subparagrafh (B) of aragrai:h (1) cf sal:secticn (b) of section 501 of the "Condominium Act cf 1976 D.c. La1o1 1-89) is amended to read as follo ws: 11 (i) multiply t he number of r&amp;amp;ctal urits in the following categories by the correspcndi~g rent I gt;228. 5C fo one (1) bed::ocm rental unit II 287 for t wo 2) bedroom r~ntal units c rr 403 fee three (3) oi: more i&amp;gt;edroom rental un i ts V 174 tor effici&amp;lt;;ncy ental uni ts an d1 I.ITLE VII SU3STANTIAL ~EHIEIL:TATICN CF HCOSIXG ACCC~~ODAllOSS PRC BICK A NJ\ll ~AS EVICTED 68- sec 7CL Applica t:ility of Pro vi§icns lhe provis ions of this title apply to the substantial rehabilitation of {a) any housing accommodation with resFect to Vbicb tbe landlord has notifie d the tena nts of the rer. t al units Lberein, after tba eff ective date of this act, of the l a ndlord s in tent to substantially r ehatili tate; or (b) any bousing accommodaticn with resFect to which the la ndlord ~a s notified the t enan t s cf tbe rental units tbcr~in prior t o the e ffeccive date of thi~ act of the landlord s intenL to sub s~aotially reba~ilitate. Sec 702. £~titio n for Adi~.§.J;ment in Fent C~l SL Q~ t o Substantia1 5!Jlabilitaticn. A landlord of a housing acccmmoda t icn fer wbicb tbe allowable r ent ceiling is computed acccrdins t o sec t ion 206 of this act from which any tenant of any rental un i t therein wo uld be evicted for the purpose of s u.tstantiai cebabili~ation, must petition the Bent Administratcr in order to substantially rehabilitate the bousin9 accoomodation and for an adj~stment io the allo wable rent ce.1..ling n on compl etion oi t"e substantial re hal:ili t ation. The landl ot s ;i e titio t shall be tiled and con~idered in accordance with ~be adjust~ent proced u•e set fcrth io seetion 214 of this ac t. Sec. 703. Criter ia for A£,Erovi.n.g__f£tition 69 a} =n determining whether to apFtcve a i;etiticn for substantial -c·eha bilita ti on of a housi 1:9 accc111 mcda ti on from which any tenant Dust be evicted the &amp;amp;ent Ad~inistrator shall 1) consider the impact of the prcpcsed substantial rehabilitation on the tenai:ts cf the housing acco m 111oda ti on 2) consider the existing conditicn cf the housing accommodation and the rental units containec therein and the degree to vhich a~y viclaticns of the Hcusing Regulations constitute an impairmert to the health, welfare and safety of the tenants 3) eiamine the plans, specifications and projected costs for the substantial rebabilitaticn all of vhich sr.all be made available to the Bent Administrator by the landlord of the housing accommodaticn and (4) evaluate such other factc s as the Rent Administrator may deem relevant b) If the !tent Administrator cetei:mines that 1) a housing accom:rndation is tc be substantially r~habilitated; a~d (2) the interests of tenants cf tr.e housing acco~moda~ion to be substantially rehatilitatEd have been ully considered, then the Rent Acministzatcr sl:all a rove 7 c- contingent u~oo the ac tual completion cf the ~utstaotial rehabil itation ir. accotdance with tbe Flans, specifications a nd at a cost equal to or exc eeding fifty fe r cent (50 of t b e mar~et va lue of t he housi ng accoz~cdaticn, an adjustment in th e allowable r e nt ceiling for the rental units conta ined i n the housin g accommodation. Sec. 704 Ja.Q Jlt cf Adiustment in ]ent Ceiling for S ubstantial ~eh~JU.litation Oo ma k ing th e determina tion permi tted zy section 703 b) of this a ct for a ho using acco mmodatio n to which t itle II o f this ~ct is applicable, the Rent Admini~tratot may approve for each rental unit in the housin g acccmmcdaticn, an adjust~ent in th e r a nt c e ilin g during t he ini tial leasing ?eriod o r the i r s t year o f t e nancy fol l c v ing cospletion of the subs~antial r e ha bili tatio n of the hcusing acco~moda tion w ~ich is no greater than the equivale n t of cne hundred aod t wa nty-five perce nt (125 of the rent ceiling applicable to that rental unit i n the :iousir.q acccmitcdaticn prior to su b s tantial r~ha bi li~~tioo For purpo~Es cf the ap~licatioo oi lhe ~rovisioo s of s ectio n 206 of t h i~ act ther~after t h e re~t ceil inq as a djus~ed i s deemed to be the eguivalent of making t he c omp utations specified in secticn 206 (a of tnis act Sec. 705. llehabilita te 71 otice cf Intent to sutstan!iaJ1 a) The lan C.lor d of a housing ace cu:modat i en which the landlord intends to sutstantially rehabilitat€ shall provide the tenants of every rental unit thereir. with a written sLatement of intent tc substantially r ehabilitate at least one hun~red and twenty {120) days prior to the commencement oi the sutstanLial rehabilitation b) The land.lord s written statemei:t cf intent to subztantially rehabilitate the housinq acccmmcdaticn shall be on sue~ form a nd contain such inforu:atict as the Commission, by regulation, may require Sec. 706 Q.tice to vaca~e for SEt§.t Ll;isl Rehab i li tajj,Qn No tenant shall be served •ith a notice to vacate any rental unit i n a housing accommodation ~hicb the landlord intends to substantially i:ehabilitate u::til ninety (90) days after the tenant received tbw landlord's state~ent of intent to substantially i:ehabilitate the hcusing accc~~cda~ion in which the tenant i:esid€S Sec. 707 enant §..Riqht to Re-rent. Any tenant dis~laced frora a r ental unit by the sutstantial rehabilitation of the housing accoro~odation in which the r e ntal unit is located shall have a riqbt to i:e-rent the -7 2- re ntal unit imoedi a tely upon the co mpl&amp;amp;tion of the s ubstantial r ehabilitation fI~E VIII EEL OC ATION ASSISTANC POR T.EN A!l'r-S DISfl.ACED BY SUBSTANTIAL REH AEILITATIC~ C f DEeOIITI CN Sec. 801 Qi~cf Right t o Relccation_Assistance »oil.sd Originel No landJ.o r d shall substantially rehabilitate ct demolish an7 housing accommodat i on unless t here bas fir s t t e en served u pon each tenant residing therein a written notice of intent to rehabilitat e or de mclish the hou si ng acccm mcdation, i n acco rdance with sections 701 or 501 (b 5 E such no tice s hall advise the tenants of t heir r i gb t to relocati o n assi s t ance under this act o r any othe r i;.c 1. a v, and tlle procedures for applyi ng tor such assistance. The Commission s hall prescribe th e content of s uch notice. No ten an t may b~ evicte d fro~ a housing accommodatio n which the landlord intends to substaotially Iehabilita t e er d emolish (or which the landlorc intends tc sel~ to another pe rscn wbc to t~e landlord's koo wled9e intends to sutsta otially rehabi li tate or demol ish it unles s this sectio n ha~ been ccm flied wi th Nothing contained in this section s ha ll be constr ued to licit a landlord s ri9bt to e vict a ten ant for aoo-~ayment of rent or vio:a t ico of ~n obl i ga t ion cf t he tenancy i::JJ1'0ll Ori~inai -73- p=ovided such actior. to evict is in co 1pli;:ince wit.'i section 501 o f this act. Sec. u02 Eligibility Requirements for ~eloc;:i tier. } ssi stance. F.ach landlord con~encing substar.tial rehabilita t ion or deirolition on or after t.'ic effective date of this act shall pay relocation assistance in an amount calculated pursuant to section 803 of this act, to all tenants of such housing a ccanmodation who al were living in the rental uni ts contained therein f ror:t which t.'iey are being dis9laced at the tine the notice required by section 701 or sec t ior. 50l(b 5 3 of this act is given; and (b ire displaced fron rental units because such ousing accorrrnodation in which t.'iey are located is to be s ubstantially rehabilitated or denolished Sec. 803. Relocation i'.ssistance I'ayme!1ts a) The amou~t of relocation assist;:ince ~ayable to a d i splaced tenant shall be calculated as follows 1) Relocati or. ass istance in t.'ie anount of cne hundred and twenty ive dollars 125.00) for euch =ocrn in the r e ntal unit shall be payable to the tenants or subten;:ints beuring the cost of rcr.oving the majority of &amp;lt;:he furnishi."lgS. For t.'le puQoses of t."iis section, il "rom" in a rental unit ~eil s any S?ucc sh:ty EO) squ~re feet or 74- larg e r vbic h has a fix ed c eiling a nd a flocr and i s subdivided vi th f ixed farti~ioos oo al l side s but does not mean bathrooms, balconies, c lose ts pa ntries, kitche ns foyers hallvays storage areas, utility cc cms or t he lik e 2) 7he ~a yo r shall ad just the a~cunt to he pai1 tenants f o r reloca tion assis tance from time tc time in order to reflect chanoes i o t he cost of movi c g vithic the vash ington ~etropoli~a o Ar ea. Such ad just ~ents shall be made pursuaot t o t he Cis~rict of Col uctia Administrative Proced ure Act D. c. Cede, sec 1-1501 et seg not more than or.ce in any calendar year b) Relocation assis1:aoce shall be faid to eligible tena nts, not la1:er tha n t wenty-four (2 hcurs pri er to the da t e the r e ntal unit i~ 1:0 be vaca t ed t y the tenant (s) or subte nant (s PROVIDED, Tha t the landlcrd ha s received at l e a s t ten (10) da ys (e llclud.1.n9 Sa turday s sun c!ays and holida ys) advance wr itte n notice of th e datE UfCD which the unit is to be va cated. where the tenant dces net pto vide tile landlo::il ith a l east a ten (1 0) day cctice, the relocatio n assistance s hall be pai d withir. th i rty (30) days a fter t;he uni t is vaca ted c) Payment of r: e loca1:ioo ass istance sha ll not be requ~red wi t h respect 1:0 any rental unit which is the s ub ject of an o~ts ta ndiog ju~g~eot for fcsse ssicn ottained 75- ny the la ncilord or landlora•s pr edecesscr io interest again s t t he ten ants or subtena nts for a cause of action va ether suc h cause of action arises be f cre er after the serv icP. o f th e notice of intention to rehabilitate or t o :I e niolisb. If ho we ver the judgment fe r pcssession is ba s ed upon noo-pay:1&amp;lt; e nt of rent and arises af ti; r the ncti ce of inten t to r ehabilitate or to demolish bas l:eeo given, the n r elocatio n assis tance shall be regu ired in an a mount r educed by the amount determined to he due and c wing to the landlord ~y t he c ourt rendering the judg ~ent fer possession. Sec 804 gelocation Advisory Services The first sentence of section 5- 132(b) of the District o f Co lumbia Cocie (as added by seci;ion 5 1&amp;amp; of the 11Ccndc1tilliu:n Act o f 1976 11 i c. La 11 1- as ef fect ive arch 27 1$7'7) is hereby a~endnd by adding the words or is sub~t antial ly re habili t 'ited or demolished 11 i:1111ed ia tely a ft e r the phrase "conv erted t.roc re ntal to condominium unit s and by inserting the phrase 11 substantially rehabilita ted or :ie31olishe d bet.Veen the words "converte d" and 11 buildin9 at the e nd of such sen~P.nce in ascert3ining th e relocation need s of tenan cs d ispl aced by suDstaotia l r ehabilitat ion or de3olition t he St 3ndards set forth ic sectio n 517(a) of the "C.:ondominiu1:1 Act of 1976 r c La w 1-es effecti·1e /larc h 27, 1977 sh;ill be used 76- Sec. 805 SlJlant liot 1.ine. W ithi thirty (30) days free the ef fective dat E of this act t he Re ntal AccoiDJDodations Commission s hall establish a Ienaa t Bot Line The primar y purpose o f this hot line is t o provid e assistance to lo v and moderate income t enants Tc carry out this purpcse, t he functions a nd r esponsibilit i es shall include but not be limited to the fcllc vini a) ans~ering r ent control Froce cural questicn s and directing tenan ts toward possibl e co ur sEs of action in resolving proble:iis bl p rovicinq adv i ce on housing cede viola ti ons C) e xplaining r er.t increases dJ providing guidance on eme rgency shelter e) pc:ovidinq guidance on housing assi st a nce i: roqra11s £) providioq gui cance i n r esoluticn cf water, beat i ng, repairs and otbe r proble ms lt pr oviding a dvice oo possible action in response to all~gation s of narassment er neglect 01 laodlc rds bJ ansverinq r-relicina y questions al:cut. re:nedies through t he courts i) Froviding guidance ben tenants a rE faced vith eviction; and jJ ?Coviding gui danc e on oth~r tenant proble&amp;gt;s 77- TITLE I X ~USC£LL~ i\EOUS PE~ALTI£S SEVER ABI.LITY; SUPERSE tENCF ERVICE; EFFECTIVE OA1'1 ERn !IA'.CIOtl Sec 901. Penalties a) Any person vhc 1) de~and s er r eceives any rent tot a rental unit in excess of t~e maxi mum allo wable r a ot apfli ca cle to that r e ntal un it under tb e ~revi sions of ti tle II cf this act or 2) substantially reduces or eliJJina t es elate d services pre viou sl y provided fo r a rental uni t s ball be held l iaol e by t he Re nt Ad JJinistrator, or Cc %missi cn as applicabl e for ~reble the amo unt by which the rent exce eds the ap plica~le r ent ceiling o r for seventy-fiv e dcllars (S75 00 whichever is greater and/or fer a roll Lack of the re nt to such amo ur.t a s the Ren t Ad JJin is tratcr e r Commissicn shall deterlrine b 1) Any person who wil lfully ccllects a rent t o c~ease af te r the sa me has been ii s apFroved under this act (UD l an~ unles s such disapproval bas tee n r eversed by a coart of c ompetent joris~iction or (2) any pa rty who willfull y ir.ail~s a fa lse s t a :ement l~ any docu ment fil ed under this act; or EllroLled Orisioal 78 3) aoy person v ho villfuliy ccmmits any other act in violation of ao y pr o visicn of this act er c f any f i nal administrative order i ssu e d pursuant t c this act; or (4) any pers cn vho i.r ill fully ai ls t o do anything required under this act, s hall be fined cot mere than fi ve thousan~ dollars 5 0GO. OOJ fo r each ~iola ticn Cl Any lan dlord who has pro vided relccaticn a ssista nce under this act ma y bring a civ il actic n to I ecc ver the amount of relocation a ssistance paid tc ar. y p e rson who vas not eligib le co r eceiv e s uch assistance d) Any person v h o knowingly oc wi llfully mai:es a fals e or fraudulent a pplicatio n ceport or s tatement io orde r to obtain o r for the purfose cf obtaining any r £ntal supplemen t grant o r payme nt; or any person ce as ing to becc me eligible for such grant o r payme nt and vbo dCES net im mediate ly notify t h e Ma yor of his ineligibili ty shall be iined not oore tha n five thou sand dcllars 5 000 00J f o r each of fense S uch person found guilty of ~aking false or fraudulent ce poc ts e r stat ements or of a ili.o q t o promptly noti fy the jayor of hi s i neligibility shall r epay t o the District of Columbia any a nd all a moun ts p~id ty the Ols tc~ct o f Columbia in reliance en such false er fradulent applicatic n, ceport or s t~tement, or all a «cunts paid after eligibilit1 ceases and shall be liabl e for i n t erest on such 79- amounts at the t:ate of ona-hali of one i:e rceot l/2:l) per ;iionth Wlti l t:epaid sec. 902 evet:ab .ll,1.ty f any pre vision of this act or any sec tion senten ce clause hrasc er vcrd or t he application thereof sba.l.l ill an y cir cu i s t ances ce held invalid the vali~ity c f t he remaiuder cf the act and of the application of any such pro vision, section, sentence, c lause, pbrasa or vord sha ll not be affected. Sec. 903 uuet:sgdence. This act $hall be deeme d t o SU?ersete the gental Accomcodation s Act of 1975 C.C. Lav 1-33 effective November 1, 1975, as ame nded by t he Rental Accomm odations Act AmeodmeGts of 1976 c c. Lav 1-122, e fective April 4 1977. Sec. 904. Service a) Unless otherwise ~ro viued by the Ccmm ission regulation s a ny info r~aticn er docume nt requ ired to be served upon any person shall be served upon t ha t per son e r the =epresentati ve designated by t ha t perscn or by the l a w to recei ve se =vice of such document s whe n a party bas appeared throuqh a rep resenta ti ·1e of re cc r d ser vice sha 11 be :11ade upon tilat repr es~n tative. Ser ice upcn a person Qay ~e completed ~1 any ~I the foll owing vays 1 by handing the docu mant tc th e t erson, by ~eavinq it at such pe=son s ?lace of bcsi ness with some ao- resyon sible person i n charge or by l e a ving it at t he pe r s on 's usual pl~ce o f residence vi th a per scn o f s ui tabl e a~e an~ d iscr etion t he n present t herei r; or 2) by tel eg raa 11 he n t he ccnten t of t he lnforma t~on o r doc uQeot i s gi ven to a t eleg ra ph cc ~pan y pr ope rl y address~d a nd prepaid; oc (3) b y mail o i: depos it with the Dnited S·t ates Posi;a l s ervi c e p roperl y st a mped and addr essed or Ii) by any other me ans that i s i c c cnf o rmity vi t."1 a n or der o f the Co sm ission or the Re nt Ad mi nistra t or i n a ny proc ee di ng b) No re~t i nc reas es, whether purs ua nt t o t his act th e Rental Acco~modations Act of 1975 n. c La v 1-33 effecti ve November 1, 197S, a s amend&amp;amp;d b y t he "Ren~a l ACCOQ'110dations Ac t Alle Dd me n ts of 19 76 11 D. C. I.a v 1- 122 effective AFril q, 1977, o r an y ad~io i stra tive decisions i ssuea thereunder s hall be effec t i ve uatil the f i r s t day on vbich rent is norma.l.ly paid oc curring mer e t han tbi rty (J O) days after notice o f socb i ncr ease i s given t ~e tenant- Sec. 905. Effecti vP. Date This act sta l l t a ke effe ct as pro vi d ed for acts o f the c ouncil of the Di strict of Colu m~ia in 3eCtion 602 (c) of t he Di s tric t cf Columbia Se lf- Gove r noen t and Gover nnent al Reor;aoizaticn Act nro:1cd Original 81- Sec 90 6 amp;J ination. This ac shall t e rm inate on Se ptember 30, 1980 0o io 2 L_S_2 S ot s ea: 1'1ovember 15 1977 ,II ROLL CA~ VOT:l TIJC~R Ix I I I 1 MASON Ix i I I !I S \\J~l Ix I I I liAJO'l' I x I I r COOP 0 I x l \\-U.,SCN I y I j I SA t l I x I I I l \COOR.E ]. I x I I I l\ fl'Z I y I I I CI.A I I I X I 1 R01-AP lt; I X I I I I I I I I I VOIC VCT Sec~e ta tc h t Counci: L I ROLL CA.LL VCT::z I ltilG f ll.tCOl'J o 1 MCCa.I Jovem bar 29 1977 L I VOICE VCTE: N RC CALl- VC Z: u C I 1f I I c aw C'!lo I v c I •rC J IX I I I j MA.50 x I r I p ji IX I HA y I I i f MCCi\Z, D. I I \( I I l•VU S~:O lt; I I I 3A.'L._Y I v I I I p.cooll.Z. 1 X I I I VDl ]. l I I I l l c 1..A] I X I I I oL.Ar x I I I I I I I I I :ll:XC:-f IX I I I S CY.l 011 x I I I I I I I x-;ziWll'N J J•IC f. V i(cl{ 7&amp;lt;tdaor 1 r I I Cl&amp;lt;:cket No: 2- 152 NOV 2 2 1977 1 5 OE f!!T1 I hereby certify that Council Bill 2-152 was presented to the Mayor of t he District of Columbia o n December 1, 1977 and tha t the Mayor neither approved nor disapproved the bill within t he ten day period speci ied in Section 404(e) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governme."ltal Reorganiza::ion Act, l?ublic Law 93- 198 of December 24, 1973 SECRETARY, D. C. December lS, 1977 DATE !I MOO O. I I MOOli l. I L I R.•4o.&amp;amp;c=c F oveC I I ~ye-e's ·rc.o;c St o e~ DEC 2 7 W/7 Ho\l.se .A ce t. c $ob o ol" u.c b e -z 1</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
