<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-55">
  <num type="law">2-55</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-03-16</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-55.pdf">D.C. Law 2-55</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 5424</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-55 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-146, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 8, 1977 and November 22, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 15, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-121 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE March 23, 1978 D.C LAW 2 55 "Act to rirovide for 11-mendments to D.C. Law Nos. 1-11 0 and 1-124" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Gove rnmental Reo rgani za tion Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbi a adopted Bill No. 2-146 on first and second readings Tovember 8, 1 977, and November 22, 1977, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on December 15, 1977, this leg i slation was assigned Act No 2-121, published in the December 30, 19 77 edition of the D. C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress f or a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act. The Counci l of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, the r efore, c i tes the fol lowing legislation as D. C. Law 2- 55, e ff ective March 16, 1978 Chairman d--L TU'JER of the Council (Vol 24, D.C. Register,5424, December 30 19 77 District of Columbia Register 3 0 DEC 1'177 AN ACT ·2-121 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMDIA pECEMBER 15, l&amp;lt;fft To provide for certain amendments to D.C. Lall Nos 1-110 and 1-124, to the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, and to Title 32 of the District of Columbia Rules and Regulations. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUnBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Act to p~ovide for Amendments to D.C. Law Nos. 1-110 and 1-124 Sec 2 Section S{b) of the ttotorized Bicycle Act, effective April 7, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-11 is a~ended by striking out 12.00 and inserting in lieu thereof 21.00. tt. Sec. 3. Section 101(c) of the Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978, effective Apri~ 19, 1977 (D.C Lav 1-124 s amended by striking out "G" and inserting in lieu thereof "H Sec 4 Section 104 of the Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978, effective April 19, 1977 (D.C Law ·1-124) is amended by striking out the entire section and inserting in lieu thereof the following new section Sec. 104 The paragraphs entitled 'Class B' and 'Vehicles equipped with solid tires• in Part II of Appendix 5424 District of Columbia Register 8 0 DEC f977 I •I A to Chapter III of Title 3~ of the D.C. Rules and Regulations are hereby repealed sec. 5. Subsection (b) of section 3 of the District of I I \ Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 is amended by adding immediately after the paragraph describing "Class F" the following new paragraph: nc1ass G. For dealers• identification tags and dealers• transport identification tags, first set of tags 53, and $19 for each additional set Sec. 6. Part II of Appendix A of Chapter III of Title 32 of the District of Columbia Rules and Regu.la.tions is amended by adding immediately after the paragraph describing "Class F" the following nev paragraph Class G. Dealers• identification tags and dealeis• transport identification tags. First set of tags 53.00 Each additional set 19.00 Sec 7 This act shall take effect at the end of the period providef for Congressional ~eview of acts of the Council of the District of Columbi~ in section 602(c) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act 5425</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
