<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-73">
  <num type="law">2-73</num>
  <heading type="short">Third Amendment to the Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978 and Other Purposes</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-04-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-73.pdf">D.C. Law 2-73</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 7066</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-73, the “Third Amendment to the Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978 and Other Purposes,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-206, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, and second readings on November 22, 1977, December 6, 1977 and January 10, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 9, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-149 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF TilE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C. Law 2-73 "Third Amendment to the Revenue Act for Fiscal Year 1978 and Other Purposes 11 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Seli- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, P. L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-206, on first, amended first, and second readings November 22, 1977, December 6, 1977, and January 10, 1978, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on February 9, 1978, this legislation was assigned Act No. 2- 149, published in the February 24, 1978 edition of the D. C. Register and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review in accordance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 2-73, eifective April 18, 1978 j STERLING TUcXKER Chairman of th.k Council (Vol. 24, D. C. Register, 7066, February 24, 1978) J.C. LAW 2-73 IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTR ICT OF COLUM5I~ APRIL 18, 1979 To change the effective date for payment of real prop erty taxes of $lOQ,QOQ or more in the District of Cvlumbia; to permit sale of alcoholic ~everaijes in legitimate theaters an1 to reduce the r ate of tax on s~irits and ~lcono l, and other purposes 3E IT ENACTED 3Y THE COUNCIL OF TH~ DIS TRICT OF COLU~8IA1 T'13t tn is ~ct .11av ie cit ed as the "Thi rd A nend'Tlent t o tf"1 evenue Act for Fi sea l Yea r 1971 a nd CJther 0•1r oses Sec 2 The "R e venue &amp;lt;\ct for l=iscal Y r 1978 ffective l\pril 19, 1977 (O.c. Law 1-12 4 is amP.nded as fol lo ws a) Section 30l(a) of Title III is amended hy insert i ng ~fter "March 31 and before "Persona l taxes" thP. following Ex ce p t that the real es t ate taxes for cooper at ive hous in g =i s soc i =i t i on s w i th tax 1 i ab i 1 i t i e s of l 0 0, O O 0 or more sh a ·i l ~e payable in two installments, the first insta l lment to be oaid on or befor~ September is, and the second installment to be paid on or befor e ~arch j1. For the purposes of this section the term 'coope rative housing association eans an assoc i ation whether incorporated or unincorporated o r ganized for the purpose of o~ning and operdtin g Enrolled Original 2 r i ,j 1 t i .J l r i=&amp;gt; l l i; r e rt 'I t f: s '1 .1 r r. o l d c~ r s r r r s r: f° r t i f c t a p r op r i e t a r y l lt;:J s e c r o t e r v i r n c o f 1 r e n t S c t i .Jn l l 8 l i o F T i t l 3 X I i s J :r n ·j c o r 1 J s J r t i r c f c i i 1 r i _J r f 1 J J r r rt J l l 1 i t r 5 c r r 1 i n i n J i c rt i o n s o f s 2 c t i o ri J n l i ;i c 1 u i j t 1 r v i s i o 1 s r 1 J t i n ·J t gt; t h f 1 y "e ;1 t .J J r s ri 3 l t x s J f j l l i 1 rJ 5 n ·i f r ~a 1 s t &amp;lt;'l t e t J x s l c I r 1 t i v 1 s i r j J s s o c i i t i o 1 s s h 1 1 1 J J 1 i r s c- c t t J t .l \: s Ju1e 3 1?7 J T n 12 J i st r i c t o f c l u 11 t: i :3 \ l c in 0 l i c I n t r c l c t f 1 7 3 't J C C c.i d c&amp;gt c 2 l 1 e s &amp;gt f f c t i v J 1 u 1 r 2 4 l q 3 4 i s ,1 rr n J o i s f -i l l o s l S C t i n J J S C l J 3 i S C 1 C i .1 n s .J c t i o, 1 r r 1 J s f 1 s Enrolled Original r) t:-ie \·1 r~ s 'l c;iti a ~i t heJ t r 1 e -rn r i is s in h i c;1 t H i nci ;Jal ~u sir'!ess s 1all be 8 gt;2 r ation of live t 1tric:il, 1r r 3 tic o r 1anc J1?rfor&amp;lt;nJ'1 c 2s J r s ·JC l ct'IPr r 1 i b i t r. h t h i s c 'i a p t r r J l l I) y r 0 g u l t i o c l J s i f r l i i'.Jil ity T or d s s r i l 1 :1 o t: i n c 1 J c, t i Jr&amp;gt i c u r r I• I 2 f.Jr ·J clu'.J lt25 ;Jer Jnnu 1 c) r~e f ir s t s~ntenc~ of i1ss r in J fir s Jr:J~r 1 is f i rs t f 1 r J; r a h t h o r 1: 4 S c t i o n 2 3 a ft 1 n C J s c 5 l 2 } i s a 11 C) n d 1 t y s t r i lt; i n g 1 f i r h 9 r v r i d ~J p a r s 01 n :1 y i n s r t i n g t n 0 f i J ~J r .2 1 5 C i n 1 a c e t: h r gt;O f 1) v c r n 11 n t 3 l o r d f1 i z 3 t i on c t Docket No 2 2_0_6_ First .Rea.cling Action: November 22, 1977 LI VOICE VOT.E I T/ RO LI CA.Ll. VOTE: Secretary to the Cound.l ooca&amp;amp CM•C• I .uc I I I ii u,.cza C c• I •f'C I r I I au,.cu c c• 1 •T'C 1 I i 1 TUC~ t x I I II MASON I X I I t ll5rAtiLD!NCi I I I Ix ~y I x I I I ii MOOP.Z. D. I I x I I II WU.SON I x I I I I .OAB Y I x I I IL OO:U J. I I x I I ii WWTZ3. I x I I I c~ I I I X !I .a.oI..A..tt I I x I I ii I I I I DIXON I I I x !I S C:UZ"IC il x I I I !I I I I I \ Vr~u t O.A..z c{'.C.1 ttnc Secretary to the Counc:il Amended irst Rea.ding Ac:tion: December 6, 1977 LI VOICE VOTE: Secretary to. the Council {i R.OLI C.Al t. VOTE: Ttl'C A t ii MASON I X I I ;jS?.A.uUJI:-iC IX I I :i..uu:lY 11 M.OCS.Z, O. I I I [j71I SON I I X I .BA y II MCOP I. I I I· i! WtNT 3. I X I CL a C I ii OLA I I X I :j I DIXON 1 x r AC'i 7"!t 1 x I I I Sec:reca.ry to the Council Fma.l Reading or E:mericnc:y Action: January 10, 1978 IAJ VOICE VOTE: Secretary to the Cowic:il I I ROLL C.Al t. von I I I I I COUNCii CA I •PC I r I d e CU c C• I AP'C I T I lt u cu c I •PC I i v I 1 rnc:cs I I I MASON I I I I ~3 J r L lG I I I I HA I I I ii MOORE D. I I I I ij\V!LSON I I I I I 3A t.R'Y I I I I !j MOOR 1. I I I I :I l'!N I I I I I Cl..A {Z I I I I ii OLA I I I I ti I I I I I DIXON I I I I ii So!C N 1 I I ti I I I I I X'~aa.ic:u.n ote 3 a f r rat 7 oc I Sec:reca.ry :o le Council I I I </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
