<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-9">
  <num type="law">2-9</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-06-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-9.pdf">D.C. Law 2-9</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 1215</citation>
    </citations>
    <search-text>District of Columbia Register 12 AUG 1977 COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLW1BIA NOTICE Jun e 17, 1977 D.C LAW 2-9 "Clinical Health Services Act of 1977" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of t he District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-31 on first and second readings February 22, 1977, and March 8, 1977, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on ~arch 30, 1977, this legislation w~s assigned Act No. 2- 18, published in the April 22, 1977, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 2-9, effective June 15 1977 STERLI NG TU;~R Chai rman of the Council (Vol. 23, D.C. Register 8185 April 22 1977) 1215 District of Columbia Register 2 2 APR f!T7 AN ACT 2-18 IU THE COU!ICIL OF TiIE DIS RIC'l OF COLuilBIA March 30, 1977 To authorize the charging of fees for t c provision of clinical servicGs at i){strict of Colur ia health clinics, and £or othe:c purposes BE I'l' E~Jl~CT:t::D BY TE:i: COl.i:·ICIL OF TEE DI S EICT or COLm:DIJ I That this act r..ay be ci teJ. as t:-ie "Clini cal Eeal t'.1 Services Act of 1977 Sec. 2 i1e fourth proviso unc~er t:1e :ica&amp;lt;lin&amp;lt;J "i:eal ti1 uepartr~ent" in sectio:1 1 of t:1e Di.strict of Colur,!J ia Appropriations Act of 19·!0 approveC. July 9, 19-16 (6 0 Sta 511; D.C. Code, sec. 32-322 is amende d to re ad as follovs a) A fee based on rates to be est.:tblisi1e&amp;lt;l Jy the liayor, shall :oe charged to persons Hho arc r.o t indigent for all clinicul services provided at District of Colur.1bia health clinics, including t !1e out2atient clinic at District of Columbia General Eospi tal lo such fee shall be c:-targ~d where so specified by an ag:r-cer.:ent \·li tl1 t'.1e fe eral governncnt, or where the µrovision of u. specified clir.ical service has been deter~ine&amp;lt;l to be in the public interest pursuant to subs8ctio~1 of t his section. 1:0 per3on shall 8185 Distriot -ot Columbia Fegi ter 2 2 APR 1'117 be denied clinical services because he.is unable to pay he !Iayor shall file 1i th t:1e Council of the District of Colunfuia notice of a p~oposeu rate or a change in a ra te, at least· thirty days prior to its effective &amp;lt;late b) The following clinical health services shall be r charge, at District of ColmruJia heal th clinics, including the outpatient clinic at the District of ColuQbia General Hospita l 1) Screening Services (A) Hypertension (B) Sickle ce l l anemia (2) Screening and Treab~ent Services (A) Drug addiction (B) Lead poisoning (C) Venereal disease (D) Tuberculosis outpatient care (E orensic psychiatr y (3) In~unization Services (A) Communicable d i sease i n at.1ul ts and children (B) Rabies in anima l s c} The Hayer is hereby authori::ed to add to or delete from t!1ose services specified in su~section (b) such other 8186 District ot Columbia Register 2 2 APR '1f7 clinical heal th services he deterr.1ines to be necessary on t:1c basis of any of t he following hc&amp;lt;ilt!1 fac tors 1) threat of corumunicable diseas e o .c 2 danger to the public heal th or 3f mo.ftaii'ty rid m6rbidi ty r~iated t o specific disease d) At the beginning of each f i scal year c or.rencing wit!1 the fiscal year beginning Octobe r 1, 1977, t he Ilayor shall cause to be published in the Dis t ri c t of Col unbia aegister such addi t ions to or de l e t i ons fron t ho se s e r v ic e s specified in subse ction (b) as he ~ay p ropo s e. If no such additions o~·deletions are proposed fo r a ny g i ven fis cal year, a statement to that e f fect shall be pub li s~etl i n the District of Colunbia Reg i ster Sec. 3. To the extent t!1at the provisions of this a ct are i nconsis tent wi t h the provisions of a ny o the r ac t regulation, resolutio:i, or e ccuti vc orc~er t he provis ion s of this act shall be deemed to supe rsec: e t he provis i on s o f such other act, regulation, resolut i on, or executive o r c er. Sec. 4. This act shall be e ffective at t he end of the period provided for 9ongressiona l r e v i ew of acts of the Council of t~1e Distric t 0£ Golur.1 iia in s ec t ion 60 2 (c) of the District of Colu1:ll)ia Sel Governr.:ent a nd Gove:cu c n ta. l Reorganization Ac t. 8187</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
