<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-91">
  <num type="law">2-91</num>
  <heading type="short">Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Tax Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-07-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-91.pdf">D.C. Law 2-91</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 9765</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-91, the “Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Tax Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-101, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first, amended first, second amended first, and second readings on February 21, 1978, March 7, 1978, March 21, 1978 and April 4, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 27, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-189 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCI~ OF THE DISTR!CT OF COLvr!B!A NOTICE D. C. Law 2-91 "Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Tax Act of 1978" F1 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Gover~.mental Reorganization Act, P.L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-101 on first, aroended first, second amended first reading, and second readings February· 21, 1978, March 7, 1978, March 21, 1978 and April 4, 1978, respectively. Pollowing the signature of the Mayor on April 27, 1978, this legislation was assigned Act 2-189, published in the May 26, 1978, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses o! Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District cf Colwnbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional review period has expired a~d, therefore, cites the following legislation as D.C. Law 2-91, effective July 13, 1978 1_ STERLDl G T_U-r:KER Chairman of the Council (Vol. 24, D.C. Register, 9765, May 26, l97g) l I O.C. LAW z-q1 i'J r IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish a Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Tax. to require recordation of transfers of real property• to provide for tne licensing of t~ose who deal in residential real property• and for other purposes. SE lT ENACTED SY THE COUNCIL OF THE O!STRICT OF CCLUM8 1A. That this act may be cited as the •Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Ta~ Act of 1978 TITLE I DEFINITIONS Sec. 101. For the purposes of this act, unless otherwise indicated a The term "basis" sha'll have the same1meaning as does tnat term wnen determin i ng gain or loss under subtitle A. chapter 1, subchapter o. part II of the Internal Revenue Code (b8A Stat. 4 et seq Zb u.s.c.1 et seq.J b) The term "Charter eans title IV of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, approved Oece=ber 24t 1973 (87 Stat. 785; D~C· Code, sec. l-lZ4 CJ The term •comm ission means the Real Estate Commission of the District o.f Columtlia as established in z- section 3 of the Act of August zs. 1937 (50 Stat 788; n c Code• sec 45- 1403 d) The ter consideration means t he a~ount paid or required to be paid or the value exchanged or required to be exchanged by a tra nsferee to acquire residential real property e} The term council eans the Council of the District of Columbia established under section 401 of the Charter fl The term dealer in resident; a1 real p r operty and the term dealer mean s any per son who transfer s three (3) or more residential real p r opert1es within a period of t hirty (30) months The following transfers of residential real property (as defined by this title) shall not be considered fo r the purpose of determin i ng whetne~ the tr ansferor i s a dealer: {l) transfe rs prior to the effective date 2) transfe r s of a transferor s principal r esidence (as defined by this title 3) transfers to or t&amp;gt;y a Distr ic t of Columbia non- profit organization which is o r gan ized and operated for the purpose of constructing improving, or renovating residential real property: PROV10ED• That such organization is exe0pt from federal income t axation under section SOl(a) h::rolled Ori5 al -3- a nd is described i n section 501(c)(3) of t he Internal Revenue Code. Transfers by sucn organization mus t be a ade in furtherance of the organization s exempt purpose 4) trans f ers to or by the federa l governme nt or the government of the Di st rict of Co lumbia their agencies and instrume ntalities and t he first tr ansfer a fter the transfer by said governments: PROVIDED• That s a i d f i rst tr a nsfer afte r the transfer by said g overnmen ts i s go ve rn e d by laws and regu lations pertaining to a housing or community deve lopment prog ram administe r ed by the District or feder al government 5) transfers i n which t he t rans feree ne i ther I ve s no r is required to give any consideration in any form (inc luding t ransfe rs by gift• deeds o f correction deed s wnicn merely chang e tenancy and deed s of trust PROVIDED, Tha t the bas i s of t h e property in the ha nds o f the tran sfer e e s ha ll be the s a me a s it wa s in the hands of the tr ans f e ror b) transfers where the property being t r ansferred wa s received by t he transfer o r wi t h out givi n g or be ing r equire d to g ive a ny co ns iderat ion in any for PROVfDED Tn at the trans f eror shall pr o ve by clea r and conv incing evidence uoon all the fact s and circumsta nc es t h at t he trans f e r in wh i ch t h e transferor rece i ved the p rop er t y was .E:a:-olled Orig!nal not Made for the purpose of excluding the instant transfer from consideration in determining if the transferor is a dealer {as defined by this subsection It shall be presu~ed that the transfer in which the transferor received the property without consideration was made for the purpose of excluding the instant transfer from consideration in determining whether the transferor is a dealer. The transferor must include sufficient information on the return. filed pursuant to section 205 of title ll of this act. to rebut said presumption. The regulat ions prescribed by the ~ayor snall set forth the infor~ation which wil l be deemed sufficient to rebut said presumption 7) transfers by devise. or as a result of intestate succession 8) transfers where the property being transferred was received by the transferor by devise or as a result of intestate succession 9) transfers executed by persons in their capacity as court-appointed receivers. refer ees administrators, executors. conservators. guardians of tne estates of minors. and committees of the estates of persons judic ially determined to be mentally i ncompetent 10) the first transfer of property, the construction of which was completed after the effective date 5 as defined b y th i s t itle) regar dless of when the construction began The construction of property shall be consider ed complete at the ti ~e s uch construction is co p l eted t o the same extent required for t he issuance of a c ertifi c ate of occupancy as that term is used in s ection l O of the Act of June 20 1 9~8 (52 Stat 800; o. c. Code sec 5- 422 relating to certificates of occ upa ncy This paragraph a pplies only to newly-constructed structures and not t o r eha bi litated structur e s 11) foreclosure sales, and t he f ir s t tr ansfer tnereafter i f sa i d f i rst transfer is made by t he mor tgagee who i nstitute d the fo r eclosure proceedings and pu r chased t he p r operty at the foreclosure sale or obtained t itle directly fr om t ne defaul t ing party without a foreclosure s ale ROVI OEO Th at sa id mortgagee i s licensed i n the Distr i c t of Columbia as a bank or other financi al institution 12) deeds of rel eas e o f property where :he property wa s s ecurity for a debt or o ther obli gation; and 1 3) t r ansfers by a tr a nsfer o r whose hold i ng period a s def i ned by this title) for the property being tra nsferred was l onger t han t hir ty-si x (36) months 9) The t e r m dee d r ecor dation tax means t~e t ax posed by section 303 of the Act of Ma r ch z, 1962 as amended (7b St 3 t 12; o. c. Code s ec 45-723 6 h) The term •cefic iency• shall have the same meaning given to that term by section 4 of title I of the Act of July 16. 1947 {&amp;amp;1 Stat. 332; o.c. Code. sec 47-155lc(q} i) The term •effective date• means the date on wh ich this act takes effect according to the provisions of section 602(c)(l) of the Charter j) The term •equitable title• means a right in a party to have the legal title to a residential real property (or real property, solely for purposes of title III of this act) transferred to such party. The term snail also include any right to receive equitable title by means of an option to purcnase or otherwise k) The term "gain" means the excess of the consideration received by a transferor over the transferor's basis for the property (as defined by this title) transferred 1) The term •fair market value" means the price at wnicn a willing seller and a willing buyer will trade or the price which would in all probability have been arrived at between a willing seller and a willing buyer m) The term "holding period" shall nave the same meaning as does that term for purposes of section 1223 of the Internal Revenue Code 7 n) The term •Internal Revenue Code eans the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (68 Stat 4 et seq 26 u s c 1 et seq and any amendments thereto oJ The term legal holiday eans any Di st r ict of Columbia public holiday i ncluding Saturday and Sunday as des ignated by t he Act of August 30 1964 as amended (78 Stat. 671; D. c Code sec 28-2701 p) The term •1 egal title• means complete and perfect title to residential real pr operty (or real property so l ely for purposes of t i tle I!I of this act) i n the party t.o whor.i such title belongs so far as reg ards the aoparent ri ght of ownership anj possession of the residential real property (or real property solely for purposes of title III of this act) but which car ries no beneficial interest in the property another person being equitably entitled thereto IQ) The term major app l i ances sha 11 inc I ude the followi ng appliances if a transferor transfer• such appliances wne n transfering residential real prop~rty: refric;erator cooking range, oven. dishwasher garoage disposal trash compactor, and washer and dryer r) The term ayor neans the ~ayor of the Dist ric t of Columbia establishe d under section 421 of the Charter SI The term person means any i ndiv i dua l, firm partnersh i p, copartnersni joint venture associat ion ollac Origi ne a- corporat ion (domestic or f o reign trust trustee of any estate or court appointed receive r t) The term principal res idence• shall have t h e same 111eaning as does that term for purposes of section 1034 of the Internal Revenue Code: EXCEPT That in determining whet her a residen tial real property is the principal residence of a transferor in addition to consideration of all t he f a cts a nd c i rcumstances as p rovi ded by section 1034 of the Internal Revenue Code. the property must h a ve been the principal residence of t h e tran sferor f o r the one hundred and eigh ty (180) day period immed iately precedin g the trans fer u) The term rea l covenant• me ans an a g reement bet een two {ZI o r more persons relating to a prope rty• the ter ms of wnich shall ~e binding on any heir or a~sign of t he promisor under the agreement and wh ich shall be enforceabl e by t he pe rson holding l egal title to sa id property v Th e term rea l proper ty mean s improved as wel l as unimproved land in the Distri ct of Columb i a w) The term •residential real property or property means improved real pr operty In the Ois~rict of Columbia whi c h at any time during tne twe lve (lZ) months immed iately ?receding its tr ans fer contained not more than four (4 d wel ling units The ter dwelli ng unit snal1 ~ave the olled Origi~al -9- same aeaning as gi ven to that ter~ in the Zoning Regulations of the District of Columbia (Chapter I article lz, section 1202• p age 5, as a mended through May 11 1977 x) The term solicitation" mean s any act which would cause a person to c o• e within the definition of solicitor of resi~ential rea l p r operty y) The term solicitor of resi dential r e al property means a person who, without prior invitation from the hol der of legal t itl e to a residential r eal p roperty offers to purchase or expresses a des i re t o purchase sucn property or in any other way attempts t o persuade or induce such holder to sell or otherwise transfer su ch title Z) The term t a x excise" or excise tax" means t he tax im~osed by this act aa) The term "third party eans all persons who are not parties to a contract. agreement or instrument of wr itir1g by wnlcn tne 1r Interest in t ne t hing conveyed is sought to be effected bbl The term transfer• means a transaction by wh i ch re sidential real p r operty (or real property• so l ely for purposes of title III of this act or any title or right to rec eive any title thereto• or any portion thereof, or any inte rest therein (excegt a proprietary lease and a r en tal l ease. unles s such rental lease inc ludes an option or right -10 °rolled Orl e a.L to buy) is e i t her direct l y or indirectly conveyed vested g ranted devised, bargained, sold exchanged or assigned by any docu•ent, instru11ent. writing agreement, or by any means whatsoever cc) The term •transferee" means the person (or persons) to whom a transfer of resi dential real property (or real property, solely for purposes of titl e III of this act) is made dd) The t erm transferor mea ns the person (o r per sons who mak es a transfer of residential re al prop er ty (or real p roperty, solely for purposes of titl e I ll of th is act ee) The term •vacant• means no t occupied by t h e person having legal ti tle or othe r titl e to the property and without other lawful occupants TITLE I I RESIDENTI AL REAL PROPER TY TR A~SFER EXCISE TAX Sec. 201 Imposjti on of Exci s e Tax (a) Except as provided under subsect ions (b) and (dJ of th i s s ection and section 202 of th is title there is her eby imposed, in addit ion to a ll other taxes. an exc ise tax on t he transfer of resident i al rea l p r operty The tr ansferor shall be liabl e for payment of the excise Enrolled Original -11 bl If a transferor transfers both e q uitab le t itle and legal t itle to a r esidential real property t hen the t ax imposed in subsec tion a of this section shall apply only to the transfer of t he legal ti tl e to the property c} Where t wo (2) or ~ore transferors jointly t ransfer prope rty each t ransferor shall be jointly and severally l iab le f o r the excise tax i mposed in s ubse ction (a {d) The tax imposed by subsection a) of this sect i on sha ll be appl i e d only during t he three (3) year period a f ter the e ffective d a te Se&amp;lt 2 0 2 Exempt Tr ans f ers The followin g transfers of property are exempt from the excise t a x impos~d by t hi s t i tle: {a}(l tr ansfer s of prope rty which t he tr an sferor warrants in wr i t ing t ha t t he property is fit for occupancy and use and agains t defect ive structure. materials and workmanship for a per iod of two {2) years from tne d a te o f the transfe r Sai d t wo (2} ye ar warranty shal l apply to t he cost of l abo r materials and any related cost s for at l eas t the follo wing: roof; gu ttering and downspout; heating system (including fur nace electr ical sys tem; plu~bing syst em; hot wat e r heater and tank d ry b asement a nd air- conditioning system J 12 2) transfers of property which the transferor warrants in writing that the Major appliances, as defined in title l of this act, transferred with the property are fit for the purpose for which they were ~ade and against defective ~aterials and workmanship, for a period of one (1) year from the date of the transfer, not to exceed the period of coverage of any manufacturer•s warranty on any ~ajor appliance. Said one (1) year warranty shall apply to the cost of labor. materials and any related costs for such appliances. The warranties set forth in paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection Shall be real covenants during th~ period of their duration and shall not include the cost of labor, materials, and any related costs for damage intentionally or negligently caused by the transferee nor shall they include maintenance work resulting from normal wear and tear; and (3) transfers of property wh ich are certified by a District of Columbia agency designated by the ~ayor that the property meets the standards required by the applicable articles of chapters l and 2 of the Housing Regulations of the Oistrict of Columbia as of the date of the transfer. A transferor claiming an exemption under this subsection shall submit a wr itten request to the agency designated oy the Mayor requesting an inspection of the property. Such agency E::irolled O~igi~a 13- sha ll w ithin t wenty (20) c alendar days a fter rece ipt of such request issue in writing a state ment setting forth the street a ddress and the lot and squar e numoer of t he property inspected t he date o f ins pection the name of t he inspector and whethe r the property ~ee ts the st a ndards r equired by t he applicab le articles of chapters land 2 of the Housi ng Regulations of t he Distr ict of Columb ia. lf such agency after i nspection deter~ines t hat t he p r operty does not meet the standa rds required by t he app lic ab le ar ticl es of ch3pter s land 2 of the Hous i ng Regul a tions of the Dist r ict of Columb i a the stat ement issued by t he agency s hall s et fo r th the reasons for such determination 4 If s uch agency falls wi thin said t wenty 20) calendar day pe riod to complete the inspect ion and issue a ritten sta tement, as se t f orth in par agraph (3 indicating whe ther t he property meets the standards required Oy the applicable articles of chapters land Z of the Hous ing Regulations of tne Dis trict of Columbo a t then in 1 ieu ther eof the tr ans fe ror may under t he fo llowing p r econditions cert i fy that the property meets sa i d articles of t ne Housing Re gulations of the District of Col umb ia: {A) a person selected by or appro~ed in wri ting b y t he tr ansferee inspects t he propert y 14 8) that the person selected is a professional engineer (i e e1ectrica1 structural mechanical or civil) or a contractor 1 icensed by t he District of Colufllbia government CJ the person inspecting t h e property states in writ ing item by item. whether the property meets the standards required by the apolicable arti c les of chapters l and 2 o f t h e Housing Regulati ons of t h e District of Columbi a 0) such i nspecto r s wr i tten itemized s tatement is provided to the trans feror and a copy provided to the transferee and (El a ny c o sts incurred f or t h e i nspection a re borne by the trans feror only Within th i rty (30) days from t he effect i ve dat e the Kay~r shall develop s uch forms and procedures as are necessary to ca rry out the pro visions of th is su bsect ion The Narranti es set f orth in paragr a phs (l) a nd (2 of t his s ubsect i on and tne certificat ion set fo r th in paragraph 3 and (4) of this suosection whiche ve r is applicable shall be executed onl y on t h e forms deve lope d by th ayor. a nd shal l be executed under oath and fully ac~nowledged. The transferor g iving the warr anties set f o rth in t his s ubsect ion s hall prov ide a copy to the transferee and f i l e a copy with the Ma yor in a -15- Manner presc ribed by the Mayo r A copy of the ce rtifi cation as provided by paragraph (3) and of t hi s subsection whichever is applicable, shall be provided to the tran sferor and the transferee a nd a c opy s ha11 be filed with the Ma yor in a ~anner prescribed by the "ayor The warranti es and certification filed with the "ayor shall be l ist ed on a public record determined by the Mayo r b) transfers of a tran s feror s princ ipal residence c) transfers by an employee of the Uni ted State s gover nment whose p rincipal residence is outside of the Washington o. c. Standard Metropolitan S t atistical Area: PROVlOEO That the tr ans feror resided in tne property for the six (6 onth per iod immedi ately preceding t he t ransfer d} the first tran s fer during the first s ix (6) montn s after t he e ffective dat e• of r e si dential rea l property hich was vacan t on or befor e July 1, 1977 and which has been vacant s ince t hat date e) transfe rs to or by the fede ral gover nment or the government of t he District o f Columbia tneir agencies and instrumenta liti e s. and the first transfer after ~he transf er by said governments= PROVIDED. Tha t sa id f i rst transfer after the transfe r by said go vernments i s go verned by la~s a nd regulations pe rtaining to a nousing o r c~mmuni~y -16- development prog ram adfti nistered by t h e Distr ict or federal govern11ent; {f) transfers to or by a District of Columbia non- profit organization which is organized and operated for the purpose of constr1.1Ctin9. improving, or renovating residential real property: PROVlOED. That such organization is exempt from federal income taxation under section SOl(aJ and is described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code Transf e rs by such organization mu st be ~ade in furtherance of the organ ization 's exempt purpose 9) transfers i n wh rch the transferee neither gives nor is requi red to give any consideration, in any form includ_ing transfers by gift deeds of correction deeds wh ich merely change tenancy, and deeos of trust PROVIuED That the basis of the property in the hands of the transfer ee shall be t he same as it was in t he hands of the transferor; {h) the first transfer of property the construction of which ~as completed a fter the effecti v e date regardless of when construction began The constructi on of proper~y s hall be consi dered compl ete at the time such construction is completed to the same extent requir ed for the issuance of a certifi cate of occupancy, as t hat term is useo in section 10 of the Act of June 20 1938 (52 Stat 800; o.c. coae sec 17- 5 t22 relat ing t o certif ica t e s of occ upancy Th i s suosection sha ll apply only t o newly-cons tructed structures and not to r enaoil itated structures i foreclos ure s ales a nd t he f i rst transfer t her eafter if said first transfer is made by the mor tgagee who instituted t ne f o r eclosure proceedings and pu rchased the property at the foreclosure s a le or obtained title directly from t he defaul ting party wi t hout a foreclosur e sal e: PRO VI DED That sa id mortgage e is 1 icen s ed in t he Dis t rict of Colu moia as a oanl&amp;lt or other financi a l inst itut ion j) d e eds of release of property where t he property was secu rity for a debt or other ob ligat ion k) transfe rs by devise o r a s a resul t of inte state succession 1) tran s fers wher e the property being tra nsferred was recei ved b y devise o r as a res u lt of intestate succession m) transfers e xecuted by perso ns i n t~ei r capaci ty as court-appoint ed receivers r e f eree s adminis tr ato rs execu t o rs c ons e rvato r s. guardians o f the est a tes of minors, and c ommittees o f the estates of persons judicially determ ine d t o b e mentall y incompe tent n) tr ansfer s pu rs ua nt to a va l i d and binding separ ation a g reement. and b y court o r der pursuant t o a sepa r ation or di vorc e decr e olled O~iginaJ 18 o) transfers by involuntary conversion as defined in section 1033 of the Internal Revenue Code; and (p){l) transfers of residential real property in exchange solely for residential real property of a like kind (as defined in section 1031 of the Internal Revenue Code PROVIDED. That each party to such exchange shall keep the same basis in the property received as that party had in the property transferred 2) If an exchange would be exempt under paragraph (1) of this subsection if it were not for the fact that the exchange consisted not only of property of a l ike kind but also of money or other consideration. then the exchange shall be taxable under section 201 of this title. E.ach party to the exchange shall be treated as a transferor of the property exchanged by that party The consideration received by each transferor shall be t ne fair market value of the property received plus the amount of any money or other consideration received. Each transferor shall have a basis in the ~roperty received equal to the fair market value of the property exchanged by that transferor plus any money or other consideration given by that transferor and minus any money or other consideration received by that transferor 1 9- Sec 203. Oeter~ination of Excise Tax The exci se imposed by th is t itle is d etermined as fo l lows a) compute t he transferor s ga in as def ined in s ection 101 of t h is act b) compute the per centage of ga in by expressing ga in as a pe r centage of bas is CJ determi ne the a ppl icab l e tax rate by matching the per cent age of ga in wi th t he approp riate ho lding period in the tab le in section 20~ of t his t i t le d) det e r mine t he t a x liab il i ty by mu lti pl yi n g t he applicable tax r ate by t he t ransfero r s gain Zzlrolled Origi~a 20- Sec 204. Excise Tax Table TAX SCHEOULE Holding Period (in months or fractions thereof} Remainder a s percent: age of prior consi~tion 0-6 7-12 13-18 19-24 25-30 ~2 11 10 O:t O:t Ol; O:t o~ 12 17 0 o 0 o 0 13 24 0 0 0 0 0 14 29 0 0 0 0 0 15 34 0 0 0 0 0 16 38 5 0 0 0 0 17 42 18 0 0 0 0 18 &amp;lt;t5 22 0 0 o o 19 48 26 o 0 0 0 20 50 30 o 0 0 o 21-2 2 55 33 10 0 o 0 23- 2 4 59 39 17 o o 0 25-26 62 48 Z&amp;lt;t 0 0 0 27-28 65 5 2 30 0 0 0 29-30 67 55 34 7 0 o 31-32 69 58 39 16 0 0 33-3't 71 61 'tZ 21 0 0 35-36 73 63 't6 26 3 o 37-38 74 6 5 49 30 a 0 ~ol!ed or:gi=al -21- Rema;nder as percentage of prior consideration 0- 6 7-12 13-18 19-24 25-30 31~ 39~0 75 67 51 33 15 0 41 3 77 68 5 37 20 0 't't 6 79 70 57 4 1 2 5 0 47-49 80 72 60 4 5 34 6 50-55 82 76 64 5 0 38 14 51&amp;gt;-59 84 79 6 8 5 5 45 27 60-65 85 80 70 56 48 32 66-70 86 82 71 62 53 38 71-75 87 83 73 65 56 42 76-80 BB 84 75 67 59 'r6 81-90 89 85 77 69 62 49 91-99 90 87 79 7 3 66 55 1 00-109 91 89 82 7 6 70 61 ll0-119 92 90 81t 78 7 3 65 120-134 93 91 85 80 75 08 135-149 94 92 87 82 78 71 150-174 95 93 88 84 80 74 175-199 95 94 90 86 83 78 200-249 96 95 92 89 85 82 250-299 97 96 93 91 68 85 300• 97 97 95 93 90 SB arolled Origi~ai 22- Sec. 205 ayor Authorized to Develop Tax Return Form The Mayor shall devel op no later t han t hirty (30) d ays after the ef fective date the follo wing a) a residential real property tr ansfer tax return form or form s a nd (bl regulations and procedures governi ng the fi ling of returns on a quarterly basi s for transfe rors cla;mi ng any exemption under section 202 of this titl e whose vol ume of exemp t transfe r s is suc h t ha t it woul d be unduly burdensome t o requi re t he filing of a separate return f or each such tr ansfer All r e turns r equired under thi s title sha ll be filed on the forms and in the manner presc ribed by the 11ayor Sec 206 Payment of Tax (a) Except as provided In section 20 l(bl and section 205(0) of this t itle. wi thin thirty (30) days after tne e xecution of a deed or other document by whi c h l e5al t i t le to a property is transferr ed (unless t he thirtieth (30th) day is a legal holiday. in which case the first day t her eafter which is not a leg al nol iday all transf e rors of legal title a nd all transferors of e qui table tit l e t o such p r operty. including all tr a nsferors claim i ng any exemption under section 202 of thi s t i tle shall iilrolled Crig! nel -23 l) file ith the Mayor a co~pleted resi den tial real property transfer tax return and any other i nfor~ation the ~ayor r equires; and (2) pay into a depository designa ted by the Mayor the full amount of the tax due under t hi s title if any bl Where a transfer qua l ifi es under section 453 of t he Internal Re ven ue Code (relating to the installment method and where the t ax imposed under this title is five hundred dolla r s (S5 00 o r greater the Mayo r shall prescribe p rocedures and regu l ations providing fo r the payment of the tax i n installments: EXCEPT That the tax must be paid in f u l l withi n three (3) year s fr o m t he date o f the transfer. Sec 207 Tax Return (a) In the case of a transfer descr ibed in s ubse ct i on (p)(2) of section 202 o f this ti t l e e ach trans fer o r shalt i nc lude in the return required by section 205 of this tit1e the current one hundred (100 per cent assessed market val u e as of the da t e of the liKe kind exchange Wheneve r a return conta i ns insu ff i ci ent i n f orma tion as to the one hundred (1 00) perc en t assessed market va lue the Mayor is a uthor ized t o make a reas onable determination the reof from t he best informat ion av ai l abl e {bl Whe re the property bei ng transfer red wa s recei v ed by t he transferor ~y gift th~ transfe ror s r e turn mu s t -z include t he amount and k ind of cons ideration gi ven b y t he transferor s donor in acquirin g such property and said donor• s bas is for such p r operty as of the date of the gift If sucn information i s not a vailabl e the Mayor shall ~ake a dete r mination t hereof fro~ the best inf o r mation av a ilable c) Where a transfer is exempt fr o m the tax the tran sfe ror s return sha ll only need t o include sufficient infor mat ion to establ ish the e xemption clai med The Mayor b y regulati o n shall set forth what information i s to be deeme d s ufficient to establish the exemp t i on cl a imed d) A transferor shall ma intain documentation t o sup port the informat ion i n the return f or three 3) years after the date of t he transfer Sec 208 Return Asses sme nt and Collection; Time of P a yment; Penalties and Interes t1 Appeal To the e xtent applicable to t he provisi ons a n d purposes of th is t i tle t he f ol lowing sections and ti tl es of article l of the District of Columbia lncome and Franchise Tax Act of 19"7 approved J uly 16• 1947 (61 Stat 3 31 o. c. Code sec 47- 155 1 et seq snall apply for purposes of adm i nistra tion of this ti t le: section 3 of t i tl e V (ol S tat. 342; o. c. Code sec 47-1564b(b title XIl (61 Stat 352 o. c. Code sec 7-158 6 and titl e XIII (61 Stat 356 Enrolled O~iginal 25- o. c. Code. sec. 47-1 589 and section l of title XV (61 Stat. 3 59 o. c. Code sec. 47-l593 Sec zoq Willful Breach of Warrant y (a) If the Mayor or a c ourt of c ompet en t juri s dicti on in the District of Columbia de termines that any warr anty pr ovided under s ection 202(aJ o f this title has been willfully breached o r i n t enti o nally dishonored and but for s uch wa rran ty the tr a nsfe r wou ld h a ve been sub ject t o t he tax t h en the t ax a nd any add i tions t hereto that would h a ve been due fr om t he tr ansf e ror sha ll become due and pa yable in t he s a~e manner as i f such war ran t y never existed The Mayor b y regulation s hall set forth the standards and ad~inis trat i ve p roce s s t o De foll o wed for the de termi ndt ion by t he Mayor t hat a warranty has been willfully b re ached o r ir1tention ally dishonored b If the ~ayor determines that a warranty has been wi ll fully breached or intentionally disho nored in addi tion to a ny other penal t ies the ~ayor shall order t he warrantor to do either o f the foll o wi ng• at the op t ion o f the wa rrantee: {l) make the repa irs whi c h for~ t he basis of t h e b reac h. to the sa t isfaction of t he warrantee or 2 pa y to the warrantee 1 after the recei p t of two (2) esti~ates in writing from t he warr ant ee 1 t ne full amount llrolled Original -Zb- necessary to hav e t he repairs a ade by s ome person other t han the warr antor. Wl'lere the transferor certified that the p roperty ~eets the stand.;irds set fort h in the applicab le articles of chapters 1 and Z of the Hous ing ~egulat ions of the Distric t of Columbia as set f o rth in section Z02(a)(4) of this title and where such cert if i cati on was fals e o r bas e d on fa lse information and the tr ansferor knew or Should have k no wn of such f al sifi cat i on or f alse information then the ~ayor shall determine t hat t he warranty. as provided Dy s ection 202( a l) t has been willfu ll y breac hed and the pr o v isi ons of this subsect i on shall apply. Sec 210. Report by Mayo r The Ma yor s hall report t o the Council by Februa ry 1st of each year f or the preceding fi scal year the fo llowing i nformation for the Distri ct of Columbia aJ the number of transaction s falling within each exemption provided b y sectio~ 202 o f this title bl the sales pri ces for t ransact ions falli ng within each exemption under section 202 of t his title cl the holding periods f o r all tr a nsaction s subj ect t o the tax imposed by this t itle d) the sales prices f or transact ions sub ject t o t he tax imposed by this title I l J.rolled o~:gina 27 e) the average holding period for transact ions subject to the tax imposed by this title f) the average gain for transact ion s subject to the tax imposed by t his title g) the number of evict ions caused by eac h t ransaction if any; and (hl the Mayor shall require that the De partment of Finance and Revenue provide for this report the foll o wing l) the number of unincorporated business tax r e turns filed by dealers in residential real p r operty and the states in which the returns wer e f i l ed including the District of Columbia Z) the average number of transfers per return and the t otal fr om each jurisdiction and (3) the total amoun t of unincorporate d business taxes paid by those engaged in the buying and se lli ng of residential r eal pr~perty and the averag e per retur n Sec 211. Autho r izati on to Promul gate Regulati ons The Mayor shall promulgate regulations to carry out the provislons of thi s titl e 28- TITLE III COMPULSORY RECOROATID~ OF TRANSFERS OF REAL PROPERTY ANO AMENOME~TS TO THE DEED RECOROATION TAX Sec. 301. Comp&amp;lt;Jlsory Recordation l lrolle~ Orig!~e a) Within thirty (30) days after the execut i on of a deed or other document by which lega l title t o a real property is transferred. all transferees of said legal title shall record a fully acknowledged copy of said deed or other document including the lot and square number of the real property trans ferred. with the Recorder of Oeeds of t he District of Columb ia If the thirtieth (30th) da y is a lega l holiday t he time f o r record i ng shall be e~tended to include the first day after the thirtieth (30th) day which i s not a legal holiday b) Whenever any portion of an instrument. wh ich conveys or provides for the conveyance of eqJitabl e title to a real property is transfe rred by or on behalf of a party to sucn instrument to a third party. tnen the party so trans ferrin g Shall re~ord. at t he same time as provided by subsection (a) of this section a fully acknowl edged copy of said instrument including the lot and square number of t ne real property transferred, with the Recorder of Deeds of the Distr ict of Columbia and t he third party shall record at Ei:rollec Crig l the same time as provided by subsection (a) of thi5 sect ion with the Recorder of Oeeds of the District o f Coluabia a f ully acknowledged instrument• includin9 the lot and square number of the property transferred evidencing the transfer to himself (or herself or itself as the case may be All subsequent transfers of equitable title made prior to the tr ansfer of le9al title Shall be recorded by each subsequent transferee thereto. in the same manner and at the s a me t ime as provided in s ubsection (a) of th i s sec t ion Sec. 302. Presumptions and Burden of Proof For t he purpose of proper administration of thi s title and t o prevent evasion of the recor dation requirements. the Mayor shall ~resume that all transfers as described in section 301 of t his title ar e required to be recor ded The bur den shall be upon the person requi red to record to prove that a deed or a ny other document is exempt from the reco r dation requirement Sec 303 Penalties for Failure to Record (a) Where a dealer fails to record as required by section 301 of tnis title. and such failure i s due to negligence t h ere shal l be imposed on said dealer a penalty of twenty-five dollars (S25 00) for each ~onth o r po rtion thereof that such failure continues, not to exceed t wo hundred fif t y dollars (S250 00 30 bJ Any dealer who with the intent to evade the tax icposed in title II of this act• knowingly fails to record, as required by section 301 or who knowingly nakes a false or •isleading statement in connection with such recordation, shallt in addition to other penalties provided by law, be guilty of a n isdemeanor and shall be fined not more than five thousand dollars (SS.000) or imprisoned for not nore than one (l) year. or both, together with costs of prosecution. All prosecutions under this section shall be brought in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia on information by the Corporation Counsel in the name of the Oistrict of Columbia. The word •dealer in addition to the meaning assigned to that term in title I of this act, shall, for purposes of this subsection, include an officer or an employee of a corporation. or a member or an employee of a partnership, who i.s under a duty to perfor~ the aci in respect to wh ich the violation occurs c) Where a person other than a dealer fails to record, as required by section 301 of this title, there shall be imposed on such person a penalty in the amount of ten I dollars {Sl0.00} for each month or portion thereof that such failure continues, not to exceed fifty dollars SS0.00 Whenever it is shown by such person that failure to record was due to r2asonabl e cause and was not due to knowing Enrolled Oris~~el -31- o•ission o r neglect the Mayor Na y wai v e part of or all of the penalty fee p rovi ded by this subsection. In ever y cas e of •part ial or total waiver t he reason f or t he wai ver shall be stated c lear ly on a public reco rd det ermi ned by the Mayor d) Any person other than a dealer, who with the intent to evade the t a x imposed in title II of this act knowingly fail s to r ecor d as requi r ed by section 301, or who knowingly makes a false or misl e ading statement i n connection wi t h such recorda tion shall in addition to ot~er pena l ties p r o vi ded by law, be gu ilty of a mi sdemeanor and s hall be fined not more than f i v e thousa nd dollars S5 t 000) o r imprisoned fo r not more than one l) year, or both t o gether with cost of prosecution eJ The penalty fee s p r ovided under this section shall be collected at t he s ame t ime and in t he same ma nner and as a part of the deed reco rdat lon t ax I f the t ransaction i s exempt f rom t he deed recordation t a x. the n the Mayor shal l collect the fees in a manner p rescribe d by the ~ayor f) If t he Mayor determines that a pe rson has failed t o record or has failed to pay a ny f ee as requi r ed by this act the procedures se t f orth in t i t le Ill s e cti on 308 o f the Act of ~arch 2 1962 (76 Sta t 13; o.c Code, sec 45-728 32- {relating to deficiencies in tax-notice of deter~ination­ protests-hearings-time for payment) shall apply. Sec. 304. Certain Amendments to the Deed Recordation Tax (a) Section 303(b) of title III of the Act of March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 12; o.c. Code, sec. 45-723(b is amended as follows: {l) the words "and" through •require" in subsection fb) are hereby deleted 2) insert after the word •payable the words •whether the property to which the deed or document refers is a residential real property as def [ned in section lOl of the Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Tax Act of 1978. and such other information as the Mayor may require so as to provide an accurate and complete public record of each transfer of residential real property and (b) Section 305 of title III of the Act of March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 12; o.c. Cadet sec. 45-725) is amended by inserting after the words "upon which a tax is imposed and before the words "is authorized to examine the words "or for the purposes of as.certaining "hether a deed or other document was required to be recorded pursuant to section 301 of the Residential Real Property Transfer Excise Tax Act of 1978 l!:nrolled or:g:~a 33- TITLE IV LICENSING OF DEALERS IN RESIDENTIAL REAL ?RO?ERTY Sec 401 Def i nitions For the purposes of this title a) The term real est ate bro ker or broker shall hav e t he same meaning as given t he term real estate broker in section 2 of the Act of August zs. 1937 (50 Stat 787; o.c. Code sec 45-1402 DJ The t er m real esta te salesman or salesman• shal l have the same me aning as given the term real estate salesman• in section 2 of the Act o f August 25 1937 (50 Stat 787; o. c. Code. sec 45-1402 c) The t e rm firm unless other wise indi cated mean s a par tners~ip copartnershi p associ ati on corporati o n (forei gn or domestic) or unincor~orated busi ness Sec 402 Requir ement of License Gn a nd aft er one hundred ei ght y 180) days from t h e effective date. it shal l be unlawful In the Distric t of Colu~bia for a d ealer to t ransfer res iden tial real property other than property which is a deale r's principal resi denc e without a license issued b y the Commission A dealer 's license s hall be obtai ned by a person prior t o a tr ans fer wnicti would cause t he transfe ror to be deemed a deal e r Z:irolled o:is i ial 34- When a person requi re d by this title to be licensed as a dealer fails to acquire a license but de~onstrat es tot l'layor· t hat. such fa i 1 ure was due to r easonab 1 e cause and was no t due to knowing omission or neglect. the Mayor ~ay wai ve part or all of any penalty imposed for failure t o acqui re a license: PROYIOEO. That lack of knowledge as to any p r ovision of this act s hall not constitute r easonable cause. Sec. 403 Appl ication for License (a) A license to act as a d ealer under t he provisions of this t itl e shall not be issued to any p erson who has not a ppli ed for t he license required by this title or hose l icense to act as a deal er was revoked in the District of Columbia during the twelve (12) month period immed iately preceding the date of t he appl icati on for sa jd license bl Except as prov ided i n subsection (e) of tni s section the application of e v e rf firm for a license to be d dealer sh&amp;lt;1l l state 1) t he addres s or addresses of t he p r incipal p l ace or places of business for which the license is desired Zl a complete l i st of al l former a ddresses wh ere the applicant was engaged in any real estate business for a conti nuous period of at least th i rty (30) days J!:l::rolle~ Orig!nal -35 3) the name and residence a ddres s of each emp loyee. l!e&amp;lt;nb er off icer or associate who partic i pates a s a deal er in t he a pplicant's business of d ea ling in residential J real property 41 In the case of a corporation t he applicat ion shall also state the nane and address of each offic e r, director and r egistered agent. ln t h e case o f a fi rm o t her than a corporation the applicati on sha ll also state the name a nd address of each partner assoc i ate, member or employee who i s author ized t o accept lega l notice on behalf of t h e orga n i zat ion; and (5) the address, inc lud i ng l ot and square number of each property located in the District of Columbia. wh ich was transferr ed i n whol e or i n part by o r on behalf of the a ppl icant du r ing the t wenty-four 24) month period immediate ly preceding the date of t h e appli ca tion {c) Exce pt as provided in subsection (e of thi s s ection t he appli c ation of each individual associated with a firm f o r a license to be a deal er shall sta t e l) the f u ll name and residence address of the appl leant 2J t he full name and business address of t he firm wi th whi c h such applicant i s associ ated the l ength of t ime :Eiirolled Original -36- such applicant has been so associated. and in what capacity and (3) the period of time. if any. during which said applicant was or has been engaged as a real estate broker, salesman• or dealer, together with a complete list of all former addresses where the applicant was so engaged for a period of thirty (30) days or ~ore preceding the date of application d) Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section• the application of each individual, not affiliated with a firm or other entity, for a license to be a dealer shall state the same information as required in subsection (Cl paragraphs {l) and {2) of this section e) Whenever any applicant for al icense to be a dealer is licensed as a real e·state broker or real estate salesman in the Oistrict of Columbia, such applicant shall not be required to repeat on the application for a dealer's license any information that the applicant has provided on an application for a broker's or salesman's license which is currently on file with the Commission. Sec. 404. Issuance and Display of License (a) The Com"li ss ion shal 1 issue a non-transferable 1 icense to each dealer qualifying for such under the ~revisions of this title. A dealer's license snail be in ~roUeo O igin11l 37- such for m and size as prescri bed by the Coemission. Every li cense shall show the n ame and address of the dealer t o who• lt is issued. and if a pplicable the full name and addr es s of the fircri w ith which said dea·ler is associated Each 1 icense shall have inprinted thereon the seal of the ColM&amp;gt;ission. and such other matter as shall be prescribed by the Commissi on All de aler s shall display their licenses consp icuously in their place s of business bl No licens e shall be issued by the Commissi on to a firm unless ever y e mployee member or officer who par~icipates in such firm as a deale r is licensed as requi r ed by this title. Sec 405. License Expiration Fees a nd Renewals (a) Every license to be a dealer s hall expir e on the anniversary date of its issuance b) The fee for the initial dealers 1 icense s hall be one hundred dol la rs (S lOO c) The annual fee for an y renewal of a license shal l be one hundred dol lars SlOO) in the case of a deal e r who transfe rs twen ty (20J or ~ore residential real properties during the ~welve (12 onths immediate ly preceding the written request for such renewal; seventy- five dollars (S 75 i n t he case of a deal er who t ransfers at l east ten (10) but no more than nineteen (19) such properties ouring said tn~ollec Crigioal -38- period; fifty dollars 50) in the case of a dealer who traosfers at least five (SJ but not more than nine (9) such properties during said period; and twenty-five dollars (S25) in the case of a dealer who transfers four (4) or fewer such properties during said period: PROVIDED, That whenever a person licensed in the District of Columbia as a real estate broker or real estate salesman applies for an initial license to be a dealer or requests renewal thereof, the amount of the fee paid for the broker's or salesman s license shall be applied toward satisfaction of the fee for a dealer•s license. In determining the number of transfers by a dealer during the twelve (12) months immediately preceding the transfer all transfers made by the dealer (except the transfer of the dealer's principal residence) shall be considered, including transfers made by the dealer prior to being deemed as a dealer d) Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c) of this section. no fee shall be charged for any initial license or renewal thereof issued to any firm where all of the employees members or officers who actively participate in the firm's business of dealing in residential real property have been issued a dealer s license e) On written request of the applicant upon receipt of the annual fee and in the absence of any reason Enrolled Or~giLel -39- war ranting refusal the Com~is sion shall r ene w each deal er•s licanse annually The causes for suspension and revocation of a dealer's license as s e t forth in section 408 of this title shall serve as r easons wa rrant ing the Commi ssion t o refuse t o renew a dealer's license A dealer mus t also submit all facts necessary to keep al l i nformation in the i nitial applic a tion for a deale r s li c ense accurate, complete and cur r ent n applicant who on or before t he app licable anniversary date fails to file t he ritten request t o renew and to pay the appropriate renewal fee must comply with all the provisions of this title applicable to a pers on making a n initial a pplication fo r a dealer s license f) Upon a c hange in the location of the principal place of business of a dealer sai d dealer shall give in writing notic e of suc h c hange to the Commission The Commi ssion shall prescribe t he time within which said not i ce mus t b e r e c eivec in order that sa i d notice be con s id e red as timely At the time notice is given. said dea ler mu s t surrender the dealer s license to the Commission Fai lure to not ify the Commission or to return t he 1 icensa automatically c ancels the dealer 's license When timely notice is g iven t o the Commission it may ithout additional fe9 issue a new dealer's license for t~e bal a nce ~olled Origical -40- of the year. where appl;cable: PROVIOED, That said dealer files a written request for such new license. Se&amp;lt 406. Dealer's Place of Business and Nonresident Dealers (a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this sectionr every dealer licensed under the provisions of this title shall maintain a place of business in the District of Columbia. If a dealer ~aintains more than one place of business within the District of Columbia, a duplicate license shall be issued to such dealer for each additional office maintained. The fee charged for such duplicate license shall not exceed its cost to the District of Columbia b) A nonresident of the District of Columbia may become a dealer by complying with all of the requirements of this title: EXCEPT, That such nonresident need not maintain a place of business within the District of Columbia CJ Every nonresident applicant for a dealer's license shall comply with the provisions of section 10 of the Act of August z5, 1937 (30 Stat. 795; o.c. Code, sec. 45-1410{2 relating to irrevocable consent to serv i ce of process Sec. 407. Suspension or Revocation of License (a) Paragraphs (a b Cl j and (p) of section 8 of the Act of August zs, 1937 (50 Stat. 793; o.c Enrolled Orig!ne l -41- Code, sec 45-1408 relating to causes for suspens ion or revocation of 1 icenses) shall be appl icable to deale rs as causes for suspension or revocation of a dealer s l icense b) ln addition to subsection (a) of th i s s ection the Co•m ission ~ay upon its o wn motion and s ha ll upon the ve rifi ed complaint i n wri ting of any pe rson (provided such complaint or such complainant together wi t h ev idence documentary or otherwi se presented in conne ct ion t nerewi tn, establishes a prima f a cie case&amp;gt investigate the conduct of any dealer With i n thirty (30) days after the receipt by tne Commiss ion o f sai d veri fied complaint the Commision shall no t ify said compl ain ant in wr iting as to its decision o r other action taken with regard to the complaint The Commission snall have the power at any time to suspend or t o revoke a l icense i ssued under the provisions of thi s t itle: PROVIDED That in t he case of a knowing violat ion of sections 407(b)(l) and (2 of t h is act the Commission shall at minimum suspend the license for not less than o~e (l) aonth: PROVlDEO FURTHER That the dealer shall be prohibited from signing any additional contracts fo r t he sa le of houses for that period if the dealer has 1) fa i led to file the return a nd pay the excise tax as reQuired oy t itl e II of this act or knowingly made any false or misl eading statement in connection there with; i (2) failed to record a transfer as required by ti tle III of this ac t• or to pay the deed recordat ion tax. or h as a ade a fals e o r mislead ing statement in connection •ith such recordat i on or recordation tax 3) fail ed t o co~ply with or honor a warranty g iven pursuant to sections 202 (a)(1) o r a 2) of this act 4) violated any of the Commiss ion s regulation s pertaining to deal ers 5) made a false or mi sl eading sta tement concerning a certification g i ven pursuant to paragraphs (3) or (41 of section 202(aJ of this act; or (6) v iolated any of t he provisions of secti on 409{b) of this title Sec 408 Fr a udulent Tr an sfer s by Dea le rs {a) A contract or agreement for t he transfer of property shall be rescindable by the tr ansferee without penal t y at any time before legal title to the property i s transfe rred if at the time of the contract or agreemen 1) the transferor is a dealer; and (2) the transferor was not duly licensed as a de aler in the Di strict of Columbia b) A contrac t or ag ree~ent for the tr a nsfer o f property shall be rescindab le by t he t ransferor wi thout penalty at any t ime befor e legal t i tle to the p r ooe r t y is Enrolled Crigi=e~ transferred, if the transferor is not a dealer if the transferee is a dealer. and if the transferee 1) fails to furnish tne transferor with a fully exe&amp;lt;:uted copy of any contract pertaining to the transfer The ~ayor, within thirty (30) days after the effective date shall develop procedures governing said contract; or (2) fails. at the time of tne execution of the contract. to furnis h a notice to the transferor of his or her right to cancel the contract within a period of time to be determined by the Mayor. The Mayor, within t~irty (30) days after the date of enactment shall develop forms and procedures governing such notice or (3) fails. before furnishing copies of such notice of cancellation to the transferor, to fully complete said notice form; or includes in a contract a confession of judgment or a waiver of any of the rights to which t he transferor is entitled under this section, including specifically his or her right to cancel the transfer; or (5) misrepresents to the transferor the transferor's right to cancel; or (6) fails or refuses to honor any val id notice of cancellai;ion l:ilrolled origi~e.1 (c) Section 9 of the Act of August zs 1937 (50 Stat 794; o c Code sec s-1,.09 relating to hearing procedures 1&amp;gt;efore suspension or r evocation court review appe al) shall a pply as the procedures for suspenslon or revocation of a dealer s li cense Sec 09. Mayor to Notify Co~mission Whenever it comes to the attention of the Mayor tha t a dealer has failed to file a return and pay the exc ise tax and other amounts related thereto as provided in title II of this act or has failed to record a deed or other docu~ent as reQuired by title III of this act or to pay the deed recordation tax. or has made a false or misleading statement in connection with such recor dation. rec ordation tax or excise tax the ~ayor shall In addition to other e nfor cement procedures report such failure t o the Commission Sec 410 Report by Co~m i ssion The Commission shall report in writing to the Council annually no later than the first Tuesday in September on its activi tes regarding the licensing and disciplining of dealers under the provisions of this title The report shall include at least the following information for tne twelve (12 onths i~mediately preceding t he r epor t a) the number of new applications bl the number o f initial dea ler l icenses gran ted and renewals t hereof CJ the number of dealer licenses suspended or revoked and the reason fo r such action; and (d) the number a nd a mount of any recoveries on bonds and the reasons therefor. Sec l l Mayor and co~mi ss ion to Promulgate Regul at ions (a) The ~ayo r shall p r omulgate regulations t o carry out the purposes of th is titl e bl Witnin one (l) year from tne effective date. the Commission after no tice and hearings shall issue r e gulations establi shing standards for t ne conduct of those soliciting residential real property to insure aga inst harassment, nuisance misr epre s entation and othe r unwarranted o r abusive practices c For a v iolati on of the r egu lations promu lgated pursuant t o subsec t ion {b) of th is sec tion a solicitor of res iden t ial property shall in add i tion to any othe r pe nalties be penalized as provided in section 16 of t he Act of August 25 1937 (50 Stat 797; o c Code sec 45-1416 TITLE V MISCELLANEC'US PROVI SI ONS Sec 501 Report of Costs a nd Reve nues I For the first. second and t h ird year after t he effective date and not late r th an the date on which the ~ayor• s budget proposal is trans~itted to the Council the Mayor s hal l repor t to t he Counc il t he total a nd t he net cost of administ er ing the provi si ons o f th is act The repo rt shall indicate. b y department or b ranch of the Di str ict of Columbi a gove rnment, the c os t of administeri ng each title of this act The r eport shall also indi c ate the r e venues reali zed under t i tles II Ill• and IV of thi s act (includ ing f ees, fi nes. p ena lties and exci se s bl The repo rt equired in subsec tion (a) of th i s s ecti on s halt be in a ddi t ion t o any o ther report or information that is or shall be reQu i red Sec soz. Pro mul gation of Regul ati on s to be Con si stent wi t h Administ r ative Procedure Act The Mayo r s ha ll promulgate r egul a t i ons ne ces sary to carry out the provis ions of thi s act ano to deve lop necessary for ms and procedur es. All regul ations promulgated by the ~ayor pursuant to this act incl uding tho se t o be p r o mul gated within t hirty (30) days a fter the e ffect i ve date shall be done s o consistent wi t h tr&amp;gt;€ Distr ict o f Columbia olled Ori~ir.el -47- AdNinistrative Procedure Act. approved October Zlt 1968 (hereinafter. o c .A. P.A t (82 Stat 1204; o.c. Code. sec. 1-l~Ol et seq If co~pl iance with such act would extend pro11Ulgation of the regulations beyo~d thirty (30) days after the effective date then the time for promulgating the regulations shall be extended to thirty (30) days after compl i ance with the O.C.A.P. A. Sec 503. Repeal of Requirement for Property Tax Incentives Section 431 of the Oistrict of Columbia Property Tax Revision Act of 1974 (88 Stat. 1057; o.c. Code sec. 47-651) is hereby repealed. Sec. 504. Section 50l(b}(SJ(O)(Z) of the Rental Housing Act of 1977. effective March 16, 1978 (o c Law 2-54) is amended by insert ing the words any housing• immediately prior to the first usage of tMe word use• and by deleting the words •a s a rental accommodation TITLE VI Sec. 601 Severability (a) The provisions of th is act are severable. and if any provision. sentence. clause. section or part is held illegal. inval id unconst itut ional or inapplicable to any person or circumstances, such holding shall not affect or impair any of the remain ing provisions, sentences. c1auses sections or parts of the act or t heir appl i cation to other persons or circu• s tances I t is hereby d e clar e d to be the legi slati v e i n tent that this a c t ould h ave been adopted i f such Illegal invalid• inapplicable o r unconstitutional prov i si on sent ence claus s e ct i on or part had not been includ ed herein and i f t he person or circu~stances to which the act or any part is i napplicable had been specifi cally exempted b) Th e r epeal or amendment by this act of an y provision o f law shall not affect any act done or any ri gn t accrued or accru ing under suc h provision o f law before the effective d a te or under a ny suit or proceeding had or commenced before t h e ef fec tive date but a l l righ ts a nd liabllites under such l a w shall continue and may be enfo rced i n tne s ame manner and t o the same e xtent as i f the repeal o r amendment had not been made TITLE VI I Sec 701 Ef fective Dat e Th is act s hall take effect on t he date t nis act becomes l a w accord ing to the p r ovisions of s e ction b02(c)(l) of the District o f Columbia Self-Governme nt and Governmenta l Reor ganization Act 4 1 r:oc.kat No: B ill 2- 101 T a i e Ac 2 21- 78 Adopted U=ni=ously (2ab• l JMoore and Win~er r-cr11) 1ge1 CA I j { e~v..c:Dr I •9' f 1 v. J a..a IJ e;:kl CD Cot 1 v. 1 1 T1IC:X:U t I I j M.A.SCN J I I I I Sl'Atn l!'C I I I I o I I t 1 ){co:;u n. I t l f f i\ iON I I I I r .3.A.3.E I I I I { MCO 1 j I I I 7 I I I I I I I I I I t ;t 0 1..A lt; I I I l I I I t i &amp;lt; DO::N I f I r~c r q I r I I I l I I h11111ia 1 I. 7 t•u T~ I l1f! vctcz von Adopted Una:UrnO'-lsly 2 bs) Hardy a nd Dixon ~aw@.wifl S.c ea--r amp c a LI I.OU. C.u.L VCTZ amp;»o lfQ i •N I T I I a.;i ca I I I 1 hi amp;)oo a ri: I T1 I CC lt I !lo&amp;lt;.A.SON I I jS AJ See Page 2 for Second Amended Firs t Ree.dir.g Action Doclutc Na: Bill 2-101 Second A=a lt;loc! r M&amp;gt lt;i i A 3-Zl- 78 @ VC!C VOTZ; Ado-oted Unanirn All present auJ SeC CI C.ou c l LJ ll.O CA.W VOTZ ca..o n 1 \ .o L-1 f 1 t&amp;lt c 1 rw. 1 t I MASON I a •ccJU o CT I I l I 1 :a c:a u I I I l 1 I I I I I J)z:t~ I I I 51 t l I l I t l i ci 7u \ 1 t. 7-"f•c 4-4-78 Unanimou Barry, JMoore, CtuJ. ue itr~ Ado-oted DMocre I I tO U. C..u.t. 70'rZ 1 In 1 rit l 1 ¢.:1 a c 1 c l w OC'lcr:t I I I I l~CN I l I \.li \G I I I I I I I t I I CC i I I I i Jl SCN i I I I i L,_t l I t I ceaz I I I I I I CL\ I I t I CL I I I I i I r I I I oo I I I I s 7 Z N i I I I t I I I c101 ¥-.t T c T•c I JLZt:o.eu:i o: CE i'lC::LA1. coiz:s:rc::i:i en nge 3J Ooc:li:at No: Bill 2-10 l APR 13 1978 Ac!i le.a l.uvo M :fil Lir n•ci c LI DU i c Q t.saj:i Ov•r l amp e.t :COC l!u.dfet Ac I:=c:.oo! Yit!ii c M&amp;gt;.70 Slr.-1 gt;:e cr•a.:y to e Co\ cil I I VOtCZ vo LI JI.OU. CAll V07 c::a c 1 n T r a ~w-c lt I l l.v. I c c ic\.O•C'll l" 1 TC&amp;lt I I I I M.A.SON I I I I S gt v .u::c 1 t I I I \ D~ I I i I MOC!&amp;gt;.Z 1 I t I i.~c I I I J 3A I I I MCO;t t. J I I v l I I I i 1 I CL..U lt;c I I I t l Ot U..X I I l I j i I I I I Ot:t:CN I I I I S-:AC Z-N I l I 1 I I I I a ac• 7 A u c :r f 7.C J Ac ea et e.,ic!e L I lte~c AF v• c! ii M-1.T 1 Vetci S.ucc c ~i:r.it::ec lt;&amp;gt; t!&amp;gt;e CQ"r."cs&amp;gt it/1 f</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
