<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-95">
  <num type="law">2-95</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia General Survival of Tort Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-08-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-95.pdf">D.C. Law 2-95</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1270</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-95, the “District of Columbia General Survival of Tort Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-52, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on April 18, 1978 and May 2, 1978, respectively. There being no action by the Mayor, it was assigned Act No. 2-199 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>LAWS OF TH~ DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 1S'l2 uw2'95 D.C. I.At~ 2-95 DISTRICT OF COU!eIA C&amp;gt;Blm».L SURVIVAL CF 'l'OR'l' ltCT IN THB COUNCI F T!l.E DISTRICT OF COLJ!'IBIA Augu:ot 2, 1978 Toi elilllinate the bar again~t the recove~y o~ da::iages for pain and suffering by the legal reprcsen~ativ administrator or executor of a deceased ~ictirn in to't action to eliminate the bar against recovery of damages for pain and suffering from the legal representative, adltir.istrator or execi;tor of a deceased tort-e&amp;amp;sor in tort actions, and for other purtlOaes. BB I~ ENACT.ED BY THB CJUNCIL or HE D!STr.IC OF COLUMBIA, That this act may cited ~s the "District of Cclumbia General Survival of Tort Acti~ns ACt Sec. 2. Section 12-101 of the District of Columbia Code is a111ended as follows a) by deleting the words "action survives" and inserting in lieu thereof the workd •action, for all such cases, survives and (b) by deleting the second sentence. Sec. 3. Section 20-1501 of the District of ColU111bia Code is amended as follows a) by striking the designation a at the beginning of the first sentence thereof:and (b) by deleting all of subsection (bl Sec. 4. This act shall only apply with respect to all actions, proceedings and matters commenced in any administrative or judicJ~l forWQ on or after the effective date of this act. Sec. S. This act shall take effect pursuant to the provisions of section 602(c 1) of the District of Colwnbia Self- Goverrut1ent and Governmental Reorganization Act, effective December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 814; D.C. Code, sec. l-l47(c l Purao.&amp;amp;.Dt to S.ct1oq 412 ot tbir. D1atrict 0£ Coluabi• S•lf~c~at UJd Govenatnt•l 1Utorgaa1aatlon Act (P, L. 93-19&amp;amp th&amp;amp; Act, t Couocil al tbe Dl•trict of Col\al&amp;gt;JA adopt•4 8111 No. 2-~z. Qf\ ftr•t and •iti:cmd rc.£d1a.ga April ta, l97S aod Kay 2 1971. r••p*-Cttvely. followi.01 ex-p1ra- ta JNt•~t to S•cttoo 04(e} of th• Act, thi• l•Slala.tlo~ vaa Ml•ipi.c:d Act Mo. 2•199, p~blt•h-4 ta tb.6. Au.gu•t ll, \976 ttto~ Gf th• O.C 11.ater and traa ltt-4 to bath vev a of Cou1r a for a 30-day 245 DISTRICT OF COLUMBI ATUTES AT l.,\RGE the Couac.il of th• DlJt'rtc.c o! Calub1.a barer tl 10tic: th.\t tb1 JO-illy CiiOf!°u11oaal r1ri1V pe.ri d ha U}'ir•d •ad. th•r.rlore, ¢ thl tollovic1 lt1t1l1t!oo D.C. 1-9 t lfoctlvo 2, 1971. Llw 2·95</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
