<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-124">
  <num type="bill">23-422</num>
  <num type="act">23-124</num>
  <heading type="short">School Sunscreen Safety Emergency Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Student Access to Treatment Act of 2007 to permit students to possess and self-administer sunscreen at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, and while on school-sponsored transportation without a medication action plan, and to permit school staff to administer sunscreen to a student at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, and while on school-sponsored transportation without a medication action plan.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-09-17</introduced>
    <effective>2019-10-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/43153/Signed_Act/B23-0422-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-124</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 13156</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0422">
      <vote date="2019-09-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-10-07</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "School Sunscreen Safety Emergency Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>The Student Access to Treatment Act of 2007, effective February 2, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-107; D.C. Official Code § 38-651.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 38-651.01) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period and inserting the phrase ". The term "medication" shall not include sunscreen." in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>A new paragraph (5A) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include lvl="1">
          <para>
            <num>(5A)</num>
            <text>"Sunscreen" means a lotion, cream, spray, or gel regulated by the federal Food and Drug Administration for the purposes of absorbing, reflecting, or scattering ultraviolet radiation and preventing sunburn.</text>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-651.01"/>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 38-651.02) is amended as follows:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The section heading is amended by striking the phrase "medication." and inserting the phrase "medication and sunscreen." in its place.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The existing text is designated as subsection (a).</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows:</text>
        <include>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(1)</num>
              <text>A student may possess and self-administer sunscreen at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, and while on school-sponsored transportation, to protect against ultraviolet radiation and sunburn, without the submission of a medication action plan; provided, that the responsible person has not provided written notice to the school principal or school nurse that the student may not possess or self-administer sunscreen.</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(2)</num>
              <text>School staff may administer sunscreen to a student at the school in which the student is currently enrolled, at school-sponsored activities, and while on school-sponsored transportation, to protect against ultraviolet radiation and sunburn, without the school possessing a medication action plan for that student; provided, that the student or responsible person has provided sunscreen for that purpose, and the responsible person has not provided written notice to the school principal or school nurse that the student may not use sunscreen.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </include>
        <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      </para>
      <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-651.02"/>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
