<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-252">
  <num type="bill">23-685</num>
  <num type="act">23-252</num>
  <heading type="short">Extreme Risk Protection Order Implementation Working Group Emergency Amendment Act of 2020</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975 to establish an Extreme Risk Protection Order Implementation Working Group, to provide for its membership, and to specify its duties.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2020-03-02</introduced>
    <effective>2020-03-17</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/44309/B23-0685-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-252</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 3467</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0685">
      <vote date="2020-03-03" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-03-17</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Extreme Risk Protection Order Implementation Working Group Emergency Amendment Act of 2020".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Title X of the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, effective May 10, 2019 (D.C. Law 22-314; D.C. Official Code § 7-2510.01 <em>et seq.</em>), is amended by adding a new section 1013 to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <num>1013</num>
        <heading>Extreme Risk Protection Order Implementation Working Group.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>There is established an Extreme Risk Protection Order Implementation Working Group ("Working Group"), which shall be composed of the following individuals:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>District government members, or their designees:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>The Chairperson of the Council's Committee on the Judiciary and Public Safety;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>The Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>The Deputy Mayor for Health and Human Services;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>The Attorney General for the District of Columbia;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>The Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(F)</num>
              <text>The Executive Director of the Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(G)</num>
              <text>The Director of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(H)</num>
              <text>The Chief Medical Examiner;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(I)</num>
              <text>The Director of the Department of Forensic Sciences;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(J)</num>
              <text>The Director of the Office of Victim Services and Justice Grants;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(K)</num>
              <text>The Executive Director of the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(L)</num>
              <text>The Director of the Department of Behavioral Health; and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Community members and organizations, or their designees:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Everytown for Gun Safety;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Moms Demand Action for Gun Sense in America, D.C. Chapter;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(C)</num>
              <text>The Giffords Law Center to Prevent Gun Violence;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(D)</num>
              <text>The Coalition to Stop Gun Violence;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(E)</num>
              <text>Brady: United Against Gun Violence;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(F)</num>
              <text>The D.C. Appleseed Center for Law &amp; Justice;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(G)</num>
              <text>The D.C. Coalition Against Domestic Violence;</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(H)</num>
              <text>The D.C. Behavioral Health Association; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(I)</num>
              <text>One representative from each of the District's violence interruption contractors with the Office of Neighborhood Safety and Engagement and the Office of the Attorney General's Cure the Streets program.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>The Working Group may also request the participation of other subject matter experts, as well as designees of the following:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>The Chief Judge of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>The United States Attorney for the District of Columbia.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>The Chairperson of the Council's Committee on the Judiciary and Public Safety and the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice shall serve as the co-chairs of the Working Group.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>The duties of the Working Group shall include:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Improving public awareness of extreme risk protection orders;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>Improving the coordination of District and federal agencies regarding the filing, adjudication, and execution of extreme risk protection orders;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Facilitating the education of behavioral and mental health professionals about extreme risk protection orders;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(4)</num>
            <text>Advancing the development of District government policies and procedures to govern extreme risk protection orders, such as written directives of the Metropolitan Police Department; and</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(5)</num>
            <text>Reviewing and incorporating best practices from other jurisdictions concerning extreme risk protection order laws, policies, and procedures.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(e)</num>
          <text>This section shall expire on July 15, 2021.</text>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-2510.12" action="creation of § 7-2510.13"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
