<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:cache="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/cache" xmlns:citations="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/citations" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:macro="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/macro" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-522">
  <num type="bill">23-1004</num>
  <num type="act">23-522</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Additional Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2020</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Act of 2020, the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2020, the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2020, and the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2020 to clarify returning citizens' eligibility to apply for financial assistance for District residents impacted by the public health emergency.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2020-11-16</introduced>
    <effective>2020-12-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/downloads/LIMS/45982/Signed_Act/B23-1004-Signed_Act.pdf">D.C. Act 23-522</citation>
      <citation type="register">67 DCR 14439</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="https://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-1004">
      <vote date="2020-11-17" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2020-12-07</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Additional Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2020".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Amendatory section 203a of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, enacted on August 31, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-407; 67 DCR 10493), in section 7212 of the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Act of 2020, enacted on August 31, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-407; 67 DCR 10493), is amended to read as follows:</text>
    <include>
      <section>
        <num>203a</num>
        <heading>Assistance for excluded workers.</heading>
        <para>
          <num>(a)</num>
          <text>During the public health emergency declared in the Mayor's order dated March 11, 2020, and any extensions thereof, the Washington Convention and Sports Authority ("Events DC") shall issue, subject to the availability of funds, grants or contracts to nonprofit entities to use to provide cash assistance to District residents who are otherwise excluded from District and federal aid related to COVID-19. To qualify for cash assistance from grants or contracts awarded pursuant to this section, a District resident shall, at the time of application for assistance under this section:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>Demonstrate a loss of income due to the public health emergency;</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Be ineligible for:</text>
              <para>
                <num>(i)</num>
                <text>Unemployment insurance; or</text>
              </para>
              <para>
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <text>COVID-19 relief; or</text>
              </para>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Be a returning citizen, as that term is defined in <code-cite doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1301|(5)">section 2(5) of the Office on Ex-Offender Affairs and Commission on Re-Entry and Ex-Offender Affairs Establishment Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-243; D.C. Official Code § 24-1301(5))</code-cite>, whose incarceration ended on March 11, 2020 or later; and</text>
            </para>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(3)</num>
            <text>Provide a:</text>
            <para>
              <num>(A)</num>
              <text>Signed certification that the resident's loss of income stems from the public health emergency; and</text>
            </para>
            <para>
              <num>(B)</num>
              <text>Proof of residency and eligibility for relief, as determined by Events DC and consistent with rules and standards for COVID-19 relief programs administered by Events DC.</text>
            </para>
          </para>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(b)</num>
          <text>Any entity receiving a grant or contract pursuant to this section may use no more than 10% of the grant for administrative expenses incurred from administering the cash assistance program.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(c)</num>
          <text>Cash assistance provided to eligible individuals pursuant to this section shall not be considered in determining eligibility for any means-tested programs administered by the District.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(d)</num>
          <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
          <para>
            <num>(1)</num>
            <text>"COVID-19" means the disease caused by the novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(2)</num>
            <text>"COVID-19 relief" means federal monetary unemployment assistance provided under the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act, approved March 27, 2020 (134 Stat. 281; 15 U.S.C. § 9001 <em>et seq.</em>), which shall include tax credits but shall not include federal Economic Impact Payments or other stimulus relief for which eligibility is not contingent on the recipient's employment status.</text>
          </para>
        </para>
      </section>
    </include>
    <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    <codify:emergency doc="D.C. Code" path="§10-1202.03a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <text>The Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2020, effective October 26, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-426; 67 DCR 12848), is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Section 2192(d) is repealed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Amendatory section 203a(a)(2)(B) of the Washington Convention Center Authority Act of 1994, effective October 26, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-426; 67 DCR 12848), in section 7212 is amended by striking the phrase "not more than 6 months before the time of application for assistance under this section" and inserting the phrase "on March 11, 2020, or later" in its place.</text>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <text>Section 2(a)(3) and (b) of the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2020, effective October 14, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-416; 67 DCR 12245), is repealed.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <text>Section 2(a)(3) and (b) of the Fiscal Year 2021 Budget Support Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2020, enacted on October 28, 2020 (D.C. Act 23-447; 67 DCR 13036), is repealed.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <heading>Applicability.</heading>
    <text>This act shall apply as of October 1, 2020.</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Budget Director as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
