<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" id="D.C. Act 23-68">
  <num type="bill">23-329</num>
  <num type="act">23-68</num>
  <heading type="short">Children's Hospital Research and Innovation Campus Phase 1 Emergency Amendment Act of 2019</heading>
  <heading type="long">To amend, on an emergency basis, Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide a real property tax exemption for Lots 824 and 826, Square 2950.</heading>
  <meta>
    <introduced>2019-06-13</introduced>
    <effective>2019-06-20</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="act" url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Download/42775/B23-0329-SignedAct.pdf">D.C. Act 23-68</citation>
      <citation type="register">66 DCR 7610</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B23-0329">
      <vote date="2019-06-18" reading="Final"/>
      <enacted>2019-06-20</enacted>
      <summary/>
      <committee>Retained by the Council</committee>
    </history>
  </meta>
  <text>BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Children's Hospital Research and Innovation Campus Phase 1 Emergency Amendment Act of 2019".</text>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <text>Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <prefix>§</prefix>
          <num>47-1099.04</num>
          <heading>Children's Hospital real property tax exemption.</heading>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>A new section 47-1099.04 is added to read as follows:</text>
      <include>
        <section>
          <prefix>§</prefix>
          <num>47-1099.04</num>
          <heading>Children's Hospital real property tax exemption.</heading>
          <para>
            <num>(a)</num>
            <text>Only that portion of real property currently described for assessment and taxation purposes as Lot 808, Square 2950, which is to be subdivided in part into Lots 824 and 826, Square 2950 effective for Tax Year 2020, and the buildings located thereon ("Property"), owned by Children's National at Walter Reed, LLC, a wholly-owned subsidiary of Children's Hospital, a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation, shall remain exempt from real property taxation to the extent the Property is validly exempt as of the day before any leases being granted to certain business entities (controlled directly or indirectly by Children's Hospital) to receive the federal tax benefits, including New Markets Tax Credits under 26 U.S.C. § 45D, Opportunity Zone tax benefits under 26 U.S.C. § 1400Z-1 <em>et seq.</em>, or Historic Rehabilitation Tax Credits under 26 U.S.C. § 47; provided, that the Property shall be subject to §§ 47-1007 and 47-1009. The Property shall be subject to the provisions of §§ 47-1005, 47-1007, and 47-1009 where a sublease or lease is made to another entity (other than the certain business entities referenced in this subsection) that would not qualify for exemption under § 47-1002 if it were both the owner and user of the Property.</text>
          </para>
          <para>
            <num>(b)</num>
            <text>Any transfer, assignment, or other disposition of all or any portion of the Property, including an assignment of leasehold interest in the Property or a sublease of the Property, between Children's National at Walter Reed, LLC and Children's Hospital, or any business entity controlled directly or indirectly by Children's Hospital, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by § 42-1103 and § 47-903.</text>
          </para>
        </section>
      </include>
      <aftertext>.</aftertext>
      <codify:annotation doc="D.C. Code" path="§47-1099.04" type="Emergency Legislation" history="false" codify:applicability="2019-09-11"><cite doc="D.C. Act 23-68" path="2|(b)">
            For temporary (90 days) creation of § [47-1099.05], see § 2(b) of the Children's Hospital Research and Innovation Campus Phase 1 Emergency Amendment Act of 2019 (D.C. Act 23-68, June 20, 2019, 66 DCR 7610)</cite>.
      </codify:annotation>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <heading>Fiscal impact statement.</heading>
    <text>The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 4a of the General Legislative Procedures Act of 1975, approved October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.47a).</text>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <heading>Effective date.</heading>
    <text>This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto), and shall remain in effect for no longer than 90 days, as provided for emergency acts of the Council of the District of Columbia in section 412(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.12(a)).</text>
  </section>
</document>
