<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-153">
  <num type="law">14-153</num>
  <heading type="short">INSURANCE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT AMENDMENT ACT OF 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2002-06-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-153.pdf">D.C. Law 14-153</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 4257</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0325"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act To provide for the regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, to clarify the criteria that constitute an exempt commercial risk, and to clarify the effective applicability date. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Insurance Economic Development Amendment Act of 2002 Sec. 2. The unnumbered paragraph beginning "Exempt commercial risk" of section 1 of An Act To provide for the regulation of certain insurance rates in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved May 20, 1948 (62 Stat. 242; D.C. Official Code § 31-2701(7 is amended to read as follows Exempt commercial risk" means a person or entity which meets one of the following criteria 1) Retains or employs a certified or qualified risk manager to negotiate insurance coverage 2) Possesses a net worth in excess of $2 million 3) Generates annual revenues in excess of $2 million 4) Has at least 10 employees 5) Pays annual aggregate country-wide standard insurance premiums in excess of $10,000 6) Has total insured property value of at least $2 million; or 7) Is a nonprofit organization or public body generating annual budgeted expenditures of at least $5 million Sec. 3. Applicability. Section 2 shall apply as of May 15, 2001. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 31-2701 Note § 31-2701 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
