<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-239">
  <num type="law">14-239</num>
  <heading type="short">Housing Finance Agency Amendment Act of 2002</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2003-03-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-239.pdf">D.C. Law 14-239</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 11162</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0345">
      <narrative>Law 14-239, the “Housing Finance Agency Amendment Act of 2002”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-345, which was referred to the Committee on Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 1, 2002, and November 7, 2002, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 26, 2002, it was assigned Act No. 14-520 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-239 became effective on March 25, 2003.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act with respect to the powers and authority of the District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Housing Finance Agency Amendment Act of 2002”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-135; D.C. Official Code § 42-2701 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102(15 D.C. Official Code § 42-2701.02(15 is amended to read as follows: “(15) “Mortgage lender” means an entity as defined in section 2(11) of the Mortgage Lender and Broker Act of 1996, effective September 9, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-155; D.C. Official Code § 26-1101(11 that is deemed eligible by the Agency to participate in any of its programs.” b) Section 206 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2702.06) is amended by striking the phrase “are made” and inserting the phrase “or supportive programs” in its place c) Section 301 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2703.01 is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (4) is amended to read as follows: “(4) To acquire (by purchase or otherwise sell, construct, lease, improve, rehabilitate, repair and otherwise maintain an office or offices at such places within the District of Columbia as the Agency shall from time to time designate and to issue bonds or otherwise provide financing for such offices;” 2) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase “this act;” and inserting the phrase “this act and contracts for or relating to the development, construction, rehabilitation, improvement, maintenance, repair, operation, and management of housing projects;”in its place 3) Paragraph (15) is amended as follows A) Strike the word “rehabilitate” and insert the phrase “rehabilitate, improve,” in its place. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2003 Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 42-2701.02 Amend § 42-2702.06 Amend § 42-2703.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180 B) Subparagraph (B) is repealed 4) Add a new paragraph (15A) to read as follows: “(15A) To acquire (by purchase or otherwise own, lease, clear, construct, reconstruct, rehabilitate, improve, repair, maintain, manage, operate, assign, encumber, or sell or otherwise dispose of any real property; provided, that: “(A) The Agency shall not finance more than 4 housing projects in any one fiscal year; and” “(B) The authority of the Agency to acquire properties by purchase or otherwise under this paragraph shall terminate on December 31, 2007; provided, that before that time the Agency may submit a request for renewal of authority;” 5) Paragraph (20) is amended by striking the phrase “act; and” and inserting the phrase “act;” “ (6) Add new paragraphs (20A 20B 20C and (20D) to read as follows: “(20A) To establish funds and reserves to provide additional security for loans provided for housing projects; “(20B) To enter into such contracts with government agencies that the Agency considers appropriate for housing projects; “(20C) To establish nonprofit and for-profit corporations, partnerships, limited liability companies, business trusts, and any other entities to act in furtherance of its general powers or purposes; “(20D) To establish such supportive programs as provided in section 305 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2703.05 and” d) Section 302 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2703.02) is amended as follows 1) Designate the existing text as subsection (a 2) Add a new subsection (b) to read as follows: “(b) The Agency when purchasing property shall issue only bonds that are government entity bonds of the Agency or 501(c)(3) bonds created by the Agency for the specific purpose of undertaking a development project.” e) Section 305 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2703.05) is amended as follows 1) Designate the existing text as subsection (a 2) Add a new subsection (b) to read as follows: “(b) The Agency may establish, administer, or contract for the administration of any program that involves providing loans or other financial assistance directly by the Agency or by an entity established by the Agency under this act or indirectly through an Agency-approved financial institution, to persons residing within any state or political subdivision thereof within the meaning of section 103 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 29; 26 U.S.C. § 103 or successor provisions which loan or other financial assistance is eligible for, or made in conjunction with the provision of, mortgage insurance under any program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development or meets the guidelines established by Amend § 42-2703.02 Amend § 42-2703.05 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or the Rural Development Agency, and which loan or other financial assistance will result in the generation of revenues that will benefit programs authorized under this act f) Section 410(a D.C. Official Code § 42-2704.10(a is amended by striking the phrase “of the Agency” and inserting the phrase “of the Agency or of any entity established by the Agency pursuant to section 301(20C)” in its place. Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (84 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of a veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia Amend § 42-2704.10</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
