<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-30">
  <num type="law">14-30</num>
  <heading type="short">Election Petition Penalty Amendment Act of 2001</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2001-10-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-30.pdf">D.C. Law 14-30</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 7087</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0053">
      <narrative>Law 14-30, the “Election Petition Penalty Amendment Act of 2001”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-53, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 5, 2001, and June 26, 2001, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 12, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 14-91 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-30 became effective on October 13, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955 to clarify the penalties for violation of the act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Election Petition Penalty Amendment Act of 2001”. Sec. 2. Section 8(b) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 701; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.08(b is amended as follows a) Paragraph (3) is amended to read as follows: “(3) All signatures on a petition shall be made by the person whose signature it purports to be and not by any other person. Each petition shall contain an affidavit, made under penalty of perjury, in a form to be determined by the Board and signed by the circulator of that petition which shall state that the circulator is a registered voter and has: “(A) Personally circulated the petition; “(B) Personally witnessed each person sign the petition; and “(C) Inquired from each signer whether he or she is a registered voter in the same party as the candidate and, where applicable, whether the signer is registered in and a resident of the ward from which the candidate seeks election.” b) A new paragraph (4) is added to read as follows: “(4) Any circulator who knowingly and willfully violates any provisions of this section, or any regulations promulgated pursuant to this section, shall upon conviction be subject to a fine of not more than $10,000, or imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both. Each occurrence of a violation of this section shall constitute a separate offense. Violations of this section shall be prosecuted in the name of the District of Columbia by the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia.”. Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition West Group Publisher Amend § 1-1001.08 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Official Code § 47-392.03(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
