<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-36">
  <num type="law">14-36</num>
  <heading type="short">Campaign Finance Amendment Act of 2001</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2001-10-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-36.pdf">D.C. Law 14-36</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 7111</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0108">
      <narrative>Law 14-36, the “Campaign Finance Amendment Act of 2001”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-108, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 5, 2001, and June 26, 2001, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 12, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 14-98 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-36 became effective on October 13, 2001.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act of 1974 to prohibit the use of District of Columbia government resources, including budget authority, personal services, and nonpersonal services to encourage the support of, or opposition to any candidate, initiative, referendum, or recall measure. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Campaign Finance Amendment Act of 2001 Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Campaign Finance Reform and Conflict of Interest Act of 1974, approved August 14, 1974 (88 Stat. 447; D.C. Official Code § 1-1101.01 et seq is amended by adding a new title VI-A to read as follows Title VI-A USE OF GOVERNMENT RESOURCES FOR CAMPAIGN-RELATED ACTIVITIES Sec. 651. Prohibition on the use of District government resources for campaign related activities a) No resources of the District of Columbia government, including, the expenditure of funds, the personal services of employees during their hours of work, and nonpersonal services, including supplies, materials, equipment, office space, facilities, telephones and other utilities, shall be used to support or oppose any candidate for elected office, whether partisan or nonpartisan, or to support or oppose any initiative, referendum, or recall measure, including a charter amendment referendum conducted in accordance with section 303 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 784; D.C. Official Code § 1- 203.03 b)(1)This title shall not prohibit the Mayor, the Chairman and members of the Council, or the President and members of the Board of Education from expressing their views on a District of Columbia election as part of their official duties 2) This subsection shall not be construed to authorize any member of the staff of the Mayor, the Chairman and members of the Council, or the President and members of the Board of Education, or any other employee of the executive or legislative branch to engage in any activity to support or oppose any candidate for elected office, whether partisan or Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition West Group Publisher New § 1-1106.51 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. nonpartisan, an initiative, referendum, or recall measure during their hours of work, or the use of any nonpersonal services including supplies, materials, equipment, office space, facilities, telephones and other utilities to support or oppose an initiative, referendum, or recall matter Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the attached fiscal impact statement as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto approval by the Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Authority as provided in section 203(a) of the District of Columbia Financial Responsibility and Management Assistance Act of 1995, approved April 17, 1995 (109 Stat. 116; D.C. Official Code § 47-392.03(a a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
