<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-79">
  <num type="law">14-79</num>
  <heading type="short">Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Annual Contribution Amendment Act of 2001</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2002-03-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-79.pdf">D.C. Law 14-79</citation>
      <citation type="register">48 DCR 11266</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0150">
      <narrative>Law 14-79, the “Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Annual Contribution Amendment Act of 2001”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-150, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 2, 2001, and November 6, 2001, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 29, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 14-199 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-79 became effective on March 6, 2002.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975 to increase from $400 to $1,000, the maximum amount of funds that an Advisory Neighborhood Commission may receive annually from an individual without specific authorization from the Council. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Annual Contribution Amendment Act of 2001 Sec. 2. Section 13(l) of the Advisory Neighborhood Commissions Act of 1975, effective March 26, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-58; D.C. Official Code § 1-309.10(l is amended by striking the number “$400" wherever it appears and inserting the number “$1,000" in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. There is no fiscal impact. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-309.10 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
