<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 14-82">
  <num type="law">14-82</num>
  <heading type="short">Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital Tax Abatement Act of 2001</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2002-03-19</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/14-82.pdf">D.C. Law 14-82</citation>
      <citation type="register">49 DCR 194</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B14-0009">
      <narrative>Law 14-82, the “Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital Tax Abatement Act of 2001”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 14-9, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 6, 2001, and December 4, 2001, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 20, 2001, it was assigned Act No. 14-202 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 14-82 became effective on March</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide a 20-year tax abatement to Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital Tax Abatement Act of 2001 Sec. 2. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding the section designation “§ 47-1050. Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital.” b) A new section 47-1050 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-1050. Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital. “(a) Beginning Tax Year 2001 and ending Tax Year 2020, the property in the District of Columbia, described as lots 3 and 4, square 5919, operated as Greater Southeast Community Hospital, and the property in the District of Columbia described as parcel 252-0093, operated as Hadley Memorial Hospital, together with improvements thereon and furnishings thereon, which properties are owned by Doctors Community Healthcare Corporation, shall be exempt from taxation so long as the same properties are used in carrying on the purposes and activities of the Greater Southeast Community Hospital and Hadley Memorial Hospital b) The property tax abatement provided in subsection (a) of this section shall be contingent upon an annual certification by the Mayor that the Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation has complied with the terms of the following: “(1) The Memorandum of Understanding, dated July 19, 2001, between the Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and the District of Columbia Office of Local Business Development; “(2) The First Source Employment Agreement, dated September 26, 2001, Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2002 Supp. West Group Publisher New § 47-1050 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-228-2180. between the Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services; and “(3) The schedule of annual capital expenditures contained in Attachment S to the Committee on Finance and Revenue's October 9, 2001 Report, as filed with the Secretary to the Council of the District of Columbia, on Bill 14-9, the Greater Southeast Community Hospital Corporation and Hadley Memorial Hospital Tax Abatement Act of 2001 Sec. 3. Inclusion in the budget and financial plan. This act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
