<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-1304</num>
  <heading>Issuance of certificate of good standing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to establish a program for the issuance of a certificate of good standing to any person previously convicted of a crime in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A certificate of good standing shall include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Its date of issuance.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The date the individual’s last sentence, including parole, probation, or supervised release, was completed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Any outstanding and pending charges against the individual as of the date that the certificate of good standing is issued.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Any outstanding and pending writs and holds placed on the individual as of the date that the certificate of good standing is issued.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A statement that the information on the certificate of good standing reflects only the records, as of the date of issuance, in the database of the Department of Corrections and all other databases to which the department has access, and that the certificate is only a statement of the individual’s status and shall not be construed as a statement of the individual’s character.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An individual may petition the Mayor for a certificate of good standing at any time after his or her completion of any and all sentences, including parole, probation, or supervised release.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia shall not be liable for the actions of an individual to whom a certificate of good standing has been issued.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Mayor, pursuant to subchapter I of Chapter 5 of Title 2 [§ <cite path="§2-501">2-501</cite> et seq.], may issue rules to implement this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-243" type="History">Mar. 8, 2007, D.C. Law 16-243, § 4a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-319" type="History">as added June 15, 2013, D.C. Law 19-319, § 6, 60 DCR 2333</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-319">D.C. Law 19-319</cite> added this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
