<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-1102</num>
  <heading>Authority to enter into and execute Compact.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor is authorized to enter into and execute on behalf of the District a compact with any state or states legally joining therein in the form substantially as follows:</text>
  <text>
    <center>
      <strong>THE INTERSTATE COMPACT FOR JUVENILES</strong>
    </center>
  </text>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading>Purpose.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The compacting states to this Interstate Compact recognize that each state is responsible for the proper supervision or return of juveniles, delinquents, and status offenders who are on probation or parole and who have absconded, escaped, or run away from supervision and control and in so doing have endangered their own safety and the safety of others. The compacting states also recognize that each state is responsible for the safe return of juveniles who have run away from home and in doing so have left their state of residence. The compacting states also recognize that Congress, by enacting the Crime Control Act, 4 U.S.C. § 112, has authorized and encouraged compacts for cooperative efforts and mutual assistance in the prevention of crime.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>It is the purpose of this compact, through means of joint and cooperative action among the compacting states, to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Ensure that the adjudicated juveniles and status offenders subject to this compact are provided adequate supervision and services in the receiving state as ordered by the adjudicating judge or parole authority in the sending state;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Ensure that the public-safety interests of the citizens, including the victims of juvenile offenders, in both the sending and receiving states are adequately protected;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Return juveniles who have run away, absconded, or escaped from supervision or control or have been accused of an offense to the state requesting their return;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Make contracts for the cooperative institutionalization in public facilities in member states for delinquent youth needing special services;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Provide for the effective tracking and supervision of juveniles;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Equitably allocate the costs, benefits, and obligations of the compacting states;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Establish procedures to manage the movement between states of juvenile offenders released to the community under the jurisdiction of courts, juvenile departments, or other criminal or juvenile justice agency that has jurisdiction over juvenile offenders;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>Insure that immediate notice is provided to jurisdictions where defined offenders are authorized to travel or relocate across state lines;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>Establish procedures to resolve pending charges (detainers) against juvenile offenders prior to transfer or release to the community under the terms of this compact;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>Establish a system of uniform data collection on information pertaining to juveniles subject to this compact that allows access by authorized juvenile justice and criminal justice officials and regular reporting of compact activities to heads of state executive, judicial, and legislative branches, and juvenile and criminal justice administrators;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(11)</num>
        <text>Monitor compliance with rules governing interstate movement of juveniles and initiate interventions to address and correct noncompliance;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(12)</num>
        <text>Coordinate training and education regarding the regulation of interstate movement of juveniles for officials involved in this activity; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(13)</num>
        <text>Coordinate the implementation and operation of the compact with the Interstate Compact for the Placement of Children, the Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, and other compacts affecting juveniles, particularly in those cases where concurrent or overlapping supervision issues arise.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>It is the policy of the compacting states that the activities conducted by the Interstate Commission, created in Article III of this compact, are the formation of public policies and, therefore, are public business. Furthermore, the compacting states shall cooperate and observe their individual and collective duties and responsibilities for the prompt return and acceptance of juveniles subject to the provisions of this compact. The provisions of this compact shall be reasonably and liberally construed to accomplish the purposes and policies of the compact.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading>Definitions.</heading>
    <text>As used in this compact, unless the context clearly requires a different construction, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Bylaws” means those bylaws established by the Interstate Commission for its governance, or for directing or controlling its actions or conduct.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Compact administrator” means the individual in each compacting state, appointed pursuant to the terms of this compact, responsible for the administration and management of the state’s supervision and transfer of juveniles subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the State Council under this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Compacting state” means any state that has enacted enabling legislation for this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>“Commissioner” means the voting representative of each compacting state appointed pursuant to Article III of this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>“Court” means any court having jurisdiction over delinquent, neglected, or dependent children.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>“Deputy compact administrator” means the individual, if any, in each compacting state appointed to act on behalf of a compact administrator pursuant to the terms of this compact responsible for the administration and management of the state’s supervision and transfer of juveniles, subject to the terms of this compact, the rules adopted by the Interstate Commission, and policies adopted by the State Council under this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>“Interstate Commission” means the Interstate Commission for Juveniles created by Article III of this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>“Juvenile” means any person defined as a juvenile in any member state or by the rules of the Interstate Commission, including a(n):</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>“Accused delinquent” — a person charged with an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>“Adjudicated delinquent” — a person found to have committed an offense that, if committed by an adult, would be a criminal offense;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>“Accused status offender” — a person charged with an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>“Adjudicated status offender” — a person found to have committed an offense that would not be a criminal offense if committed by an adult; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>“Non-offender” — a person in need of supervision who has not been accused or adjudicated a status offender or delinquent.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>“Non-compacting state” means any state that has not enacted enabling legislation for this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>“Probation or parole” means any kind of supervision or conditional release of juveniles authorized under the laws of the compacting states.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>“Rule” means a written statement by the Interstate Commission promulgated pursuant to Article VI of this compact that is of general applicability, implements, interprets, or prescribes a policy or provision of this compact, or an organizational, procedural, or practice requirement of the Interstate Commission, and has the force and effect of statutory law in a compacting state, and includes the amendment, repeal, or suspension of an existing rule.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>“State” means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Marianas Islands.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading>Interstate Commission for Juveniles.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The compacting states hereby create the Interstate Commission for Juveniles. The Interstate Commission shall be a body corporate and joint agency of the compacting states. The Interstate Commission shall have all the responsibilities, powers, and duties set forth in this compact and such additional powers as may be conferred upon it by subsequent action of the respective legislatures of the compacting states in accordance with the terms of this compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall consist of commissioners appointed by the appropriate appointing authority in each state pursuant to the rules and requirements of each compacting state, in consultation with the State Council for Interstate Juvenile Supervision (“State Council”). The commissioner shall be the compact administrator, deputy compact administrator, or designee from that state who shall serve on the Interstate Commission in such capacity under or pursuant to the applicable law of the compacting state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>In addition to the commissioners who are the voting representatives of each state, the Interstate Commission shall include individuals who are not commissioners but who are members of interested organizations. Such non-commissioner members shall include a member of the national organizations of governors, legislators, state chief justices, attorneys general, Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, Interstate Compact for the Placement of Children, juvenile justice and juvenile corrections officials, and crime victims. All non-commissioner members of the Interstate Commission shall be ex-officio, non-voting members. The Interstate Commission may provide in its bylaws for such additional ex-officio, non-voting members, including members of other national organizations, in such numbers as shall be determined by the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Each compacting state represented at any meeting of the Interstate Commission shall be entitled to one vote. A majority of the compacting states shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless a larger quorum is required by the bylaws of the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall meet at least once each calendar year. The chairperson may call additional meetings and, upon the request of a simple majority of the compacting states, shall call additional meetings. Public notice shall be given of all meetings and meetings shall be open to the public.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall establish an executive committee, which shall include Interstate Commission officers, members, and others, as determined by the bylaws. The executive committee shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission during periods when the Interstate Commission is not in session, with the exception of rulemaking or amending the compact. The executive committee, managed by an executive director and the Interstate Commission staff, shall;</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Oversee the day-to-day activities of the administration of the compact;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Administer enforcement and compliance with the provisions of the compact, its bylaws, and rules; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Perform other duties as directed by the Interstate Commission or as set forth in the bylaws.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Each member of the Interstate Commission shall have the right and power to cast a vote to which that compacting state is entitled and to participate in the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission. A member shall vote in person and shall not delegate a vote to another compacting state. However, a commissioner, in consultation with the State Council, shall appoint another authorized representative in the absence of the commissioner from that state to cast a vote on behalf of the compacting state at a specified meeting. The bylaws may provide for members’ participation in meetings by telephone or other means of telecommunication or electronic communication.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(h)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission’s bylaws shall establish conditions and procedures under which the Interstate Commission shall make its information and official records available to the public for inspection or copying. The Interstate Commission may exempt from disclosure any information or official record to the extent it would adversely affect personal-privacy rights or proprietary interests.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(i)</num>
      <text>Public notice shall be given of all meetings and all meetings shall be open to the public, except as set forth in the rules or as otherwise provided in the compact. The Interstate Commission, and any of its committees, may close a meeting to the public when it determines by a two-thirds vote that an open meeting would be likely to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Relate solely to the Interstate Commission’s internal personnel practices and procedures;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Disclose matters specifically exempted from disclosure by statute;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Disclose trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Involve accusing a person of a crime;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Involve formally censuring a person;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Disclose information of a personal nature where disclosure would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Disclose investigative records compiled for law-enforcement purposes;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>Disclose information contained in or related to an examination or operating report or a condition report prepared by, on behalf of, or for the use of, the Interstate Commission with respect to a regulated person or entity for the purpose of regulation or supervision of the person or entity;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(9)</num>
        <text>Disclose information, the premature disclosure of which would significantly endanger the stability of a regulated person or entity; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(10)</num>
        <text>Specifically relate to the Interstate Commission’s issuance of a subpoena or its participation in a civil action or other legal proceeding.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(j)</num>
      <text>For every meeting closed pursuant to subsection (i) of this article, the Interstate Commission’s legal counsel shall publicly certify that, in the legal counsel’s opinion, the meeting may be closed to the public, and shall reference each provision that supports the certified opinion. The Interstate Commission shall keep minutes, which shall fully and clearly describe all matters discussed in any meeting, and shall provide a full and accurate summary of any actions taken, and the reasons for the actions, including a description of each of the views expressed on any item and the record of any roll-call vote (reflected in the vote of each member on the question). All documents considered in connection with any action shall be identified in the minutes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(k)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall collect standardized data concerning the interstate movement of juveniles as directed through its rules, which shall specify the data to be collected, the means of collection and data exchange, and reporting requirements. The methods of data collection, exchange, and reporting shall insofar as is reasonably possible conform to up-to-date technology and coordinate its information functions with the appropriate repository of records.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>IV</num>
    <heading>Powers and duties of the Interstate Commission.</heading>
    <text>The Interstate Commission shall have the power and duty to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Provide for dispute resolution among the compacting states;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Promulgate rules to effect the purposes and obligations enumerated in the compact, which shall have the force and effect of statutory law and shall be binding in the compacting states to the extent and in the manner provided in this compact;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Oversee, supervise, and coordinate the interstate movement of juveniles, subject to the terms of this compact and any bylaws adopted and rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Enforce compliance with the compact provisions, the rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission, and the bylaws, using all necessary and proper means, including, but not limited to, the use of the judicial process;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Establish and maintain offices, which shall be located within one or more of the compacting states;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Purchase and maintain insurance and bonds;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Borrow, accept, hire, or contract for services of personnel;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(8)</num>
      <text>Establish and appoint committees and hire staff that it considers necessary to carry out its functions, including, but not limited to, an executive committee as required by Article III(f), which shall have the power to act on behalf of the Interstate Commission in carrying out the powers and duties set forth in this article;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(9)</num>
      <text>Elect or appoint officers, attorneys, employees, agents, and consultants, determine their qualifications, fix their compensation, and define their duties;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(10)</num>
      <text>Establish personnel policies and programs relating to, inter alia, conflicts of interest, rates of compensation, and qualifications of personnel;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(11)</num>
      <text>Accept and utilize and dispose of donations and grants of money, equipment, supplies, materials, and services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(12)</num>
      <text>Lease, purchase, accept contributions or donations of, or otherwise to own, hold, improve, or use any property, real, personal, or mixed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(13)</num>
      <text>Sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, abandon, or otherwise dispose of any property, real, personal, or mixed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(14)</num>
      <text>Establish a budget and make expenditures and levy dues as provided in Article VIII of this compact;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(15)</num>
      <text>Sue and be sued;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(16)</num>
      <text>Adopt a seal and bylaws to govern its management and operation;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(17)</num>
      <text>Report annually to the legislatures, governors, judiciary, and State Councils of the compacting states concerning its activities during the preceding year and any recommendations that it adopted;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(18)</num>
      <text>Coordinate education, training, and public awareness regarding the interstate movement of juveniles for officials involved in this activity;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(19)</num>
      <text>Establish uniform standards for the reporting, collecting, and exchanging of data;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(20)</num>
      <text>Maintain its corporate books and records in accordance with the bylaws; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(21)</num>
      <text>Perform any other functions as may be necessary or appropriate to achieve the purposes of this compact.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading>Organization and operation of the Interstate Commission.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Bylaws — The Interstate Commission shall, by a majority of the members present and voting, within 12 months after the first Interstate Commission meeting, adopt bylaws to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the compact, including, but not limited to:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Establishing the fiscal year of the Interstate Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Establishing an executive committee and any other committees as may be necessary;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Providing for the establishment of committees governing any general or specific delegation of any authority or function of the Interstate Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the Interstate Commission and ensuring reasonable notice of each meeting;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Establishing the titles and responsibilities of the officers of the Interstate Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(6)</num>
        <text>Providing a mechanism for concluding the operations of the Interstate Commission and the return of any surplus funds that may exist upon the termination of the compact after the payment or reserving of all of its debts and obligations;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(7)</num>
        <text>Providing start-up rules for the initial administration of the compact; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(8)</num>
        <text>Establishing standards and procedures for compliance and technical assistance in carrying out the compact.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Officers and staff — (1) The Interstate Commission shall, by a majority of the members, elect annually from among its members a chairperson and a vice chairperson, each of whom shall have the authority and duties as may be specified in the bylaws. The chairperson or, in the chairperson’s absence or disability, the vice-chairperson shall preside at all meetings of the Interstate Commission. These officers shall serve without compensation or remuneration from the Interstate Commission; provided that, subject to the availability of budgeted funds, these officers shall be reimbursed for any ordinary and necessary costs and expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties and responsibilities as officers of the Interstate Commission.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Interstate Commission shall, through its executive committee, appoint or retain an executive director for the period, term, conditions, and compensation as the Interstate Commission considers appropriate. The executive director shall serve as secretary to the Interstate Commission, but shall not be a member. The executive director shall hire and supervise such other staff as may be authorized by the Interstate Commission.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Qualified immunity, defense, and indemnification — (1) The Interstate Commission’s executive director and employees shall be immune from suit and liability, personally and in their official capacity, for any claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused or arising out of or relating to any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred, or that the person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred, within the scope of his or her Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that no such person shall be protected from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of any such person.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The liability of any commissioner, or the employee or agent of a commissioner, acting within the scope of the person’s employment or duties for acts, errors, or omissions occurring within the person’s state may not exceed the limits of liability set forth under the constitution and laws of that state for state officials, employees, and agents. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to protect any such person from suit or liability for any damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of any such person.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The Interstate Commission shall defend the executive director or the employees or representatives of the Interstate Commission and, subject to the approval of the Attorney General of the state represented by any commissioner of a compacting state, shall defend the commissioner or the commissioner’s representatives or employees in any civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of the person’s Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, or that the defendant had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of his or her Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional or willful and wanton misconduct on the part of such person.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The Interstate Commission shall indemnify and hold the commissioner of a compacting state, or the commissioner’s representatives or employees, or the Interstate Commission’s representatives or employees, harmless in the amount of any settlement or judgment obtained against the person arising out of any actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of his or her Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, or that the person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of his or her Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional or willful and wanton misconduct on the part of such person.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>VI</num>
    <heading>Rulemaking functions of the Interstate Commission.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall promulgate and publish rules to effectively and efficiently achieve the purposes of the compact.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Rulemaking shall occur pursuant to the criteria set forth in this article and the bylaws and rules adopted pursuant to this article. The rulemaking shall substantially conform to the principles of the Model State Administrative Procedures Act (1981 Act) (Uniform Laws Annotated, Vol. 15, p.1 (2000)), or such other administrative procedures act that the Interstate Commission considers appropriate, consistent with the due process requirements of the U.S. Constitution, as now or hereafter interpreted by the U.S. Supreme Court. All rules and amendments shall become binding as of the date specified, as published with the final version of the rule as approved by the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>When promulgating a rule, the Interstate Commission shall, at a minimum:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>Publish the proposed rule’s entire text stating the reason for the proposed rule;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Allow and invite any and all persons to submit written data, facts, opinions, and arguments, which shall be added to the record and be made publicly available;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Provide an opportunity for an informal hearing if petitioned by 10 or more persons; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>Promulgate a final rule and its effective date, if appropriate, based on input from state and local officials or other interested parties.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(1)</num>
        <text>The Interstate Commission shall allow, not later than 60 days after a rule is promulgated, any interested person to file a petition for judicial review of the rule in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the federal district court where the Interstate Commission’s principal office is located. If the court finds that the Interstate Commission’s action is not supported by substantial evidence in the rulemaking record, the court shall hold the rule unlawful and set it aside.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>For purposes of this subsection, evidence is substantial if it would be considered substantial evidence under the Model State Administrative Procedures Act.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(e)</num>
      <text>If a majority of the legislatures of the compacting states rejects a rule, those states may, by enactment of a statute or adoption of a resolution, using the same manner used to adopt the compact, cause that the rule shall have no further force and effect in any compacting state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(f)</num>
      <text>The existing rules governing the operation of the Interstate Compact on Juveniles superseded by this act shall be null and void 12 months after the first meeting of the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(g)</num>
      <text>Upon determination by the Interstate Commission that a state-of-emergency exists, it may promulgate an emergency rule, which shall become effective immediately upon adoption; provided, that the usual rulemaking procedures provided in this article shall be retroactively applied to the rule as soon as reasonably possible, but no later than 90 days after the effective date of the emergency rule.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>VII</num>
    <heading>Oversight, enforcement, and dispute resolution.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Oversight — (1) The Interstate Commission shall oversee the administration and operations of the interstate movement of juveniles subject to this compact in the compacting states and shall monitor such activities being administered in non-compacting states that may significantly affect compacting states.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The courts and executive agencies in each compacting state shall enforce this compact and shall take all actions necessary and appropriate to effectuate the compact’s purposes and intent. The provisions of this compact and the rules promulgated pursuant to this compact shall be received by all the judges, public officers, commissions, and departments of the state government as evidence of the authorized statute and administrative rules. All courts shall take judicial notice of the compact and the rules. The Interstate Commission shall be entitled to receive all service of process in any judicial or administrative proceeding in a compacting state pertaining to the subject matter of this compact that may affect the powers, responsibilities, or actions of the Interstate Commission and have standing to intervene in the proceeding for all purposes.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Dispute resolution — (1) The compacting states shall report to the Interstate Commission on all issues and activities necessary for the administration of the compact as well as on issues and activities pertaining to compliance with the provisions of the compact and its bylaws and rules.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The Interstate Commission shall attempt, upon the request of a compacting state, to resolve any dispute or other issue that is subject to the compact that may arise among compacting states or between compacting and non-compacting states. The Interstate Commission shall promulgate a rule providing for both mediation and binding dispute resolution for disputes among the compacting states.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The Interstate Commission, in the reasonable exercise of its discretion, shall enforce the provisions and rules of this compact using any or all means set forth in Article XI.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>VIII</num>
    <heading>Finance.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall pay or provide for the payment of the reasonable expenses of its establishment, organization, and ongoing activities.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall levy and collect an annual assessment from each compacting state to cover the cost of the internal operations and activities of the Interstate Commission and the cost of its staff that shall be in a total amount sufficient to cover the Interstate Commission’s annual budget as approved each year. The aggregate annual assessment shall be allocated based upon a formula to be determined by the Interstate Commission, which shall take into consideration the population of each compacting state and the volume of interstate movement of juveniles in each compacting state. The Interstate Commission shall promulgate a rule, which shall be binding on all compacting states, that governs the assessment.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall not incur any obligation of any kind prior to securing the funds adequate to meet the obligation or pledge the credit of any compacting state except by and with the authority of the compacting state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission shall keep an accurate account of all receipts and disbursements. The receipts and disbursements of the Interstate Commission shall be subject to the audit and accounting procedures established under its bylaws. All receipts and disbursements of funds handled by the Interstate Commission shall be audited yearly by a certified or licensed public accountant. The report of the audit shall be included in and become part of the annual report of the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>IX</num>
    <heading>The State Council.</heading>
    <text>“Each member state shall create a State Council for Interstate Juvenile Supervision. While each state may determine the membership of its own State Council, its membership must include at least one representative from the legislative, judicial, and executive branches of government and a victims’ group, and include the compact administrator, deputy compact administrator, or designee. Each compacting state retains the right to determine the qualifications of the compact administrator or deputy compact administrator. Each State Council will advise and may exercise oversight and advocacy concerning that state’s participation in Interstate Commission activities and duties as determined by that state, including, but not limited to, development of a policy concerning operations and procedures of the compact within that state.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>X</num>
    <heading>Compacting states, effective date, and amendment.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Any state as defined in Article II(12) is eligible to become a compacting state.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The compact shall become effective and binding upon legislative enactment of the compact into law by no less than 35 states. The initial effective date shall be the later of July 1, 2004, or enactment into law by the 35th state. Thereafter, it shall become effective and binding as to any other compacting state upon enactment of the compact into law by that state. The governors of non-member states, or their designees, shall be invited to participate in the activities of the Interstate Commission on a nonvoting basis prior to adoption of the compact by all states.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>The Interstate Commission may propose amendments to the compact for enactment by the compacting states. No amendment shall become effective and binding upon the Interstate Commission and the compacting states until it is enacted into law by unanimous consent of the compacting states.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>XI</num>
    <heading>Withdrawal, default, termination, and judicial enforcement.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Withdrawal — (1) Once effective, the compact shall continue in force and remain binding upon each compacting state; provided, that a compacting state may withdraw from the compact by specifically repealing the statute that enacted the compact into law.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>The effective date of withdrawal is the effective date of the repeal.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>The withdrawing state shall immediately notify the chairperson of the Interstate Commission in writing upon the introduction of legislation repealing this compact in the withdrawing state. The Interstate Commission shall notify the other compacting states of the withdrawing state’s intent to withdraw within 60 days of its receipt of the notice.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>The withdrawing state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of withdrawal, including any obligations, the performance of which extend beyond the effective date of withdrawal.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(5)</num>
        <text>Reinstatement following withdrawal of any compacting state shall occur upon the withdrawing state reenacting the compact or upon such later date as determined by the Interstate Commission.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Technical assistance, fines, suspension, termination, and default — (1) If the Interstate Commission determines that any compacting state has at any time defaulted in the performance of any of its obligations or responsibilities under this compact, or the bylaws or rules, the Interstate Commission may impose any or all of the following penalties:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Remedial training and technical assistance as directed by the Interstate Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Alternative dispute resolution;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Fines, fees, and costs in amounts considered reasonable and fixed by the Interstate Commission; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Suspension or termination of membership in the compact, which shall be imposed only after all other reasonable means of securing compliance under the bylaws or rules have been exhausted and the Interstate Commission has determined that the offending state is in default.</text>
        <para>
          <num>(2)</num>
          <text>Immediate notice of suspension shall be given by the Interstate Commission to the Governor, the Chief Justice or the Chief Judicial Officer of the state, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature, and the State Council.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(3)</num>
          <text>The grounds for default include, but are not limited to, failure of a compacting state to perform the obligations or responsibilities imposed upon it by this compact, the bylaws, or rules, and any other grounds designated in the Interstate Commission’s bylaws and rules.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(4)</num>
          <text>The Interstate Commission shall immediately notify the defaulting state in writing of the penalty imposed by the Interstate Commission and of the default, pending a cure of the default. The Interstate Commission shall specify the conditions and the time period within which the defaulting state must cure its default. If the defaulting state fails to cure the default within the time period specified by the Interstate Commission, the defaulting state shall be terminated from the compact upon an affirmative vote of a majority of the compacting states, and all rights, privileges, and benefits conferred by this compact shall be terminated upon the effective date of termination.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(5)</num>
          <text>Within 60 days of the effective date of termination of a defaulting state, the Interstate Commission shall notify the Governor, the Chief Justice or Chief Judicial Officer, the majority and minority leaders of the defaulting state’s legislature, and the State Council of the termination.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(6)</num>
          <text>The defaulting state is responsible for all assessments, obligations, and liabilities incurred through the effective date of termination, including any obligations, the performance of which extends beyond the effective date of termination.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(7)</num>
          <text>The Interstate Commission shall not bear any costs relating to the defaulting state unless otherwise agreed upon in writing between the Interstate Commission and the defaulting state.</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(8)</num>
          <text>Reinstatement following termination of any compacting state requires both a reenactment of the compact by the defaulting state and the approval of the Interstate Commission pursuant to the rules.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(c)</num>
      <text>Judicial enforcement — The Interstate Commission may, by majority vote of the members, initiate legal action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or, at the discretion of the Interstate Commission, in the federal district where the Interstate Commission has its offices to enforce compliance with the provisions of the compact, its rules, or bylaws against any compacting state in default. If judicial enforcement is necessary, the prevailing party shall be awarded all the costs of litigation, including reasonable attorney fees.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(d)</num>
      <text>Dissolution of the compact — (1) The compact dissolves effective upon the date of the withdrawal or default of the compacting state that reduces membership in the compact to one compacting state.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>Upon the dissolution of this compact, the compact becomes null and void and shall be of no further force or effect, and the business and affairs of the Interstate Commission shall be concluded and any surplus funds shall be distributed in accordance with the bylaws.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>XII</num>
    <heading>Severability and construction.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>The provisions of this compact shall be severable. If any phrase, clause, sentence, or provision is deemed unenforceable, the remaining provisions of the compact shall be enforceable.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>The provisions of this compact shall be liberally construed to effectuate its purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <prefix>Article</prefix>
    <num>XIII</num>
    <heading>Binding effect of compact and other laws.</heading>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>Other Laws — (1) Nothing in this compact shall prevent the enforcement of any other law of a compacting state that is not inconsistent with this compact.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>All compacting states’ laws other than state constitutions and other interstate compacts conflicting with this compact are superseded to the extent of the conflict.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>Binding effect of the compact — (1) All lawful actions of the Interstate Commission, including all rules and bylaws promulgated by the Interstate Commission, are binding upon the compacting states.</text>
      <para>
        <num>(2)</num>
        <text>All agreements between the Interstate Commission and the compacting states are binding in accordance with their terms.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(3)</num>
        <text>Upon the request of a party to a conflict over the meaning or interpretation of an Interstate Commission action and a majority vote of the compacting states, the Interstate Commission may issue advisory opinions regarding the meaning or interpretation.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(4)</num>
        <text>In the event any provision of this compact exceeds the constitutional limits imposed on the legislature of any compacting state, the obligation, duty, power, or jurisdiction sought to be conferred by the provision upon the Interstate Commission shall be ineffective and the obligation, duty, power, or jurisdiction shall remain in the compacting state and shall be exercised by the agency of the compacting state to which the obligation, duty, power, or jurisdiction are delegated by law in effect at the time this compact becomes effective.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358" type="History" path="§402">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 658, Pub. L. 91-358, title IV, § 402</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-264" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-264, § 35, 46 DCR 2118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-81" type="History">Jan. 19, 2012, D.C. Law 19-81, § 2, 58 DCR 8911</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 32-1102.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 32-1102.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-81">D.C. Law 19-81</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-362">D.C. Law 18-362</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-362">D.C. Law 18-362</cite> provides that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Interstate Compact for Juveniles Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-695, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 700).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Interstate Compact for Juveniles Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2011 (D.C. Act 19-49, April 27, 2011,  58 DCR 3859).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Interstate Compact for Juveniles Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-294, January 20, 2012,  59 DCR 474).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
