<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-111</num>
  <heading>Truth in sentencing commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <heading>Establishment. —</heading>
    <text>There is established as an independent agency of the District of Columbia a District of Columbia Truth in Sentencing Commission (hereafter in this chapter referred to as “the Commission”), which shall consist of 7 voting members. The Attorney General, or the Attorney General’s designee, shall be the chairperson of the Commission and shall have the duty to convene meetings of the Commission to ensure that it fulfills its responsibilities under this Act. The members shall serve for the life of the Commission and shall be subject to removal only for neglect of duty, malfeasance in office, or other good cause shown.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <heading>Membership. —</heading>
    <text>The members of the Commission shall have knowledge and responsibility with respect to criminal justice matters. Two members of the Commission shall be judges of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia, and shall be appointed by the chief judge of that court; one member shall be a representative of the District of Columbia Council and shall be appointed by the chairperson or chairperson pro temp of the Council; one member shall be a representative of the executive branch of the District of Columbia government with official responsibilities for criminal justice matters in the District of Columbia and shall be appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia; one member shall be a representative of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service and shall be appointed by the Director of such Service; and one member shall be a representative of the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia and shall be appointed by the United States Attorney. A representative of the Federal Bureau of Prisons and a representative of the office of Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia shall each serve as a nonvoting, ex officio member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <heading>Vacancy. —</heading>
    <text>Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. Members of the Commission shall receive no compensation for their services, but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of duties vested in the Commission, but not in excess of the maximum amounts authorized under section 456 of title 28, United States Code.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 740, Pub. L. 105-33, § 11211</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§24-101">24-101</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-1211.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">“This Act,” referred to in (a), is the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, title XI of Pub. L. 105-33, 111 Stat. 712.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
