<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-251.02</num>
  <heading>Authority to grant furloughs.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia, or his designated agent, may grant a resocialization furlough to any eligible resident for the purposes specified in this subchapter and according to the procedures provided for in this subchapter. The decision to grant or deny a furlough shall not be made on the basis of rewarding a resident for good behavior nor for punishing misbehavior. Furloughs shall not be used to shorten sentences; any resident furloughed shall be considered, while on furlough, to still be in custody, and time spent on furlough shall be credited toward the remainder of his sentence.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, an eligible resident shall be any resident who:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Has attained minimum custody status;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Has demonstrated responsible attitudes and behavior in the institution or facility so that there is reasonable assurance that he will comply fully with the conditions of the furlough;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Has received, where applicable, a favorable recommendation by the appropriate committee; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Is mentally, physically, and financially capable of completing the furlough without escort or assistance from any officer or employee of the Department after his release from the institution or facility.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any individual who is incarcerated in any institution or facility operated by the Department after being convicted of having violated either § <cite path="§22-2101">22-2101</cite> (relating to first degree murder), § <cite path="§22-2102">22-2102</cite> (relating to first degree murder), or § <cite path="§22-2103">22-2103</cite> (relating to second degree murder), § <cite path="§22-4801">22-4801</cite> [repealed] (relating to rape), or § <cite path="§22-3801">22-3801</cite> [repealed] (relating to indecent acts with a minor) shall not be eligible for any furlough under the provisions of this subchapter, except where such individual is within 12 months of a firm release date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any eligible resident who is within 12 months of a firm release date or who is participating in an approved work training or higher education program may be considered for 1 furlough per month. All other eligible residents may be considered for 1 furlough every 3 months.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-130" type="History" path="§3">Apr. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 1-130, § 3, 23 DCR 9694</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-482.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-482.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
