<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-201.17</num>
  <heading>Execution of judgments in capital cases; failure to make specific appropriation not abolition of position.</heading>
  <text>The Superintendent of the Washington Asylum and Jail appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia is hereby directed, authorized, and required to execute the judgments of the law prior to March 4, 1923, pronounced and thereafter to be pronounced in the District of Columbia by the courts thereof in all capital cases, and the power prior to March 4, 1923, given to and now vested in such Mayor to appoint such Superintendent and all appointments to the position of such Superintendent made by such Mayor are hereby ratified and confirmed; and any failure on the part of Congress, either prior to or after March 4, 1923, to make a specific appropriation for the salary or compensation of such Superintendent shall not be construed either as an abolition of such position of Superintendent of the Washington Asylum and Jail or as a repeal of the power and authority of such Mayor to appoint such Superintendent.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 4, 1923, 42 Stat. 1533, ch. 292</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-417.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-417.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
