<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-251.05</num>
  <heading>Records and reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Residents being released on furlough shall be reported as “furloughed” on appropriate Departmental records and statistical forms, identifying such movement as a furlough. Because time spent on furlough is creditable toward the service of a sentence, such status will not preclude the earning of good time or pay.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Each caseworker or counselor assigned to handle a furloughed resident will, upon the completion of each such furlough, prepare a brief report to include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and Department number of the furloughed resident to whom the report relates;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the furlough being completed;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A statement of the results of the furlough, including an explanation of any unusual circumstances or events;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The reporter’s assessment of the circumstances or events in relation to the resident’s correctional goals; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The dates of any previous furloughs granted, including the one to which the report relates.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Copies of all executed furlough release authorization forms shall be kept in the office of the Administrator. Within 5 calendar days before the beginning of each month, the information on these forms (in digested form) will be reported to the designee of the Director. These reports will include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The name and Department number of each resident who has been granted a furlough during the reporting period;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Sentence data relating to such resident, including his earliest release date;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The purpose of the furlough;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The beginning and ending dates of the furlough;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>The name of the officer authorizing the furlough;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>The number of furloughs previously granted to such resident; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>The total number of furloughs granted to all residents during the reporting period.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 1-130" type="History">Apr. 23, 1977, D.C. Law 1-130, § 6, 23 DCR 9694</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-485.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-485.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
