<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-211.06</num>
  <heading>Charge against United States for care of convicts.</heading>
  <text>The cost of the care and custody of persons confined in the said institutions charged with or convicted of offenses under any law of the United States not applicable exclusively to the District of Columbia shall be charged against the department or agency of the United States primarily responsible for the care and custody of such persons in quarterly accounts to be rendered by the Director of the Department of Finance and Revenue. The amount to be charged for such care and custody shall be ascertained by multiplying the average daily number of such persons so confined during the quarter by the per capita cost for the same quarter for all prisoners in the institution where confined, excluding expenses of construction or extraordinary repair of buildings. The sum so derived shall be credited to the current appropriation for the maintenance and operation of such institutions.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 27, 1946, 60 Stat. 321, ch. 507, § 6</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-446.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-446.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition of section, see § 2 of Immigration Detainer Compliance Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-379, June 15, 2012,  59 DCR 7383).</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Pursuant to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer’s “Notice of Public Interest” published in the April 18, 1997, issue of the District of Columbia Register ( 44 DCR 2345) the Office of Tax and Revenue assumed all of the duties and functions previously performed by the Department of Finance and Revenue, as set forth in Commissioner’s Order 69-96, dated March 7, 1969. This action was made effective January 22, 1997, nunc pro tunc.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
