<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-201.27</num>
  <heading>Rewards.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor of the District of Columbia, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Council of the District of Columbia, is authorized to provide for the payment of rewards for the capture, or for information leading to the apprehension, of fugitives from District of Columbia penal, correctional, and welfare institutions and of conditional release and parole violators. Funds appropriated pursuant to this section shall be apportioned and expended in the discretion of, and upon such conditions as may be imposed by, the Mayor of the District of Columbia. No reward money shall be paid to any officer or employee of the Metropolitan Police Department, or of any penal, correctional, or welfare institution, or of any court, legal agency, or other agency closely involved in the criminal justice system.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 93-140" type="History" path="§11">Oct. 26, 1973, 87 Stat. 506, Pub. L. 93-140, § 11</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to the District of Columbia Council and to a Commissioner of the District of Columbia. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-426.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-426.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
