<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-201.71</num>
  <heading>Central Detention Facility requirements.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The number of inmates housed at any one time in the Central Detention Facility shall not exceed the number of persons established by an independent consultant pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 90 days of January 30, 2004, the Mayor shall develop and submit to the Council for a 30-day period of review, excluding days of Council recess, a plan for establishing the maximum number of inmates that can be housed at any one time within the Central Detention Facility.  The plan shall consist of a contract with an independent consultant, who, upon approval of the plan by the Council, will determine the maximum number of inmates that can be housed at any one time within the Central Detention Facility based upon physical capacity, programming, classification system, and housing plan of the Central Detention Facility.  If the Council does not approve or disapprove the plan, by resolution, within the 30-day period, the plan shall be deemed disapproved.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish, by rule, the maximum number of inmates to be housed at any one time in the Central Detention Facility.  The maximum number shall be determined by an independent consultant contracted with by the Mayor pursuant to the plan approved under subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>One year following implementation of the population ceiling pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Mayor shall evaluate the results of the Central Detention Facility classification system, housing plan, and population ceiling, and shall propose modifications, if necessary.  A copy of the evaluation shall be forwarded to the Council.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Department of Corrections shall obtain accreditation by the American Correctional Association for the Central Detention Facility within 4 years of January 30, 2004, and shall meet all American Correctional Association requirements for recertification of the facility.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Within 210 days of January 30, 2004, the Mayor shall forward to the Council an implementation plan by which the Department shall achieve accreditation for the Central Detention Facility by the American Correctional Association.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-62" type="History">Jan. 30, 2004, D.C. Law 15-62, § 5, 50 DCR 6574</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) Central Detention facility requirements, see § 4 of Jail Improvement Emergency Amendment Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-188, October 24, 2003,  50 DCR 9495).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of Authority Pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 16-62">D.C. Law 16-62</cite>, the District of Columbia Hail Improvement Amendment Act of 2003, see Mayor’s Order 2006-53, May 9, 2006 ( 53 DCR 5305).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Resolutions">Resolution 15-484, the “Central Detention Facility Plan Emergency Approval Resolution of 2004”, was approved March 2, 2004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 8 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 15-62">D.C. Law 15-62</cite> provided: “Sec. 8. Applicability. Section 5(a) shall apply 210 days after the effective date of this act.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
