<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-261.03</num>
  <heading>Inmates confined to CTF.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An inmate confined in the CTF shall be deemed to be at all times in the legal custody of the Department of Corrections. Only the Department of Corrections shall have authority to transfer or assign inmates into or out of the CTF. All laws and regulations governing conduct of inmates, including, without limitation, Title 22 of the District of Columbia Official Code, shall apply to inmates confined to the CTF during such time as the CTF is operated by a private operator. All laws and regulations establishing penalties for offenses committed against correctional officers or other correctional employees, including, without limitation, the penalties provided for in § <cite path="§22-405">22-405</cite>, shall apply mutatis mutandis to offenses committed against any private correctional officer or other employee of the private operator.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An inmate confined in any privately-operated prison facility established pursuant to Subtitle C of the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997, approved August 5, 1997 (P.L. 105-33; 111 Stat. 712), shall be deemed to be at all times in the legal custody of the Federal Bureau of Prisons. Only the Federal Bureau of Prisons shall have authority to transfer or assign inmates into or out of the privately-operated prison facility. All laws and regulations governing conduct of inmates in Federal Bureau of Prisons facilities shall apply to inmates confined in any privately-operated prison facility during such time as the prison facility is operated by a private operator. All laws and regulations establishing penalties for offenses committed against correctional officers or other correctional employees shall apply wherever applicable to offenses committed against any private correctional officer or other employee of the private operator.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-276" type="History" path="§4">June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-276, § 4, 44 DCR 1416</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-281" type="History">May 28, 1999, D.C. Law 12-281, § 2(f), 45 DCR 7991</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(c) of the Correctional Treatment Facility Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-315, March 31, 1998,  45 DCR 2126), § 2(c) of the Correctional Treatment Facility Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-388, June 29, 1998,  45 DCR 4625), and § 2(f) of the Correctional Treatment Facility Firearms Registration and Health Occupations Licensing Emergency Amendment Act of 1998 (D.C. Act 12-442, September 3, 1998,  45 DCR 6517).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-164">D.C. Law 12-164</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-164">D.C. Law 12-164</cite> added (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-495.3.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
