<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-211.07</num>
  <heading>District compliance with federal immigration detainers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District of Columbia is authorized to comply with civil detainer requests from United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (“ICE”) by holding inmates for an additional 24-hour period, excluding weekends and holidays, after they would otherwise be released, but only in accordance with the requirements set forth in subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon written request by an ICE agent to detain a District of Columbia inmate for suspected violations of federal civil immigration law, the District shall exercise discretion regarding whether to comply with the request and may comply only if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There exists a prior written agreement with the federal government by which all costs incurred by the District in complying with the ICE detainer shall be reimbursed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The individual sought to be detained:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Is 18 years of age or older; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has been convicted of:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>A dangerous crime as defined in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(3) or a crime of violence as defined in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(4), for which he or she is currently in custody;</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>A dangerous crime as defined in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(3) or a crime of violence as defined in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(4) within 10 years of the detainer request, or was released after having served a sentence for such dangerous crime or crime of violence within 5 years of the request, whichever is later; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(iii)</num>
          <text>A crime in another jurisdiction which if committed in the District of Columbia would qualify as an offense listed in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(3) or (4); provided, that the conviction occurred within 10 years of the detainer request or the individual was released after having served a sentence for such crime within 5 years of the request, whichever is later.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (b)(2)(B)(ii) and (iii) of this section, a detainer request for an individual who has been convicted of a homicide crime, pursuant to § <cite path="§22-2101">22-2101</cite> et seq., or a crime in another jurisdiction which if committed in the District of Columbia would qualify as a homicide crime, may be honored regardless of when the conviction occurred.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The District shall not provide to any ICE agent an office, booth, or any facility or equipment for a generalized search of or inquiry about inmates or permit an ICE agent to conduct an individualized interview of an inmate without giving the inmate an opportunity to have counsel present.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>This subsection shall not be construed to establish a right to counsel that does not otherwise exist in law.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 27, 1946, ch. 507, § 7</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-194" type="History">as added Dec. 11, 2012, D.C. Law 19-194, § 2, 59 DCR 10153</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-194">D.C. Law 19-194</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of section, see § 2 of the Immigration Detainer Compliance Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-475, October 9, 2012,  59 DCR 12098), applicable as of September 13, 2012.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Former § <cite path="§24-211.07">24-211.07</cite> was omitted from this part.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
