<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-241.01</num>
  <heading>Authority granted to establish program.</heading>
  <text>There is hereby authorized to be established in the District of Columbia a work release program under which any person who is: (1) convicted of a misdemeanor or of violating a municipal regulation or an act of Congress in the nature of a municipal regulation, and is sentenced to serve in a penal institution a term of 1 year or less; (2) imprisoned for nonpayment of a fine, or for contempt of court; or (3) committed to jail after revocation of probation pursuant to § <cite path="§24-304">24-304</cite>, may, whenever the judge of the sentencing court is satisfied that the ends of justice and the best interests of society as well as of such person would be subserved thereby or whenever after service by the person of 1/3 of his or her sentence, the Board of Parole is satisfied that the ends of justice and the best interests of society as well as of the sentenced person would be served thereby, be granted the privilege of a work release for the purpose of working at his employment or seeking employment. Such a work release privilege may also be granted, in the discretion of the sentencing court or the Director of the Department of Corrections, whenever there exist such special circumstances as merit the granting of the privilege. As used in this subchapter, the word “sentence” and its derivatives shall be construed to include sentencing, imprisonment, and commitment as referred to in this section.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 89-803" type="History" path="§2">Nov. 10, 1966, 80 Stat. 1519, Pub. L. 89-803, § 2</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-202" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-202, § 5, 30 DCR 173</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-273" type="History">June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-273, § 4(a), 43 DCR 6168</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 4(a) of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-390, August 26, 1996,  43 DCR 4986), § 4(a) of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Congressional Adjournment Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-436, December 4, 1996,  43 DCR 6651), and § 4(a) of the Zero Tolerance for Guns Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-35, March 11, 1997,  44 DCR 1928).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-461.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-461.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§24-241.02">24-241.02</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
