<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-306</num>
  <heading>Psychiatric services.</heading>
  <text>The Mayor shall appoint a qualified psychiatrist and a qualified psychologist whose services shall be available to the following officers to assist them in carrying out their duties:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>In criminal cases, the judges and probation officers of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia and the judges and Director of Social Services of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The judges and such personnel assigned to the Family Division of the Superior Court as the Chief Judge may designate;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>Such officers of the Department of Corrections as the Director thereof shall designate; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The Board of Parole of the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>June 29, 1953, 67 Stat. 105, ch. 159, § 405</annotation>
      <annotation>Aug. 16, 1954, 68 Stat. 730, ch. 737, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-60">July 8, 1963, 77 Stat. 77, Pub. L. 88-60, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation doc="Pub. L. 91-358">July 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 577, Pub. L. 91-358, title I, § 159(d)</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-275">June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-275, § 15, 44 DCR 1408</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Board of Parole, creation, powers and duties, see §§ <cite path="§24-401.01">24-401.01</cite> to 24-401.03.</annotation>
      <annotation>Confinement in mental hospital while in penal institution, see § <cite path="§24-502">24-502</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Department of Corrections, see §§ <cite path="§24-211.011">24-211.011</cite> to 24-211.06.</annotation>
      <annotation>Investigations and reports by probation officers, see § <cite path="§24-303">24-303</cite>.</annotation>
      <annotation>Physical and mental examinations and treatment of child, see § <cite path="§16-2315">16-2315</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§24-502">24-502</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 24-106.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 24-106.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
      <annotation>This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
