<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-461</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Geriatric inmate” means a person 65 years of age or older convicted of a violation of a District of Columbia criminal law by a court in the District of Columbia, who suffers from a chronic infirmity, illness, or disease related to aging, and poses a low risk to the community;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Permanently incapacitated inmate” means a person convicted of a violation of a District of Columbia criminal law by a court in the District of Columbia and who, by reason of an existing physical or medical condition which is not terminal, is permanently and irreversibly physically incapacitated, and who does not constitute a danger to himself or to society; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Terminally ill inmate” means a person convicted of a violation of the District of Columbia criminal law by a court in the District of Columbia who has an incurable condition caused by illness or disease which would, within reasonable medical judgment, produce death within 6 months and does not constitute a danger to himself or to society.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-271" type="History" path="§2">May 15, 1993, D.C. Law 9-271, § 2, 40 DCR 792</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-275" type="History">June 3, 1997, D.C. Law 11-275, § 16, 44 DCR 1408</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§24-462">24-462</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-261.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-261.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
