<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>24-531.06</num>
  <heading>Court hearings during and after treatment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Court shall hold a prompt hearing, with reasonable notice of such hearing given to the prosecuting attorney, the defendant, and the defendant’s attorney of record, and make a new finding as to the defendant’s competence when:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Any period of treatment ordered under § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(b), (c), or (e) is completed; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The treatment provider reports to the court that reasonable grounds exist to believe that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>An incompetent defendant has attained competence;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>There is no longer a substantial probability that a defendant will attain competence during the allowable treatment period;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>If the defendant is committed to an inpatient treatment facility, such commitment is no longer the least restrictive setting considering the factors in § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(a); or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>If the defendant has been ordered to undergo competence treatment on an outpatient basis, such a setting is no longer appropriate considering the factors in § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(a).</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In advance of any hearing held pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the treatment provider shall submit a written report to the court addressing:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The defendant’s competence, including any progress or lack thereof made toward attaining competence;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Whether there is a substantial probability that the defendant will attain competence during the foreseeable future, or make substantial progress toward that goal;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the defendant is committed to an inpatient facility, whether such commitment remains the least restrictive setting considering the factors in § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(a); and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the defendant has been ordered to undergo treatment on an outpatient basis, whether such a setting is no longer appropriate considering the factors in § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>At the conclusion of a hearing held pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the court shall:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Find that the defendant is competent; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Find that the defendant is incompetent and:</text>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>There is a substantial probability that the defendant will attain competence or make substantial progress toward that goal with an additional period of time; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>There is no substantial probability that he or she will attain competence or make substantial progress toward that goal in the foreseeable future.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>If the court finds the defendant is competent, it shall order the criminal case or transfer proceeding to be resumed.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>If the court finds the defendant is incompetent pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(i) of this subsection, the court shall order treatment for an additional period of time in accordance with § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(b), (c), or (e), after making a finding as to the least restrictive placement for treatment pursuant to § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(a).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>If the court finds the defendant is incompetent pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(ii) of this subsection, the court shall either order the release of the defendant or, where appropriate, enter an order for treatment pursuant to § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>(a) for up to 30 days pending the filing of a petition for civil commitment pursuant to subchapter IV of Chapter 5 of Title 21 or subchapter IV of Chapter 13 of Title 7. The court also may order treatment pursuant to § <cite path="§24-531.07">24-531.07</cite>(a)(2) for such period as is necessary for the completion of the civil commitment proceedings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-358" type="History">May 24, 2005, D.C. Law 15-358, § 106, 52 DCR 2015</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§24-531.04">24-531.04</cite>, § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>, § <cite path="§24-531.07">24-531.07</cite>, and § <cite path="§24-531.09">24-531.09</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
