<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-531.08</num>
  <heading>Dismissal.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If a defendant charged with any offense other than a crime of violence, as defined in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(4), does not attain competence within 180 days of an order for treatment pursuant to § <cite path="§24-531.05">24-531.05</cite>, the charge shall be dismissed without prejudice upon:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The completion of civil commitment proceedings, if a petition for commitment was filed; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A determination by the court that the time within which the government must file a petition for civil commitment has expired and a petition for civil commitment has not been filed.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a defendant charged with a crime of violence, as defined in § <cite path="§23-1331">23-1331</cite>(4), except murder, first degree sexual abuse, or first degree child sexual abuse, has not attained competence within 5 years of the initial order for treatment pursuant to § <cite path="§24-531.04">24-531.04</cite>, the charge shall be dismissed without prejudice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Any charge dismissed pursuant to subsection (a) or (b) of this section may be refiled if, at any time within the statute of limitations, the defendant attains competence; provided, that a defendant may not be arrested or detained on such a charge unless a court has found that the defendant is competent.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Nothing in this section shall preclude the prosecutor or the defendant from moving to dismiss a case at an earlier time on any appropriate grounds.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-358">May 24, 2005, D.C. Law 15-358, § 108, 52 DCR 2015</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
