<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-707</num>
  <heading>Hearing.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Upon the evidence introduced at a hearing held for that purpose the court shall determine whether the patient is a drug user. The hearing shall be conducted without a jury unless, before such hearing and within 5 days after the date on which the petition is filed pursuant to § <cite path="§24-705">24-705</cite>, a jury is demanded by the patient or by the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia. Each patient concerning whom a report is filed shall be detained at such place as the Mayor may designate until the completion of such hearing or until released as provided in § <cite path="§24-705">24-705</cite>(b).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The rules of evidence applicable in civil judicial proceedings shall be applicable to hearings pursuant to this section, including the right of the patient to present evidence in his own behalf and to subpoena and cross-examine witnesses. However, no patient examined pursuant to the provisions of §§ <cite path="§24-701">24-701</cite> to 24-711, shall be permitted at any hearing order pursuant to this section to object to the submission of testimony concerning such examination on the ground of privilege.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">June 24, 1953, 67 Stat. 78, ch. 149, § 8</annotation>
    <annotation type="History">July 24, 1956, 70 Stat. 610, ch. 676, title I, § 101</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§24-704">24-704</cite> and § <cite path="§24-706">24-706</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-607.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 24-607.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 401 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to a single Commissioner. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
