<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>24-902</num>
  <heading>Facilities for treatment and rehabilitation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall provide facilities and personnel for the treatment and rehabilitation of youth offenders convicted of misdemeanor offenses under District of Columbia law and sentenced according to this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall periodically set aside and adapt facilities for the treatment, care, education, vocational training, rehabilitation, segregation, and protection of youth offenders convicted of misdemeanor offenses.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Insofar as practical, these institutions maintained by the District of Columbia shall treat committed youth offenders convicted of misdemeanor offenses only, and the youth offenders shall be segregated from other offenders, and classes of committed youth offenders shall be segregated according to their needs for treatment.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Federal Bureau of Prisons is authorized to provide for the custody, care, subsistence, education, treatment, and training of youth offenders convicted of felony offenses and sentenced to commitment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-69" type="History">Dec. 7, 1985, D.C. Law 6-69, § 3, 32 DCR 4587</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-302" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-302, § 9(b), 47 DCR 7249</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 24-802.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 13-302">D.C. Law 13-302</cite> rewrote the section which had read:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(a) The Mayor shall provide facilities and personnel for the treatment and rehabilitation of youth offenders convicted under District of Columbia law and sentenced according to this subchapter.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(b)(1) The Mayor shall periodically set aside and adapt facilities for the treatment, care, education, vocational training, rehabilitation, segregation, and protection of youth offenders.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">“(2) Insofar as practical, these institutions shall treat committed youth offenders only, and the youth offenders shall be segregated from other offenders, and classes of committed youth offenders shall be segregated according to their needs for treatment.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90-day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of the Sentencing Reform Emergency Amendment Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-410, August 11, 2000,  47 DCR 7271).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of the Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 13-462, November 7, 2000,  47 DCR 9443).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of Sentencing Reform Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-2, February 2, 2001,  48 DCR 2239).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 9(b) of Sentencing Reform Second Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2001 (D.C. Act 14-51, May 2, 2001,  48 DCR 4370).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
