<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>49-1101.05</num>
  <heading>Educational records and enrollment.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If official educational records cannot be released to the parents of a student for the purpose of transfer, the custodian of the records in the sending state shall prepare and furnish to the parent a complete set of unofficial educational records containing uniform information as determined by the Interstate Commission. Upon receipt of the unofficial educational records by a school in the receiving state, the school shall enroll and appropriately place the student based on the information provided in the unofficial records, pending validation by the official records, as quickly as possible.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Simultaneous with the enrollment and conditional placement of the student, the school in the receiving state shall request the student’s official educational record from the school in the sending state. Upon receipt of this request, the school in the sending state will process and furnish the official educational record to the school in the receiving state within 10 days or within such time as is reasonably established under the rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Compacting states shall give students 30 days from the date of enrollment, or such time as is reasonably established under the rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission, to obtain any immunizations required by the receiving state. For a series of immunizations, initial vaccinations must be obtained within 30 days, or within such time as is reasonably established under the rules promulgated by the Interstate Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Students shall be allowed to continue their enrollment at the grade level in the receiving state commensurate with their grade level (including kindergarten) from a local education agency in the sending state at the time of transition, regardless of age. A student that has satisfactorily completed the prerequisite grade level in the local education agency in the sending state shall be eligible for enrollment in the next highest grade level in the receiving state, regardless of age. A student transferring after the start of the school year in the receiving state shall enter the school in the receiving state on his or her validated level from an accredited school in the sending state.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-304">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-304, § 6, 60 DCR 2717</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
