<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>49-1101.11</num>
  <heading>Organization and operation of the Interstate Commission.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Interstate Commission shall, by a majority of the members present and voting, within 12 months after the first Interstate Commission meeting, adopt bylaws to govern its conduct as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the compact, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Establishing the fiscal year of the Interstate Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Establishing an executive committee, and such other committees as may be necessary;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Providing for the establishment of committees and for governing any general or specific delegation of authority or function of the Interstate Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Providing reasonable procedures for calling and conducting meetings of the Interstate Commission, and ensuring reasonable notice of each such meeting;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Establishing the titles and responsibilities of the officers and staff of the Interstate Commission;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Providing a mechanism for concluding the operations of the Interstate Commission and the return of surplus funds that may exist upon the termination of the compact after the payment of, and the reservation of funds for payment of, all of its debts and obligations; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Providing start-up rules for the initial administration of the compact.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Interstate Commission shall, by a majority of the members, elect annually from among its members a chairperson, a vice-chairperson, and a treasurer, each of whom shall have such authority and duties as may be specified in the bylaws. The chairperson or, in the chairperson’s absence or disability, the vice-chairperson, shall preside at all meetings of the Interstate Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The officers elected pursuant to subsection (b) of this section shall serve without compensation or remuneration from the Interstate Commission; provided, that, subject to the availability of budgeted funds, the officers shall be reimbursed for ordinary and necessary costs and expenses incurred in the performance of their responsibilities as officers of the Interstate Commission.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The executive committee shall have such authority and duties as may be set forth in the bylaws, which shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Managing the affairs of the Interstate Commission in a manner consistent with the bylaws and purposes of the Interstate Commission;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Overseeing an organizational structure and appropriate procedures for the Interstate Commission to provide for the creation of rules, operating procedures, and administrative and technical support functions; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Planning, implementing, and coordinating communications and activities with other state, federal, and local government organizations to advance the goals of the Interstate Commission.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The executive committee may, subject to the approval of the Interstate Commission, appoint or retain an executive director for such period, upon such terms and conditions, and for such compensation as the Interstate Commission considers appropriate.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The executive director shall serve as secretary to the Interstate Commission, but shall not be a member of the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The executive director shall hire and supervise such other persons as may be authorized by the Interstate Commission.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Interstate Commission’s executive director and its employees shall be immune from suit and liability, either personally or in their official capacity, for a claim for damage to or loss of property or personal injury or other civil liability caused or arising out of or relating to an actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred, or that such person had a reasonable basis for believing occurred, within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that such person shall not be protected from suit or liability for damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of such person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The liability of the Interstate Commission’s executive director and its employees or Interstate Commission representatives, acting within the scope of their employment or duties for acts, errors, or omissions occurring within such person’s state may not exceed the limits of liability set forth under the laws of that state for state officials, employees, and agents. The Interstate Commission is considered to be an instrumentality of the states for the purposes of any such action.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to protect such person from suit or liability for damage, loss, injury, or liability caused by the intentional or willful and wanton misconduct of such person.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The Interstate Commission shall defend the executive director and its employees, and, subject to the approval of the Attorney General or other appropriate legal counsel of the member state represented by an Interstate Commission representative, such Interstate Commission representative in any civil action seeking to impose liability arising out of an actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, or that the defendant had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional or willful and wanton misconduct on the part of such person.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>To the extent not covered by the state involved, member state, or the Interstate Commission, the representatives or employees of the Interstate Commission shall be held harmless in the amount of a settlement or judgment, including attorney’s fees and costs, obtained against such persons arising out of an actual or alleged act, error, or omission that occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities, or that such persons had a reasonable basis for believing occurred within the scope of Interstate Commission employment, duties, or responsibilities; provided, that the actual or alleged act, error, or omission did not result from intentional or willful and wanton misconduct on the part of such persons.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-304">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-304, § 12, 60 DCR 2717</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
