<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>49-1101.04</num>
  <heading>Applicability.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, this compact shall apply to the children of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Active duty members of the uniformed services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Members or veterans of the uniformed services who are severely injured and medically discharged or retired for a period of one year after medical discharge or retirement; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Members of the uniformed services who have died on active duty or as a result of injuries sustained on active duty for a period of one year after death.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this compact shall only apply to local education agencies as defined in this compact.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this compact shall not apply to the children of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Inactive members of the National Guard and military reserves;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Members of the uniformed services now retired, except as provided in subsection (a) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Veterans of the uniformed services, except as provided in subsection (a) of this section; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Other U.S. Department of Defense personnel and other federal agency civilian and contract employees not defined as active duty members of the uniformed services.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-304" type="History">May 1, 2013, D.C. Law 19-304, ยง 5, 60 DCR 2717</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
