<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>49-906</num>
  <heading>Deductions for lost property; officers’ clothing; use of fines and appropriations.</heading>
  <text>All moneys collected on account of deductions made from the pay of any officer or enlisted man of the National Guard of the District of Columbia, on account of government property lost or destroyed by such individual shall be repaid into the United States Treasury to the credit of the officer of the militia of the District of Columbia who is accountable to the United States government for such property lost or destroyed; provided, that there may be paid to all commissioned officers (without discrimination, and in lieu of the limited pay authorized by this section) an allowance to be used by them in the purchase and maintenance of clothing and equipment; provided further, that after March 2, 1911, all moneys collected on account of deductions made from the pay of any officer or enlisted man of the National Guard of the District of Columbia for or on account of any violation of the regulations governing said National Guard, and all moneys which, by reason of the absence of officers or enlisted men from duly ordered assemblies or other duty, are not expended for pay of troops, shall be held by the Commanding General of the militia of the District of Columbia, who is authorized to expend such moneys for necessary clerical and general expenses of the service, heretofore or hereafter incurred, including law books and books of reference, or for the pay of troops, other than government employees; and for all moneys so expended the Commanding General shall make an accounting in like manner as for the appropriation disbursed for pay of troops; provided further, that after March 2, 1911, any of the moneys appropriated for the District of Columbia Militia may be used to supplement specific appropriations or allotments which may be found insufficient for the purposes for which made, and authority is hereby given to supplement the regular ration by purchase of such additional articles of subsistence as may be deemed necessary; provided further, that after March 2, 1911, the Commanding General of the District of Columbia Militia is hereby authorized to make such deductions from any pay of any officer or enlisted man derived from appropriations or allotments made under the provisions of § 1661, United States Revised Statutes [repealed] or other federal enactments as may be necessary to reimburse the United States or the District of Columbia for public property lost, destroyed, or damaged by such individual.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">Mar. 2, 1911, 36 Stat. 1004, ch. 192</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 39-706.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 39-806.</annotation>
    <annotation type="References in Text">Section 1661, United States Revised Statutes, referred to near the end of the section, was repealed by the Act of March 3, 1933, 47 Stat. 1428, ch. 202, § 1.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
