<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>42-2651</num>
  <heading>Creation.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall establish within the District government, or cause to be provided through one or more non-government entities pursuant to a contract or contracts with the District of Columbia, a Homeownership Counseling Program (“Program”). The Program shall provide:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Information concerning credit ratings, credit management, and credit counseling;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Warnings regarding predatory lending practices;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Information on how to purchase a home;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Information concerning financial resources available to first-time homebuyers in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Information concerning financial planning after purchasing a home; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>A compilation and explanation of all federal and District of Columbia tax provisions and public and private programs providing homeownership assistance.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The information required under subsection (a) of this section shall be made available over the Internet and shall be provided to each public library in the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-114" type="History" path="§1001">Apr. 19, 2002, D.C. Law 14-114, § 1001, 49 DCR 1468</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 1101 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 14-114">D.C. Law 14-114</cite> provided: “The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code <cite path="§2-501">§ 2-501</cite> et seq.), shall promulgate rules to implement this act.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
