<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1012.06</num>
  <heading>Winding up.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved limited cooperative association shall wind up its activities and affairs, and except as provided in <cite path="§29-1012.07">§ 29-1012.07</cite>, continue after dissolution only for the purpose of winding up.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>In winding up a limited cooperative association’s activities, the board of directors:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Shall discharge its liabilities, settle and close its activities, and marshal and distribute its assets; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>May:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Preserve the association or its property as a going concern for no more than a reasonable time;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Prosecute and defend actions and proceedings;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Settle disputes by mediation or arbitration;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Deliver to the Mayor for filing a statement of termination stating the name of the company and that the company is terminated;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>Transfer the association’s property; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>Perform other acts necessary or appropriate to the winding up.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>After dissolution and upon application of a limited cooperative association, a member, or a holder of financial rights, the Superior Court may order judicial supervision of the winding up of the association, including the appointment of a person to wind up the association’s activities, if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>After a reasonable time, the association has not wound up its activities; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The applicant establishes other good cause.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If a person is appointed pursuant to subsection (c) of this section to wind up the activities of a limited cooperative association, the association shall promptly deliver to the Mayor for filing an amendment to the articles of organization to reflect the appointment.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(j)(8)(A), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-1002.01">§ 29-1002.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 1206 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
