<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1208.05</num>
  <heading>Other claims against dissolved statutory trust.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A dissolved statutory trust may publish notice of its dissolution and request persons having claims against the trust to present them in accordance with the notice.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A notice under subsection (a) of this section shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Be published at least once in a newspaper of general circulation in the District or, if it has no principal office in the District, in the city in which the trust’s principal office is or was last located;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Describe the information required for a claim;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Provide a mailing address to which the claim may be sent; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>State that a claim against the trust shall be barred unless an action to enforce the claim is commenced not later than 3 years after publication of the notice.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a dissolved statutory trust publishes a notice in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the claim of each of the following claimants is barred unless the claimant commences an action to enforce a claim against the trust not later than 3 years after the publication date of the notice:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A claimant that did not receive notice in a record under <cite path="§29-1208.04">§ 29-1208.04</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A claimant whose claim was timely sent to the trust but was rejected or not acted on; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A claimant whose claim is contingent at, or based on an event occurring after, the effective date of dissolution.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A claim not barred under this section or <cite path="§29-1208.04">§ 29-1208.04</cite> may be enforced against:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A dissolved statutory trust, to the extent of its undistributed property; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A beneficial owner, except as provided in <cite path="§29-1208.06">§ 29-1208.06</cite>, if property of the trust has been distributed after dissolution, against a beneficial owner to the extent of that person’s proportionate share of the claim or property distributed to the beneficial owner after dissolution, whichever is less.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A person’s total liability for all claims under subsection (d)(2) of this section does not exceed the total amount of assets distributed to the person after dissolution.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(l)(8)(D), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “Other claims against dissolved statutory trust” for “Publication of notice” in the section heading; in (c), substituted “the claim of each of the following claimants is barred unless” for “unless”, and deleted “the claim of each of the following claimants shall be barred” following “date of the notice”; and rewrote (d) and (e).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-1206.15">§ 29-1206.15</cite>, <cite path="§29-1208.03">§ 29-1208.03</cite>, and <cite path="§29-1208.06">§ 29-1208.06</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 805 of the Uniform Statutory Trust Entity Act.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
