<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-1008.17</num>
  <heading>Committees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, a board of directors may create one or more committees and appoint one or more individuals to serve on a committee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, an individual appointed to serve on a committee of a limited cooperative association need not be a director or member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>An individual who is not a director and is serving on a committee shall have the same rights, duties, and obligations as a director serving on the committee.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Unless the organic rules otherwise provide each committee of a limited cooperative association may exercise the powers delegated to it by the board of directors, but a committee shall not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Approve allocations or distributions except according to a formula or method prescribed by the board of directors;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Approve or propose to members action requiring approval of members; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Fill vacancies on the board of directors or any of its committees.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 817 of the Uniform Limited Cooperative Association Act. Edition</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-1001.09">§ 29-1001.09</cite>, <cite path="§29-1008.10">§ 29-1008.10</cite>, and <cite path="§29-1008.21">§ 29-1008.21</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
