<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-308.06</num>
  <heading>Articles of amendment.</heading>
  <text>After an amendment to the articles of incorporation has been adopted and approved in the manner required by this chapter and by the articles of incorporation, the corporation shall deliver to the Mayor for filing articles of amendment, which shall set forth:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The name of the corporation;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The text of each amendment adopted or the information required by <cite path="§29-301.04">§ 29-301.04</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>If an amendment provides for an exchange, reclassification, or cancellation of issued shares, provisions for implementing the amendment if not contained in the amendment itself, which may be made dependent upon facts objectively ascertainable outside the articles of amendment in accordance with <cite path="§29-301.04">§ 29-301.04</cite>;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>The date of each amendment’s adoption; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>If an amendment:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Was adopted by the incorporators or board of directors without shareholder approval, a statement that the amendment was duly approved by the incorporators or by the board of directors, as the case may be, and that shareholder approval was not required;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Required approval by the shareholders, a statement that the amendment was duly approved by the shareholders in the manner required by this chapter and by the articles of incorporation; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is being filed pursuant to <cite path="§29-301.04">§ 29-301.04</cite>, a statement to that effect.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-308.07">§ 29-308.07</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
