<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-306.72</num>
  <heading>Directors’ action.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) of this section, directors’ action respecting a director’s conflicting interest transaction shall be effective for the purposes of <cite path="§29-306.71|(b)|(1)">§ 29-306.71(b)(1)</cite> if the transaction has been authorized by the affirmative vote of a majority, but no fewer than 2, of the qualified directors who voted on the transaction, after required disclosure by the conflicted director of information not already known by such qualified directors, or after modified disclosure in compliance with subsection (b) of this section; provided, that:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The qualified directors have deliberated and voted outside the presence of and without the participation by any other director; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>If the action has been taken by a committee, all members of the committee were qualified directors; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <para>
          <num>(i)</num>
          <text>The committee was composed of all the qualified directors on the board of directors; or</text>
        </para>
        <para>
          <num>(ii)</num>
          <text>The members of the committee were appointed by the affirmative vote of a majority of the qualified directors on the board.</text>
        </para>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, when a transaction is a director’s conflicting interest transaction only because a related person described in <cite path="§29-306.70|(5)|(E)">§ 29-306.70(5)(E)</cite> or (F) is a party to or has a material financial interest in the transaction, the conflicted director shall not be obligated to make required disclosure to the extent that the director reasonably believes that doing so would violate a duty imposed under law, a legally enforceable obligation of confidentiality, or a professional ethics rule; provided, that the conflicted director discloses to the qualified directors voting on the transaction:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>All information required to be disclosed that is not so violative;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The existence and nature of the director’s conflicting interest; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The nature of the conflicted director’s duty not to disclose the confidential information.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A majority, but no fewer than 2, of all the qualified directors on the board of directors, or on the committee, constitutes a quorum for the purposes of action that complies with this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>If directors’ action under this section does not satisfy a quorum or voting requirement applicable to the authorization of the transaction by reason of the articles of incorporation, the bylaws, or a provision of law, independent action to satisfy those authorization requirements shall be taken by the board of directors or a committee, in which action directors who are not qualified directors may participate.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-301.21">§ 29-301.21</cite>, <cite path="§29-306.31">§ 29-306.31</cite>, <cite path="§29-306.70">§ 29-306.70</cite>, <cite path="§29-306.71">§ 29-306.71</cite>, <cite path="§29-306.80">§ 29-306.80</cite>, <cite path="§29-311.01">§ 29-311.01</cite>, and <cite path="§29-311.50">§ 29-311.50</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
