<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-406.33</num>
  <heading>Directors’ liability for unlawful distributions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A director who votes for or assents to a distribution made in violation of this chapter shall be personally liable to the nonprofit corporation for the amount of the distribution that exceeds what could have been distributed without violating this chapter if the party asserting liability establishes that, when taking the action, the director did not comply with <cite path="§29-406.30">§ 29-406.30</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A director held liable under subsection (a) of this section for an unlawful distribution shall be entitled to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Contribution from every other director who could be held liable under subsection (a) for the unlawful distribution; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Recoupment from each person of the pro-rata portion of the amount of the unlawful distribution the person received, whether or not the person knew the distribution was made in violation of this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A proceeding to enforce:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The liability of a director under subsection (a) of this section shall be barred unless it is commenced within 2 years after the date on which the distribution was made; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Contribution or recoupment under subsection (b) of this section shall be barred unless it is commenced within one year after the liability of the claimant has been finally adjudicated under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-402.02">§ 29-402.02</cite> and <cite path="§29-406.31">§ 29-406.31</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
