<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>29-704.06</num>
  <heading>Management rights of general partner.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Each general partner shall have equal rights in the management and conduct of the limited partnership’s activities and affairs. Except as expressly provided in this chapter, any matter relating to the activities and affairs of the limited partnership may be exclusively decided by the general partner or, if there is more than one general partner, by a majority of the general partners.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The consent of each partner shall be necessary to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Amend the partnership agreement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Amend the certificate of limited partnership to add or, subject to <cite path="§29-710.06">§ 29-710.06</cite>, delete a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Sell, lease, exchange, or otherwise dispose of all, or substantially all, of the limited partnership’s property, with or without the good will, other than in the usual and regular course of the limited partnership’s activities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A limited partnership shall reimburse a general partner for payments made and indemnify a general partner for liabilities incurred by the general partner in the ordinary course of the activities of the partnership or for the preservation of its activities or property.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A limited partnership shall reimburse a general partner for an advance to the limited partnership beyond the amount of capital the general partner agreed to contribute.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>A payment or advance made by a general partner which gives rise to an obligation of the limited partnership under subsection (c) or (d) of this section shall constitute a loan to the limited partnership which accrues interest from the date of the payment or advance.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>A general partner shall not be entitled to remuneration for services performed for the partnership.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-378" type="History">July 2, 2011, D.C. Law 18-378, § 2, 58 DCR 1720</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-210" type="History">Mar. 5, 2013, D.C. Law 19-210, § 2(g)(4)(E), 59 DCR 13171</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> substituted “activities and affairs” for “activities” twice in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§29-701.07">§ 29-701.07</cite>, <cite path="§29-704.04">§ 29-704.04</cite>, and <cite path="§29-704.09">§ 29-704.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Application of Law 19-210: Section 7 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-210">D.C. Law 19-210</cite> provided that the act shall apply as of January 1, 2012.</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based on § 406 of the Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2001 Act).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
