<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-103.15</num>
  <heading>Subpoena and inspection powers of Mayor.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue a subpoena to compel the presentation of information pertinent to the regulation of the quality of District waters. If any person neglects or refuses to obey the subpoena, the Mayor may invoke the aid of a court of competent jurisdiction to compel compliance with the subpoena. The court may issue an order requiring the subpoenaed person to appear before the Mayor to produce the information requested. The court may punish any failure to obey an order issued pursuant to this subsection as a contempt thereof.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of enforcing this subchapter or any rule issued pursuant to this subchapter, the Mayor or his or her designated representative may, at any reasonable time, upon the presentation of appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Enter without delay any place to inspect any facilities, discharges, activities, equipment, wells, wetlands, underwater lands, or any other item that reasonably relates to the regulation of the quality of District waters;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Inspect and obtain samples of any water or soil that will assist in regulating the quality of District waters; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Inspect and copy any record, report, information, or test result required to be maintained pursuant to the rules issued pursuant to this subchapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor is denied access to any place, that reasonably relates to the regulation of the quality of District waters, the Mayor may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for a search warrant.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-188" type="History" path="§16">Mar. 16, 1985, D.C. Law 5-188, § 16, 32 DCR 919</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-39" type="History">Nov. 13, 2003, D.C. Law 15-39, § 612(f), 50 DCR 5668</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-103.09">8-103.09</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-935.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-39">D.C. Law 15-39</cite>, rewrote subsecs. (a) and (b); and added subsec. (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 612(f) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-105, June 20, 2003,  50 DCR 5613).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 612(f) of Fiscal Year 2004 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2003 (D.C. Act 15-149, September 22, 2003,  50 DCR 8360).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
