<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-108.03</num>
  <heading>Restrictions on the use of perchloroethylene and n-propyl bromide in dry cleaning.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>After January 1, 2014, no person or legal entity shall install a machine designed to use perchloroethylene or n-propyl bromide as a cleaning agent for clothes or other fabrics.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>After January 1, 2029, no person or legal entity shall use perchloroethylene or n-propyl bromide as a cleaning agent for clothes or other fabrics.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term a “child-occupied facility” means a building, or portion of a building, which, as part of its function, receives children under 6 years of age on a regular basis and is required to obtain a certificate of occupancy as a precondition to performing that function. The term “child-occupied facility” includes a daycare center, nursery, preschool center, kindergarten classroom, child development center, child development home, child development facility, child-placing agency, infant care center, or similar entity. The location of a child-occupied facility as part of a larger structure does not make the entire structure a child-occupied facility. Only the portion of the facility occupied or regularly visited by children 6 years of age shall be considered the Child-occupied facility.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Beginning 12 months after April 20, 2013:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A dry cleaning establishment shall use perchloroethylene or n-propyl bromide as a cleaning agent for clothes or other fabrics only after obtaining a source category permit from the District Department of the Environment in accordance with Chapter 2 of Title 20 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations (20 DCMR § 200 et seq.).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>No permit shall be issued to a dry cleaning establishment to use perchloroethlyene or n-propyl bromide as a cleaning agent for clothes or other fabrics that is located within 200 feet of an existing child-occupied facility. The 200-foot restriction shall not apply at a location where a dry cleaning establishment has used perchloroethylene or n-propyl bromide within 90 days before April 20, 2013.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-336" type="History">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-336, § 4, 58 DCR 605</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-262" type="History">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 302, 60 DCR 1300</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-262">D.C. Law 19-262</cite> rewrote the section heading, which formerly read: “Phase out of perchloroethylene in dry cleaning”; substituted “perchloroethylene or n-propyl bromide” for “perchloroethylene” in (a) and (b); and added (c) and (d).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
