<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-104.04</num>
  <heading>Fertilizer public education program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within 180 days of April 20, 2013, a retail establishment that sells fertilizer for turf shall prominently display information prepared by the Department that references:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The requirements of this subchapter;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The effects of fertilizers on local waterbodies;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A warning not to apply fertilizer:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Within a 15-foot buffer area from a waterbody or a 10-foot buffer if a drop spreader, rotary spreader with a deflector, or targeted spray liquid is used;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>When insufficient water is applied to the soil within 24 hours of application to immobilize the fertilizer and prevent fertilizer loss by runoff;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>When a heavy rainfall is occurring, soils are saturated, and the potential for fertilizer movement off-site exists;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Before March 1st or after November 15th in any calendar year;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(E)</num>
        <text>When the ground is frozen; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(F)</num>
        <text>In an amount consistent with an annual recommended rate established by the Department; and</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The proper use of lawn care products to reduce pollution in the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Department shall develop a program of public education that shall include the dissemination of information regarding nutrient pollution, soil testing, proper interpretation of fertilizer label instructions, and the proper use and calibration of fertilizer application equipment, best management practices for fertilizer use in the urban landscape, the requirements of this subchapter, and the effects of fertilizers on the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-262" type="History" path="ยง204">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, ยง 204, 60 DCR 1300</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
