<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1031.08</num>
  <heading>Interagency Waste Reduction Working Group.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established an Interagency Waste Reduction Working Group (“Working Group”) that shall regularly evaluate the District’s solid waste management and diversion activities and policies, and sustainable waste management and diversion practices, policies, and techniques that could be established in the District. The purpose of the Working Group shall be to advise and guide the Mayor, the Council, and the Office of Waste Diversion on sustainable solid waste management and waste diversion policy in the District in accordance with the sustainable solid waste management hierarchy established in § <cite path="§8-1031.02">8-1031.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Working Group shall be composed of at least 7 members selected by the Mayor from District agencies that have expertise and experience in solid waste management, environmental policy development, and implementation of public waste diversion programs, including, at a minimum, DPW and DDOE.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Working Group shall, at a minimum:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Advise the Office of Waste Diversion in the implementation of policies, outreach, and enforcement techniques that have the potential to reduce the generation of solid waste in the District and increase the District’s solid waste diversion rate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Develop a zero waste plan for the District outlining steps the District can take to achieve at least an 80% waste diversion rate;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Design and ensure the development of education and outreach programs with purpose of reducing the generation of solid waste and increasing the waste diversion rate in the District;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Design and guide the development of educational materials reflecting the District’s source separation requirements;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Ensure that the educational materials developed pursuant to this section are updated at least every 5 years and upon the addition of a new source separation requirement;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Ensure issuance and accuracy, to the maximum extent practicable, of the reports and studies required by § <cite path="§8-1031.13">8-1031.13</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(7)</num>
      <text>Meet at least quarterly to fulfill the requirements of this section and to evaluate the effectiveness of the programs established pursuant to this section.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The source separation education materials developed pursuant to subsection (c)(4) of this section shall be placed on the DPW and DDOE websites and posted in public places where these kinds of materials are customarily placed.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 108, 61 DCR 9971</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
