<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-103.03</num>
  <heading>Protection of aquatic life.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>While regulating against water pollution and except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, the Mayor shall protect aquatic animals and plants, and shall preserve and restore aquatic life in District waters for aesthetic enjoyment, for recreation, and for industry.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall study the number and the well-being of aquatic plants and animals, and shall determine the need to license or otherwise limit fishing and other forms of hunting, sports or industry which take or destroy aquatic life or the aquatic habitat. The Mayor shall consider the economic impact upon the various segments of the public before establishing fees for licenses.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may establish fishing seasons and other seasons for hunting, sports or industry, which take or destroy aquatic life or the aquatic habitat.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Revenues from licensing regulatory schemes under this section shall not be used for purposes other than the administration and management of the District’s fisheries and wildlife resources. License fees paid by anglers and other users of these resources shall not be used for purposes other than the administration of the District’s Fisheries and Wildlife Division.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may enter into agreements with state and federal agencies to manage and protect aquatic life.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may protect against aquatic life which creates a nuisance in the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-188" type="History" path="§4">Mar. 16, 1985, D.C. Law 5-188, § 4, 32 DCR 919</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-57" type="History">Mar. 8, 2006, D.C. Law 16-57, § 2, 53 DCR 12</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-923.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-57">D.C. Law 16-57</law-cite> rewrote subsec. (b)(3) which had read as follows: “(3) Revenues from a licensing regulatory scheme under this section shall be used only for protecting and managing aquatic life.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Water Pollution Control Temporary Amendment Act of 2004 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 15-321">D.C. Law 15-321</law-cite>, April 8, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 4710).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Water Pollution Control Emergency Amendment Act of 2004 (D.C. Act 15-655, December 29, 2004,  52 DCR 477).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Water Pollution Control Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-54, March 17, 2005,  52 DCR 3172).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Water Pollution Control Emergency Amendment Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-201, November 17, 2005,  52 DCR 10509).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2 of Water Pollution Control Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-280, February 27, 2006,  53 DCR 1626).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
