<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1041.06</num>
  <heading>Agency responsibilities.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Beginning January 1, 2015, the Mayor shall work with any interested manufacturers, partnerships, or representative organizations to identify District properties that could be utilized for ongoing collection opportunities or collection events.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon approval of a manufacturer, partnership, or representative organization registration, the Mayor shall provide information on an appropriate public website about the available electronic recycling opportunities in the District, including collection sites and collection events. The website shall also include the definition of covered electronic equipment, the proper methods for disposal of covered electronic equipment, the proper methods for disposal of noncovered equipment, and links to relevant portions of manufacturers’ websites. The Mayor may fulfill this requirement by providing a link to a website managed by a third party that contains the required information.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If the District chooses to receive collection or recycling services from a manufacturer, partnership, or representative organization established under this chapter for covered electronic equipment waste collected by the District, the District shall not charge the manufacturer, partnership, or representative organization for the cost of collection services and shall offer the manufacturer, partnership, or the representative organization the covered electronic equipment at no cost. Nothing in this chapter shall require a manufacturer, partnership, or representative organization to provide recycling services for covered electronic equipment waste collected by the District.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History">Feb. 26,2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 120, 61 DCR 9971</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
