<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-103.09b</num>
  <heading>Stormwater In-Lieu Fee Payment Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>There is established as a special fund the Stormwater In-Lieu Fee Payment Fund (“In-Lieu Fee Fund”), which shall be administered by the Mayor in accordance with subsection (c) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The In-Lieu Fee Fund shall consist of revenue from payments to the In-Lieu Fee Fund to achieve stormwater retention obligations of regulated properties, as required by the Municipal Separate Storm Sewer System permit issued to the District by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The In-Lieu Fee Fund shall be used for the installation, operation, and maintenance of stormwater retention facilities.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The money deposited into the In-Lieu Fee Fund, and interest earned, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Subject to authorization by Congress, any funds appropriated in the In-Lieu Fee Fund shall be continually available without regard to fiscal year limitation.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The District Department of the Environment shall publish on its website at least annually a report which includes a description of how revenues are spent from the In-Lieu Fee Fund and Anacostia River Clean Up and Protection Fund, established by subchapter I-A of this chapter [§ <cite path="§8-102.01">8-102.01</cite> et seq.].</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The report on the In-Lieu Fee Fund required by subsection (e) of this section shall include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The total amount of in-lieu fees collected to date;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The total amount of funds spent to date;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>For each sub-drainage area or watershed, the aggregate off-site retention volume per year purchased with in-lieu fees, based on the location of regulated projects paying in-lieu fees; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>For each of the stormwater retention facilities installed using In-Lieu Fee Fund dollars, the type of best management practices used by the facility, the gallons per year of stormwater volume achieved by the facility, the sub-drainage or watershed location of the facility, and a summary of the capital and maintenance costs of the project.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 5-188" type="History">Mar. 16, 1985, D.C. Law 5-188, § 10b</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-61" type="History">as added Dec. 24, 2013, D.C. Law 20-61, § 6022, 60 DCR 12472</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> added this section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 6022 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-130, July 30, 2013,  60 DCR 11384, 20 DCSTAT 1827).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) addition of this section, see § 6022 of the Fiscal Year 2014 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2013 (D.C. Act 20-204, October 17, 2013,  60 DCR 15341, 20 DCSTAT 2311).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Section 6021 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that Subtitle C of Title VI of the act may be cited as the “Stormwater In-Lieu Fee Special Purpose Revenue Fund Amendment Act of 2013”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite>: Section 11001 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-61">D.C. Law 20-61</cite> provided that, except as otherwise provided, the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
