<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1031.10</num>
  <heading>Contract and licensing authority.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may enter into a contract or agreement for a period not to exceed 10 years for:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Solid waste collection, disposal, and diversion services;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The operation of recycling buy-back centers, composting facilities, and intermediate processing facilities for the collection, storage, processing, and disposition of source separated recyclable or compostable materials; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The marketing and sale of recyclable and compostable materials.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may purchase or lease any equipment necessary to facilitate the marketing and sale of recycling or compostable materials.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may issue to universities, nonprofit institutions, and businesses grants for solid waste research, collection, marketing, and other services.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may designate, select, or acquire, by purchase, a site or sites that are suitable for the purpose of solid waste disposal or diversion.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may acquire a site or sites that are suitable for the purpose of solid waste disposal or diversion through condemnation, in accordance with the provisions of Chapter 13 of Title 16.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall submit a proposed site to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed site, in whole or in part, by resolution within this 45-day review period, the proposed site shall be deemed approved.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History" path="ยง110">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, ยง 110, 61 DCR 9971</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
