<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1318</num>
  <heading>Hazardous waste and toxic chemical source reduction plans.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Pursuant to rules issued by the Mayor in accordance with <cite path="§8-1322">§ 8-1322</cite>, beginning on January 1, 1992, and every 4 years thereafter, each business required to submit EPA Form R, and any additional data required, in accordance with <cite path="§8-1317">§ 8-1317</cite>, including any District or federal government operations where applicable, shall submit a source reduction plan to the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Any source reduction plan submitted to the Mayor shall include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A statement of facility-wide management policy regarding hazardous waste and toxic chemical reduction;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A statement of the scope and objectives of the plan, including the anticipated facility-wide reduction for each hazardous waste generated or toxic chemical used during the next 4 years;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An identification of the type and amount of any hazardous waste generated or toxic chemical released into the environment; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>A comprehensive economic and technical evaluation of appropriate technologies, procedures, and training programs to achieve hazardous waste and toxic chemical source reduction, including a schedule for and the estimated costs of implementation of the reduction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-64" type="History" path="§20">Mar. 16, 1978, D.C. Law 2-64, § 20</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 8-229" type="History">as added Mar. 8, 1991, D.C. Law 8-229, title I, § 102(c), 38 DCR 246</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-734.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
