<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1423</num>
  <heading>Prohibition on shipments of hazardous materials.</heading>
  <text>Except in cases of emergency, it shall be illegal in the Capitol Exclusion Zone, without a permit, to:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Transport any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Explosives of Class 1, Division 1.1, or Class 1, Division 1.2, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 500 kilograms;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Flammable gasses of Class 2, Division 2.1, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 10,000 liters;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Poisonous gasses of Class 2, Division 2.3, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 500 liters, and belonging to Hazard Zones A or B, as defined in 49 C.F.R. § 173.116; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Poisonous materials, other than gasses, of Class 6, Division 6.1, in a quantity greater than 1,000 kilograms, and belonging to Hazard Zones A or B, as defined in 49 C.F.R. § 173.133; or</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Operate a vehicle or move a rail car which:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Is capable of containing explosives of Class 1, Division 1.1, or Class 1, Division 1.2, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 500 kilograms, and has exterior placarding or other markings indicating that it contains such materials;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Is capable of containing flammable gasses of Class 2, Division 2.1, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 10,000 liters, and has exterior placarding or other markings indicating that it contains such materials;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Is capable of containing poisonous gasses of Class 2, Division 2.3, as designated in 49 C.F.R. § 173.2, in a quantity greater than 500 liters, and belonging to Hazard Zones A or B, as defined in 49 C.F.R. § 173.116, and has exterior placarding or other markings indicating that it contains such materials; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(D)</num>
      <text>Is capable of containing poisonous materials, other than gasses, of Class 6, Division 6.1, in a quantity greater than 1,000 kilograms, and belonging to Hazard Zones A or B, as defined in 49 C.F.R. § 173.133, and has exterior placarding or other markings indicating that it contains such materials.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-80">Apr. 4, 2006, D.C. Law 16-80, § 4, 53 DCR 1047</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1424">8-1424</cite> and § <cite path="§8-1425">8-1425</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Addition of Section</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (225 day) addition, see § 4 of Terrorism Prevention in Hazardous Materials Transportation Temporary Act of 2005 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 16-2">D.C. Law 16-2</cite>, May 14, 2005, law notification  52 DCR 5425).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Terrorism Prevention in Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-43, February 15, 2005,  52 DCR 3048).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Terrorism Prevention in Hazardous Materials Transportation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-90, June 1, 2005,  52 DCR 5428).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Second Terrorism Prevention in Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Act of 2005 (D.C. Act 16-236, December 22, 2005,  53 DCR 245).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 4 of Terrorism Prevention in Hazardous Materials Transportation Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2006 (D.C. Act 16-325, March 23, 2006,  53 DCR 2576).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
