<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-152.03</num>
  <heading>Stormwater User Fee Discount Program.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Within one year of the enactment of an impervious area stormwater user fee by DC WASA, the Mayor shall establish a Stormwater User Fee Discount Program to be coordinated between DC WASA and the Administration.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The program shall allow property owners who implement measures to manage stormwater runoff from their properties to receive a discount on the stormwater user fee assessed to them under <cite path="§34-2202.16">§ 34-2202.16</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Stormwater user fee discounts approved by the Mayor shall be retroactive to no earlier than the date of the implementation of the impervious area stormwater fee. A property owner may not qualify for a stormwater user fee discount until the stormwater management measures for which they seek a discount are demonstrated to be fully functional.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Any discount earned under this section will be revocable upon a finding by the Mayor of non-performance. Upon a finding of non-performance, the Mayor may require reimbursement of any portion of fees discounted to date.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Findings of non-performance by the Mayor may be appealed by an applicant pursuant to rules established by the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>Failure to reimburse may result in a lien being placed upon the property without further notice to the owner. The Mayor may enforce the lien in the same manner as in <cite path="§34-2407.02">§ 34-2407.02</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-51" type="History" path="§153">Feb. 15, 2006, D.C. Law 16-51, § 153</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-371" type="History">as added Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-371, § 2(b), 56 DCR 1353</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 58(c), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in (f).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
