<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-151.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“CapStat” means an accountability program that examines performance data to improve government services to make the District of Columbia government run more efficiently, using a methodical process for focusing the attention of government representatives on improving performance in priority issues that cross agency boundaries.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“DDOE” means the District Department of the Environment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Director” means the Director of the District Department of the Environment.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Environment” means the physical conditions and natural resources of the District, including the land, air, water, minerals, flora, and fauna in the District, and the waters adjacent to the District.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Environmental Management System” or “EMS” means an interagency data system to inventory, track, and report on progress towards performance standards and activities. The term “EMS” includes an adaptive management approach that incorporates planning, implementing, monitoring, evaluating, and adjusting the interagency data system.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Impervious area stormwater user fee” or “stormwater user fee” means a fee that attributes the cost of conveying stormwater run-off via a sewer from a given property, to the quantity of stormwater run-off generated from that same property, by use of impervious surface as a surrogate metric.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(7)</num>
    <text>“Impervious surface” means a surface area that either prevents or retards the entry of water into the ground as occurring under natural conditions, or that causes water to run off the surface in greater quantities or at an increased rate of flow, relative to the flow present under natural conditions.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(8)</num>
    <text>“Low Impact Development” or “LID” means stormwater management practices that mimic site hydrology under natural conditions, by using design techniques in construction and development that store, infiltrate, evaporate, detain, or reuse and recycle runoff.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(9)</num>
    <text>“MS4” means the Municipal Separate Storm Sewer System serving approximately two-thirds of the District, and comprised of 2 independent piping systems: one system for sewage from homes and businesses, and one system for stormwater.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(10)</num>
    <text>“Natural conditions” means the state of the environment prior to anthropogenic intervention.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(11)</num>
    <text>“Primacy” means the grant or delegation of authority under certain federal environmental laws that allows states and the District to assume primary authority to enforce and implement the environmental laws and promulgate regulations pursuant to those laws.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(12)</num>
    <text>“SDWA” means the Safe Drinking Water Act, approved December 16, 1974 (88 Stat. 1660; 42 U.S.C. § 300f et seq.).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(13)</num>
    <text>“Sewer” shall have the same meaning as provided in § <cite path="§34-2202.01">34-2202.01</cite>(9).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(14)</num>
    <text>“Stormwater best management practice” means a structure used to reduce the volume or the pollutant content of a stormwater discharge.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(15)</num>
    <text>“Stormwater Permit” or “MS4 Permit” means NPDES No. DC0000221, issued to the District of Columbia by the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-51" type="History">Feb. 15, 2006, D.C. Law 16-51, § 101, 52 DCR 10812</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-371" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-371, § 2(a), 56 DCR 1353</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 149(a), 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-371">D.C. Law 17-371</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> deleted “April 20, 2000” following “No. DC0000221, issued” in (15).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 902 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-222">D.C. Law 18-222</cite> rewrote subsec. (e) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(e) Monies shall not be disbursed from the Enterprise Fund for costs associated with:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(1) Stormwater management activities carried out prior to April 20, 2000, including street sweeping, except to the extent those activities were enhanced, and their costs increased, to comply with the terms of the Stormwater Permit; or</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(2) Stormwater management activities otherwise required by law or regulation, unless specifically permitted by the Director.”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2002(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-222">D.C. Law 18-222</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 902 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-450, June 28, 2010,  57 DCR 5635).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 902 of Fiscal Year 2010 Balanced Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-531, August 6, 2010,  57 DCR 8109).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
