<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1778.43</num>
  <heading>Approval of application.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The administrator shall review the property owner’s application and, if it finds that the application satisfies all requirements, shall enter into a loan, or other, agreement with the property owner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The property owner may request in the loan application that the Energy Efficiency Loan include an amount equal to all or part of the cost of the Energy Efficiency Audit. If the amount requested is reasonable, the administrator shall include the amount in the Energy Efficiency Loan.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before entering into an Energy Efficiency Loan Agreement with a property owner, the administrator shall verify, based upon information provided in the property owner’s application, that the value of the savings from the installation of the Energy Efficiency Improvements is reasonably expected to exceed the amount of the principal of, and interest on, the Energy Efficiency Loan, including any cost of the Energy Efficiency Audit included pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-183" type="History">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-183, § 303, 57 DCR 3406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-262" type="History">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 102(h), 60 DCR 1300</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1778.42">8-1778.42</cite> and § <cite path="§47-895.31">47-895.31</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-262">D.C. Law 19-262</law-cite> substituted “an Energy Efficiency Loan Agreement with a property owner, the administrator shall verify, based upon information provided in the property owner’s application, that the value of the savings from” for “a loan, or other, agreement with a property owner, the administrator shall verify, based upon information provided in the property owner’s application, that the value of the energy saved by” in (c).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 204 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-156">D.C. Law 18-156</law-cite> added a section to read as follows: “Sec. 204. Approval of application. The administrator shall review the property owner’s application and, if it finds that the application satisfies all requirements, shall enter into a loan, or other, agreement with the property owner.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 402(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 18-156">D.C. Law 18-156</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 204 of Energy Efficiency Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-324, March 1, 2010,  57 DCR 1851).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
