<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1774.05</num>
  <heading>Implementation of the Sustainable Energy Utility contract.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The District Department of the Environment shall be responsible for the procurement and monitoring of the contract for the SEU, including:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Drafting and revising the RFP for the SEU;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Staffing the Advisory Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Accepting the bids for the SEU contract;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Reviewing bids for the SEU contract; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>All other responsibilities not otherwise expressly delegated to another entity for purposes of operation under this chapter.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>At least 90 days before issuing a new RFP for the SEU contract, DDOE shall solicit recommendations from the Board and the public for performance benchmarks for the contract. In preparing the RFP, DDOE shall hold an industry day to solicit the advice and input of private entities that may bid on the contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>If the DDOE determines that there is not a sufficient bid, DDOE shall modify the RFP, if necessary, and solicit additional bids.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The DDOE shall maintain the brand name adopted pursuant to § <cite path="§8-1774.06">8-1774.06</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The DDOE shall administer the transition from one SEU to another.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Prior to the execution of the contract with the SEU, $775,000 shall be allocated annually for the purposes of:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Preparing the RFP;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Staffing the Board;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Maintaining the brand name adopted pursuant to § <cite path="§8-1774.06">8-1774.06</cite>; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Operating the renewable energy rebate program established by § <cite path="§8-1774.09">8-1774.09</cite>.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>After the execution of the contract with the SEU, 10% of the annual cost of the SEU contract shall be allocated to DDOE for administrative costs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>The DDOE shall submit to the Council, within 90 days following the end of each fiscal year, a report detailing the expenditures of money from the SETF and EATF during the previous fiscal year. The DDOE shall make this document available to the public on its website within 10 days of its receipt.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>The DDOE shall commission, on an annual basis, an independent review of the performance and expenditures of the SEU and shall provide the results of this review to the Board and Council within 6 months of the conclusion of each year of the SEU contract.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-250" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-250, § 205, 55 DCR 9225</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-331" type="History">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-331, § 3(c), 58 DCR 22</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-370" type="History">Apr. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-370, § 612(a), 58 DCR 1008</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 6092(d), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1774.04">8-1774.04</cite> and § <cite path="§8-1774.10">8-1774.10</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-331">D.C. Law 18-331</cite> repealed subsec. (d), which had read as follows: “(d) Within 30 days of the completion of the bidding period, the DDOE shall submit the bids to the Board. The Board shall have 30 days to recommend a bidder or, failing the submission of a bid considered adequate by the Board, recommend the modification of the RFP.”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite>, in subsec. (h), substituted “$775,000” for “$1 million”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “on a contract-term basis” for “on an annual and contract-term basis” in (d); and substituted “75% of the amount” for “75%, and no greater than 125%, of the amount” in (h) and (i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(c) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-269">D.C. Law 18-269</cite> repealed subsec. (d).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-269">D.C. Law 18-269</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 205 of Clean and Affordable Energy Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-508, September 25, 2008,  55 DCR 10856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(c) of Sustainable Energy Utility Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-521, July 30, 2010,  57 DCR 7999).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 612(a) of Fiscal Year 2011 Supplemental Budget Support Emergency Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-694, January 19, 2011,  58 DCR 662).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6092(d) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Short Title">Short title: Section 611 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided that subtitle B of title VI of the act may be cited as “Clean and Affordable Energy Second Amendment Act of 2010”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 613 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-370">D.C. Law 18-370</cite> provided: “Sec. 613. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of October 1, 2010.”</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
