<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1704</num>
  <heading>Composition.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Soil and Water Conservation District, reestablished by § <cite path="§8-1721">8-1721</cite>, shall be governed by 7 members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Five members, at least 4 of whom shall be directors of appropriate agencies or departments of the District of Columbia government, shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Mayor. Two members shall be appointed by the Council of the District of Columbia upon the recommendation of the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia from among its members.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Each member of the Water and Soil Conservation District may designate a person to serve and act in the absence of the appointed member.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The members shall serve without compensation. Members shall be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties in implementing the provisions of this subchapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-143" type="History">Sept. 14, 1982, D.C. Law 4-143, § 5, 29 DCR 3118</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-117" type="History">May 23, 1986, D.C. Law 6-117, § 2, 33 DCR 2442</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-39" type="History">Oct. 9, 1987, D.C. Law 7-39, § 3(a), 34 DCR 5331</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-104" type="History">Apr. 30, 1988, D.C. Law 7-104, § 8(a), 35 DCR 147</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-91" type="History">Apr. 12, 2000, D.C. Law 13-91, § 130, 47 DCR 520</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 1-2804.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">D.C. Law 13-91, in subsec. (a), substituted “§ 1-2803.1” for “§ 1-2803” 1981 Ed. .</annotation>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Department of Transportation were transferred to the Department of Public Works by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984.</text>
    <text type="Transfer of Functions">The functions of the Department of Environmental Services were transferred to the Department of Public Works by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1983, effective March 1, 1984.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
