<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1778.22</num>
  <heading>Bond authorization.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The Council approves and authorizes the issuance of one or more series of bonds in an aggregate principal amount not to exceed $250 million. The bonds, which may be issued at any time and from time to time, in one or more series, shall be tax-exempt or taxable as the Mayor shall determine and shall be payable and secured as provided in § <cite path="§8-1778.23">8-1778.23</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Mayor is authorized to pay from the proceeds of a bond’s issuance costs, the cost of funding capitalized interest and required reserves, and other costs authorized by § <cite path="§1-204.90">1-204.90</cite>(f). In the event bonds are sold other than through a public offering, the issuance costs may be paid from the Special Energy Assessment Program Administrative Account.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The remaining proceeds of the bonds shall be paid into the National Capital Energy Fund established by § <cite path="§8-1778.41">8-1778.41</cite> and used to provide funds for the initial installation of Energy Efficiency Improvements that are permanently attached to residential, commercial, industrial, or other real property as authorized under subchapter III of this chapter.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-183" type="History">May 27, 2010, D.C. Law 18-183, § 202, 57 DCR 3406</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-262" type="History">Apr. 20, 2013, D.C. Law 19-262, § 102(c), 60 DCR 1300</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2013 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-262">D.C. Law 19-262</cite> rewrote (b).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>Section 103 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-156">D.C. Law 18-156</cite> added a section to read as follows: “Sec. 103. Bond authorization.</text>
      <text>“(a) The Council approves and authorizes the issuance of one or more series of bonds in an aggregate principal amount not to exceed $250 million. The bonds, which may be issued at any time and from time to time, in one or more series, shall be tax-exempt or taxable as the Mayor shall determine and shall be payable and secured as provided in section 104.</text>
      <text>“(b) The Mayor is authorized to pay from the proceeds of the bonds the financing costs and expenses of issuing and delivering the bonds, including, but not limited to, underwriting, legal, accounting, and financial advisory fees; bond insurance or other credit enhancement; expenses for marketing and selling the bonds; printing costs and expenses; and the costs of funding capitalized interest and required reserves.</text>
      <text>“(c) The remaining proceeds of the bonds shall be paid into the National Capital Energy Fund created by section 202 and used to provide funds for the initial installation of energy efficiency and renewable energy improvements that are permanently attached to residential, commercial, industrial, or other real property as authorized under Title II.”</text>
      <text>Section 402(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-156">D.C. Law 18-156</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 103 of Energy Efficiency Emergency Act of 2009 (D.C. Act 18-324, March 1, 2010,  57 DCR 1851).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
