<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1774.02</num>
  <heading>Structure of the SEU contract.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>The initial SEU contract shall be for a period of not less than 5 years. Upon the expiration of the initial SEU contract, including any option years, subsequent SEU contracts shall be multiyear contracts of not less than 4 years. If options to extend the SEU contract are included in subsequent SEU contracts, the option periods shall be for not less than 2 years.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall be funded as provided in § <cite path="§8-1774.01">8-1774.01</cite>(e).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall be performance-based and shall provide financial incentives for the SEU to surpass the performance benchmarks set forth in the SEU contract. The SEU contract shall also provide financial penalties to be applied to the SEU if the SEU fails to meet the required performance benchmarks.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall require that the SEU energy efficiency programs shall, when taken as a whole, meet the societal benefit test on a contract-term basis.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Each bid shall detail how the contractor proposes to nearly meet, meet, or exceed each performance benchmark. The performance benchmarks shall be set forth in the bid.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall permit the programs, benchmarks, and level of funding to be changed at any time with the approval of both the SEU and the DDOE. No change to the funding shall allow the Mayor to exceed the SETF funding limits set forth in § <cite path="§8-1774.10">8-1774.10</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall be revocable if the SEU fails to meet the performance benchmarks of the contract.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall provide that the annual expenditure on natural gas-related programs shall be no less than 75% of the amount provided in the contract from the assessment on the natural gas company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall provide that the expenditure on electricity-related programs shall be no less than 75% of the amount provided in the contract from the assessment on the electricity company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>Subsections (h) and (i) shall not apply to funds from a source other than an assessment on the gas company or the electric company.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>The SEU contract shall provide that the SEU shall submit, to the DDOE and Board, a quarterly report detailing expenditures under the contract and performance of SEU programs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-250" type="History">Oct. 22, 2008, D.C. Law 17-250, § 202, 55 DCR 9225</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-331" type="History">Mar. 31, 2011, D.C. Law 18-331, § 3(a), 58 DCR 22</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 6062(b), 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 21-36" type="History">Oct. 22, 2015, D.C. Law 21-36, § 6092(b), 62 DCR 10905</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 18-331">D.C. Law 18-331</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “energy efficiency programs” for “program”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite> added the last two sentences in (a).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 21-36">D.C. Law 21-36</cite> substituted “on a contract-term basis” for “on an annual and contract-term basis” in (d); and substituted “75% of the amount” for “75%, and no greater than 125%, of the amount” in (h) and (i).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-269">D.C. Law 18-269</cite>, in subsec. (d), substituted “energy efficiency programs” for “program”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-269">D.C. Law 18-269</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) addition, see § 202 of Clean and Affordable Energy Emergency Act of 2008 (D.C. Act 17-508, September 25, 2008,  55 DCR 10856).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 2(a) of Sustainable Energy Utility Emergency Amendment Act of 2010 (D.C. Act 18-521, July 30, 2010,  57 DCR 7999).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6072(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-377, July  14, 2014, 61 DCR 7598, 20 STAT 3696).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6062(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-449, October 10, 2014, 61 DCR 1091, 20 STAT 4188).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6062(b) of the Fiscal Year 2015 Budget Support Second Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-566, January 9, 2015, 62 DCR 884, 21 STAT 541).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 6092(b) of the Fiscal Year 2016 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-127, July 27, 2015,  62 DCR 10201).</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
