<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1771.06</num>
  <heading>Electric company purchases of distribution transformers — Public Service Commission rule.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this section, the term:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>“Electric company” shall have the same meaning as in § <cite path="§34-207">34-207</cite>.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>“Liquid-immersed distribution transformer” means a transformer that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Has an input voltage of 34,500 volts or less;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Has an output voltage of 600 volts or less;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Uses oil or other liquid as a coolant; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Is rated for operation at a frequency of 60 Hertz.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>“Transformer” means a device consisting of 2 or more coils of insulated wire and that is designed to transfer alternating current by electromagnetic induction from one coil to another to change the original voltage or current value.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Within 365 days of the date that the United States Department of Energy issues a final rule on liquid-immersed distribution transformers, the Public Service Commission shall adopt a rule governing the purchase of liquid-immersed distribution transformers by the electric company. The rule shall ensure that, subject to availability, all such purchases occurring on or after January 1, 2009 are based on the life-cycle cost methodology contained in section 2 of Standard TP 1-2002 published by the National Electrical Manufacturers Association. The Public Service Commission may also consider additional inventory management costs as costs for inclusion within the life-cycle cost methodology to be used by an electric company for purposes of this section. Except as provided herein, the rule shall be consistent with regulations pertaining to liquid-immersed distribution transformers adopted by the United States Department of Energy.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-64" type="History">Dec. 11, 2007, D.C. Law 17-64, § 7, 54 DCR 10964</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§34-302.01">34-302.01</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
