<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-1808</num>
  <heading>Prohibited conduct.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No owner of an animal shall allow the animal to go at large.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>No person shall knowingly and falsely deny ownership of any animal.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>No person shall remove the license of a dog without the permission of its owner.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>No person shall change the natural color of a baby chicken, duckling, other fowl or rabbit.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>No dog shall be permitted on any school ground when school is in session or on any public recreation area, other than a dog park, unless the dog is leashed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>No person shall sell or offer for sale a baby chicken, duckling, other fowl, or rabbit that has had its natural color changed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No person shall sell or offer for sale a rabbit under the age of 16 weeks or a chick or duck under the age of 8 weeks except for agricultural or scientific purposes.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Except as provided in this subsection, no person shall import into the District, possess, display, offer for sale, trade, barter, exchange, or adoption, or give as a household pet any living member of the animal kingdom including those born or raised in captivity, except the following: domestic dogs (excluding hybrids with wolves, coyotes, or jackals), domestic cats (excluding hybrids with ocelots or margays), domesticated rodents and rabbits, captive-bred species of common cage birds, nonpoisonous snakes, fish, and turtles, traditionally kept in the home for pleasure rather than for commercial purposes, and racing pigeons (when kept in compliance with permit requirements).</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A person may offer the species enumerated in paragraph (1) of this subsection to a public zoo, park, or museum for exhibition purposes.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>This section shall not apply to federally licensed animal exhibitors; however, the Mayor retains the authority to restrict the movement of any prohibited animal into the District and the conditions under which those movements are made.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The Mayor may allow a licensed wildlife rehabilitator, a licensed veterinarian, or a licensed animal shelter to maintain an animal prohibited in this subsection for treatment or pending appropriate disposition.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to persons who own or possess domestic dog hybrids of wolves, coyotes, or jackals prior to March 17, 1993.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>No person may sponsor, promote, train an animal to participate in, contribute to the involvement of an animal in, or attend as a spectator any activity or event in which any animal engages in unnatural behavior, is wrestled or fought, mentally or physically harassed, or displayed in such a way that the animal is struck, abused, or mentally or physically stressed or traumatized, or is induced, goaded or encouraged to perform or react through the use of chemical, mechanical, electrical, or manual devices in a manner that will cause, or is likely to cause, physical or other injury or suffering. This prohibition applies to any event or activity at a public or private facility or property and is applicable regardless of the purpose of the event or activity and regardless of whether a fee is charged to spectators.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <text>No person who has control or custody of a dog shall, direct, encourage, cause, allow or otherwise aid or assist that dog to threaten, charge, bite, or attack a person or other animal, except that a person may keep a properly trained dog on private property to defend it and its occupants from intruders, and may order a dog to defend a person under attack. This section shall not apply to dogs who work for the Metropolitan Police Department or any other law enforcement agency.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(k)</num>
    <text>No person may display, exhibit, or otherwise move animals in the District of Columbia as part of a circus, carnival, or other special performance or event, without first obtaining a permit, issued by the Mayor, that governs the care and management of the animals.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-30" type="History" path="§9">Oct. 18, 1979, D.C. Law 3-30, § 9, 26 DCR 765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-97" type="History">Sept. 16, 1980, D.C. Law 3-97, § 2(d), (e), (g), 27 DCR 3523</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 4-199" type="History">Mar. 10, 1983, D.C. Law 4-199, § 4(b), 30 DCR 119</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-236" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-236, § 2(d), 40 DCR 614</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-303" type="History">June 8, 2001, D.C. Law 13-303, § 4, 47 DCR 7307</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-40" type="History">Dec. 10, 2005, D.C. Law 16-40, § 2(b), 52 DCR 9087</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-281" type="History">Dec. 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-281, § 104(e), 55 DCR 9186</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§7-1009">7-1009</cite> and § <cite path="§8-1802">8-1802</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1008.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2408.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 13-303">D.C. Law 13-303</law-cite> added subsec. (j).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 16-40">D.C. Law 16-40</law-cite>, in subsec. (e), substituted “public recreation area, other than a dog park,” for “public recreation area”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-281">D.C. Law 17-281</law-cite>, in subsec. (h)(2), substituted “or museum for exhibition purposes” for “museum, or educational institution for educational, medical, scientific, or exhibition purposes”; and added subsec. (k).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 2 of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-209">D.C. Law 19-209</law-cite> added (h)(6) to read as follows:</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(h)</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">*****</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">“(6) Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to educational institutions that possess animals for educational and instructional purposes and that otherwise comply with humane, sanitary, and safe treatment requirements, as set forth in section 502 of the Animal Protection Amendment Act of 2008, effective December 5, 2008 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 17-281">D.C. Law 17-281</law-cite>; D.C. Official Code § <cite path="§8-1851.02">8-1851.02</cite>).”</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">Section 4(b) of <law-cite doc="D.C. Law 19-209">D.C. Law 19-209</law-cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Temporary Amendment Act of 2014 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-104">D.C. Law 20-104</law-cite>, May 20, 2014, 61 DCR 2572).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal For Educational Purposes Clarification Second Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-255">D.C. Law 20-255</law-cite>, Apr. 30, 2015,  62 DCR 2257).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Second Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 20-255">D.C. Law 20-255</law-cite>, April 30, 2015,  62 DCR 2257).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">For temporary (225 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Temporary Amendment Act of 2015 (<law-cite doc="D.C. Law 21-88">D.C. Law 21-88</law-cite>, Mar. 9, 2016,  63 DCR 794).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Dangerous Dog Designation Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-351, August 12, 1996,   43 DCR 4553).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (h)(6), see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-466, October 5, 2012,  59 DCR 11767).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary addition of (h)(6), see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-624, January 18, 2013,  60 DCR 1344), applicable as of January 3, 2013.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-274, February 10, 2014,  61 DCR 1208).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see §§ 2, 3 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2014, (D.C. Act 20-326, May 14, 2014, 61 DCR 5198).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Second Emergency Amendment Act of 2014 (D.C. Act 20-578, Jan. 13, 2015, 62 DCR 1256, 21 STAT 723).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Clarification Congressional Review Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 21-28, Mar. 27, 2015,  62 DCR 4520, 21 DCSTAT 863).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 days) amendment of this section, see § 2 of the Classroom Animal for Educational Purposes Emergency Amendment Act of 2015 (D.C. Act 20-226, Dec. 17, 2015,  62 DCR 16247).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
