<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1804</num>
  <heading>Licenses and fees.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>For purposes of this section, “owner” shall not include:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>A licensed veterinary hospital;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A licensed pet shop; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>An incorporated animal welfare agency not engaged in the sale of animals.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>An owner who has a dog over the age of 4 months shall before July 1st of each year, or within 10 days of acquiring the dog, or within 10 days after the dog becomes 4 months of age, obtain an annual license. An owner shall ensure that his dog wears a collar and a license.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Before any annual license may be issued, the owner of the dog shall have the dog vaccinated against rabies and distemper, and shall pay any outstanding fines.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The annual license fees for dogs is as follows:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>No fee for a dog trained as a service animal and actually used for the purpose of assisting a person with a physical or sensory impairment, such as a vision or hearing impairment;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>$15 for a male or female dog certified by a licensed veterinarian as neutered or spayed or certified as incapable of enduring spaying or neutering; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>$50 for all other dogs.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e-1)</num>
    <text>All the fees collected pursuant to subsection (e) of this section shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(f)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may periodically revise the schedule of fees by rulemaking.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(g)</num>
    <text>No license may be transferred from 1 dog to another.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(h)</num>
    <text>Any license issued pursuant to this section may be issued by the Department of Health or by a veterinarian licensed in the District of Columbia pursuant to § <cite path="§3-512.02">3-512.02</cite> [repealed]. A veterinarian may collect an additional $2 for each license issued as reimbursement for administrative costs.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(i)</num>
    <text>Repealed.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(j)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>There is established as a nonlapsing fund the Sterilization Fund (“Fund”), which shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in this subsection.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Deposits into the Fund shall include:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Two dollars from each fee paid for the application, issuance, or renewal of a dog license;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Funds authorized by an act of Congress, a reprogramming, or an intra-District transfer to be deposited into the Fund;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>Any other monies designated by law or regulation to be deposited into the Fund;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(D)</num>
        <text>Interest on money deposited in the Fund.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>All funds deposited into the Fund, and any interest earned on those funds, shall not revert to the unrestricted fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of a fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in subsection (d) of this section without regard to fiscal year limitation, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Monies in the Fund shall be used to subsidize sterilization of cats and dogs owned by persons within the District of Columbia.</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>The Mayor may issue grants to appropriate animal welfare organizations that are experienced in subsidized sterilization efforts.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-30" type="History">Oct. 18, 1979, D.C. Law 3-30, § 5, 26 DCR 765</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-236" type="History">Mar. 17, 1993, D.C. Law 9-236, § 2(a), 40 DCR 614</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-52" type="History">Sept. 26, 1995, D.C. Law 11-52, § 101, 42 DCR 3684</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-261" type="History">Apr. 20, 1999, D.C. Law 12-261, § 2004, 46 DCR 3142</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-305" type="History">Apr. 24, 2007, D.C. Law 16-305, § 30, 53 DCR 6198</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-281" type="History">Dec. 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-281, § 104(c), 55 DCR 9186</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-21" type="History">Sept. 14, 2011, D.C. Law 19-21, § 9073, 58 DCR 6226</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-168" type="History">Sept. 20, 2012, D.C. Law 19-168, § 8005, 59 DCR 8025</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-171" type="History">Sept. 26, 2012, D.C. Law 19-171, § 64, 59 DCR 6190</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1801">8-1801</cite>, § <cite path="§8-1806">8-1806</cite>, and § <cite path="§8-1807">8-1807</cite>.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-1004.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-2404.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-305">D.C. Law 16-305</cite>, substituted “deaf, hearing impaired,” for “audio-handicapped”, throughout the section.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-281">D.C. Law 17-281</cite> repealed subsec. (d); rewrote subsecs. (e), (f), and (h); and added subsecs. (i) and (j).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 19-21">D.C. Law 19-21</cite> added subsec. (e-1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> repealed (i).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2012 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-171">D.C. Law 19-171</cite> substituted “this subsection” for “subsection (d) of this section” in (j)(1).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Amendment of Section">For temporary (225 day) amendment of section, see § 101 of Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Temporary Act of 1995 (<cite doc="D.C. Law 10-253">D.C. Law 10-253</cite>, March 23, 1995, law notification  42 DCR 1652).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 101 of the Multiyear Budget Spending Reduction and Support Emergency Act of 1994 (D.C. Act 10-389, December 29, 1994,  42 DCR 197).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8005 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-383, June 19, 2012,  59 DCR 7764).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see § 8005 of Fiscal Year 2013 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2012 (D.C. Act 19-413, July 25, 2012,  59 DCR 9290).</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 8010 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-168">D.C. Law 19-168</cite> provided that §§ 8002, 8003, 8004, 8005, 8006, and 8007 of the act shall apply as of September 14,  2011.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Delegation of Authority">Delegation of authority pursuant to Law 3-30, see Mayor’s Order 83-206, August 2, 1983, as amended by Mayor’s Order 86-64, April 22, 1986.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
