<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1901</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this chapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Dangerous dog” means any dog that without provocation:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Causes a serious injury to a person or domestic animal; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>Engages in behavior described in paragraph (4)(A)(i) of this section subsequent to having been determined to be a potentially dangerous dog pursuant to § <cite path="§8-1902">8-1902</cite>.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term “dangerous dog” shall not include dogs used by law enforcement officials when the dog is being used for legitimate law enforcement purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Impound” means taken into the custody of the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Owner” means any person, firm, corporation, organization, or department possessing, harboring, keeping, having an interest in, or having control or custody of a dog.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>“Potentially dangerous dog” means any dog that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(i)</num>
        <text>Without provocation, chases or menaces a person or domestic animal in an aggressive manner, causing an injury to a person or domestic animal that is less severe than a serious injury;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(ii)</num>
        <text>In a menacing manner, approaches without provocation any person or domestic animal as if to attack, or has demonstrated a propensity to attack without provocation or otherwise to endanger the safety of human beings or domestic animals; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(iii)</num>
        <text>Is running at-large and has been impounded by an animal control agency 3 or more times in the District within any 12-month period.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>The term “potentially dangerous dog” shall not include dogs used by law enforcement officials when the dog is being used for legitimate law enforcement purposes.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Proper enclosure” means secure confinement indoors or secure confinement outdoors in a locked structure designed and constructed to:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Deter escape of the dog;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Protect the dog from the elements; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Prevent contact with the dog from humans and other domestic animals.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Serious injury” means any physical injury that results in broken bones or lacerations requiring multiple sutures or cosmetic surgery.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-176">Oct. 18, 1988, D.C. Law 7-176, § 2, 35 DCR 4787</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-281">Dec. 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-281, § 105(a), 55 DCR 9186</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1801">8-1801</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1021.1.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-281">D.C. Law 17-281</cite> rewrote the section.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(a) of the Pit Bull and Rottweiler Dangerous Dog Designation Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-257, April 16, 1996,  43 DCR 2156).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(a) of the Dangerous Dog Designation Emergency amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-351, August 12, 1996,  43 DCR 4553).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Delegation of Authority</heading>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-176">D.C. Law 7-176</cite>, the Dangerous Dog Amendment Act of 1988, see Mayor’s Order 90-83, June 4, 1990.</annotation>
      <annotation>Delegation of authority under <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-176">D.C. Law 7-176</cite>, the “Dangerous Dog Amendment Act of 1988”, see Mayor’s Order 2000-98, June 14, 2000 ( 47 DCR 5277).</annotation>
      <annotation>pursuant to <cite doc="D.C. Law 7-176">D.C. Law 7-176</cite>, the Dangerous Dog Amendment Act of 1988, see Mayor’s Order 2009-40, March 23, 2009 ( 56 DCR 6777).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
