<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-1903</num>
  <heading>Consequences of a dangerous or potentially dangerous dog determination.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the Mayor determines that a dog is a potentially dangerous or dangerous dog, the owner shall comply with the requirements of §§ <cite path="§8-1904">8-1904</cite> and <cite path="§8-1905">8-1905</cite> and any other special security or care requirements the Mayor may establish.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If a potentially dangerous or dangerous dog has been impounded and determined to pose a threat to public safety, the Mayor may only return the dog to its owner if the owner has:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Met the registration requirements of § <cite path="§8-1904">8-1904</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Agreed to comply with the requirements of § <cite path="§8-1905">8-1905</cite>, where necessary; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Met or agreed to comply with any additional security or care requirements established by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>The Mayor may humanely destroy a dog if:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The dog has been determined to be a threat to public safety if it is returned to the owner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The owner fails to comply with the registration requirements of § <cite path="§8-1904">8-1904</cite>, the requirements of § <cite path="§8-1905">8-1905</cite>, or any special security or care requirements established by the Mayor;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The owner fails to reimburse the animal control agency for the costs and expenses of the dog’s impoundment as required by § <cite path="§8-1902">8-1902</cite>(d)(2); or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The owner forfeits the dog for humane destruction.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 7-176">Oct. 18, 1988, D.C. Law 7-176, § 4, 35 DCR 4787</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-281">Dec. 5, 2008, D.C. Law 17-281, § 105(c), 55 DCR 9186</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-1902">8-1902</cite> and § <cite path="§8-1905">8-1905</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 6-1021.3.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Effect of Amendments</heading>
      <annotation><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-281">D.C. Law 17-281</cite> rewrote the section which had read as follows: “If a determination is made that a dog is a dangerous dog under § <cite path="§8-1902">8-1902</cite>, the owner shall comply with the provisions of §§ <cite path="§8-1904">8-1904</cite> and <cite path="§8-1905">8-1905</cite> and any other special security or care requirements established by the Mayor, and in accordance with a time schedule established by the Mayor. A dangerous dog determined to constitute a significant threat to the public health and safety if returned to its owner may be humanely destroyed.”</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 2(d) of the Pit Bull and Rottweiler Dangerous Dog Designation Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-257, April 16, 1996,  43 DCR 2156).</annotation>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 3(d) of the Dangerous Dog Designation Emergency Amendment Act of 1996 (D.C. Act 11-351, August 12, 1996,  43 DCR 4553).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
