<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-2131.05</num>
  <heading>Abatement of a public health nuisance.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When the Mayor determines that a public health nuisance exists on a property, the Mayor shall issue a notice of violation to the person alleged to have created the public health nuisance or the owner or occupant of the property. The Mayor may serve the notice of violation on the owner, occupant, or any other responsible person at the premises, deliver the notice of violation by prepaid mail, return receipt requested to the owner or occupant of the property, or post the notice in a conspicuous place on the property in violation. The notice of violation shall include the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The location, date, and time that the public health nuisance took place or that the Mayor investigated the public health nuisance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>The nature of the public health nuisance;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The time, not later than 10 days, within which the public health nuisance shall be abated;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>The specific corrective actions the owner or occupant shall take to abate the public health nuisance; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>A statement that failure to abate the public health nuisance shall constitute a violation of this chapter, with each day of violation constituting a separate offense.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Upon receipt of a notice of violation, the person responsible for the property shall abate the public health nuisance within the time specified in the notice of violation. The Mayor may grant additional time to abate the public health nuisance upon a request from the responsible person and a good faith showing that the person has made an effort to abate the public health nuisance and that a longer time for abatement is necessary.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-163" type="History">May 18, 2004, D.C. Law 15-163, ยง 6, 51 DCR 3683</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in ยง <cite path="ยง8-2131.03">8-2131.03</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
