<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-2103.01</num>
  <heading>Definitions.</heading>
  <text>For the purposes of this subchapter, the term:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>“Abate” means removing rodent infestations by eliminating or rodent-proofing rodent food sources, eliminating rodent nesting areas, rodent-proofing building entry ways, and poisoning or trapping existing rodent  populations.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>“Debris” means any of the following:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Construction or demolition waste that is not stored in a rodent-proof   container and not removed after 14 days or longer;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Yard waste and branches that are not bundled and set out for waste collection, but not yard waste placed in a properly maintained compost pile; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(C)</num>
      <text>Fire wood that is stored next to a building or left in loose piles on   the ground, but not fire wood that is stored away from buildings and at least   18 inches above the ground or in a rodent-proof building.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>“Grease” means used cooking oil, vegetable oil, shortening, margarine or  any other used fat or oil used for cooking, frying or baking intended for  recycling or disposal.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(4)</num>
    <text>“Harborage” means rodent infestation or providing food or nesting areas for rodents, which may be identified by the presence of burrows, droppings, tracks, runways, gnawings, urine stains, odor, live or dead rodents, nests, and rodent gnawed food.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(5)</num>
    <text>“Hardware cloth” means galvanized metal cloth or netting with small  diameter holes used to prevent rodents from entering buildings.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(6)</num>
    <text>“Rodent-proof” or “rodent-proofing” includes:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(A)</num>
      <text>Heavy duty plastic or metal containers with tightly-fitting lids  fastened to the container; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(B)</num>
      <text>Using hardware cloth to seal building openings.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 13-172" type="History">Oct. 19, 2000, D.C. Law 13-172, § 904, 47 DCR 6308</annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary (90 day) amendment of section, see §§ 902 to 908 of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 2000 (D.C. Act 13-438, October 20, 2000,  47 DCR 8740).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
