<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-2207</num>
  <heading>Service records and annual reports.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A wildlife control operator shall maintain records of all wildlife control services documenting the following information at each service call:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Client’s name and address;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Date of service;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Nature of the complaint;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Methods employed to alleviate problem;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Number and species of wildlife handled; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(6)</num>
      <text>Method of disposition of all animals, including place of disposition of all animals.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>On or before January 15 of each year, a wildlife control operator shall submit an accurate summary of activities of the preceding calendar year on forms provided by the Department. The summary shall contain the following information:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Name, phone number, and address of wildlife control operator;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Total number of complaints;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Number and kinds of wildlife handled and their disposition;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Number of wildlife euthanized and method of euthanasia employed; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Period covered.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A wildlife control operator shall keep all required records for 3 years and shall make the records available for inspection by the Director or his or her designee at any reasonable time.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Department shall keep records of all wildlife control operator summary reports and shall regularly compile and publish the information online.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>Within 2 years after March 8, 2011, the Department shall provide a report to the Council on the effectiveness of the regulation of wildlife control services, including the prohibitions on the use of certain control techniques, and recommendations for further legislation to improve regulation of wildlife control.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 18-289" type="History" path="§8">Mar. 8, 2011, D.C. Law 18-289, § 8, 57 DCR 11499</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-155" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-155, § 7008, 61 DCR 9990</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Applicability of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-289">D.C. Law 18-289</cite>: Section 13 of <cite doc="D.C. Law 18-289">D.C. Law 18-289</cite>, codified as <cite path="§8-2212">§ 8-2212</cite>, provided that §§ 8-2204 through 8-2209 shall apply upon the inclusion of their fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Section 8-2212 was repealed by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-155">D.C. Law 20-155</cite>, § 7008.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
