<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-241.04</num>
  <heading>Indoor mold remediation obligations at residential properties.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A residential property owner who receives written or electronic notice from a tenant that indoor mold or suspected indoor mold exists in the dwelling unit or in a common area of the property shall inspect the property within 7 days and remediate the condition in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of this section within 30 days of the inspection unless a shorter timeframe is ordered by a court or the Mayor.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Where professional indoor mold remediation is not required under subsection (c) of this section, a residential property owner notified of indoor mold by a tenant in accordance with subsection (a) shall clean and remove the indoor mold from the contaminated surface in accordance with the guidelines established under § <cite path="§8-241.02">8-241.02</cite>(a)(4). Failure of the Director to issue guidelines under § <cite path="§8-241.02">8-241.02</cite>(a)(4) shall not excuse the residential property owner from the obligation to clean and remove visible indoor mold from the contaminated surface.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>If a residential property owner knows or has reason to know that indoor mold contamination exists in a tenant’s dwelling unit or in a common area of the property, the residential property owner shall cause the mold to be remediated by an indoor mold remediation professional.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section may be enforced pursuant to § <cite path="§8-241.05">8-241.05</cite>.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-135" type="History">Sept. 9, 2014, D.C. Law 20-135, § 305, 61 DCR 6767</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
