<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-405</num>
  <heading>Pesticide dealers.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>No person shall act in the capacity of, or advertise as, or assume to act as a pesticide dealer at any time unless he is licensed by the Mayor in accordance with this subchapter and the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall provide for the licensing of pesticide dealers located within the District; provided, that any manufacturer, registrant, or distributor whose products are distributed or who distributes products in the District and who has no pesticide dealer outlet licensed within the District shall obtain a pesticide dealer’s license from the Mayor for his principal out-of-state location or outlet.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Application for a pesticide dealer’s license shall be made in writing on a form prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>The Mayor shall establish fees in an amount sufficient to cover the cost of the licensing. The license shall be valid for the time period prescribed by the Mayor.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A pesticide dealer shall be responsible for the acts of each of his employees in the solicitation and sale of restricted use pesticides, and for all claims and recommendations for the use of restricted use pesticides.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The provisions of this section shall not apply to a licensed pesticide operator who sells restricted use pesticides only as an integral part of his pesticide application service, or to any District or other governmental agency which provides pesticides only for its own programs.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 2-70" type="History">Apr. 18, 1978, D.C. Law 2-70, § 6, 24 DCR 6867</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-751.5.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
