<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-434</num>
  <heading>Exemptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Section 8-433 shall not apply to the use of a pesticide for the purpose of improving or maintaining water quality at:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Drinking water treatment plants;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Wastewater treatment plants;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Reservoirs and swimming pools; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Related collection, distribution, and treatment facilities.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>A person or entity may apply to the Department for an exemption from § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite> for a District restricted-use pesticide. The Department may grant an exemption if the applicant demonstrates:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That the applicant has made a good-faith effort to seek effective and economical alternatives to the restricted-use or District restricted-use pesticides, and they are unavailable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That providing a waiver will not violate District or federal law; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That use of the restricted-use or District restricted-use pesticide on the property prohibited under § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite> is linked to a need to protect health, the environment, or property.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>A person or entity may apply to the Department for an exemption from § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite> for a non-essential pesticide. The Department may grant an exemption to apply a non-essential pesticide on property prohibited under § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite> if the applicant demonstrates:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>That effective alternatives are unavailable;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>That providing a waiver will not violate District or federal law; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>That use of the non-essential pesticide is critical and necessary to protect human health or prevent imminent and significant economic damage.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>A person or entity subject to § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite> may apply to the Department for an emergency exemption if an emergency pest outbreak poses an imminent threat to public health or if significant economic damage would result from the inability to use a pesticide prohibited or restricted by § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite>. The Department shall impose specific conditions for the granting of emergency applications.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(e)</num>
    <text>The Department may, as set forth by the Mayor in regulations, require that an applicant who applies for substantially the same exemption at substantially the same property due to managing pests with proper adherence to IPM principles attend a District-approved IPM course.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 19-191" type="History">Oct. 23, 2012, D.C. Law 19-191, § 5, 59 DCR 10166</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-433">8-433</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Section 14(a) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 19-191">D.C. Law 19-191</cite> provided that §§ 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, and 13 of the act shall apply as of October 1, 2013.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
