<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>8-503</num>
  <heading>Label requirements.</heading>
  <text>The label required by § <cite path="§8-502">8-502</cite> shall consist of a tag which shall be sewed or otherwise securely attached to the mattress. In case the mattress has not been renovated the label shall contain in plain, legible print in the English language a statement showing: (1) the name and address of the manufacturer; (2) a description of the materials used in the manufacture of such mattress; and (3) whether such materials are in whole or in part secondhand. In case the mattress has been renovated the label shall contain in such print the word “Renovated” and a statement of: (1) the name and address of the renovator; and (2) a description of the materials used in the renovated mattress. For the purposes of this chapter the materials so used shall be described in such manner as the Council of the District of Columbia shall by regulation prescribe.</text>
  <annotations>
    <annotation type="History">July 3, 1926, 44 Stat. 839, ch. 768, § 3</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-502">8-502</cite>.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 6-803.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 6-603.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
    </annoGroup>
    <annotation type="Change in Government">This section originated at a time when local government powers were delegated to a Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia (see Acts Relating to the Establishment of the District of Columbia and its Various Forms of Governmental Organization in Volume 1). Section 402(142) of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (see Reorganization Plans in Volume 1) transferred all of the functions of the Board of Commissioners under this section to the District of Columbia Council, subject to the right of the Commissioner as provided in § 406 of the Plan. The District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act, 87 Stat. 818, § 711 ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.11">1-207.11</cite>), abolished the District of Columbia Council and the Office of Commissioner of the District of Columbia. These branches of government were replaced by the Council of the District of Columbia and the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia, respectively. Accordingly, and also pursuant to § 714(a) of such Act ( D.C. Code, § <cite path="§1-207.14">1-207.14</cite>(a)), appropriate changes in terminology were made in this section.</annotation>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Change in Government</heading>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
