<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-671.08</num>
  <heading>Duration; amendment by court action.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>An environmental covenant is perpetual unless it is:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>By its terms limited to a specific duration or terminated by the occurrence of a specific event;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Terminated by consent pursuant to § <cite path="§8-671.09">8-671.09</cite>;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Terminated pursuant to subsection (b) of this section;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>Terminated by foreclosure of an interest that has priority over the environmental covenant; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(5)</num>
      <text>Terminated or modified in an eminent domain proceeding, but only if:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>The environmental agency that signed the covenant is a party to the proceeding;</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>All persons identified in § <cite path="§8-671.09">8-671.09</cite>(a) and (b) are given notice of the pendency of the proceeding; and</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(C)</num>
        <text>The court determines, after hearing, that the termination or modification will not adversely affect human health or the environment.</text>
      </para>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the environmental agency that signed an environmental covenant has determined that the intended benefits of the covenant can no longer be realized, a court, under the doctrine of changed circumstances, in an action in which all persons identified in § <cite path="§8-671.09">8-671.09</cite>(a) and (b) have been given notice, may terminate the covenant or reduce its burden on the real property subject to the covenant. The environmental agency’s determination or its failure to make a determination upon request is subject to review pursuant to Chapter 5 of Title 2.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Except as otherwise provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, an environmental covenant may not be extinguished, limited, or impaired through issuance of a tax deed, foreclosure of a tax lien, or application of the doctrine of adverse possession, prescription, abandonment, waiver, lack of enforcement, or acquiescence, or a similar doctrine.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-95" type="History" path="§108">May 12, 2006, D.C. Law 16-95, § 108, 53 DCR 1652</annotation>
    <annotation type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 8 of the Uniform Environmental Covenants Act.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in § <cite path="§8-671.03">8-671.03</cite> and § <cite path="§8-671.07">8-671.07</cite>.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
