<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>8-807.01</num>
  <heading>Solid Waste Nuisance Abatement Fund.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A Solid Waste Nuisance Abatement Fund (“Fund”) is hereby established, separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia, into which all fines, penalties, interest, charges and costs assessed pursuant to this chapter shall be deposited. The deposit of these monies shall be subject to § <cite path="§8-807">8-807</cite>(f)(2).</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The Fund shall be nonlapsing. Revenues deposited in the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available to the Department of Public works for the uses and purposes set forth in this chapter, subject to authorization by Congress.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>Monies deposited into the Fund shall be used to offset some of the costs of implementing this chapter, the costs of the abatement of solid waste nuisances, and to fund waste recovery and recycling education and activities in accordance with Chapter 10A of this title and Chapter 10B of this title.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(d)</num>
    <text>The Mayor shall submit to the Council an annual statement of the Fund’s receipts and disbursements for the preceding fiscal year.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 6-100" type="History">Mar. 25, 1986, D.C. Law 6-100, § 8a</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 14-78" type="History">as added Mar. 6, 2002, D.C. Law 14-78, § 2(c), 48 DCR 11262</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 15-105" type="History">Mar. 13, 2004, D.C. Law 15-105, § 52, 51 DCR 881</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 16-191" type="History">Mar. 2, 2007, D.C. Law 16-191, § 105, 53 DCR 6794</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-154" type="History">Feb. 26, 2015, D.C. Law 20-154, § 201(b), 61 DCR 9971</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 15-105">D.C. Law 15-105</cite>, in subsec. (a), validated a previously made technical correction.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 16-191">D.C. Law 16-191</cite>, in the section heading and subsec. (a), substituted “Solid Waste Nuisance Abatement” for “Clean City”.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments">The 2015 amendment by <cite doc="D.C. Law 20-154">D.C. Law 20-154</cite> substituted “nonlapsing” for “continuing” in the first sentence in (b); and rewrote (c).</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
