<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28-5002</num>
  <heading>Prohibitions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>A person or entity shall not:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Transmit, or assist in the transmission of, a commercial electronic mail message that:</text>
      <para>
        <num>(A)</num>
        <text>Falsely identifies electronic mail transmission information, including header information, or other routing information; or</text>
      </para>
      <para>
        <num>(B)</num>
        <text>Contains false or misleading information in the subject line; or</text>
      </para>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Transmit, or assist in the transmission of, a commercial electronic mail message using a third party’s Internet address, domain name, or identity without the third party’s consent for the purpose of transmitting electronic mail in a manner that makes it appear that the third party was the sender of the message or that results in responses to the message being directed to the third party.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The prohibitions contained in this section shall apply to any person or entity who transmits, or who assists in the transmission of, a commercial electronic mail message:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>From a computer located in the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>To an electronic mail address held by a resident of the District of Columbia;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>To an electronic mail service provider with equipment or its principal place of business in the District of Columbia; or</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(4)</num>
      <text>To a domain name registered to a resident of the District of Columbia.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-230" type="History">Sept. 11, 2008, D.C. Law 17-230, § 3, 55 DCR 8311</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 17-353" type="History">Mar. 25, 2009, D.C. Law 17-353, § 245(c), 56 DCR 1117</annotation>
    <annotation type="Effect of Amendments"><cite doc="D.C. Law 17-353">D.C. Law 17-353</cite> validated a previously made technical correction in the section designation.</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
