<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2-322</num>
  <heading>Delivery “ex-ship”.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Unless otherwise agreed a term for delivery of goods “ex-ship” (which means from the carrying vessel) or in equivalent language is not restricted to a particular ship and requires delivery from a ship which has reached a place at the named port of destination where goods of the kind are usually discharged.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Under such a term unless otherwise agreed</text>
    <para>
      <num>(a)</num>
      <text>the seller must discharge all liens arising out of the carriage and furnish the buyer with a direction which puts the carrier under a duty to deliver the goods; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(b)</num>
      <text>the risk of loss does not pass to the buyer until the goods leave the ship’s tackle or are otherwise properly unloaded.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="Pub. L. 88-243" type="History">Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 651, Pub. L. 88-243, § 1</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1973 Ed., § 28:2-322.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2-322.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Term”.  Section 1-201.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Seller”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”.  Section 2-105.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross References:</strong> “Buyer”.  Section 2-103.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross Reference:</strong> Point 1:  Section 2-319(2).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">4. A contract fixing a price “ex ship” with payment “cash against documents” calls only for such documents as are appropriate to the contract. Tender of a delivery order and of a receipt for the freight after the arrival of the carrying vessel is adequate. The seller is not required to tender a bill of lading as a document of title nor is he required to insure the goods for the buyer’s benefit, as the goods are not at the buyer’s risk during the voyage.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">3. The appropriate place and manner of unloading at the port of destination depend upon the nature of the goods and the facilities and usages of the port.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">2. Delivery need not be made from any particular vessel under a clause calling for delivery “exship”, even though a vessel on which shipment is to be made originally is named in the contract, unless the agreement by appropriate language restricts the clause to delivery from a named vessel.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> 1. The delivery term, “exship”, as between seller and buyer, is the reverse of the F.A.S. term covered.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Prior Uniform Statutory Provision:</strong> None.</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
