<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>28:2A-106</num>
  <heading>Limitation on power of parties to consumer lease to choose applicable law and judicial forum.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>If the law chosen by the parties to a consumer lease is that of a jurisdiction other than a jurisdiction in which the lessee resides at the time the lease agreement becomes enforceable or within 30 days thereafter or in which the goods are to be used, the choice is not enforceable.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>If the judicial forum chosen by the parties to a consumer lease is a forum that would not otherwise have jurisdiction over the lessee, the choice is not enforceable.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-128" type="History">July 22, 1992, D.C. Law 9-128, § 2(b), 39 DCR 3830</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 28:2A-106.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Section References">This section is referenced in <cite path="§28:1-301">§ 28:1-301</cite>.</annotation>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Party”.  Section 1-201(29).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Goods”. Section 2A-103(1)(h).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lessee”. Section 2A-103(1)(n).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">“Lease agreement”. Section 2A-103(1)(k).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Definitional Cross Reference:</strong> “Consumer lease”. Section 2A-103(1)(e).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Cross Reference:</strong>Section 9-103(1)(c).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (2) prevents enforcement of potentially abusive jurisdictional consent clauses in consumer leases. By using the term judicial forum, this section does not limit selection of a nonjudicial forum, such as arbitration. This section has no effect on choice of forum clauses in leases that are not consumer leases; such clauses are, as a matter of current law, “prima facie valid“.  The Bremen v. Zapata Off-Shore, Co., 407 U.S. 1, 10 (1972). Such clauses would be governed by other law, including the Model Choice of Forum Act (1968).</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment">Subsection (1) limits potentially abusive choice of law clauses in consumer leases. The 30-day rule in subsection (1) was suggested by  Section 9-103(1)(c). This section has no effect on choice of law clauses in leases that are not consumer leases. Such clauses would be governed by other law.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Purposes:</strong> There is a real danger that a lessor may induce a consumer lessee to agree that the applicable law will be a jurisdiction that has little effective consumer protection, or to agree that the applicable forum will be a forum that is inconvenient for the lessee in the event of litigation. As a result, this section invalidates these choice of law or forum clauses, except where the law chosen is that of the state of the consumer’s residence or where the goods will be kept, or the forum chosen is one that otherwise would have jurisdiction over the lessee.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Changes:</strong> Substantially revised.</text>
    <text type="Uniform Commercial Code Comment"><strong>Uniform Statutory Source:</strong> Unif. Consumer Credit Code s 1.201(8), 7A U.L.A. 36 (1974).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
