<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-23">
  <num type="law">17-23</num>
  <heading type="short">Ballpark Parking Completion Amendment Act of 2007</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2007-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-23.pdf">D.C. Law 17-23</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 8009</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0021">
      <narrative>Law 17-23, the “Ballpark Parking Completion Amendment Act of 2007”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-23 which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 21, 2007, and July 10, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 25, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-85 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-23 became effective on October 18, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984 to exempt from zoning the government’s use of parking garages on the ballpark site. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Ballpark Parking Completion Amendment Act of 2007”. Sec. 2. Section 7(a) of the District of Columbia Comprehensive Plan Act of 1984 Land Use Element Amendment Act of 1984, effective May 23, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-129; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.68(a is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase "and (4 and inserting the phrase 4 and (5 in its place b) A new paragraph (5) is added to read as follows 5) The government's use of the parking structures that will provide approximately 1,325 parking spaces on areas commonly known as “parcel A” (adjacent to South Capitol Street and N Street, S.E “parcel B” (adjacent to N Street and First Street, S.E and “parcel C” (adjacent to Potomac Avenue and South Capitol Street, S.E within the ballpark site, as defined under section 105(a)(2) of the Ballpark Omnibus Financing and Revenue Act of 2004, effective April 8, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-320; D.C. Official Code § 10-1601.05(a)(2 or ballpark, as defined under D.C. Official Code § 47-2002.05(a)(1)(A shall not be subject to zoning Sec. 3. Sunset. This act shall expire on the earlier of the completion of the construction in 2006 through 2008 of the parking structures, including the issuance of a certificate of occupancy for such structures, on the Ballpark Site or December 31, 2008. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-301.68 Note, § 1-301.68 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
