<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-279">
  <num type="law">17-279</num>
  <heading type="short">Performance Parking Pilot Zone Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2008-11-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-279.pdf">D.C. Law 17-279</citation>
      <citation type="register">55 DCR 11059</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0580">
      <narrative>Law 17-279, the “Performance Parking Pilot Zone Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-580 which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 15, 2008, and September 16, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 6, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-534 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-279 became effective on November 25, 2008.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish a performance parking pilot program to protect neighborhood parking, to manage the imminent demand for curbside parking created by new major retail and entertainment destinations, to promote retail patronage, and to limit congestion, to establish an Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Pilot Program, and to establish a Mount Pleasant Visitor Pass Pilot Program. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Performance Parking Pilot Zone Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. Performance Parking Pilot Program a) The Mayor may establish a Performance Parking Pilot Program for the purpose of managing curbside parking and reducing congestion within and around established performance parking pilot zones b) The Mayor shall establish zone-specific parking management targets, and implement regulations, to achieve the following performance parking pilot zone goals 1) Protect resident parking in residential zones 2) Facilitate regular parking turnover in busy commercial areas 3) Promote the use of non-auto transportation; and (4) Decrease vehicular congestion within each zone c) Within each performance parking pilot zone, the Mayor shall designate residential permit parking zones on currently undesignated residential blocks d) Within each performance parking pilot zone, and notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, the Mayor may employ the following to achieve the goals and targets established pursuant to subsection (b) of this section 1) Set or adjust curbside parking fees 2) Set or adjust the days and hours during which curbside parking fees apply 3) Adjust parking fines, as needed, to dissuade illegal parking; and (4) Exempt vehicles displaying valid, in-zone residential permit parking stickers from meter payment, as needed. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Spring Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 e) When increasing curbside parking fees within a performance parking pilot zone, the Mayor shall 1) Monitor curbside parking availability rates on commercial streets to establish a need for any fee increase 2) Except for fees in loading zones, not increase any fee by more than $0.50 in any one-month period, or more than once per month; and (3) Except for fees in loading zones, provide notice to the affected Ward Councilmember and Advisory Neighborhood Commission (“ANC”) of any changes in curbside parking fees at least 10 days before implementation f) Curbside signage, meter decals, and electronic displays shall provide sufficient notice of changes to restrictions within a performance parking pilot zone, except for changes to curbside parking fees pursuant to subsection (d)(1) of this section g) The Mayor shall designate a project manager who will serve as the main point of contact for the public on matters related to each performance parking pilot zone h) The Mayor shall publish a public web site that includes the following: pilot zone boundaries, rules or regulations, information about how to use new parking fee technologies, and a parking pilot project manager’s name and contact information i) The Performance Parking Pilot Program shall terminate 2 years from the effective date of this act. Sec. 3. Ballpark Performance Parking Pilot Zone a) The Ballpark Performance Parking Pilot Zone is designated as the area bounded by 1) The Southeast/Southwest Freeway on the north, 10th Street, S.E on the east, 12th Street, S.W on the west, and the Washington Channel and Anacostia River on the south, including both sides of boundary streets, but not including the Southeast/Southwest Freeway; and (2) East Capitol Street on the north, 11th Street, S.E on the east, Washington Avenue, S.W and South Capitol Street on the west, and the Southeast/Southwest Freeway on the south, including both sides of boundary streets, but not including the Southeast/Southwest Freeway b) The Mayor shall assign parking control and traffic control officers for implementation of the pilot program within the Ballpark Performance Parking Pilot Zone, and enhanced enforcement on stadium event days c) Pursuant to section 2(d)(1 the Mayor shall adjust fees to achieve 10% to 20% availability of curbside parking spaces d) Notwithstanding section 2(e)(2 for curbside parking spaces where there are not established parking fees on the effective date of this act, the Mayor may increase fees up to once per month by an amount up to 50% of the initial fee set for this parking pilot zone e) Notwithstanding section 2(d)(1) and except south of the Southeast/Southwest Freeway, where curbside fees existed before the establishment of the performance parking pilot ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. zone, the Mayor shall not set the initial performance parking pilot zone fee higher than the existing fee f) Notwithstanding any other provision of this act, the Mayor shall not charge curbside parking fees on District or federal holidays g) Within the first 30 days of implementation of the Ballpark Performance Parking Pilot Zone, the Mayor may issue warning citations for curbside parking violations related to the pilot program in the zone. Sec. 4. Columbia Heights Retail Performance Parking Pilot Zone a) The Columbia Heights Retail Performance Parking Pilot Zone is designated as 1) The area bounded by A) 1100 through 1500 blocks of Monroe Street, N.W B) 1100 through 1500 blocks of Harvard Street, N.W C) 2900 through 3400 blocks of 11th Street, N.W and (D) 2900 through 3300 blocks of 16th Street, N.W including both sides of boundary streets 2) Both sides of the 2900 through 3400 blocks of 14th Street, N.W and (3) Both sides of the 1400 block of Girard Street, N.W b) The Mayor shall take the following actions for the Columbia Heights Retail Performance Parking Pilot Zone 1) Install, on all residential streets in the zone and all other approaches to the municipal parking garage, signs that direct traffic toward off-street parking within the retail complex on the west side of the 3100 block of 14th Street, N.W state the price for the off-street parking, and encourage public transportation use 2) Assign a sufficient number of parking control officers and traffic control officers to enforce parking regulations 7 days per week; and (3) Implement revisions to residential permit parking zones c) Notwithstanding section 2(d)(1 any curbside parking fee set within the Columbia Heights Retail Performance Parking Pilot Zone at the initiation of the pilot program shall not exceed $2 per hour d) Notwithstanding section 2(d)(3 any increases in parking fines in the Columbia Heights Retail Performance Parking Pilot Zone shall be subject to the Council review and approval requirements of section 12 of the District of Columbia Motor Vehicle Parking Facility Act of 1942, effective July 21, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-175; D.C. Official Code § 50-2610 e) Within the first 30 days of implementation of the Columbia Heights Retail Performance Parking Pilot Zone, the Mayor shall only issue warning citations for curbside parking violations related to the pilot program in this zone. Sec. 5. Expenditure of Performance Parking Pilot Program revenue a) One hundred percent of annual curbside parking fee revenue from each performance ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. parking pilot zone shall be used for the following purposes 1) Twenty percent shall be for general purposes of the District Department of Transportation Operating Fund 2) Up to 60% shall be used to repay the cost of procurement and maintenance of new meters and related signage for the pilot program in that zone 3) Once the cost of meter procurement is paid in full for a zone, up to 5% shall be used to pay for meter maintenance and related signage in that zone; and (4) The remaining balance of curbside parking revenues shall be used solely for the purpose of non-automobile transportation improvements in that zone b) The Mayor shall involve performance parking pilot zone residents, businesses, ANCs, and Ward Councilmembers in prioritizing non-automobile transportation improvements. The improvements may include 1) Enhancements to bus and rail facilities to improve access and level of service such as electronic real-time schedule displays outside of stations and stops, display of large, full-color bus and rail maps, bus-only and bus priority lanes, and programs to increase electronic fare payment technologies 2) Enhancements to increase the safety, convenience, and comfort of pedestrians, such as new or improved sidewalks, lighting, signage, benches, improved streetscapes, countdown crosswalk signals, and neighborhood traffic calming; and (3) Improvements to bicycling infrastructure, such as painted and separated bicycle lanes, installation of public bicycle racks, and way-finding signage for bicyclists. Sec. 6. Reporting requirements and oversight of performance parking pilot zones a) Before implementation, or upon the effective date of this act, whichever is later, the District Department of Transporation (“DDOT”) shall transmit a detailed performance parking pilot zone plan to the Council and to the Chairs of all ANCs within a performance parking pilot zone. The plan shall set zone-specific parking management targets and shall detail parking changes, which may include new parking restrictions and curbside parking fees b) During the term of a performance parking pilot zone, DDOT, in collaboration with the Ward councilmember, shall conduct quarterly public meetings to provide an update on all parking management targets within the zone and an opportunity for public comment on the program c) If a performance parking pilot zone is not meeting established parking management targets after the 2nd quarter of operation, DDOT shall re-evaluate the strategies used and implement a revised plan. Within 30 days after the 2nd quarter of operation, any revised plan shall be implemented and transmitted to the Council and ANCs, pursuant to subsection (a) of this section d) The Mayor shall submit an annual report for the prior fiscal year on each performance parking pilot zone. The report shall be transmitted to the Council within 30 days after the 4th quarter for each performance parking pilot zone, and shall provide an update on all ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. parking management targets within the zone. At a minimum, the report shall include 1) Any changes to established parking fees 2) A description of curbside parking availability 3) A description of parking turnover rates on retail streets 4) Congestion and double-parking statistics for retail streets 5) Statistics on use of pay-by-phone technology 6) Number, location, and nature of parking violations and citations issued 7) Total revenue from the pilot zone 8) An itemization of expenditures for meter procurement and maintenance, enhanced enforcement, and non-auto transportation improvements in each pilot zone; and (9) Any recommendations for legislative or regulatory initiatives to improve curbside parking efficiency e) Sixty days before the expiration of a performance parking pilot zone, the Mayor shall produce a final report evaluating the success of the performance parking pilot zone, including recommendations for continuation of some or all aspects of the pilot program within the zone. Sec. 7. Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Pilot Program a) The Mayor shall establish a taxicab zone in Adams Morgan by July 15, 2008, which shall include, at a minimum, the following areas 1) The width of 18th Street, N.W from the intersection of 18th Street, N.W and Wyoming Avenue, N.W to the intersection of 18th Street, N.W and Columbia Road, N.W and (2) The width of Columbia Road, N.W from the intersection of Columbia Road, N.W and Biltmore Street, N.W to the intersection of Columbia Road, N.W and Euclid Street, N.W b) Except as provided in this section, Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations shall apply to the established taxicab zone c) The Mayor shall post signage throughout the zone identifying zone hours, zone restrictions, and taxicab stand locations, and give notice of the same to the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission, affected ANCs, and business organizations before implementation of the Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Pilot Program d) A taxicab, as defined in Article XI of Title II of the Washington Metropolitan Transit Regulation Compact, approved September 15, 1960 (74 Stat. 1031; D.C. Official Code § 9-1103.01 shall not pick up a passenger for hire within a designated taxicab zone during taxi zone hours, except at a designated taxicab stand e) For the purposes of this section, the term “taxi zone hours” shall mean from 9:00 p.m. Thursday though 4:00 a.m. Friday; from 9:00 p.m. Friday though 4:00 a.m. Saturday; and from 9:00 p.m. Saturday though 4:00 a.m. Sunday f) The Mayor shall establish at least one taxicab stand within or adjacent to the Adams ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Morgan taxicab zone. Any taxicab stand shall 1) Be clearly identified with signage 2) Have adequate queue space for a maximum number of taxicabs, as identified by the Mayor; and (3) Have adequate space for taxicab patrons to queue g) Taxicabs shall stand in taxicab stands established pursuant to subsection (f) of this section only while awaiting passengers for hire h) The provisions of this section shall be enforced pursuant to section 13 (f) and (g) of the District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code § 50-312 (f) and (g i) The Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Pilot Program shall terminate on October 1, 2010 j) Forty-five days before the termination of the Adams Morgan Taxicab Zone Pilot Program, the Mayor shall present a report to the Council on the efficacy of the program, which shall include recommendations on the continued need for a designated taxicab zone in Adams Morgan. Sec. 8. Mount Pleasant Visitor Pass Pilot Program a) The Mayor shall implement a one-year visitor parking pilot program for residential permit parking areas within ANC1D boundaries b) For the purposes of this pilot program, DDOT may 1) Charge a fee for each permit issued pursuant to this program; and (2) Limit the hours for which a visitor parking permit is valid c) Within 90 days of the effective date of this act, the Mayor, pursuant to Title 1of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq shall issue rules to implement the provisions of this section. The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 30-day period of review. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, by resolution, within the 30-day period, the rules shall be deemed approved. Sec. 9. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 10. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by this Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2531"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2531.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2532"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2532.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2532.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2533"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2534"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2535"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>7</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2536"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>8</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-2537"/>
  </section>
</document>
