<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-227">
  <num type="law">17-227</num>
  <heading type="short">DOWNTOWN BID AMENDMENT ACT OF 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2008-09-11</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-227.pdf">D.C. Law 17-227</citation>
      <citation type="register">55 DCR 8305</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0713"/>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996 to revise the tax rate for commercial properties and hotels. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Downtown BID Amendment Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. Section 201(c)(1) of the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective March 17, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-257; D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.51(c)(1 is amended as follows a) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase “Fourteen cents” and inserting the phrase “The amount of 149835” in its place b) Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase “Fourteen cents” and inserting the phrase “The amount of 149835” in its place c) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the phrase “Sixty dollars” and inserting the phrase “The amount of $74.215” in its place d) Subparagraph (D) is amended by striking the phrase “Fourteen cents” and inserting the phrase “The amount of 149835” in its place. Sec. 3. Applicability a) Section 2(a b and (d) shall apply as of October 1, 2007 b) Section 2(c) shall apply as of April 1, 2008. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the June 30, 2008 fiscal impact statement of the Chief Financial Officer as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1- 206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2008 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 2-1215.51 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
