<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-210">
  <num type="law">17-210</num>
  <heading type="short">Compensation and Holdover Clarification Amendment Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2008-08-15</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-210.pdf">D.C. Law 17-210</citation>
      <citation type="register">55 DCR 6982</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0452">
      <narrative>Law 17-210, the “Compensation and Holdover Clarification Amendment Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-452 which was referred to Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 6, 2008, and June 3, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on June 18, 2008, it was assigned Act No. 17-406 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-210 became effective on August 15, 2008.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend AN ACT To provide a People’s Counsel for the Public Service Commission in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to fix the compensation of the People’s Counsel at the maximum rate of Level II of the Senior Executive Attorney Service. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Compensation and Holdover Clarification Amendment Act of 2008”. Sec. 2. Section 1(b) of AN ACT To provide a People’s Counsel for the Public Service Commission in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved January 2, 1975 (88 Stat. 1975; D.C. Official Code § 34-804(b is amended as follows a) Strike the phrase “Level III” and insert the phrase “Level II” in its place b) Strike the phrase “at the midpoint rate” and insert the phrase “at the maximum rate” in its place. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2008 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 34-804 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
