<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-353">
  <num type="law">17-353</num>
  <heading type="short">Technical Amendments Act of 2008</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2009-03-25</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-353.pdf">D.C. Law 17-353</citation>
      <citation type="register">56 DCR 1117</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0994">
      <narrative>Law 17-353, the “Technical Amendments Act of 2008”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-994 which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 2, 2008, and December 16, 2008, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 15, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 17-687 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-353 became effective on March 25, 2009.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend various acts to correct technical errors, provide clarifications, and make conforming amendments. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the "Technical Amendments Act of 2008 TITLE I. Sec. 101. Section 2(a) of the Mechanic’s Lien Amendment Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2995 (D.C. Law 16-31; 52 DCR 7195 is amended by striking the section designation “1236a” both times it appears and inserting the section designation “1238a” in its place. Sec. 102. Section 2 of the Karyn Barquin Adult Protection Services Self-Neglect Expansion Amendment Act of 2005, effective March 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-67; 53 DCR 40 is amended as follows a) Subsection (d)(1)(A) is amended by striking the phrase “be terminated,” both times it appears and inserting the phrase “be terminated” in its place b) Subsection (k) is amended by striking the subsection designation “(c)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(b)” in its place. Sec. 103. Section 2 of the Parkside Terrace Economic Development Act of 2006, effective April 4, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-84; 53 DCR 1062 is amended by striking the section designation “47-4608" wherever it appears and inserting the section designation “47-4607" in its place. Sec. 104. Section 5(d) of the Office and Commission on African Affairs Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-111; 53 DCR 2532 is amended by striking the phrase “(Ex-officio” and inserting the word “Ex-officio” in its place. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 105. Section 804(a)(1) of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code § 2-308.04(a)(1 is amended by striking the semicolon at the end of the lead-in language and inserting a colon in its place. Sec. 106. Section 2 of the Procurement Practices Timely Competition Assurance and Direct Voucher Prohibition Amendment Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-122; 53 DCR 2834 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase “for quality.” and inserting the phrase “for quality;” in its place b) Subsection (c) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(29A-1)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(29A-i)” in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended as follows A) Strike the subsection designation “(a)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(A)” in its place B) Strike the subsection designation “(b)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(B)” in its place C) Strike the subsection designation “(c)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(C)” in its place D) Strike the subsection designation “(d)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(D)” in its place E) Strike the subsection designation “(e)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(E)” in its place F) Strike the subsection designation “(f)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(F)” in its place G) Strike the subsection designation “(g)” and insert the subparagraph designation “(G)” in its place. Sec. 107. Section 312(a)(1)(C) of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code § 2-303.12(a)(1)(C is amended by striking the word “section” and inserting the word “paragraph” in its place. Sec. 108. The School Modernization Financing Act of 2006, effective March 30, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-123; 53 DCR 2843 is amended as follows a) Section 141 is amended by striking the phrase “this title” both times it appears and inserting the phrase “part A” in its place b) Section 204(b) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “section 2" and insert the phrase “section 2302" in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 2) Strike the phrase “Disadvantaged Business” and insert the phrase “Disadvantaged Business Enterprise” in its place. Sec. 109. Section 201(b) of the Uniform Environmental Covenants Act of 2006, effective May 12, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-95; 53 DCR 1652 is amended by striking the phrase “Act of 2005" and inserting the phrase “Act of 2006" in its place. Sec. 110. Section 2(c)(2) of the Illegal Dumping Enforcement Amendment Act of 2006, effective May 12, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-96; 53 DCR 1661 is amended by striking the phrase “for a period not less than” and inserting the phrase “for a period of not less than” in its place. Sec. 111. The Income Withholding Transfer and Revision Amendment Act of 2006, effective May 12, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-100; 53 DCR 1886 is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “Subchapter I of Chapter 2" and insert the phrase “subchapter I of Chapter 2" in its place B) Strike the phrase “the act” and insert the phrase “subchapter I of Chapter 2 of Title 46" in its palce 2) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase “Subchapter I of Chapter 2" and inserting the phrase “subchapter I of Chapter 2" in its place 3) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase “Subchapter I of Chapter 2" and inserting the phrase “subchapter I of Chapter 2" in its place b) Section 3 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (g) is amended by striking the phrase “Implementation of Withholding” and inserting the phrase “Implementation of withholding” in its place 2) Subsection (h) is amended by striking the phrase “Subchapter II" and inserting the phrase “subchapter II" in its place. Sec. 112. Section 2 of the DC-USA Economic Development Act of 2006, effective May 20, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-105; 53 DCR 2051 is amended by striking the section designation “47- 4606" wherever it appears and inserting the section designation “47-4608" in its place. Sec. 113. Section 302(a) of the First Source Employment Agreement Amendment Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-118; 53 DCR 2602 is amended by striking the phrase “this title” and inserting the phrase “this act” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 114. Section 2(a) of the Displaced Workers Protection Act of 1994, effective April 26, 1994 (D.C. Law 10-105; D.C. Official Code § 32-101 et seq is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place b) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place c) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. Sec. 115. Section 2 of the Home Again Initiative Community Development Amendment Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-119; 53 DCR 2609 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(1a)” both times it appears and inserting the paragraph designation “(1A)” in its place b) Subsection (b) is amended as follows 1) Add a comma after the word “improved” 2) Strike the comma after the phrase “blighted area”. Sec. 116. Section 2(a) of the Financial Institutions Deposit and Investment Act of 2006, effective June 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-125; 53 DCR 4707 is amended by striking the section designation “(25)” and inserting the section designation “(2A)” in its place. Sec. 117. Section 47-2853.46 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a comma after the phrase “firm of certified public accountants”. Sec. 118 Section 47-2853.152(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “registration until the Board rules” and inserting the phrase “registration shall apply until the Board’s rules” in its place. Sec. 119. Section 2302(a)(1)(B) of the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1999, effective October 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 13-38; D.C. Official Code 7- 1811.01(a)(1)(B is amended by striking the word “and” at the end. Sec. 120. Section 3(b)(3) of the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund and Tobacco Settlement Financing Amendment Act of 2006, effective July 25, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-142; 53 DCR 4412 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(b-1)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(c)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 121. Section 47-825.01(a)(1)(D) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “this subchapter” and inserting the phrase “this subparagraph” in its place. Sec. 122. Title II of the New Convention Center Hotel Omnibus Financing and Development Act of 2006, effective September 19, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-163; 53 DCR 5430 is amended as follows a) Strike the title designation “VII” wherever it appears and insert the title designation “II-A” in its place b) Strike the title designation “VIII” wherever it appears and insert the title designation “II-B” in its place c) Strike the title heading “AUTHORIZATION TO LEASE LAND FOR NEW CONVENTION CENTER HOTEL.” and insert the title heading “LAND LEASE AUTHORITY FOR HOTEL.” in its place d) Strike the section designation “701" and insert the section designation “221" in its place e) Strike the section designation “702" and insert the section designation “222" in its place f) Strike the section designation “703" and insert the section designation “223" in its place g) Strike the section designation “801" and insert the section designation “231" in its place h) Strike the section designation “802" and insert the section designation “232" in its place i) Strike the section designation “803" and insert the section designation “233" in its place. Sec. 123. Section 6 of the People First Respectful Language Modernization Act of 2006, effective September 29, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-169; 53 DCR 6223 is amended by striking the phrase “(Enrolled version of Bill 16-665).” and inserting the phrase “(Enrolled version of Bill 16-665);” in its place. Sec. 124. The Parking Amendment Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-175; 53 DCR 6499 is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended by adding a comma after the phrase “18 DCMR” b) Section 3 is amended by striking the section designation “47-2892(c)” and inserting the section designation “47-2829(c)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 125. Section 2(c) of the Low-Income Disabled Tenant Conversion Protection Amendment Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-179; 53 DCR 6698 is amended as follows a) Strike the phrase “the title” and insert the phrase “this act” in its place b) Strike the phrase “this title” and insert the phrase “this act” in its place. Sec. 126. Section 2(b) of the Historic Preservation Amendment Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-185; 53 DCR 6712 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “Paragraph (1) is amended” and insert the phrase “Subsection (a) is amended” in its place 2) Strike the subparagraph designation “(A)” and insert the paragraph designation “(1)” in its place 3) Strike the subparagraph designation “(B)” and insert the paragraph designation “(2)” in its place 4) Strike the subparagraph designation “(C)” and insert the paragraph designation “(3)” in its place 5) Strike the subparagraph designation “(D)” and insert the paragraph designation “(4)” in its place b) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph (3A) is amended” and inserting the phrase “Subsection (c-1) is amended” in its place c) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(4A)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(d-1)” in its place d) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph (6)(B) is amended” and inserting the phrase “Subsection (f)(2) is amended” in its place e) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(6A)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(f-1)” in its place f) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph (12) is amended” and inserting the section designation “Subsection (l) is amended” in its place. Sec. 127. The Enhanced Professional Security Amendment Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-187; 53 DCR 6722 is amended as follows a) Section 203(b) is amended by striking the section designation “47-2839a” and inserting the section designation “47-2839.01" in its place b) Section 221(c) is amended by striking the phrase “Security Officer” and inserting the phrase “The Security Officer” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 128. Section 2 of the Targeted Historic Preservation Assistance Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-189; 53 DCR 6786 is amended as follows a) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the subsection designation “(d)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(e)” in its place b) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the section designation “11a” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “11b” in its place. Sec. 129. The Workforce Investment Implementation Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-150; D.C. Official Code § 32-1601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 4 is amended as follows 1) Strike the word “Council” and insert the phrase “Council of the District of Columbia” in its place 2) Strike the word “Board” wherever it appears and insert the word “Council” in its place b) Section 5 is amended as follows 1) Strike the word “Council” wherever it appears and insert the phrase “Council of the District of Columbia” in its place 2) Strike the word “Board” and insert the word “Council” in its place c) Section 6 is amended by striking the word “Board” and inserting the word “Council” in its place d) Section 7 is amended by striking the word “Board” wherever it appears and inserting the word “Council” in its place e) Section 8 is amended as follows 1) Strike the word “Council” wherever it appears and insert the phrase “Council of the District of Columbia” in its place 2) Strike the word “Board” wherever it appears and insert the word “Council” in its place f) Section 11 is amended as follows 1) Strike the word “Council” and insert the phrase “Council of the District of Columbia” in its place 2) Strike the word “Board” and insert the word “Council” in its place g) Section 12 is amended by striking the word “Board” and inserting the word “Council” in its place h) Section 13 is amended by striking the word “Board” and inserting the word “Council” in its place i) Section 14 is amended by striking the word “Board” and inserting the word “Council” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 8Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 130. The AIDS Health-Care Response Act of 1986, effective June 10, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-121; D.C. Official Code § 7-1601 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(3) is amended by striking the phrase “Department of Human Services, established by Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, approved February 21, 1980" and inserting the phrase “Department of Health, established by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1966, effective July 17, 1996" in its place b) Section 5(a) is amended by striking the phrase “Human Services” and inserting the word “Health” in its place. Sec. 131. The Technical Amendments Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-191; 53 DCR 6794 is amended as follows a) Section 18(b) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(5)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(6)” in its place b) Section 72 is amended by striking the section designation “47-138.01a” and inserting the section designation “47-318.01a” in its place. Sec. 132. Section 1012(a)(2) of the Clean Hands Licensing Revision Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(b)(1)” and inserting the subsection designation “(b)” in its place. Sec. 133. Section 1072 of the Far Southeast Community Organization Tax Exemption and Forgiveness for Accrued Taxes Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by striking the section designation “47-1074" wherever it appears and inserting the section designation “47-1075" in its place. Sec. 134. Section 2002(b) of the Retail Incentive and Tax Increment Financing Re- Authorization and Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by striking the date “January 1, 2003" and inserting the date “August 1, 2006" in its place. Sec. 135. Sections 2052, 2053, and 2054 of the Deed Transfer and Recordation Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 are amended by striking the subsection designation “(a-3)” wherever it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(a-4)” in its place. Sec. 136. Section 2182(b) of the Free Clinic Assistance Program Coverage Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by striking the phrase “, or for which” and inserting the phrase “clinic to pay, or for which” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 9Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 137. Section 4022(2) of Higher Education Financial Aid Assistance Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by adding the phrase “of Part A” before the phrase “of Title IV”. Sec. 138. Section 15b(e)(2) of the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-245; D.C. Official Code § 31- 3514.02(e)(2 is amended by striking the phrase “this subtitle” and inserting the phrase “this act” in its place. Sec. 139. Section 104 of the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act, approved October 17, 1968 (82 Stat. 1156; D.C. Official Code § 10-1101.01 et seq is amended by striking the phrase “titles I and III” and inserting the phrase “titles II and III” in its place. Sec. 140. Section 102a(a)(1)(C) of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-184; D.C. Official Code § 9-111.01a(a)(1)(C is amended by striking the section designation “101(e)” and inserting the section designation “102(e)” in its place. Sec. 141. Section 8(a)(1)(D) of the Anti-Drunk Driving Clarification Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-195; 53 DCR 8675 is amended as follows a) Strike the word “individual” and insert the phrase “an individual” in its place b) Strike the word “person” and insert the phrase “a person” in its place. Sec. 142. Section 3 of the Library Procurement Amendment Act 0f 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-197; 53 DCR 8827 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(s)” and inserting the subsection designation “(r)” in its place. Sec. 143. The Domestic Violence Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-204; 53 DCR 9059 is amended by striking the second section designation designated as section “3 inserting the section designation “4" in its place, and renumbering the remaining sections accordingly. Sec. 144. Section 47-1807.08(b)(3) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “under 47-1807.02(b)” and inserting the phrase “under § 47- 1807.02(b)” in its place. Sec. 145. Section 47-1808.08(b)(3) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “under 47-1808.03(b)” and inserting the phrase “under § 47- 1808.03(b)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 10Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 146. Section 2 of the Audiology and Speech-Language Pathology Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 6, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-219; 53 DCR 10211 is amended as follows a) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(20)” both times it appears and inserting the paragraph designation “(19)” in its place b) Subsection (g) is amended by striking the phrase “SUBCHAPTER VIII-B” and inserting the phrase “TITLE VIII-B” in its place. Sec. 147. Section 2(c) of the Marriage and Family Therapy Amendment Act of 2003, effective March 10, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-88; 50 DCR 10999 is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(19)” both times it appears and inserting the paragraph designation “(6A)” in its place. Sec. 148. Section 2(a) of the Qualified Massage Therapists Amendment Act of 1994, effective March 14, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-205; 41 DCR 7712 is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(6A)” both times it appears and inserting the paragraph designation “(6B)” in its place. Sec. 149. Section 204(b) of the Personal Mobility Device Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 6, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-224; 53 DCR 10225 is amended as follows a) Designate the existing language as paragraph (1 b) A new paragraph (2) is added to read as follows: “(2) The newly designated paragraph (6) is amended as follows: “(A) Designate paragraph (1) as subparagraph (A “(B) Designate paragraph (2) as subparagraph (B).”. Sec. 150. Section 641(e) of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1206.41(e is amended by striking the phrase “the term 1) “Supervising surgeon” and inserting the phrase “the term “supervising surgeon” in its place. Sec. 151. Section 2(j) of the Surgical Assistant Licensure Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 6, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-228; 53 DCR 10244 is amended by striking the section designation “(z)” and inserting the section designation “(aa)” in its place. Sec. 152. Section 6 of the Digital Inclusion Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-210; 53 DCR 9122 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(a)”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 11Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 153. Section 11f of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective May 21, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-137; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.36 is amended by adding the section heading “Consolidation with WMATA” after “Sec. 11f”. Sec. 154. Section 5(i) of the Green Building Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-234; 54 DCR 377 is amended by striking the phrase “Muncipal Regulations” and inserting the phrase “Municipal Regulations” in its place. Sec. 155. Section 2(b) of the Summary Enclosure of Nuisance Vacant Property Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-241; 54 DCR 599 is amended by inserting the phrase “The Mayor” after the phrase “natural causes.” and inserting the phrase “the Mayor” after the phrase “vacant building,”. Sec. 156. Section 2 of the Mount Vernon Triangle BID Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-246; 54 DCR 618 is amended by striking the phrase “section 8" and inserting the phrase “section 9" in its place. Sec. 157. The Homeland Security, Risk Reduction, and Preparedness Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-262; 54 DCR 794 is amended as follows a) Strike the heading for Title II “HOMELAND SECURITY” and insert the heading “HOMELAND SECURITY PROGRAM IMPLEMENTATION.” in its place b) Section 205(c) is amended by striking the phrase “this act” and inserting the phrase “this title” in its place c) Section 207 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(a)” d) Section 305 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(a)” e) Section 401 is amended by adding the phrase “(Commissioner’s Order 74-261)” after the phrase “the phrase “Emergency Management Agency”. Sec. 158. The Medical Malpractice Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-263; 54 DCR 807 is amended as follows a) Section 202 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (e)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “section 204" both times it appears and inserting the phrase “this section” in its place 2) Subsection (f) is amended by striking the phrase “this title” and inserting the phrase “this section” in its place b) Section 302 is amended by striking the section designation “16-28223" and inserting the section designation “16-2822" in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 12Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 159. The Childhood Lead Screening Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-265; 54 DCR 827 is amended by adding the word “ages” after the word “between” both times it appears. Sec. 160. The Public Charter School Assets and Facilities Preservation Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-268; 54 DCR 833 is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “Except as provided” and inserting the phrase “(a) Except as provided” in its place 2) Subsection (e) is amended to read as follows: “(e) Section 2212 (D.C. Official Code § 38-1802.12) is amended as follows: “(1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. “(2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. “(3) A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows: ““(3) The articles of incorporation and bylaws of the nonprofit corporation operating the charter school, which shall contain provisions satisfying the requirements of section 2213a.”” b) Section 5(a) is amended by inserting a comma before the phrase “and the Mayor”. Sec. 161. The Inclusionary Zoning Implementation Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-275; 54 DCR 880 is amended as follows a) Section 102 is amended by striking the section heading “Unlawful Acts.” and inserting the section heading “Unlawful acts.” in its place b) Section 106 is amended by striking the section heading “Ineligibility of Students.” and inserting the phrase “Ineligibility of students.” in its place c) Section 107 is amended by adding the word “the” before “Mayor” in the section heading. Sec. 162. Section 102(8) of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-502(8 is amended as follows a) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end b) Subparagraph (D) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place c) Subparagraph (E) is amended by striking the word “Request” and inserting the word “Requests” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 13Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 163. Section 102 of the Workforce Housing Production Program Approval Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-278; 54 DCR 895 is amended by striking the second subsection designation designated as subsection “(b)”, inserting the subsection designation “(c)” in its place, and redesignating the remaining subsections “(c)” through “(k)” as “(d)” through “(l)”. Sec. 164. The Department of Motor Vehicles Service and Safety Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-279; 54 DCR 903 is amended as follows a) Section 209 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended by adding a semicolon after the phrase “§ 31-2401 et seq.)” 2) Subsection (c) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “Section 47-2863(c)” and insert the phrase “Section 47-2863(a)(3)” in its place B) Strike the phrase “(c) Upon receipt” and insert the phrase “(3) Upon receipt” in its place b) Section 301(g) is amended by striking the second paragraph designation “(3)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(4)” in its place. Sec. 165. The Captive Insurance Company Act of 2004, effective May 17, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-262; D.C. Official Code § 31-3931.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 203(a) is amended by striking the section designation “29" and inserting the section designation “20" in its place b) Section 204 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (d) is amended by striking the phrase “section 2(b)” and inserting the phrase “section 12(b)” in its place 2) The subsection designated as subsection (h) is amended by striking the subsection designation “(h)” and inserting the subsection designation “(g)” in its place 3) The subsection designated as subsection (i) is amended by striking the subsection designation “(i)” and inserting the subsection designation “(h)” in its place c) Section 212 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “Title I” 2) Subsection (c)(3) is amended by striking the phrase “Title I”. Sec. 166. Sections 5(b)(41) of the Captive Insurance Company Act of 2004, effective March 17, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-262; D.C. Official Code § 31-3931.04(b)(41 is amended by striking the phrase “to e established” and inserting the phrase “to be established” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 14Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 167. The Community Access to Health Care Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-288; 54 DCR 976 is amended as follows a) Section 102(c)(4) is amended by striking the comma after the phrase “Trust Fund” b) Section 103(a) is amended by striking the phrase “subsection (b)(7) of this section” and inserting the phrase “section 102(b)(7)” in its place c) The lead-in language for Title III is amended by striking the phrase “Section 47- 1050(a)” and inserting the phrase “Sec. 301. Section 47-1050(a)” in its place. Sec. 168. Section 2 of the Domestic Partnerships Joint Filing Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-292; 54 DCR 1080 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(3) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “(A) Subparagraph (A)” and insert the phrase “Subparagraph (A)” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “(B) Subparagraph (B)” and insert the phrase “(4) Paragraph (27)” in its place b) Subsection (f) is amended by adding the phrase “everywhere it appears” before the phrase “and inserting”. Sec. 169. Section 2(d) of the Anti-Deficiency Act Revision Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-293; 54 DCR 1083 is amended by striking the word “officer” both times it appears and inserting the word “officers” in its place. Sec. 170. The Second Technical Amendments Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-294; 54 DCR 1086 is amended as follows a) Section 11(a) is amended by striking the period after the word “initiative” b) Section 12 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(a-3)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(a-4)” in its place c) Section 13(b) is amended by striking the section designation “47-1074" the second time it appears and inserting the section designation “47-1075" in its place. Sec. 171. Section 4 of the Comprehensive Plan Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-300; 54 DCR 924 is amended by striking the date “April 27, 1999" and inserting the phrase “the effective date of the Comprehensive Plan Amendment Act of 1998" in its place. Sec. 172. The People First Respectful Language Conforming Amendment Act of 2006, effective April 24, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-305; 53 DCR 6198 is amended as follows a) Section 45(b)(1) is amended by adding the word “individuals” after the word “blind” the first time it appears and after the word “handicapped”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 15Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) Section 50 is amended by striking the word “person” and inserting the word “persons” in its place c) Section 55 is amended by striking the word “has” d) Section 57(b) is amended by adding the phrase “both times it appears” before the phrase “and inserting” e) Section 73 is amended to as follows 1) Subsection (g) is amended by adding a semicolon after the word “conditions” 2) Subsection (i) is amended by striking the word “having” and inserting the word “developed” in its place 3) Subsection (j) is amended by striking the word “has” and inserting the word “develops” in its place. Sec. 173. The Omnibus Public Safety Amendment Act of 2006, effective April 24, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-306; 53 DCR 8610 is amended as follows a) Section 203(a)(3) is amended by striking the phrase “Subsection (c) is” and inserting the phrase “Subsections (b) and (c) are” in its place b) Section 216(d) is amended by striking the phrase “sections and” and inserting the phrase “sections 201 through 205 and” in its place c) Section 227(a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “a semicolon” and inserting the phrase “; or” in its place. Sec. 174. Section 204(a) of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, effective March 25, 1977 (D.C. Law 1-96; D.C. Official Code § 2-534(a is amended as follows a) Paragraph (12) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end b) Paragraph (13) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. Sec. 175. Section 2(f) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(f is amended as follows a) Paragraph (42) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end b) Paragraph (43) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. Sec. 176. Section 301(q) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-603.01(17 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (53) is amended by striking the phrase “Communications; and” and ENROLLED ORIGINAL 16Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. inserting the phrase “Communications;” in its place b) Paragraph (54) is amended by striking the phrase “Services.” and inserting the phrase “Services; and” in its place. Sec. 177. Section 1814(8) of the Office of the Chief Technology Establishment Act of 1998, effective March 26, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-175; D.C. Official Code § 1-1403(8 is amended by adding the word “and” at the end. Sec. 178. Section 804(a)(1) of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code § 2-308.04(a)(1 is amended by striking the semicolon at the end of the lead-in language and inserting a colon in its place. Sec. 179. Section 208(c)(3) of the Business Improvement Districts Act of 1996, effective May 29, 1996 (D.C. Law 11-134; D.C. Official Code § 2-1215.58 is amended by striking the section designation “8(b)” and inserting the section designation “9(b)” in its place. Sec. 180. Section 47-2853.152(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “registration until the Board rules” and inserting the phrase “registration shall apply until the Board’s rules” in its place. Sec. 181. Section 501(b) of the Brownfield Revitalization Amendment Act of 2000, effective June 13, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-312; D.C. Official Code § 8-635.01(b is amended as follows a) The lead-in language is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “cleaned up properties” and insert the phrase “cleaned-up properties” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “the same or pertinent the” and insert the phrase “instruments pertaining to properties cleaned up pursuant to this act or other pertinent” in its place b) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the word “runs” and inserting the word “run” in its place. Sec. 182. Section 431(2)(C) of the Abatement and Condemnation of Nuisance Properties Omnibus Amendment Act of 2000, effective April 27, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-281; D.C. Official Code § 42-3171.01(2)(C is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period in its place. Sec. 183. Section 47-2853.46(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended ENROLLED ORIGINAL 17Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. by adding a comma after the word “accountants”. Sec. 184. The Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3501.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 103(5)(C) is amended by striking the phrase “rent ceilings” and inserting the phrase “rents charged” in its place b) Section 205(a)(7)(C) is amended by striking the phrase “rent ceilings” both times it appears and inserting the phrase “rents charged” in its place c) The section heading to section 206 is amended by striking the phrase “Rent ceiling.” and inserting the phrase “Rent ceilings abolished.” in its place d) Section 209(c) is amended by striking the phrase “rent ceilings” and inserting the phrase “rent charged” in its place Sec. 185. Section 7 of the District of Columbia Fund Accounting Act of 1980, effective June 14, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-70; D.C. Official Code § 3-308 is amended by striking the phrase “established by section 8 Sec. 186. The District of Columbia Funeral Services Regulatory Act of 1984, effective May 22, 1984 (D.C. Law 5-84; D.C. Official Code § 3-401 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 6 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (e)(3) is amended by striking the section number “4(i)” and inserting the section number “22a" in its place 2) Subsection (g)(7) is amended by striking the section number “4(i)” and inserting the section number “22a" in its place 3) Subsection (h)(4)(B) is amended by striking the section number “4(d)” and inserting the section number “22a" in its place b) Section 7(b) is amended by striking the section number “4(i)” and inserting the section number “22a" in its place c) Section 8(b) is amended by striking the section number “4(i)” and inserting the section number “22a" in its place. Sec. 187. Section 3 of the Litter and Solid Waste Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-84; D.C. Official Code § 3-1003 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end b) Paragraph (7) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. Sec. 188. The District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 et seq is amended as ENROLLED ORIGINAL 18Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. follows a) Section 203(a)(8) is amended as follows 1) The subparagraph designated (B-1) is redesignated as (B-i 2) The subparagraph designated (B-2) is redesignated as (B-ii b) Section 502 is amended as follows 1) Designate the existing language as subsection (a 2) Paragraph (4) of the newly designated subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the phrase “this subsection” and inserting the phrase “this section” in its place B) Subparagraph (D) is redesignated as subsection (b 4) The newly designated subsection (b) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “subparagraphs (A B and (C) of this paragraph” and insert the phrase “subparagraphs (A B and (C) of subsection (a)(4) of this section” in its place B) Strike the phrase “this paragraph shall” and insert the phrase “subsection (a)(4) of this section shall” in its place c) Section 901(a-1) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in language of paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “section,:” and inserting the phrase “section:” in its place 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. Sec. 189. Section 25-1002(c)(4)(C) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “paragraph (4) of this subsection” and inserting the phrase “this paragraph” in its place. Sec. 190. Section 2(c) of the NoMa Improvement Association Business Improvement District Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 8, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-245; 54 DCR 615 is amended by striking the phrase “section 8(b)” and inserting the phrase “section 9(b)” in its place. Sec. 191. Section 6(b) of the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code § 2-1831.03(b is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end 3) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 19Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 192. Section 631(c)(4) of the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 6, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-228; D.C. Official Code § 3-1206.31(c)(4 is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period in its place. Sec. 193 Section 203(a)(2) of the Omnibus Public Safety Amendment Act of 2006, effective October 17, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-306; 53 DCR 8610 is amended by adding a new subparagraph (C) to read as follows: “(C) Strike the phrase “Child Protective Services Division of the Department of Human Services" and insert the phrase “Child and Family Services Agency” in its place.”. Sec. 194. Section 2052 of the Registration and Inspection of Weighing and Measuring Devices Amendment Act of 2004, effective December 7, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-205; 51 DCR 8441 is amended by striking the phrase “$900" and inserting the phrase “$900)” in its place. Sec. 195. Section 102(b) of the Placement of Students with Disabilities in Nonpublic Schools Amendment Act of 2006, effective December 19, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-269; D.C. Official Code § 38-2561.02(b is amended by striking the comma after the word “act”. Sec. 196. Section 2 of the Taxicab and Passenger Vehicle for Hire Impoundment Act of 1992, effective March 16, 1993 (D.C. Law 9-199; D.C. Official Code § 50-331 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(3) is amended as follows 1) Strike the period after the phrase “been imposed” and insert a comma in its place 2) Strike the last sentence b) A new subsection (a-1) is added to read as follows: “(a-1) For the purposes of this section, a notice of infraction is considered unpaid if the infraction has been deemed to have been admitted or sustained after a hearing, pursuant to sections 305 or 306 of the District of Columbia Traffic Adjudication Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-104; D.C. Official Code §§ 50-2303.05 and 50-2303.06 section 902 of the Fiscal Year 1997 Budget Support Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-198; D.C. Official Code § 50-2209.02 or subsection 323.3 of Title 31 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations Sec. 197. The Department of Motor Vehicles Service and Safety Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-279; 54 DCR 903 is amended as follows a) Section 101 is amended by striking the phrase “The Director” and inserting the phrase “Additional reporting obligations. – The Director” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 20Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) Section 403(c)(3) is amended by striking the phrase “section 2(j).” and inserting the phrase “section 2(j);” in its place. Sec. 198. Section 4(a)(3) of the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, approved August 17, 1937 (50 Stat. 680; D.C. Official Code § 50-1501.04(a)(3 is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; or” in its place. Sec. 199. Section 12(h)(2)(B) of An Act To regulate the business of life insurance in the District of Columbia, approved June 19, 1934 (48 Stat. 1166; D.C. Official Code § 31- 4712(h)(2)(B is amended by striking the phrase “have a total” and inserting the phrase “come to have a total” in its place. Sec. 200. Section 2(3) of the Health-Care Facility Unlicensed Personnel Criminal Background Check Act of 1998, effective April 20, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-238; D.C. Official Code § 44-551(3 is amended by striking the phrase “the mentally retarded” and inserting the phrase “persons with mental retardation” in its place. Sec. 201. Section 70 of the People First Respectful Language Conforming Amendment Act of 2006, effective April 24, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-305; 53 DCR 6198 is amended as follows a) Strike the word “disabled” and insert the phrase “functionally disabled” in its place b) Strike the word “functional” before the word “disabilities”. Sec. 202. Section 47-864.01 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the section designation “§ 47-864.01" and inserting the section designation “§ 47-864" in its place. Sec. 203. The Public Education Reform Amendment Act of 2007, effective June 12, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-9; 54 DCR 4102 is amended as follows a) Section 304(a) is amended by striking the phrase “families, which shall be an office of and” and inserting the phrase “families. The program shall be” in its place b) Section 802(e)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “the chartering authority” and inserting the phrase “the eligible chartering authority” in its place c) Section 1001(b) is amended as follows 1) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(61)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(55)” in its place 2) Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(62)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(56)” in its place 3) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(63)” both times it appears and inserting the paragraph designation “(57)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 21Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 d) Section 1002(b) is amended by striking the subsection designation “(r)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(s)” in its place e) Section 1005(a) is amended as follows 1) Add the phrase “of the District of Columbia” after the word “Education” 2) Add the phrase “of the District of Columbia Public Schools” after the word “Chancellor”. Sec. 204. Section 3(2) of the District of Columbia Public School Support Initiative of 1986, effective February 17, 1988 (D.C. Law 7-68; D.C. Official Code § 38-917(2 is amended by striking the phrase “Chancellor of its” and inserting the phrase “Chancellor of his or her” in its place. Sec. 205. Section 103 of the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-137; D.C. Official Code § 7- 1301.03 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (4) is amended by striking the phrase “is at least moderately mentally retarded” and inserting the phrase “has at least moderate mental retardation” in its place b) Paragraph (21)(B) is amended by striking the phrase “the mentally retarded” and inserting the phrase “persons with mental retardation” in its place. Sec. 206. Section 3 of the School Governance Companion Amendment Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-149; 47 DCR 4639 is amended by striking the subsection designation “(h)” both times it appears and inserting the subsection designation “(g)” in its place. Sec. 207. Section 204 of An Act To authorize improvements in the operation of the government of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approve October 16, 2006 (120 Stat. 2038; Pub. L. 109-356 is amended by striking the section designation “Sec. 4.” and inserting the section designation “Sec. 4a.” in its place. Sec. 208. Section 2(f)(28) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective Marcy 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(f)(28 is amended by striking the word “Counsel” and inserting the word “Council” in its place. Sec. 209. Section 47-363 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Subsection (e)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “and requests pursuant to § 47- 364(a)”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 22Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) Subsection (h) is amended by striking the phrase “and the D.C. General Hospital Commission”. Sec. 210. Section 47-308(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase "in process" and inserting the phrase "in recess" in its place. Sec. 211. Section 5082 of the Nursing Facility Quality of Care Fund Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by striking the word "ninety Sec. 212. Section 3017 of the Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; 52 DCR 7503 is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph 91A of section 8 of the An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen, and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 993; D.C. Official Code § 34-804(b))” and inserting the phrase “Section 1(b) of An Act To provide a People’s Counsel for the Public Service Commission in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved January 2, 1975 (88 Stat. 1975; D.C. Official Code § 34-804(b))” in its place. Sec. 213. Section 2(a) of the Parking Enhancement Amendment Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-186; 53 DCR 6719 is amended by striking the section designation "2411.9" and inserting the section designation "2411.19" in its place. Sec. 214. Section 3(b)(3) of the Nonprofit Organizations Oversight Improvement Amendment Act of 2007, effective June 12, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-4; 54 DCR 4085 is amended as follows a) The lead-in language is amended by striking the phrase “subsection (c)” and inserting the phrase “subsection (d)” in its place b) Strike the subsection designation “(c)(1)” and insert the subsection designation “(d)(1)” in its place. Sec. 215. The Fiscal Year 2008 Budget Support Act of 2007, effective September 18, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-20; 54 DCR 7052 is amended as follows a) Section 1032(a) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(13)” both times it appears and inserting the paragraph designation “(14)” in its place b) Section 1042(b) is amended as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 23Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) Strike the phrase “§§ 47-1801.04(26)(A)” and insert the phrase “paragraph (26)(A) of this section” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “47-1801.04(26)(B)” and insert the phrase “paragraph (26)(B) of this section” in its place 3) Strike the phrase “47-1806.02" both times it appears and insert the phrase “§ 47-1806.02" in its place c) Section 2003(b) is amended by striking the phrase “the Department” and inserting the phrase “The Department” in its place d) Section 4012(a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(5)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(14)” in its place 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(6)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(15)” in its place 3) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the paragraph designation “(7)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(16)” in its place e) Section 6052 is amended by striking the section designation “20d” both times it appears and inserting the section designation “20e” in its place. Sec. 216. Section 2375 of the Small, Local, and Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective September 18, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-20; 54 DCR 7052 is amended as follows a) Subsection (d) is redesignated as subsection (e b) The second subsection (c) is redesignated as subsection (d c) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “to 2363(c)” and inserting the phrase “to section 2363(c)” in its place. Sec. 217. Section 2 of the Safe and Stable Homes for Children and Youth Amendment Act of 2007, effective September 20, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-21; 54 DCR 6835 is amended as follows a) Strike the chapter designation “8" wherever it appears and insert the chapter designation “8a” in its place b) Strike the section designation “16-801" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.01" in its place c) Strike the section designation “16-802" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.02" in its place d) Strike the section designation “16-803" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.03" in its place e) Strike the section designation “16-804" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.04" in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 24Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 f) Strike the section designation “16-805" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.05" in its place g) Strike the section designation “16-806" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.06" in its place h) Strike the section designation “16-807" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.07" in its place i) Strike the section designation “16-808" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.08" in its place j) Strike the section designation “16-809" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.09" in its place k) Strike the section designation “16-810" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.10" in its place l) Strike the section designation “16-811" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.11" in its place m) Strike the section designation “16-812" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.12" in its place n) Strike the section designation “16-813" wherever it appears and insert the section designation “16-1831.13" in its place. Sec. 218. Section 10(a)(1) of the District of Columbia Election Code of 1955, approved August 12, 1955 (69 Stat. 702; D.C. Official Code § 1-1001.10(a)(1 is amended by striking the phrase “referred to in sections” and inserting the phrase “referred to in section” in its place. Sec. 219. Section 2(c) of the Capitol Riverfront Business Improvement District Amendment Act of 2007, effective October 18, 2007 (D.C. Law 17-27; 54 DCR 8020 is amended by striking the section designation “8(b)” and inserting the section designation “9(b)” in its place. Sec. 220. Section 3(a) of the Bank Charter Modernization Amendment Act of 2007, effective December 11, 2007 (D.C. law 17-59; 54 DCR 10718 is amended be striking the section designation “3(b and inserting the section designation “3a(b)” in its place. Sec. 221. Section 2(b) of the Omnibus Sports Consolidation Amendment Act of 2007, effective January 29, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-84; 54 DCR 11891 is amended by adding the phrase “both times it appears” before the phrase “and insert”. Sec. 222. Section 3 of the Mortgage Disclosure Amendment Act of 2007, effective January 29, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-90; 54 DCR 11925 is amended as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 25Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 a) Strike the paragraph designation “(cc)” and insert the paragraph designation “(ff)” in its place b) Strike the paragraph designation “(dd)” and insert the paragraph designation “(gg)” in its place c) Strike the paragraph designation “(ee)” and insert the paragraph designation “(hh)” in its place d) Strike the paragraph designation “(ff)” both times it appears and insert the paragraph designation “(gg)” in its place. Sec. 223. The Jobs for D.C. Residents Amendment Act of 2007, effective February 6, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-108; 54 DCR 10993 is amended as follows a) Section 101(a) is amended by striking the phrase “D.C. Official Code § 2-139;” b) Section 201 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows: “(a)(1) The existing language is designated as paragraph (1 “(2) A new paragraph (2) is added to read as follows: “(2) The Executive Director of the Commission shall be a District resident and shall remain a District resident for the duration of his or her employment by the Commission. Failure to maintain District residency shall result in a forfeiture of the position.” 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase “a listing” and inserting the phrase “and a listing” in its place c) Section 203 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by adding the phrase “is added” before the phrase “to read” 2) Subsection (d)(1)(A) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “New paragraphs (1) and (2) are added” and insert the phrase “Paragraphs (1) and (2) are amended” in its place B) Strike the phrase “(e)(1) Notwithstanding” and insert the phrase “(1) Notwithstanding” in its place d) Section 206(b) is amended as follows 1) Strike the lead-in language 2) Strike paragraphs (1) and (2 3) Strike the phrase “(3) A new paragraph (5)” and insert the phrase “A new subsection (d-1)” in its place 4) Strike the paragraph designation “(5)” and insert the subsection designation “(d-1)” in its place 5) Strike the word “Authority” wherever it appears and insert the word “Board” in its place e) Section 210 is amended as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 26Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) Subsection (a) is amended by striking the phrase “a new sentence” and inserting the phrase “2 new sentences” in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the word “provided” and inserting the word “except” in its place f) Section 214(b)(2) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “Paragraph (2) is amended by adding 6 new sentences” and insert the phrase “A new paragraph (3) is added” in its place 2) Strike the word “Notwithstanding” and insert the phrase “(3) District residency. – Notwithstanding” in its place g) Section 215(b) is amended by striking the phrase “and the names” and inserting the phrase “the names” in its place. Sec. 224. The Public Education Personnel Reform Amendment Act of 2008, effective March 20, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-122; 55 DCR 1506 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(4) is amended by adding the word “the” before the word “Board” b) Subsection (d)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “or;” and inserting the phrase “unit;” in its place. Sec. 225. The District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-601.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 801A((b)(2) is amended as follows 1) Subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) is amended by adding a semicolon at the end 2) Subparagraph (F)(i)(III) is amended by adding the word “the” after the word “within”. Sec. 226. Section 2(a)(2) of the Downtown Retail TIF Amendment Act of 2008, effective March 20, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-129; 55 DCR 1532 is amended by adding a comma after the word “customers” the first time it appears. Sec. 227. Section 5(b)(1)(K) of the Retail Incentive Act of 2004, effective September 8, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-185; D.C. Official Code § 2-1217.74(b)(1)(K is amended by striking the phrase “retailers that co-locates” and inserting the phrase “retailers or unique entertainment attractions that co-locate” in its place. Sec. 228. Section 47-4613(a)(1) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “Title II” and inserting the phrase “Title II of the Rhode Island Metro Plaza Revenue Bonds Approval Act of 2008, effective April 2, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-140; 55 DCR 1870)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 27Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 229. Section 102(f) of the SafeRx Amendments Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-131; 55 DCR 1659 is amended by striking the phrase “section 745" and inserting the phase “section 744" in its place. Sec. 230. The Uniform Anatomical Gift Revision Act of 2008, effective April 15, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-145; 55 DCR 2532 is amended as follows a) Section 2(13) is amended by striking the phrase “section 2(6)” and inserting the phrase “section 2(a)(6)” in its place b) Section 8 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended by adding the word “section” before the number “9" and before the number “10 2) Subsection (d) is amended by adding the word “section” before the number “10 3) Subsection (f) is amended by adding the word “section” before the number “10 c) Section 9(a) is amended be adding the word “section” before the number “8 d) Section 11(j) is amended be adding the word “section” before the number “10 e) Section 26 is amended by adding a period at the end of the section heading f) Section 30 is amended by inserting the phrase “sections 2 through 29 of” before the phrase “the Uniform Anatomical Gift” wherever it appears. Sec. 231. Section 501(p) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3505.01(p is amended by striking the word “pursuant” and inserting the word “subject” in its place. Sec. 232. Section 2(a) of the Emergency Medical Services Improvement Amendment Act of 2008, effective April 15, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-147; 55 DCR 2558 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “Fire Department of the District of Columbia” and insert the phrase “Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department (“Department”)” in its place b) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase “Fire and Emergency Medical Services”. Sec. 233. Section 5 of the Commission on Fashion Arts and Events Establishment Act of 2008, effective April 15, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-148; 55 DCR 2219 is amended by striking the word “Events” and inserting the phrase “Events, established by section 2 of the Commission on Fashion Arts and Events Establishment Act of 2008, effective April 15, 2008 (D.C. Law 17- 148; 55 DCR 2219)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 28Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 234. Section 2(e)(1) of the Producer Licensing Amendment Act of 2008, effective May 13, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-155; 55 DCR 3683 is amended by adding the word “for” before the phrase “resident insurance”. Sec. 235. Section 5(b)(2)(A) of the Fire-Standard-Complaint Cigarettes Act of 2008, effective May 13, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-157; 55 DCR 3703 is amended by striking the colon at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place. Sec. 236. The Prohibition of Discrimination on the Basis of Gender Identity and Expression Amendment Act of 2008, effective June 25, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-177; 55 DCR 3696 is amended as follows a) Section 12(a)(1) is amended by striking the word “or” before the word “gender” b) Section 17(a) is amended by striking the section designation “(17A)” both times it appears and inserting the section designation “(7A)” in its place. Sec. 237. Section 2(3) of the Washington Convention Center Authority Advisory Committee Amendment Act of 2008, effective July 18, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-181; 55 DCR 6094 is amended by striking the semicolon both times it appears. Sec. 238. The Bicycle Policy Modernization Amendment Act of 2008, effective July 18, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-184; 55 DCR 6101 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended by adding the word “District” before the phrase “Department of Transportation” wherever it appears b) Subsection (b) is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “(1) Thirteen community” and insert the phrase “Thirteen community” in its place 2) Strike the phrase “(2) Each community” and insert the phrase “(2)(A) Each community” in its place 3) Strike the phrase “(3) The representative” and insert the phrase “(B) The representative” in its place c) Subsection (c)(2) is amended by adding the word “District” before the phrase “Department of Transportation” d) Subsection (d) is amended by adding the word “District” before the phrase “Department of Transportation”. Sec. 239. Section 6(e) of the District of Columbia Medical Liability Captive Insurance Agency Establishment Act of 2008, effective July 18, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-196; 55 DCR 6261 is amended by striking the phrase “section (f)” and inserting the phrase “subsection (f)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 29Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 240. The Child Abuse and Neglect Investigation Record Access Amendment Act of 2008, effective July 18, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-198; 55 DCR 6283 is amended as follows a) Section 2 is amended by striking the phrase “under Title I” and inserting the phrase “this title” in its place b) Section 3 is amended by adding a period after “(11)” the first time it appears. Sec. 241. Section 25-113(g) is amended by striking the subsection designation “(g)(4)” and inserting the paragraph designation “(4)” in its place. Sec. 242. Section 25-402(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Paragraph (6) is redesignated as paragraph (5 b) Paragraph (7) is redesignated as paragraph (6 c) Paragraph (8) is redesignated as paragraph (7 d) Paragraph (9) is redesignated as paragraph (8 e) Paragraph (10) is redesignated as paragraph (9 Sec. 243. Section 2(g) of the Department of Small and Local Business Development Subcontracting Clarification, Benefit Expansion, and Grant-making Authority Amendment Act of 2008, effective July 18, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-207; 55 DCR 6107 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph (1)” and inserting the phrase “The lead-in language” in its place b) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph (2)” and inserting the phrase “Paragraph (3)” in its place. Sec. 244. The Fiscal Year 2009 Budget Support Act of 2008, effective August 16, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-219; 55 DCR 7598 is amended as follows a) Section 1005 is amended by striking the section designation “1806j” both times it appears and inserting the section designation “1806k” in its place b) Section 2020 is amended by striking the section designation “1(a)(4)” both times it appears and inserting the section designation “1(b)(4)” in its place c) Section 5018(4) is amended by striking the phrase “D.C. Official Code § 7-751.16a” and inserting the phrase “D.C. Official Code § 7-751.15a” in its place d) Section 5033(e) is amended by striking the phrase “D.C. Official Code § 7-751.16a” and inserting the phrase “D.C. Official Code § 7-751.15a” in its place. Sec. 245. The Spam Deterrence Act of 2008, effective September 11, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-230; 55 DCR 8311 is amended as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 30Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 a) The long title is amended by striking the phrase “To prohibit” and inserting the phrase “To amend Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code to prohibit” in its place b) Strike the phrase “Sec. 2. Definitions.” and insert the following in its place: “Sec. 2. Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows: “(a) The table of contents for the title is amended by adding a new chapter after Chapter 49 to read as follows: “Chapter 50. Spam Deterrence. “§ 28-5001. Definitions. “§ 28-5002. Prohibitions. “§ 28-5003. Civil relief; damages.”. “(b) A new chapter 50 is added to read as follows: “Chapter 50. Spam Deterrence. “§ 28-5001.” c) Strike the phrase “Sec. 3.” and insert the section designation “§ 28-5002 in its place d) Strike the phrase “Sec. 4.” and insert the section designation “§ 28-5003.” in its place e) Strike the phrase “this act” wherever it appears and insert the phrase “this chapter” in its place f) Strike the phrase “D.C. Official Code § 28-3909" and insert the section designation “§ 28-3909" in its place. Sec. 246. Section 7 of the Compulsory/No Fault Motor Vehicle Insurance Act of 1982, effective September 18, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-155; D.C. Official Code § 31-2406(f)(B is amended by striking the phrase “insured denies coverage” and inserting the phrase “insurer denies coverage” in its place. Sec. 247. Section 3017 of the Fiscal Year 2006 Budget Support Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; 52 DCR 7503 is amended by striking the phrase “Paragraph 91A of section 8 of the An Act Making appropriations to provide for the expenses of the government of the District of Columbia for the fiscal year ending June thirtieth, nineteen hundred and fourteen, and for other purposes, approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 993; D.C. Official Code § 34-804(b))” and inserting the phrase “Section 1(b) of AN ACT To provide a People’s Counsel for the Public Service Commission in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved January 2, 1975 (88 Stat. 1975; D.C. Official Code § 34-804(b))” in its place. Sec. 248. Section 301(q) of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1- ENROLLED ORIGINAL 31Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 603.01 is amended as follows 1) Strike the word "and" at the end of paragraph (62 2) Strike the period at the end of paragraph (63) and insert the phrase and" in its place 3) A new paragraph (64) is added to read as follows 64) Office of Cable Television and Telecommunications Sec. 249. Section 2(f) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(f is amended as follows a) Paragraph (45) is amended by striking the phrase “; and” and inserting a semicolon in its place b) Paragraph (46) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place b) A new paragraph (47) is added to read as follows: “(47) The Commission on African Affairs, established by section 4 of the Office and Commission on African Affairs Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-111; D.C. Official Code § 2-1393).”. Sec. 250. The Parking Amendment Act of 2006, effective November 16, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-175; 53 DCR 6499 is amended as follows a) Section 3 is amended by striking the section citation "47-2892(c and inserting the section citation "47-2829(c in its place b) Section 5(a)(3) is amended by striking the phrase "where a wedding" and inserting the phrase "where a non-recurring event such as a wedding" in its place. Sec. 251. Section 9b(a)(2) of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.10(a)(2 is amended by striking the phrase "transferred or revert to the fund balance of" and inserting the phrase "transferred to" in its place. Sec. 252. Section 2102 of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended by striking the phrase "of $950,000 million" and inserting the phrase "of $950,000" in its place. Sec. 253. Section 206(a) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.06(a is amended by striking the phrase “June 6, 1006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-109 Petitions and voluntary agreements pending as of the effective date of the Rent Control Reform Amendment Act of 2006 2006, passed on 2nd reading on June 6, 1006” and inserting the phrase “June 6, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-109 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 32Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Petitions and voluntary agreements pending as of the effective date of the Rent Control Reform Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on June 6, 2006” in its place. Sec. 254. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by striking the phrase “47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.”and inserting the phrase “47-1075. Far Southeast Community Organization; Lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.” in its place b) Strike the phrase “§ 47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75 in square 5753.” and insert the phrase“47-1075. Far Southeast Community Organization; Lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.” in its place. Sec. 255. Section 3(c)(1)(A) of the Tobacco Settlement Trust Fund and Tobacco Settlement Financing Amendment Act of 2006, effective July 25, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-142; 53 DCR 4412 is amended by striking the phrase "District and" and inserting the phrase "District) and" in its place. Sec. 256. Section 5 of the Washington Stage Guild Tax Exemption Act of 2007, effective September 26, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-172; 53 DCR 6432 is amended as follows a) Strike the subsection designation “(a)” b) Subsection (b) is repealed. Sec. 257. Section 302 of the Medical Malpractice Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 14, 2007(D.C. Law 16-263; 54 DCR 807 is amended by striking the phrase “§16- 28223. Mediator costs and inserting the phrase “§ 16-2822. Mediator costs in its place. TITLE II. Sec. 301. Sections 2 and 3 of the Dishonored check Act of 2006, effective May 12, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-93; 53 DCR 1645 are amended to read as follows: “Sec. 2. Title 28 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new Chapter 31A to read as follows: “Chapter 31A “Dishonored Checks. “§ 28-3151. Definitions. “For the purposes of this chapter, the term “merchant” means a person who does or would sell, lease, or transfer, either directly or indirectly, consumer goods or services, or a person who does or would supply the goods or services which are or would be the subject matter of a trade practice. “§ 28-3152. Merchant’s civil recovery for dishonored checks. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 33Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(a) Any person who, for himself or herself, or for another person, with intent to defraud, makes, draws, utters, or delivers any check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money for goods or services upon any bank or other depository and knows or should have known that payment of the check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money for goods or services will be refused by the drawee bank or other depository, either because the drawer does not have sufficient funds in or credit with the bank or other depository, or the drawer, with intent to defraud, has ordered a stop payment on the check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money for goods or services, shall be civilly liable to the payee who has presented the check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money as provided in this section. “(b) A person shall be liable under subsection (a) of this section only if the check, draft, order, or other instrument for payment of money is dishonored and the drawer fails to pay the face amount of that check, draft, order, or other instrument for payment of money within 30 days following the mailing by the merchant of a written demand for payment as provided in subsection (f) of this section. “(c) Any person liable under subsection (a) of this section shall be liable to the merchant for the face amount of the check, and: “(1) Additional damages in the amount of 2 times the amount of the check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money, or $100, whichever is greater; “(2) Costs; and “(3) Reasonable attorney fees. “(d) The refusal of the drawee bank or other depository to make payment on a check, draft, order, or other instrument because the drawer does not have sufficient funds in or credit with the bank or other depository shall be prima facie evidence of the drawer’s intent to defraud and of knowledge of insufficient funds in or credit with such bank or other depository. “(e) The additional damages authorized under subsection (c)(1) of this section shall only be available to those merchants that post or otherwise give conspicuous notice at their place of business of the additional damages, including reference to the section of law authorizing the additional damages. “(f) The written demand for payment of the dishonored check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money required by subsection (b) of this section shall be in the form prescribed in subsection (g) of this section and shall be sent to the drawer's last known residence address and the last known place of business, if any, by first-class mail and by certified mail, return receipt requested with delivery restricted to the drawer, on or after the date the merchant received notice that the check, draft, order, or other instrument for the payment of money has been dishonored. “(g) The written demand for payment required by subsection (f) of this section shall be in substantially the following form and shall be printed in at least 10-point type: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 34Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “‘DEMAND FOR PAYMENT OF DISHONORED CHECK, DRAFT, ORDER, OR OTHER ‘INSTRUMENT FOR THE PAYMENT OF MONEY ‘Notice: You may be sued 30 days after this notice if you don't make payment within 30 days of this notice ‘DATE: ‘TO: Name of Drawer Last known residence address or place of business ‘YOUR CHECK, DRAFT, ORDER, OR OTHER INSTRUMENT FOR THE PAYMENT OF MONEY IN THE AMOUNT OF DATED PAYABLE TO THE ORDER OF HAS BEEN DISHONORED BY THE BANK/DEPOSITORY UPON WHICH IT WAS DRAWN, BECAUSE: ‘ YOU HAD NO ACCOUNT WITH THAT BANK/DEPOSITORY ‘ YOU HAD INSUFFICIENT FUNDS OR CREDIT WITH THAT BANK/DEPOSITORY ‘ A STOP PAYMENT ORDER WAS ISSUED ‘ OTHER (specify) ‘IF YOU DO NOT MAKE PAYMENT, YOU COULD BE SUED UNDER SECTION OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA OFFICIAL CODE TO RECOVER PAYMENT. IF JUDGMENT IS RENDERED AGAINST YOU IN COURT, IT MAY ALSO INCLUDE NOT ONLY THE ORIGINAL FACE AMOUNT OF THE CHECK, BUT ALSO ADDITIONAL DAMAGES, AS FOLLOWS: ‘(1) TWO TIMES THE FACE AMOUNT OF THE CHECK, OR $100, WHICHEVER IS GREATER; ‘(2) COSTS; AND ‘(3) REASONABLE ATTORNEY FEES. ‘NAME OF PAYEE: ‘(PHONE NUMBER) ‘ADDRESS TO WHICH PAYMENT SHOULD BE DELIVERED ‘IF YOU DISPUTE ANY OF THE FACTS LISTED ABOVE, CONTACT THE PAYEE IMMEDIATELY.’. “(h) The remedies provided by this chapter are in addition to civil remedies otherwise provided by law. “(i) The recovery of damages from the alleged offender shall not prohibit criminal prosecution of the alleged offender under § 22-1510. “(j) The recovery of civil damages by a merchant or a finding of liability under this act shall not be admissible in a criminal proceeding. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 35Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(k) A conviction or plea of guilty of making, drawing, or uttering a check, draft, order, or other instrument for payment of money with the intent to defraud under § 22-1510 is not a prerequisite to the maintenance of a civil action under this chapter.”. Sec. 302. Section 2142(a)(2) of the D.C. Housing Authority Rent Supplement Act of 2006, effective March 2, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-192; 53 DCR 6899 is amended to read as follows: “(2) “(19A) “Extremely-low income” means an individual or family whose gross income does not exceed 30% of the area median income. “(19B) “For-profit activities” means ancillary activities to the main activities of the District of Columbia Housing Authority, such as retail, commercial office, manufacturing, or recreational real property development activities undertaken by for-profit entities intended to support or contribute to the financial viability of Housing Properties, but does not include residential real property development activities Sec. 303. The District of Columbia Redevelopment Act of 1945, approved August 2, 1946 (60 Stat. 794; D.C. Official Code § 6-301.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 is repealed b) Section 5 is repealed c) Section 22 is repealed. Sec. 304. Section 2(f) of the Medicaid Benefits Protection Act of 1994, effective March 14, 1995 (D.C. Law 10-202; D.C. Official Code § 1-307.41(f is amended by striking the phrase “hospital and medical service plan as defined in section 2 of the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992, effective July 22, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Code § 35-1941(8))” and inserting the phrase “member insurer as defined in section 2 of the Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association Act of 1992, effective July 22, 1992 (D.C. Law 9-129; D.C. Official Code § 31-5401(8))” in its place. Sec. 305 a) Section 801 of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-138; 55 DCR 1689 is repealed b) This section shall be apply as of September 29, 2008. Sec. 306. Section 302(b) of the Pre-k Enhancement and Expansion Amendment Act of 2008, effective July 18, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-202; 55 DCR 6297 is amended by striking the phrase “an Act to fix and regulate the salaries of teachers, school officers, and other employees of the board of education of the District of Columbia, approved June 20, 1996 (34 Stat. 316; D.C. Official § 38-101 et seq.)” and inserting the phrase “law and regulation” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 36Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 307. Section 4 of the Initiative, Referendum, and Recall Procedures Act of 1979, effective June 7, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-1; D.C. Official Code § 1-1104.02 is repealed. Sec. 308. The District of Columbia Uniform Disclaimer of Property Interests Act of 1990, effective December 14, 1990 (D.C. Law 8-204; D.C. Official Code § 21-2091 et seq is repealed as of March 2, 2007. Sec. 309. The SafeRx Amendment Act of 2008, effective March 26, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-131; 55 DCR 1659 is amended as follows a) Section 102(b 55 DCR 1659) is amended by striking the word “biologic” and inserting the phrase “biologic for human use” in its place b) Section 202 (D.C. Official Code § 48-841.02) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “prescription drug” and inserting the phrase “prescription drug for human use” in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase “prescription drugs” and inserting the phrase “prescription drugs for human use” in its place. Sec. 310. Section 501(b) of the National Capital Revitalization Corporation and Anacostia Waterfront Corporation Reorganization Act of 2008 D.C. Law 17-138; D.C. Official Code § 2-1225.31(b is amended by striking the phrase “The Mayor” and inserting the phrase “The Mayor, after referral to the National Capital Planning Commission for a 30-day review period,” in its place. Sec. 311. The Accrued Sick and Safe Leave Act of 2008, effective May 13, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-152; D.C. Official Code § 32-131.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3(c D.C. Official Code § 32-131.02(c is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (3) is amended by striking the phrase “at the beginning of his or her employment. An employee may begin to access paid leave after 90 days of service with his or her employer” and inserting the phrase “when he or qualifies as an employee” in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is repealed b) Section 10 (D.C. Official Code § 32-131.09(c is amended by striking the phrase “in languages in accordance with the Language Access Act of 2004, effective June 19, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-167; D.C. Official Code § 2-1931 et seq ”. Sec. 312. The Office on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs Establishment Act of 2001, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 2-1371 et seq is amended as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 37Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 a) Section 305(e)(2 D.C. Official Code § 2-1374(e)(2 is amended by striking the phrase “the date a majority of the members are sworn in” and inserting the phrase “April 17, 2008” in its place b) Section 307 (D.C. Official Code § 32-1376) is amended to read as follows: “Sec. 307. Transition provisions. “(a) The Commission shall commence operations, and the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor’s Order 95-119 shall be abolished, on April 17, 2008. The members of the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor’s Order 95-119 shall hold over as members of the Commission until new members are appointed pursuant to section 305. “(b) All records and functions of the Commission on Asian and Pacific Islander Affairs established pursuant to Mayor’s Order 95-119 shall be transferred to the Commission on April 17, 2008.”. Sec. 313 Section 3(c) of the District of Columbia Commission for Women Act of 1978, effective September 22, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-109; D.C. Official Code § 3-702(c is amended by striking the phrase “‘with the advice and consent of the Council,”. Sec. 314. The first sentence of section 906(f)of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-139; D.C. Official Code § 1-609.06(f is amended to read as follows f) Subsections (a) through (e) of this section shall not apply to any person applying for, or accepting, a position in the Excepted Service as an attorney prior to the effective date of the Technical Amendments Act of 2008, passed on 2nd reading on December 16, 2008 (Enrolled version of Bill 17-994 Sec. 315. Section 4 of the Retail Service Station Amendment Act of 2000, effective June 24, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-130; 47 DCR 2688 is repealed. Sec. 316. Section 17 of the Nurse's Rehabilitation Program Act of 2000, effective May 1, 2001 (D.C. Law 13-297; D.C. Official Code § 3-1251.16 is repealed. Sec. 317. Section 22a of the Health Services Planning Program Re-establishment Act of 1996, effective June 5, 2003 (D.C. Law 14-307; D.C. Official Code § 44-422 is repealed. Sec. 318. The Living Wage Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-118; D.C. Official Code § 2-220.01 passim is amended as follows a) Section 103(e D.C. Official Code § 2-220.03(e is repealed. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 38Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) Section 203(f D.C. Official Code § 32-752(f) is amended by striking the phrase "Subject to the availability of funds, the" and inserting the word “The” in its place. Sec. 319. Section 6 of the District Department of Transportation DC Circulator Amendment Act of 2006, effective March 6, 2007 (D.C. Law 16-225; 53 DCR 10232 is repealed. Sec. 320. Section 401 of the Rhode Island Metro Plaza Revenue Bonds Approval Act of 2008, effective April 2, 2008 (D.C. Law 17-140; D.C. Official Code § 47-4613, note is repealed. TITLE III. Sec. 401. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02©)(3 Sec. 402 Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-602.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
