<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 17-67">
  <num type="law">17-67</num>
  <heading type="short">Doubled Fines in Construction or Work Zones Amendment Act of 2007</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2008-01-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/17-67.pdf">D.C. Law 17-67</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 11646</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B17-0108">
      <narrative>Law 17-67, the “Doubled Fines in Construction or Work Zones Amendment Act of 2007”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 17-108 which was referred to the Committee on Public Works and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 23, 2007, and November 6, 2007, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 19, 2007, it was assigned Act No. 17-179 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 17-67 became effective on January 23, 2008.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925 to provide for double fines, or increased criminal penalties, for traffic moving infractions when committed in a work zone, and to require the display of signs alerting drivers to the increased fines and penalties. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Doubled Fines in Construction or Work Zones Amendment Act of 2007”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Traffic Act, 1925, approved March 3, 1925 (43 Stat. 1119; D.C. Official Code § 50-2201.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 50-2202) is amended by adding a new paragraph (o) to read as follows: “(o) The term “work zone” means the area of a highway or roadway that is affected by construction, maintenance, or utility work activities, including the area delineated by and within all traffic control devices erected or installed to guide vehicular, pedestrian, and bicycle traffic.” b) A new section 9c is added to read as follows: “Sec. 9c. Motor vehicle moving infractions in work zones; signage required. “(a) For any motor vehicle moving infraction, as defined in Chapter 26 of Title 18 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, committed by the driver within a work zone, during any time when traffic is regulated or restricted through or around the zone, when work is actually being performed in the zone by workers acting in their official capacity, the civil fine shall be double the amount otherwise prescribed and, in a criminal infraction case, the fine shall be one category higher than the penalty prescribed by law. “(b) Signs or notices shall be affixed at the point of ingress of constriction or work zones alerting drivers of doubled fines and increased penalties for moving infractions within the zone.”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2008 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Note, § 50-2202 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
