<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-11">
  <num type="law">18-11</num>
  <heading type="short">Practice of Occupational Therapy Amendment Act of 2009</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2009-07-07</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-11.pdf">D.C. Law 18-11</citation>
      <citation type="register">56 DCR 3602</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0032">
      <narrative>Law 18-11, the “Practice of Occupational Therapy Amendment Act of 2009”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-32 which was referred to the Committee on Health. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on March 3, 2009, and April 7, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on April 28, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-55 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-11 became effective on July 7, 2009.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to amend the definition of the practice of occupational therapy, to provide for the regulation of dance therapy and recreation therapy by the Board of Occupational Therapy, to substitute a recreation therapist for an occupational therapy assistant on the Board of Occupational Therapy, and to update educational requirements. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Practice of Occupational Therapy Amendment Act of 2009”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102(9 D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.02(9 is amended as follows 1) Subparagraph (A) is amended to read as follows: “(A) “Practice of occupational therapy” means: “(i) The therapeutic use of everyday life activities with individuals or groups, with or without compensation, for the purpose of participation in roles and situations in homes, schools, workplaces, communities, and other settings to promote health and welfare for those who have or are at risk for developing an illness, injury, disease, disorder, condition, impairment, disability, activity limitation, or participation restriction; “(ii) Addressing the physical, cognitive, psycho-social, sensory, or other aspects of performance in a variety of contexts to support engagement in everyday life activities that affect health, well-being, and quality of life; “(iii) The education and training of persons in the direct care of patients through the use of occupational therapy; and “(iv) The education and training of persons in the field of occupational therapy.” 2) Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the phrase “supervision of or in consultation with a licensed occupational therapist” and inserting the phrase “general Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Summer Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 3-1201.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. supervision of a licensed occupational therapist” in its place 3) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the phrase “only under the direct supervision of an occupational therapist,” and inserting the phrase “under the immediate supervision of a licensed occupational therapist or licensed occupational therapy assistant,” in its place b) Section 206 (D.C. Official Code § 3-1202.06) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: “(b) The Board shall regulate the practice of occupational therapy and the practice by occupational therapy assistants, dance therapists, and recreation therapists.” 2) Subsection (c) is amended by striking the phrase “1 shall be an occupational therapy assistant licensed in the District,” and inserting the phrase “one shall be a recreation therapist registered in the District,” in its place c) Section 504(g D.C. Official Code § 3-1205.04(g is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1)(A) is amended to read as follows: “(A) Has successfully completed an entry-level occupational therapy educational program accredited by the Accreditation Council for Occupational Therapy Education (“ACOTE” and” 2) Paragraph (2)(A) is amended to read as follows: “(A) An individual applying for a license to practice as an occupational therapy assistant under this act shall establish to the satisfaction of the Board of Occupational Therapy that the individual has successfully completed an occupational therapy assistant educational program accredited by ACOTE; and” 3) Paragraph (3) is repealed. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Amend § 3-1202.06 Amend § 3-1205.04 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
