<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-291">
  <num type="law">18-291</num>
  <heading type="short">2323 Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast Redevelopment Project Real Property Limited Tax Abatement Assistance Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2011-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-291.pdf">D.C. Law 18-291</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 11508</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0628">
      <narrative>Law 18-291, the “2323 Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast Redevelopment Project Real Property Limited Tax Abatement Assistance Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-628, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 5, 2010, and November 9, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 19, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-612 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-291 became effective on March 8, 2011.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 46 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide a limited real property tax abatement to the 2323 Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E redevelopment project, described as Lot 0055, Square 5560, in the Fairlawn area of Ward 8. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “2323 Pennsylvania Avenue Southeast Redevelopment Project Real Property Limited Tax Abatement Assistance Act of 2010 Sec. 2. Chapter 46 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows: “47-4638. 2323 Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E redevelopment project.” (b) A new section 47-4638 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-4638. 2323 Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E redevelopment project. “ The tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title with respect to the real property previously described as Lots 19, 20, 54, 802, 803, 810, and 811, Square 5560, and currently described as Lot 0055, Square 5560, and any improvements thereto, shall be abated for 10 years, beginning October 1, 2011, to the extent that it exceeds the amount of the tax imposed on the real property for tax year 2009.”. Sec. 3. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of it fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2011 Winter Supp. New § 47-4638 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
