<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-292">
  <num type="law">18-292</num>
  <heading type="short">Thirteenth Church of Christ Real Property Tax Relief and Exemption Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2011-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-292.pdf">D.C. Law 18-292</citation>
      <citation type="register">57 DCR 11510</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0776">
      <narrative>Law 18-292, the “Thirteenth Church of Christ Real Property Tax Relief and Exemption Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-776, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 5, 2010, and November 9, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 19, 2010, it was assigned Act No. 18-613 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-292 became effective on March 8, 2011.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 46 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to exempt from taxation certain property of the Thirteenth Church of Christ, a tax-exempt organization, described as Lots 0169 through 0187, Square 5969, located at 3418 4th Street, S.E.,Ward 8; and to provide equitable real property tax relief. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Thirteenth Church of Christ Real Property Tax Relief and Exemption Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. Chapter 46 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding a new section designation to read as follows: “47-4644. Thirteenth Church of Christ real property tax relief.” b) A new section 47-4644 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-4644. Thirteenth Church of Christ real property tax relief. “(a) The real property, described as Lots 0169 through 0187, Square 5969, shall be exempt from the tax imposed by Chapter 8 of this title as long as the real property is owned by the Thirteenth Church of Christ and the Thirteenth Church of Christ retains its tax- exempt status under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. § 501(c)(3 “(b) The tax relief pursuant to this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other tax relief or development assistance from any other source applicable to the Thirteenth Church of Christ.”. Sec. 3. Equitable real property tax relief. The Council orders that all unpaid real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against real property described as Lots 0169 through 0187, Square 5969 since June 1, 2007, through the 1st day of the month following the effective date of this act, be forgiven, and that any payment already made for this period be refunded. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2011 Winter Supp. New § 47-4644 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition Sec. 4. Applicability. This act shall apply upon the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
