<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-377">
  <num type="law">18-377</num>
  <heading type="short">Criminal Code Amendment Act of 2010</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2011-06-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-377.pdf">D.C. Law 18-377</citation>
      <citation type="register">58 DCR 1174</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0963">
      <narrative>Law 18-377, the “Criminal Code Amendment Act of 2010”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-963, which was referred to the Committee on Public Safety and the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 7, 2010, and December 21, 2010, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on February 2, 2011, it was assigned Act No. 18-722 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-377 became effective on June 3, 2011.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975 to establish that the penalty is solely civil for failure of a registrant to notify the Chief of Police of changes in material information regarding the registration, to delay the requirement to microstamp pistols to January 1, 2013, and to clarify that gun offenders convicted at any time, who fall within the registration requirement’s time period, shall register with the gun offender registry; to amend section 12-311 of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify that the statute of limitations in asbestos injury cases is the later of either 3 years or one year after disability or death; to amend Chapter 7 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code to establish that a judgment of restitution or reparation is enforceable in the same manner as a civil judgment, and may be enforced by the United States Attorney, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, as well as the victim and other beneficiaries; to amend section 16-1005 of the District of Columbia Official Code to add language regarding animal cruelty in intrafamily offenses; to amend section 16- 2320.01 of the District of Columbia Official Code to establish that a judgment of restitution or reparation is enforceable in the same manner as a civil judgment, and may be enforced by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, as well as the victim and other beneficiaries; to amend section 16-2333 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow public inspection of law enforcement records that pertain to a civil Notice of Violation; to amend An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia to clarify the threshold for felony theft; to amend the Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Amendment Act of 2009 to establish a misdemeanor prohibition for tampering with a GPS bracelet or electronic monitoring device, to include radio frequency identification systems, and to include incarcerated individuals; to amend the Indeterminate Sentence Act to prohibit a juvenile from escaping from an institution or facility in which the juvenile was placed by the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services; to amend An Act To prohibit the introduction of contraband into the District of Columbia penal institutions to clarify that the law applies to a cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto; to amend the Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of 1994 to establish a criminal penalty for arranging for a sexual act or contact with a real or fictitious child; to amend the District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2011 Summer Supp. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. of 1982 to revise the financial thresholds for certain crimes involving property obtained, lost, or stolen; to amend An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes to clarify a provision; to amend section 23-546 of the District of Columbia Official Code to increase the financial thresholds for the offenses of destruction of property, receiving stolen property, and theft of property; to amend section 23-581 of the District of Columbia Official Code to establish a warrantless arrest for the offense of misdemeanor sexual abuse; to amend section 23-1301 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide the correct name for the Pretrial Services Agency for the District of Columbia; to amend the Youth Rehabilitation Act of 1985 to require gun offender registration for a youth whose conviction for a gun offense was set aside under the act; to amend the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001 to clarify jurisdiction of rental housing cases; to amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to clarify rulemaking authority of the Rental Housing Commission relating to rental housing cases under jurisdiction of the Office of Administrative Hearings; and to require a person selling 5 or more motor vehicles in one year to record certain identification data relating to the purchase. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Criminal Code Amendment Act of 2010”. Sec. 2. The Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, effective September 24, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-85; D.C. Official Code § 7-2501.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 203 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.03) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (4)(D) is amended to read as follows: “(D) Intrafamily offense, including any similar provision of the law of any other jurisdiction;” B) Paragraph (9) is amended by striking the word “pistol” and inserting the word “firearm” in its place C) Paragraph (14) is amended by striking the phrase “section 209(b)” and inserting the phrase “section 208" in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (3) is amended to read as follows: “(3) The present business or occupation of the applicant and the address and phone number of the employer;” B) Paragraph (8) is repealed b) Section 207a (D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.07a) is amended by striking the phrase “section 203" wherever it appears and inserting the phrase “section 203(a)” in its place. Amend § 7-2502.03 Amend § 7-2502.07a ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 c) Section 208 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.08) is amended to read as follows: “Sec. 208. Duties of registrants. “(a) Each person or organization holding a registration certificate (for purposes of this section, “registrant”) shall: “(1) Notify the Chief in writing of the loss, theft, or destruction of the registration certificate or of a registered firearm (including the circumstances, if known) immediately upon discovery of such loss, theft, or destruction; “(2) Notify the Chief in writing within 30 days of a change in the registrant’s name or address as it appears on the registration certificate; “(3) Notify the Chief in writing of the sale, transfer, or other disposition of the firearm within 2 business days of such sale, transfer, or other disposition. The notification shall include: “(A) The identification of the registrant, the firearm, and the serial number of the registration certificate; “(B) The name, address, and date of birth of the person to whom the firearm has been sold or transferred; and “(C) Whether the firearm was sold or how it was otherwise transferred or disposed of. “(b) Each registrant shall return to the Chief the registration certificate for any firearm which is lost, stolen, destroyed, sold, or otherwise transferred or disposed of, at the time the registrant notifies the Chief of such loss, theft, destruction, sale, transfer, or other disposition. “(c) Each registrant shall have in the registrant’s possession, whenever in possession of a firearm, the registration certificate, or exact photocopy thereof, for such firearm, and exhibit the same upon the demand of a member of the Metropolitan Police Department, or other law enforcement officer. “(d) The duties set forth in subsections (a) through (c) of this section are in addition to any other requirements imposed by this act or other applicable law. “(e)(1) A registrant shall be subject to a civil fine of $100 for the first violation or omission of the duties and requirements imposed by this section. “(2) A registrant shall be subject to a civil fine of $500 for the second violation or omission of the duties and requirements imposed by this section, a registrant’s registration certificates shall be revoked, and the registrant shall be prohibited from possessing or registering any firearm for a period of 5 years. “(3) A registrant shall be subject to a civil fine of $1,000 for the third violation or Amend § 7-2502.08 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. omission of the duties and requirements imposed by this section, a registrant’s registration certificates shall be revoked, and the registrant shall be prohibited from possessing or registering any firearm. “(4) For the purposes of this subsection, “a violation or omission” that applies to multiple firearms shall constitute a single violation or omission if the violation or omission pertaining to each firearm arose from the same occurrence. “(5) The penalties prescribed in section 706 shall not apply to a violation or omission of the duties and requirements imposed by this section.” d) Section 209 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2502.09) is amended is follows 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “section 203" and inserting the phrase “section 203(a)” in its place 2) Subsection (b) is repealed e) Section 408(b D.C. Official Code § 7-2504.08(b is amended by striking the phrase “January 1, 2011” wherever it appears and inserting the phrase “January 1, 2013” in its place f) Section 503 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2505.03) is amended by striking the phrase “January 1, 2011” wherever it appears and inserting the phrase “January 1, 2013” in its place g) Section 801 (D.C. Official Code § 7-2508.01) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the word “Convicted” and inserting the phrase “Convicted at any time” in its place B) Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the word “Convicted” and inserting the phrase “Convicted at any time” in its place 2) Paragraph (3) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting the phrase “, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses;” in its place B) Subparagraph (B) is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting the phrase “, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit any of the foregoing offenses;” in its place h) Section 802(a D.C. Official Code § 7-2508.02(a is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended as follows A) The lead-in text is amended by striking the phrase “48 hours of:” and inserting the phrase “48 hours (not including a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or day on which the District of Columbia government is closed) of:” in its place B) Subparagraph (C) is amended to read as follows: “(C) Receipt of notice of the obligation to register, if at a time other than sentencing; or” 2) Paragraph 2(I) is repealed. Amend § 7-2502.09 Amend § 7-2504.08 Amend § 7-2505.03 Amend § 7-2508.01 Amend § 7-2508.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 i) Section 804(d)(1 D.C. Official Code § 7-2508.04(d)(1 is amended to read as follows: “(d)(1) For a person who has not been required to comply with the requirements of this title as set forth in subsections (a) and (c) of this section, but who nevertheless qualifies and is within the period for which registration is required by this title, the Court may, upon motion of the government, enter an order certifying that a person convicted of a gun offense is a gun offender and issue an order requiring the gun offender to register and to comply with the provisions of this title.”. Sec. 3. Section 12-311(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word “or” at the end b) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; or” in its place c) A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows: “(3) Three years from the time the right to maintain the action accrues.”. Sec. 4. Chapter 7 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows 1) The table of contents is amended by adding the phrase “16-711.01. Restitution or reparation – enforcement.” after the phrase “16-711 Restitution or reparation.” 2) A new section 16-711.01 is added to read as follows: “16-711.01. Restitution or reparation – enforcement. “(a) An order of restitution or reparation requiring a person convicted of the criminal conduct to pay restitution or reparation constitutes a judgment and lien against all property of a liable defendant for the amount the defendant is obligated to pay under the order and may be recorded in any office for the filing of liens against real or personal property. “(b) A judgment of restitution or reparation may be enforced by the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, a victim entitled under the order to receive restitution or reparation, a deceased victim’s estate, or any other beneficiary of the judgment in the same manner as a civil judgment. “(c) The court shall provide each victim in a criminal case with a notarized and sealed copy of the Order of Restitution or Reparation. “(d) The name and address of the victim shall not be disclosed to the defendant or any representative of the defendant.”. Sec. 5. Section 16-1005(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The lead-in language is amended by striking the phrase “criminal offense against the petitioner,” and inserting the phrase “criminal offense against the petitioner or against Amend § 7-2508.04 Amend § 12-311 Amend § 16-1005 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. petitioner’s animal or an animal in petitioner’s household,” in its place b) A new paragraph (10A) is added to read as follows: “(10A) Directs the care, custody, or control of a domestic animal that belongs to petitioner or respondent or lives in his or her household;”. Sec. 6. Chapter 23 of Title 16 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Section 16-2320.01 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (g) is amended by adding a sentence at the end to read as follows: “The Director of Social Services shall inform the Division of the progress or status of the restitution payments.” 2) New subsections (j k l m n o p and (q) are added to read as follows: “(j) When entering a restitution order, the court shall include the restitution conditions both in the disposition order and in a separate judgement of restitution which shall be filed in a special proceedings case. An order requiring an adult to pay a judgment for restitution shall be filed in a special proceedings case. “(k) An order of restitution requiring a parent or guardian, a child, or both to pay restitution constitutes a judgment and lien against all property of the person or persons required to pay for the amount they are obligated to pay under the order and may be recorded in any office for the filing of liens against real or personal property. “(l) A judgment of restitution may be enforced by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, a victim entitled under the order to receive restitution, a deceased victim’s estate, or any other beneficiary of the judgment in the same manner as a civil judgment. “(m) A judgment for restitution that is filed in a special proceedings case shall contain the following information: “(1) The amount of the restitution; and “(2) The terms of the restitution, including the length of time in which restitution payments will be made and the amount of the installment payments. “(n) The court shall provide each victim in a juvenile case with a notarized and sealed copy of the Order of Restitution or Reparation. “(o) In addition to the information that is included in a judgment for restitution filed in a special proceedings case, the Division shall provide the following information in a supplemental information form attached to the order. This information shall be kept confidential except by order of the Division: “(1) The full name, address, telephone number, and social security number of the restitution payer or person who is ordered to pay the restitution; and “(2) The full name, address, and telephone number of the recipient of the restitution. “(p) All restitution payments shall be paid to the Superior Court. The payer shall Amend § 16-2320.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. receive a receipt for the payment. If the restitution payment is mailed, a receipt will be returned only if the payer encloses a self-addressed stamped envelope. “(q) The court shall disburse the restitution payments to the recipient and make appropriate court records.” b) Section 16-2333(a) is amended by adding a new paragraph (1A) to read as follows: “(1A) The record pertains to a civil Notice of Violation;”. Sec. 7. Section 848 of An Act To establish a code of law for the District of Columbia, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1321; D.C. Official Code § 22-303 is amended as follows a) Strike the phrase “value of $200 or more ” and insert the phrase “value of $1,000 or more” in its place b) Strike the phrase “if the value of the property be less than $200” and insert the phrase “if the property has some value” in its place. Sec. 8. Section 103(a) of the Omnibus Public Safety and Justice Amendment Act of 2009, effective December 10, 2009 (D.C. Law 18-88; D.C. Official Code § 22-1211 is amended as follows a) Paragraph (1) is amended by inserting the phrase “, or who is required to wear a device while incarcerated,” after the phrase “or commitment” b) Paragraph (2) is amended by inserting the phrase “or radio frequency identification” after the phrase “global positioning system”. Sec. 9. Section 8 of the Indeterminate Sentence Act, approved July 15, 1932 (47 Stat. 698; D.C. Official Code § 22-2601 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the word “or” at the end 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; or” in its place 3) A new paragraph (3) is added to read as follows: “(3) An institution or facility, whether located in the District of Columbia or elsewhere, in which a person committed to the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services is placed.” b) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase “original sentence.” and inserting the phrase “original sentence or disposition for the offense for which he or she was confined, committed, or in custody at the time of his or her escape.” in its place. Sec. 10. An Act To prohibit the introduction of contraband into the District of Columbia penal institutions, approved December 15, 1941 (55 Stat. 800; D.C. Official Code § 22-2603.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 22-2603.01) is amended as follows: Amend § 16-2333 Amend § 22-303 Amend § 22-1211 Amend § 22-2601 Amend § 22-2603.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 8Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows: “(1) “Cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto” means any device carried, worn, or stored that is designed, intended, or readily converted to create, receive or transmit oral or written messages or visual images, access or store data, or connect electronically to the Internet, or any other electronic device that enables communication in any form. The term “cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto” includes portable 2-way pagers, hand-held radios, cellular telephones, Blackberry-type devices, personal digital assistants or PDAs, computers, cameras, and any components of these devices. The term “cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto” also includes any new technology that is developed for communication purposes and includes accessories that enable or facilitate the use of the cellular telephone or other portable communication device.” 2) Paragraph (3)(A)(iii) is amended to read as follows: “(iii) A cellular telephone or other portable communication device and accessories thereto.” b) Section 3(e)(1 D.C. Official Code § 22-2603.02(e)(1 is amended by striking the phrase “portable communication device” and inserting the phrase “portable communication device and accessories thereto” in its place. Sec. 11. The Anti-Sexual Abuse Act of 1994, effective May 23, 1995 (D.C. Law 10- 257; D.C. Official Code § 22-3001 et seq is amended as follows a) A new section 209b is added to read as follows: “Sec. 209b. Arranging for a sexual contact with a real or fictitious child. “(a) It is unlawful for a person to arrange to engage in a sexual act or sexual contact with an individual (whether real or fictitious) who is or who is represented to be a child at least 4 years younger than the person, or to arrange for another person to engage in a sexual act or sexual contact with an individual (whether real or fictitious) who is or who is represented to be a child of at least 4 years younger than the person. For the purposes of this section, arranging to engage in a sexual act or sexual contact with an individual who is fictitious shall be unlawful only if the arrangement is done by or with a law enforcement officer. “(b) A person who violates subsection (a) of this section shall be imprisoned for not more than 5 years, fined an amount not to exceed $50,000, or both.” b) Section 210(b D.C. Official Code § 22-3011(b is amended as follows 1) Strike the phrase “Marriage between the defendant and the child” and insert the phrase “Marriage or domestic partnership between the defendant and the child” in its place 2) Strike the word “child” wherever it appears and insert the phrase “child or minor” in its place. Sec. 12. The District of Columbia Theft and White Collar Crimes Act of 1982, effective December 1, 1982 (D.C. Law 4-164; D.C. Official Code § 22-3201 et seq is amended as Amend § 22-2603.02 Amend § 22-3011 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 9Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. follows a) Section 122 (D.C. Official Code § 22-3222) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrsae “$250” and inserting the phrase “$1,000” in its place B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “if the value of the property obtained or lost was less than $250” and inserting the phrase “if the property obtained or lost has some value” in its place 2) Subsection (b) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “was $250” and inserting the phrase “is $1,000” in its place B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “if the value of the property which was the object of the scheme or systematic course of conduct was less than $250” and inserting the phrase “if the property that was the object of the scheme or systematic course of conduct has some value” in its place b) Section 125b (D.C. Official Code § 22-3225.02) is amended by striking the phrase “$250” and inserting the phrase “$1,000” in its place c) Section 125c (D.C. Official Code § 22-3225.03) is amended by striking the phrase “$250” and inserting the phrase “$1,000” in its place d) Section 127c(b D.C. Official Code § 22-3227.03(b is amended by striking the phrase “the value of ” e) Section 132(c D.C. Official Code § 22-3232(c is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “$250” and inserting the phrase “$1000” in its place 2) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “if the value of the stolen property is less than $250” and inserting the phrase “if the stolen property has some value” in its place f) Section 133(b)(2 D.C. Official Code § 22-3233(b)(2 is amended by striking the phrase $250” and inserting the phrase “$1,000” in its place g) Section 142(b)(3 D.C. Official Code § 22-3242(b)(3 is amended by striking the phrase “$250” and inserting the phrase “$1,000” in its place. Sec. 13. Section 3(a)(5)(C) of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 650; D.C. Official Code § 22- 4503(a)(5)(C is amended by striking the phrase “(as provided in § 16- 1005(c)(10)”. Sec. 14. Section 23-546(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows: Amend § 22-3222 Amend § 22-3225.02 Amend § 22-3225.03 Amend § 22-3227.03 Amend § 22-3232 Amend § 22-3233 Amend § 22-3242 Amend § 22-4503 Amend § 23-546 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 10Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 a) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “value in excess of $200” and inserting the phrase “value in excess of “$1000” in its place b) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the phrase “value in excess of $250” wherever it appears and inserting the phrase “value in excess of “$1000” in its place. Sec. 15. Section 23-581 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (a-7) to read as follows: “(a-7) A law enforcement officer may arrest a person without a warrant if the officer has probable cause to believe the person has committed the offense of misdemeanor sexual abuse or misdemeanor sexual abuse of a child or minor as provided in sections 22-3006 and 22- 3010.01).”. Sec. 16. Section 23-1301 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “District of Columbia Pretrial Services Agency” and inserting the phrase “Pretrial Services Agency for the District of Columbia” in its place. Sec. 17. Section 7(f) of the Youth Rehabilitation Act of 1985, effective December 7, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-69; D.C. Official Code § 24-906(f is amended as follows a) Paragraph (5) is amended by striking the word “or” at the end b) Paragraph (6) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon in its place c) New paragraphs (7) and (8) are added to read as follows: “(7) For gun offender registration pursuant to Title 8 of the Firearms Control Regulations Act of 1975, effective September 24, 1976 (D.C. Law 1-85; D.C. Official Code § 7- 2508.01 et seq for convictions on or after January 1, 2011; or “(8) In determining whether a person has been in possession of a firearm in violation of An Act To control the possession, sale, transfer, and use of pistols and other dangerous weapons in the District of Columbia, to provide penalties, to prescribe rules of evidence, and for other purposes, approved July 8, 1932 (47 Stat. 650; D.C. Official Code § 22- 4503).”. Sec. 18. Section 8(a)(7) of the Office of Administrative Hearings Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code § 2-1831.05(a)(7 is amended by inserting the phrase “(including rental housing cases within the jurisdiction of the Office)” after the phrase “cases before the Office”. Sec. 19. Section 202(a)(1) of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3502.02(a)(1 is amended by inserting the phrase “except rules and procedures subject to section 8(a)(7) of the Office of Administrative Hearings Amend § 23-581 Amend § 23-1301 Amend § 24-906 Amend § 2-1831.05 Amend § 42-3502.02 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 11Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Establishment Act of 2001, effective March 6, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-76; D.C. Official Code § 2- 1831.05(a)(7))” after the phrase “of this act”. Sec. 20. Required records for sale of 5 or more motor vehicles in one year. A person or auctioneer who sells or arranges the sale of 5 or more motor vehicles in one year in the District of Columbia shall record the name, address, and license number of the buyer, the vehicle identification number, and the identity of the original owner of the vehicle within 24 hours of purchase. This record shall be available to the Mayor and the Chief of Police. For the purposes of this section, the term “license” means a motor vehicle operator’s permit or commercial driver’s license. Sec. 21. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 22. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 60-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(2) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(2 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>20</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§50-1501.31"/>
  </section>
</document>
