<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 18-63">
  <num type="law">18-63</num>
  <heading type="short">Placement of Orders with District Departments, Offices, and Agencies Amendment Act of 2009</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2009-10-22</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/18-63.pdf">D.C. Law 18-63</citation>
      <citation type="register">56 DCR 6601</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B18-0004">
      <narrative>Law 18-63, the “Placement of Orders with District Departments, Offices, and Agencies Amendment Act of 2009”, as introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 18-4, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations and the Environment. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 30, 2009, and July 14, 2009, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 28, 2009, it was assigned Act No. 18-159 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 18-63 became effective on October 22, 2009.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act To grant additional powers to the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes to authorize District departments, offices, and agencies to place orders with any other department, office, or agency of the District for materials, supplies, equipment, work, or services of any kind that such requisitioned department, office, or agency may be in a position to supply or equipped to render without the prior approval of the Office of Contracting and Procurement, and to require the Mayor to submit annually a report for all such orders. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Placement of Orders with District Departments, Offices, and Agencies Amendment Act of 2009”. Sec. 2. The first sentence of section 1(k)(1) of An Act To grant additional powers to the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes, approved December 20, 1944 (58 Stat. 819; D.C. Official Code § 1-301.01(k)(1 is amended to read as follows: “The Mayor may authorize the heads of District departments, offices, and agencies to place orders with any other department, office, or agency of the District for materials, supplies, equipment, work, or services of any kind that the requisitioned department, office, or agency may be in a position to supply or equipped to render; provided, that the Mayor shall submit annually to the Council a report of all Memoranda of Understanding between District agencies involving an exchange of materials, supplies, equipment, work, or services of any kind.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2009 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 1-301.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
