<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-111</num>
  <heading>Property held by fiduciaries.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>All intangible personal property and any income or increment thereon, held in a fiduciary capacity for the benefit of another person, is presumed abandoned unless the owner, within 3 years after it becomes payable or distributable, has increased or decreased the principal, accepted payment of principal or income, corresponded in writing concerning the property, or otherwise indicated an interest as evidenced by a memorandum on file with the fiduciary.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>For the purpose of this section, if a person holds property as an agent for a business association, the agent is deemed to hold the property in a fiduciary capacity for that business association unless the agreement between the agent and the business association provides otherwise.</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(c)</num>
    <text>For the purposes of this chapter, if a person is deemed to hold property in a fiduciary capacity for a business association alone, that person is the holder of the property only insofar as the interest of the business association in the property is concerned and the business association is the holder of the property insofar as the interest of any other person in the property is concerned.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-160">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-160, § 111, 27 DCR 5150</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-161">Sept. 29, 1992, D.C. Law 9-161, § 2(i), 39 DCR 5696</annotation>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 1701(g), 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="41-130">41-130</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 42-211.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Temporary Amendment of Section</heading>
      <annotation>Section 1701(g) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</cite> substituted “3 years” for “5 years” in (a).</annotation>
      <annotation>Section 2001(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Emergency Legislation</heading>
      <annotation>For temporary amendment of section, see § 1701(g) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-152, October 17, 1997,  44 DCR 6196), and see § 1701(g) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-239, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 508).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 12 of the Uniform Unclaimed Property Act (1981 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
