<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-202</num>
  <heading>Disposal of void or lapsed instruments; termination statement; exceptions.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>Unless the Recorder of Deeds has notice of an action pending relative thereto, he may remove from the files and destroy:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>An instrument filed in his office pursuant to Chapter 12 of Title 50, which has become void or lapsed, and which has been void or lapsed for 1 year or more, together with any affidavit, release, assignment, or continuation or termination statement relating thereto;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>A lapsed financing statement, a lapsed continuation statement, a statement of assignment or release relating to either, filed pursuant to part 4 of Article 9 of Subtitle I of Title 28, and any index of any of them, 1 year or more after lapse of the financing statement and every continuation statement related thereto; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>A termination statement filed pursuant to § <cite root="28:9-404">28:9-404</cite>, and the index on which it is noted, 1 year or more after the filing of the termination statement.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>Subsection (a) of this section does not apply to a bill of sale, mortgage, deed of trust, conditional sale of, financing statement or security agreement covering, railroad rolling stock.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation>Mar. 3, 1901, ch. 854, § 546-D</annotation>
      <annotation>June 5, 1952, 66 Stat. 126, ch. 370, § 3</annotation>
      <annotation>June 18, 1953, 67 Stat. 64, ch. 126, § 1</annotation>
      <annotation>Dec. 30, 1963, 77 Stat. 772, Pub. L. 88-243, § 11</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Cross References</heading>
      <annotation>Fees, see § <cite root="42-1210">42-1210</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite root="42-1210">42-1210</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 42-102.</annotation>
      <annotation>1973 Ed., § 42-104.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
