<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-105</num>
  <heading>Conditions precedent to presumption of abandonment of traveler’s checks and money orders.</heading>
  <text>Any sum payable on a money order, traveler’s check, or similar written instrument (other than a 3rd party bank check) on which a banking or financial organization or a business association is directly liable is presumed abandoned if the appropriate conditions leading to a presumption of abandonment as described in §§ <cite path="§41-103">41-103</cite> and <cite path="§41-104">41-104</cite> are satisfied and:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>The books and records of the banking or financial organization or business association show that the money order, traveler’s check, or similar written instrument was purchased in the District;</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>The banking or financial organization or the business association has its principal place of business in the District and the books and records of the business association do not show the state in which the money order, traveler’s check, or similar written instrument was purchased; or</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(3)</num>
    <text>The banking or financial organization or the business association has its principal place of business in the District, the books and records of the banking or financial organization or business association show the state in which the money order, traveler’s check, or similar written instrument was purchased and the state of purchase does not provide an escheat or abandoned property law applicable to the delivery of the sum payable on such instrument to the state.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>History</heading>
      <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-160">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-160, § 105, 27 DCR 5150</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Section References</heading>
      <annotation>This section is referenced in § <cite path="§41-104">41-104</cite>, § <cite path="§41-118">41-118</cite>, and § <cite path="§41-126">41-126</cite>.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Prior Codifications</heading>
      <annotation>1981 Ed., § 42-205.</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
    <annoGroup>
      <heading>Editor's Notes</heading>
      <annotation>Uniform Law: This section is based upon § 4 of the Uniform Unclaimed Property Act (1981 Act).</annotation>
    </annoGroup>
  </annotations>
</section>
