<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <num>41-108</num>
  <heading>Deposits and refunds held by utilities.</heading>
  <text>The following funds held or owing by any utility are presumed abandoned:</text>
  <para>
    <num>(1)</num>
    <text>Any deposit, including any interest thereon, made by a subscriber with a utility to secure payment for, or any sum paid in advance for, utility services to be furnished, less any lawful deductions, that has remained unclaimed by the person appearing on the records of the utility entitled thereto for more than one year after the termination of the services for which the deposit or advance payment was made; and</text>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(2)</num>
    <text>Any sum which a utility has been ordered to refund and which was received for utility services rendered, together with any interest thereon, less any lawful deductions, that has remained unclaimed by the person appearing on the records of the utility entitled thereto for more than one year after it became payable in accordance with the final determination or order providing for the refund, regardless of whether the final determination or order requires any person entitled to a refund to make a claim.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 3-160" type="History">Mar. 5, 1981, D.C. Law 3-160, § 108, 27 DCR 5150</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 9-161" type="History">Sept. 29, 1992, D.C. Law 9-161, § 2(f), 39 DCR 5696</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 11-255" type="History">Apr. 9, 1997, D.C. Law 11-255, § 44(b), 44 DCR 1271</annotation>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 12-60" type="History">Mar. 20, 1998, D.C. Law 12-60, § 1701(e), 44 DCR 7378</annotation>
    <annotation type="Prior Codifications">1981 Ed., § 42-208.</annotation>
    <annotation type="Temporary Legislation">
      <text>Section 1701(e) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</cite> substituted “1 year” for “5 years” throughout the section.</text>
      <text>Section 2001(b) of <cite doc="D.C. Law 12-59">D.C. Law 12-59</cite> provided that the act shall expire after 225 days of its having taken effect.</text>
    </annotation>
    <annotation type="Emergency Legislation">For temporary amendment of section, see § 1701(e) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-152, October 17, 1997,  44 DCR 6196), and see § 1701(e) of the Fiscal Year 1998 Revised Budget Support Congressional Review Emergency Act of 1997 (D.C. Act 12-239, January 13, 1998,  45 DCR 508).</annotation>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">Uniform Law: This section is based in part upon § 4 of the Uniform Disposition of Unclaimed Property Act (1966 Act).</text>
    <text type="Editor's Notes">This section is also based upon § 8 of the Uniform Unclaimed Property Act (1981 Act).</text>
  </annotations>
</section>
