<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<section xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" containing-doc="D.C. Code">
  <num>41-310</num>
  <heading>Disposal of forfeited property.</heading>
  <para>
    <num>(a)</num>
    <text>When property is declared forfeited pursuant to <cite path="§41-305|(c)">§  41-305(c)</cite> or <cite path="§41-308">§  41-308</cite>, the District shall:</text>
    <para>
      <num>(1)</num>
      <text>Sell property that is not required by law to be destroyed and that is not harmful to the public or dispose of the property in a manner consistent with District law or, consistent with <cite path="§41-313">§  41-313</cite>, return the property, or the sale proceeds, to the owner;</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(2)</num>
      <text>Deposit in the General Fund of the District of Columbia any currency and any proceeds from the sale of property pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection; and</text>
    </para>
    <para>
      <num>(3)</num>
      <text>Beginning October 1, 2018, deposit in the General Fund of the District of Columbia the currency and sale proceeds received by a District agency from any state or federal agency pursuant to a multiple-jurisdiction or shared forfeiture program.</text>
    </para>
  </para>
  <para>
    <num>(b)</num>
    <text>The law enforcement agency that seized property forfeited under this chapter may not retain the property for its own use or sell it directly or indirectly to an employee of the agency, to a relative of an employee, or to another law enforcement agency; provided, that nothing in this section shall prohibit an employee of the law enforcement agency or relative of an employee of the law enforcement agency from purchasing property offered for sale at a public auction.</text>
  </para>
  <annotations>
    <annotation doc="D.C. Law 20-278" type="History" path="§110">June 16, 2015, D.C. Law 20-278, § 110, 62 DCR 1920</annotation>
  </annotations>
</section>
