<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-192" flag="true">
  <num type="law">16-192</num>
  <heading type="short">Fiscal Year Budget Support Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-192.pdf">D.C. Law 16-192</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 6899</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0679">
      <narrative>Law 16-192, the “Fiscal Year Budget Support Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-679, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 9, 2006, and June 6, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 8, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-476 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-192 became effective on March 2, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL -i- AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA FISCAL YEAR 2007 BUDGET SUPPORT ACT OF 2006 TABLE OF CONTENTS TITLE I. GOVERNMENT DIRECTION AND SUPPORT 7 SUBTITLE A. REPROGRAMMING POLICY AMENDMENT 7 SUBTITLE B. CLEAN HANDS LICENSING REVISION 7 SUBTITLE C. RECORDER OF DEEDS AUTOMATION AND INFRASTRUCTURE IMPROVEMENT FUND 10 SUBTITLE D. LOCAL SUPPLEMENTAL APPROPRIATIONS APPROVAL PROCEDURES AND ALLOCATION OF ADDITIONAL REVENUE 10 SUBTITLE E. SPECIAL PURPOSE REVENUE FUNDS SURPLUS BALANCE TRANSFER 11 SUBTITLE F. CLARIFICATION OF AUTHORITY TO EXAMINE BOOKS AND RECORDS 13 SUBTITLE G. FAR SOUTHEAST COMMUNITY ORGANIZATION TAX EXEMPTION AND FORGIVENESS FOR ACCRUED TAXES 14 SUBTITLE H. UNFOLDMENT, INC. EQUITABLE REAL PROPERTY TAX RELIEF 15 ENROLLED ORIGINAL -ii- SUBTITLE I. LOWER INCOME HOMEOWNERSHIP COOPERATIVE HOUSING ASSOCIATION CLARIFICATION 15 SUBTITLE J. REAL PROPERTY TAX SALE NOTICE 16 SUBTITLE K. NON-DEPARTMENTAL FUNDING 16 SUBTITLE L. SCHOOL MODERNIZATION DEED TAX ELIMINATION 17 SUBTITLE M. COMMERCIAL LINKAGE NEXUS STUDY 17 SUBTITLE N. YOUTH DEVELOPMENT PLAN IMPLEMENTATION STRATEGY.18 SUBTITLE O. JUNE RESERVE FUND AND FUND BALANCE ALLOCATION ACT 20 TITLE II. ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION 21 SUBTITLE A. TAX INCREMENT FINANCING RE-AUTHORIZATION AND INCREASE 21 SUBTITLE B. GOVERNMENT EMPLOYER-ASSISTED HOUSING PROGRAM AMENDMENT 22 SUBTITLE C. DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA TAXICAB COMMISSION FINGERPRINTING FUND 22 SUBTITLE D. DEED TRANSFER AND RECORDATION TAX INCREASE 23 SUBTITLE E. HOUSING PRODUCTION TRUST FUND AND NEW COMMUNITIES FINANCING 27 SUBTITLE F AUTHORIZATION OF NATURAL GAS TRUST FUND ASSESSMENT INCREASE 28 SUBTITLE G. MUNICIPAL AGGREGATION FUND ESTABLISHMENT 28 SUBTITLE H. GREAT STREETS CAPITAL EXPENDITURES 28 ENROLLED ORIGINAL -iii- SUBTITLE I. HOMESTEAD HOUSING AMENDMENT 31 SUBTITLE J. COMPREHENSIVE WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT STRATEGIC PLAN 31 SUBTITLE K. LOCAL SMALL AND DISADVANTAGED BUSINESS ENHANCEMENT AMENDMENT ACT 32 SUBTITLE L. D.C. HOUSING AUTHORITY RENT SUPPLEMENT PROGRAM 35 SUBTITLE M. VACANCY CONVERSION FEE CLARIFICATION AMENDMENT ACT OF 2006 38 SUBTITLE N. OFFICE OF THE CHIEF TENANT ADVOCATE FUNDING ACT 41 SUBTITLE O. FREE CLINIC ASSISTANCE PROGRAM COVERAGE AMENDMENT 41 SUBTITLE P. JOB OPPORTUNITY FUND CLARIFICATION 42 TITLE III. PUBLIC SAFETY AND JUSTICE 42 SUBTITLE A. INMATE WELFARE FUND 42 SUBTITLE B. VICTIMS OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE GRANT-MAKING 44 SUBTITLE C. NATIONAL GUARD OPERATIONS COORDINATION PLAN 44 SUBTITLE D. CIVIL LEGAL SERVICES 44 TITLE IV. PUBLIC EDUCATION SYSTEM 45 SUBTITLE A. UNIFORM PER STUDENT FUNDING FORMULA FOR PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOLS 45 SUBTITLE B. QUALITY TEACHER INCENTIVE 51 SUBTITLE C. HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE 52 ENROLLED ORIGINAL -iv- SUBTITLE D. EDUCATIONAL SERVICES FOR DETAINED AND COMMITTED YOUTH UNDER THE SUPERVISION OF THE DEPARTMENT OF YOUTH REHABILITATION SERVICES 54 TITLE V. HUMAN SUPPORT SERVICE 54 SUBTITLE A. MEDICAL HOMES GRANT-MAKING 54 SUBTITLE B. HEALTH INSURANCE OPEN ENROLLMENT PROGRAM AMENDMENT AND HEALTHY DC PROGRAM 55 SUBTITLE C. DEPARTMENT OF MENTAL HEALTH ESTABLISHMENT AMENDMENT 61 SUBTITLE D. HEALTH PROFESSIONAL RECRUITMENT AMENDMENT ACT 62 SUBTITLE E. HEALTH CARE PRIVATIZATION BENEFIT AMENDMENT ACT 63 SUBTITLE F. ACCESSRx CLARIFICATION AMENDMENT ACT 63 SUBTITLE G. TIMELY DISBURSEMENT ACT 64 SUBTITLE H. NURSING FACILITY QUALITY OF CARE FUND AMENDMENT 64 SUBTITLE I. MEDICAID ENROLLMENT AND EXPANSION 65 SUBTITLE J. MEDICAL ASSISTANCE ADMINISTRATION REPORTING REQUIREMENTS 65 SUBTITLE K. DESIGNATED APPROPRIATION ALLOCATIONS 66 SUBTITLE L. DAY CARE GRANT-MAKING AND RULEMAKING 74 SUBTITLE M. ASSESSMENT OF DISTRICT PROGRAMS TO PREVENT ABUSE AND NEGLECT IN THE DISTRICT 75 ENROLLED ORIGINAL -v- SUBTITLE N. INTEGRATED FUNDING AND SERVICES FOR AT-RISK CHILDREN, YOUTH, AND FAMILIES 76 TITLE VI. PUBLIC WORKS 79 SUBTITLE A. DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS’ BRYANT STREET FACILITY 79 SUBTITLE B. PUBLIC SPACE RENTAL FEES 79 SUBTITLE C. PUBLIC RIGHTS-OF-WAY OCCUPANCY FEES 81 SUBTITLE D. LOCAL ROADS CONSTRUCTION AND MAINTENANCE FUND EXPENDITURE PLAN APPROVAL 83 TITLE VII. GENERAL PROVISIONS 83 SUBTITLE A. INCORPORATION OF COMMITTEE REPORT RECOMMENDATIONS 83 TITLE IX. EFFECTIVE DATE 83 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. To amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to make an adjustment to the District of Columbia’s reprogramming threshold for capital projects; to amend Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to update the Clean Hands Before Receiving a License or Permit Act; An Act Providing for expenses of the Office of the Recorder of Deeds and Register of Wills of the District of Columbia to clarify allowable usage of the Recorder of Deeds Automation and Infrastructure Improvement Fund for fiscal year 2006; to establish procedures regarding the expenditure of supplemental appropriations as authorized by the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, and to allocate additional revenue realized through a 4th revised quarterly revenue estimate; to authorize specific funds and amounts to be transferred by the Chief Financial Officer to the General Fund of the District of Columbia; to amend Chapter 43 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow the Office of the Chief Financial Officer to examine the books and records of tax payers to ascertain the correctness of a return, and to establish the time and place for the examination; to amend Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to exempt from taxation real property owned by the Far Southeast Community Organization, located on lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753 that is to be used for inclusive housing, and to provide equitable real property tax relief; to provide equitable real property tax relief to Unfoldment, Inc to amend section 47-3503(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code to clarify that real property receiving an exemption thereunder shall be deemed to be receiving the homestead deduction for purposes of the owner-occupant residential tax credit; to amend section 47-1341(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code to make the form of notice optional; to amend the School Modernization Financing Act of 2006 to eliminate the deed and recordation tax increase; to authorize the commissioning of one or more nexus studies; to implement a youth development plan by requiring the Mayor to submit an annual progress report and appropriating $1 million for youth violence prevention programs; to require that $25,000 from the June Reserve Fund be used for the development of an East of the River Business and Community Guide; to amend the Tax Increment Financing Authorization Act of 1998 and the Retail Incentive Act of 2004 to allow for an increase in the authorized limit on the amount of tax increment financing bonds that may be issued and to extend the sunset date for the issuance of the bonds; to amend the Government Employer-Assisted Housing Amendment Act of 1999 to allow District government employees to receive loan assistance from the Employer –Assisted Housing Program in conjunction with assistance received from the Home Purchase Assistance Program Fund and to extend the property tax and income tax credits to eligible District of Columbia government employees and to employees of District of Columbia Public Charter Schools; to create a fund to collect fees related to the fingerprinting of applicants for hacker and limousine licenses; to amend the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act and section 47-903 of the District of Columbia Official Code to impose an additional tax of .7 except for residential ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. properties transferred for a consideration less than $400,000 and to create a nonlapsing fund for the collection of a portion of the additional tax and authorize the expenditure of funds from the additional tax in fiscal year 2007; to amend the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988 to establish the Fund as a special fund apart from the General Fund and to increase the amount from the Fund for bonds and debt service for the Sursum Corda New Communities Initiative; to amend the Omnibus Utility Amendment Act of 2005 to increase the maximum charge allowed for the Natural Gas Trust Fund; to amend the Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999 to permit the collection of an administrative fee for municipal aggregation contracts and to establish a nonlapsing fund for deposit of the fee; to amend the District of Columbia Great Streets Development Account to allow for the implementation of a spending plan for the monies appropriated in the FY 2005 Budget Support Act; to amend the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986 to grant the Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development discretion to transfer real property in the inventory of the Homestead Housing Preservation Program to other programs administered by the District government for the development of affordable housing; to appropriate funds to the Department of Employment Services to develop a Comprehensive Workforce Development Strategic Plan; to amend the Small, Local, and Disadvantaged Business Development and Assistance Act of 2005 to modify the definition of local business enterprise; to eliminate the qualified metropolitan area business enterprise designation; to modify provisions related to issuance and use of provisional certifications and to require government corporations to file quarterly and annual reports to the Department of Small and Local Business Development; to require that local, small and disadvantaged businesses receive 20% in equity and development participation in District government projects; to amend the District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999 to establish a program of rent supplements to assist private and nonprofit housing providers in providing housing at affordable rates to low-income populations, and to provide assistance to low-income persons in locating decent and affordable housing options; to amend the Rental Housing Act of 1985 to increase the rental unit registration fee by $1 for funding for the Office of the Chief Tenant Advocate; to amend the Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986 to expand the eligibility of free clinics under the act; to amend the Way to Work Act of 2006 to authorize the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development to fund grants from the job opportunity bank; to establish an effective procedure for providing commissary services to inmates under the legal custody of the Department of Corrections by establishing an Inmate Welfare Fund; to authorize the Mayor to issue grants from funds received for the Office of Victims Services to assist victims of domestic violence; to direct the Mayor to consult with the Commanding General of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to establish a plan for the National Guard to assist the Special Operations Division of the Metropolitan Police Department with its functions; to require ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. the Office of the Attorney General to award no less than $3.2 million to a nonprofit organization for the purpose of making grants to civil service organizations that deliver civil legal services to low-income people; to amend the Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools and Tax Conformity Clarification Amendment Act of 1998 to reflect inflationary adjustments; to amend section 47-1803.03 of the District of Columbia Official Code to permit teachers to deduct from gross income certain expenses; to require the State Education Office to make grant awards available under the DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program for no fewer than 800 eligible students attending District institutions of higher education; to require the District of Columbia Public Schools to enter into a Memorandum of Understanding with the Mayor that shall specify how educational services shall be provided to committed and detained youth who are under the supervision of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services; to amend the Day Care Policy Act of 1979 to authorize the Mayor to issue regulations to implement the act; to amend the Child Care Services Assistance Fund Act of 1988 to authorize the Mayor to issue grants up to $500,000; to require the Mayor to convene a working group to assess programs in the District providing primary and secondary services to prevent child abuse and neglect; to establish the Integrated Services Fund for At-Risk Children, Youth, and Families to be used to implement initiatives, programs, and services for at-risk children, youth, and families in a holistic, interdisciplinary manner, to authorize the Mayor to transfer into the fund up to one percent of local funding appropriated for designated agencies and to deposit federal and private grant funds into the fund, and to define the scope and design of programs and services to be financed by the fund; to provide the City Administrator with authority to award a grant of not more than $6 million during fiscal year 2007 to Medical Homes DC from the capital funds available to the Department of Health; to amend the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996 to modify the requirement that hospital service corporations and medical service corporations maintain open enrollment programs, to impose a tax upon premium payments received by hospital service corporations and medical service corporations, to establish a fund and a new program to finance health care and medical services for qualifying individuals in the District of Columbia; and to amend the Life Insurance Act and Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code to make conforming changes; to amend the Department of Mental Health Establishment Amendment Act of 2001 to authorize the Department of Mental Health to transfer to the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services the resources and responsibilities for mental health services for youth in the custody of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Service in secure facilities; to amend the District of Columbia Health Professionals Recruitment Program Act of 2005 to establish a nonlapsing fund to be known as the Health Professional Recruitment Fund for the sole purpose of making direct payments to Health Professional Recruitment Re-Payment Program participants; to ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. amend the Health Care Privatization Amendment Act of 2001 so that a health maintenance organization that provides health care services to persons enrolled in the D.C. HealthCare Alliance shall be required to provide enrollees only those health benefits specified in its contract with the District of Columbia; to amend the AccessRx Act of 2004 to reduce the required contractual amount for the Pharmacy Resource Center program; to create a timely disbursement program for grants awarded to entities designated in this act; to amend section 47-1262(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code to require that no less than 90% of the Nursing Facility Quality of Care Fund be used to fund quality of care initiatives; to require the Mayor to submit Medicaid State Plan Amendments to the Council of the District of Columbia; to require the Medical Assistance Administration within the Department of Health to report to the Council of the District of Columbia on the status of its efforts to reform the Medicaid Non-Emergency Transportation Program and its efforts to decrease payments to providers located outside the District of Columbia and to make designated allocations; to require that $100,000 be granted to the Crystal Meth Working Group for expanded substance abuse prevention programs related to crystal methamphetamine; to require that $150,000 be granted to the District of Columbia Hospital Association to develop a bio-terrorism preparedness plan for hospitals in the region; to require that $50,000 be granted to Greater DC Cares to continue development and maintenance of a first responders volunteer database; to require that $400,000 for prevention education services within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health; to allocate $250,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for a Medicaid Utilization Project; to allocate $50,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for the provision of culturally based training to clinicians that serve Latinos and other immigrant populations; to require that $500,000 be granted to Food &amp;amp; Friends to provide clinical nutrition to adults and children with HIV/AIDS and other life-threatening illnesses; to require that $1.525 million be granted to Whitman Walker Clinic to provide HIV/AIDS primary care, treatment and support services; to allocate $550,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health to provide continued support of the East of the River HIV/AIDS Initiative; to require that $100,000 be granted to Transgender Health Empowerment, Inc for organizational capacity-building, client support services, and prevention education for transgendered individuals; to require that $145,000 be granted to Angels and Associates, Inc for organizational capacity-building, client support services, and prevention education for women living with HIV/AIDS; to allocate no less than $250,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for burial assistance; to allocate $300,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for pre-release and post-release HIV/AIDS counseling, testing, and referral services for ENROLLED ORIGINAL 5Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. inmates at the Oak Hill Juvenile Detention Center and the D.C. Jail; to allocate $50,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for the purchase and distribution of condoms at the APRA Detoxification Facility, APRA Methadone maintenance sites, substance abuse treatment sites, and the D.C. Jail; to allocate no less than $400,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for prevention services, outreach, and education programs that target youth of color at-risk of or living with HIV/AIDS; to allocate no less than $400,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for prevention services, outreach, and education programs that target women of color at-risk of or living with HIV/AIDS; to allocate no less than $400,000 within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for prevention services, outreach, and education programs that target men of color at-risk of or living with HIV/AIDS; to require that $250,000 be granted to Greater Southeast Community Hospital to increase access to breast, cervical, and ovarian screening and treatment to reduce rates of morbidity among District women diagnosed with these types of cancer; to require that $250,000 be granted to Howard University Hospital to increase prostate cancer screening and treatment to reduce rates of morbidity among District men diagnosed with this disease; to require that $500,000 be granted to the American Lung Association of DC to conduct a comprehensive tobacco cessation program in the District of Columbia; to require that $150,000 be granted to the DC Cancer Consortium to provide continued planning support for implementation of the District’s Comprehensive Cancer Plan; to require that $250,000 be granted to the Capital Breast Care Center to raise breast cancer awareness and to provide screening and follow- up services for women; to require that $1 million be granted to Southeastern University to work in partnership with the Service Employees International Union to develop and expand training programs for allied health services; to authorize $1.9 million to support the Medical Homes DC initiative; to require that $300,000 be granted to Children’s National Medical Center for administration of pre-school immunization services; to require that $250,000 be granted to Howard University to expand diabetes screening, treatment for diagnosed uninsured District residents, and prevention education; to require that $250,000 be granted to the National Kidney Foundation to provide kidney screening to at-risk and low-income District residents; to require that $600,000 be granted to the District of Columbia Area Health and Education Center to increase the diversity, distribution, and quality of the future primary care workforce in the District; to require that $225,000 to So Others Might Eat and the Howard University School of Dentistry for a joint dental program to provide oral health services and treatment to homeless adults; to require that $100,000 be granted to the Washington Regional Transplant Consortium to conduct an organ and tissue donor public awareness and education campaign; to require that $200,000 be granted to the National Capital Poison Control Center to provide ENROLLED ORIGINAL 6Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. ongoing operational support of poison control activities; to allocate $300,000 for a health assessment of the Riggs Park community; to require that $20,000 be directed to the Council of the District of Columbia for the National Legislative Association on Prescription Drug Prices; to allocate $3.943 million within the Office of Managed Care in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health to increase the maximum eligibility standards of the State Children’s Health Insurance Program from 200% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines to 300% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines; to allocate $120,000 within the Office of Managed Care in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health, to increase the maximum eligibility standards for Qualified Medicare Beneficiaries and Special Low-Income Medicare Beneficiaries to 300% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines; to allocate $12.96 million within the Office of Disabilities and Aging in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health 12.96 million for comprehensive adult dental services; to allocate $4.25 million within the Office of Support Services in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health, for the local share of Disproportionate Share Hospital funds, subject to appropriations; to require that $100,000 be granted to the D.C. Assembly on School Based Health Care to provide operational support for school health policies and programs for the District of Columbia; to allocate $100,000 within the Department of Mental Health for mental health services at the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration Detoxification Facility; to require that $200,000 be granted to the District of Columbia Birth Center, Inc to support its parental support services; to allocate $824,000 within the Department of Mental Health for substance abuse vouchers utilizing the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration Choice in Drug Treatment Program to provide comprehensive treatment and support to substance abusers with mental illness; to allocate $4.1 million within the Department of Mental Health for school-based mental health services; to allocate $1.5 million within the Department of Mental Health to expand jail diversion programs for persons with mental health illness, to provide mental health services at the D.C. Jail, and to provide services for persons with mental illness being released from jail; to allocate no less than $2 million of Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS program resources within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for capital, rehabilitative construction, or acquisition costs to strengthen the development of facilities and units in facilities to expand the housing stock available to eligible persons living with HIV/AIDS in the District of Columbia; to allocate no less than $2 million of Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS program resources within the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health for the establishment of a long-term mortgage assistance program for eligible persons living with HIV/AIDS in the District of Columbia, which long-term mortgage assistance shall consist of at least 45% of monthly mortgage obligations, subject to appropriations; to repeal Resolution of the District of ENROLLED ORIGINAL 7Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Columbia City Council No. 69-71 to delete any reference to the public space rental fees for vaults; to amend the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act to strike language that exempts the U.S. government and any foreign government from the assessment and collection of rent associated with vaults and to increase the public space rental fees for vaults; to amend the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1996 to require that the incremental revenue generated from the increase in the public space fees for vaults be deposited in the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund; to amend Chapter 33 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations to increase the public rights-of-way occupancy fees established for stand-alone conduits or pipes, aerial wires, and structures housing surface transmission facilities; to amend the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002 to direct any excess money deposited in the District Department of Transportation Operating Fund after the payment of costs accrued, less 20 to the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund, to require that the incremental revenue generated from the increase in the public rights-of-way occupancy fees for stand- alone conduits or pipes, aerial wires, and structures housing surface transmission facilities are deposited in the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund; to amend the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1996 to provide that certain revenue be deposited into the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund, and that a specified percentage of the revenue may be use for debt service, and to provide further that sales and use taxes for parking and storing vehicles over $30 million be deposited into the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund; to approve the plan for the use of all monies in the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund for fiscal year 2007; and to incorporate the allocations and recommendations set forth in the committee reports of the Council’s legislative committees into this act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006”. TITLE I. GOVERNMENT DIRECTION AND SUPPORT. SUBTITLE A. REPROGRAMMING POLICY AMENDMENT. Sec. 1001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Reprogramming Policy Act of 2006”. Sec. 1002. Section 47-363(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the figure “$860,000” and inserting the figure “$1 million” in its place. SUBTITLE B. CLEAN HANDS LICENSING REVISION. Sec. 1010. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Clean Hands Licensing Revision Act of 2006”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 8Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 1011. Chapter 28 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended as follows 1) Strike the section designation "47-2863. Self-certification and enforcement and insert the section designation "47-2863. Self-certification and enforcement conditional in its place 2) Strike the section designation "47-2866. Enhanced enforcement and insert the section designation "47-2866. Interagency computer system and enforcement in its place b) Section 47-2861 is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended to read as follows: “(1)(A) “Applicant”means: “(i) An individual, business, or other entity that applies for the license or permit; and “(ii) Any person that owns a majority interest in the business or other entity; provided, that this sub-subparagraph shall not apply to a majority interest in a publicly-traded corporation. “(B) For the purposes of this paragraph, the term "majority interest" means: “(i) In the case of a corporation, more than 50% of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock of the corporation or more than 50% of the total value of all of the corporation; “(ii) In the case of a partnership, or entity treated as a partnership, more than 50% of the total interest in the capital or profits of a partnership or entity treated as a partnership; or “(iii) In the case of a trust, more than 50% of the beneficial interest in a trust 2) Designate paragraph (1A) as (1B 3) Add a new paragraph (1A) to read as follows: “(1A) “District government” means the Mayor, any executive branch or independent agency except the courts, the District of Columbia Water and Sewer Authority, or any board or commission other than the Alcohol Beverage Control Board.” c) Section 47-2862(a) is amended by striking the phrase “if the applicant” and inserting the phrase “if the applicant has failed to file required District tax returns or” in its place d) Section 47-2863 is amended as follows 1) Designate subsections (a b) and (c) as, respectively a)(1 2 and (3 2) Add a new subsection (b) to read as follows b) Upon the implementation of the interagency computer system required by § 47- 2866(a)(1 this section shall expire ENROLLED ORIGINAL 9Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 e) Section 47-2866 is amended to read as follows 47-2866. Interagency computer system and enforcement a)(1) On or before June 1, 2007, the Mayor shall implement an interagency computer system to enable government agencies, including the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs, the Office of Tax and Revenue, and the Department of Public Works, to maintain and access up-to-date records of outstanding fines, fees, penalties, interest, taxes, or other charges that may be owed by applicants for licenses or permits from the District government 2) At least 30 days prior to the implementation of the interagency computer system, the Mayor shall notify the Council of the date of implementation b) Upon the implementation of the interagency computer system as required by subsection (a) of this section 1) All agencies responsible for issuing licenses or permits shall utilize the interagency computer system containing records of outstanding fines, fees, penalties, interest, taxes, or other charges owing to the District government to determine whether the application for a license or permit should be denied pursuant to § 47-2862(a 2) Self-certification authority shall no longer be authorized; and 3) Section 47-2863 shall expire c) For purposes of administering and enforcing any tax law in the District of Columbia, the Mayor may require any owner, occupant, or transferor of real property and any taxpayer to provide a social security number or other tax identification number on any return or in a form and manner as the Mayor prescribes. Any use or disclosure of these numbers shall be for tax administration and enforcement purposes only. “(d) The Chief Financial Officer may promulgate such rules as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out provisions of this subchapter Sec. 1012. Title 25 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) Section 25-301 is amended as follows 1) The existing text is re-designated as subsection (a 2) A new subsection (b) is added to read as follows b)(1) Notwithstanding § 47-2861(1)(B the Board shall not issue a license or permit to an applicant if the applicant has failed to file required District tax returns or owes more than 100 in outstanding debt to the District as a result of the items specified in § 47-2862(a)(1) through (9 subject to the exceptions specified in § 47-2862(b).” b) Section 25-402(a)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “shareholders holding 25% or more of its common stock” and inserting the phrase “shareholders holding, directly or beneficially, 10% or more of its common stock” in its place. “Sec. 1013. Section 47-2862(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by striking the phrase “Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the District government shall not issue or reissue any license or permit to any applicant for a license or permit if the applicant ” ENROLLED ORIGINAL 10Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. and inserting the phrase “Notwithstanding any other provision of law except § 25-301(b the District government shall not issue or reissue any license or permit to any applicant for a license or permit if the applicant has failed to file required District tax returns or” in its place. SUBTITLE C. RECORDER OF DEEDS AUTOMATION AND INFRASTRUCTURE IMPROVEMENT FUND. Sec. 1021. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Recorder of Deeds Automation and Infrastructure Improvement Fund Use Clarification Act of 2006 Sec. 1022. An Act Providing for expenses of the Office of the Recorder of Deeds and Register of Wills of the District of Columbia, approved April 12, 1997 (44 Stat. 322, ch. 176; D.C. Official Code § 42-1214(b is amended as follows: “(b) Revenues accruing to the Fund shall be used solely and exclusively to cover the costs of updating the automated system of the Recorder of Deeds and the repair and improvement of the infrastructure located at 515 D Street, N.W Washington, D.C and any incidental costs associated with that repair and improvement. These costs shall include the purchasing of computer hardware and software, maintenance of the new computer system, training staff to implement and operate the new system, and the repair of the infrastructure components necessary to meet the overall mission of the Recorder of Deeds.”. SUBTITLE D. LOCAL SUPPLEMENTAL APPROPRIATIONS APPROVAL PROCEDURES AND ALLOCATION OF ADDITIONAL REVENUE Sec. 1041. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Local Supplemental Appropriations Approval Procedures Establishment and Fiscal Year 2007 Allocation of Additional Revenue Act of 2006”. Sec. 1042. Local Supplemental appropriations approval procedures. The following procedures for the establishment of supplemental appropriations as authorized by section 126 of the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2006, approved November 30, 2005 (Pub. L. No. 109-115; 119 Stat. 2396 Act or such subsequent Congressional authorization, are established as follows a) The Mayor may prepare and submit to the Council such proposed supplemental budget recommendations either when he or she determines such recommendations are necessary or when the Council, by resolution, requests the Mayor to submit such a recommendation b)(1) The Mayor shall include with any proposed supplemental budget recommendation submitted pursuant to subsection (a) of this section such detail as the Mayor determines necessary to reflect the agencies and purposes for which the supplemental funds are being requested; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 11Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 2) A proposed supplemental budget recommendation shall not exceed the estimated available resources, as certified by the Chief Financial Officer pursuant to the Act c) Upon passage by the Council of legislation enacting proposed supplemental budget recommendations, the Mayor shall, in compliance with the Act, submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate notification of the passage of legislation enacting supplemental budget recommendations. Sec. 1043. Fiscal Year 2007 Allocation of Additional Revenue. If the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia certifies, through the 4th revised quarterly revenue estimate for fiscal year 2007 that local funds exceed the annual revenue estimates incorporated in the approved Fiscal Year 2007 Budget and Financial Plan, those additional revenues shall be allocated, to include the following 1)(A) The first $10.5 million in fiscal year 2007, and the first $21 million in fiscal years thereafter, to the Metropolitan Police Department to hire approximately 350 new police officers B) The additional police officers shall be allocated evenly across all 7 police districts for patrol duty, shall be in addition to current patrol staffing levels, and shall be assigned to foot patrol, bike patrol, scooter patrol, mounted patrol, and Segway (or other electric personal assistive mobility device) patrol 2) An amount of $500,000 for the Office of the City Administrator for Cease Fire Don’t Smoke the Brothers, Inc to support the organizations’ multiple programs that target at-risk youth in the District of Columbia; and (3) An amount of $500,000 for the Office of the City Administrator for the Brookland Manor Community Relations Office Offender Neighborhood Reintegration Program. Sec. 1044. This subtitle does not have a negative fiscal impact. SUBTITLE E. SPECIAL PURPOSE REVENUE FUNDS SURPLUS BALANCE TRANSFER. Sec.1051. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Special Purpose Revenue Funds Surplus Balance Transfer Act of 2006 Sec. 1052. Special purpose revenue funds surplus transfer authorization. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the dedication of funds to a particular use and D.C. Official Code § 47-368.01, beginning October 1, 2006, the amounts identified below as surplus funds in the balance of each Other-Type Fund, as defined in D.C. Official Code § 47-368.01(a shall be transferred by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer to the General Fund of the District of Columbia: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 12Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 1) An amount of $646,000 from the Department of Property Management’s Other-Type Fund for utility payments for non-District agencies 2) An amount of $1 million from Cable Television Special Account established by section 203 of the Cable Television Reform Act of 2002, effective October 9, 2002 (D.C. Law 14-193; D.C. Official Code § 34-120.03 3) An amount of $39,000 from the Occupations and Professions Licensing Special Account established by D.C. Official Code § 47-2853.11 4) An amount of $223,000 from the Office of the Chief Technology Officer’s Other-Type Fund for Tech City 5) An amount of $1.41 million from the Department of Health, of which A) An amount of $33,000 shall be from the Office of the Chief Medical Examiner Fund established by section 2918(a) of the Fiscal Year 2001 Budget Support Act of 2000, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 5-1418 B) An amount of $19,200 shall be from the Other-Type fund for an Oil Spill Fee court-ordered settlement C) An amount of $1 million shall be from the Other-Type fund for vital records revenue D) An amount of $81,000 shall be from the Other-Type fund for the University of the District of Columbia Health Clinic reimbursement E) An amount of $4,000 shall be from the Other-Type fund for the General Counsel Freedom of Information fees F) An amount of $239,000 shall be from the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Fund established by section 5 of the District of Columbia Low-Level Radioactive Waste Generator Regulatory Policy Act of 1980, effective March 7, 1991 (D.C. Law 8-226; D.C. Official Code § 8-1504 G) An amount of $22,000 shall be from the Other-Type fund for the collection of medical licenses and fees; and (H) An amount of $12,000 shall be from the Addiction Recovery Fund established by section 5 of the Choice in Drug Treatment Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-145; D.C. Official Code § 7-3004 6) An amount of $1 million from the Real Estate Guaranty and Education Fund established by section 29 of the District of Columbia Real Estate Licensure Act of 1982, effective March 10, 1983 (D.C. Law 4-209; D.C. Official Code § 42-1706 7) An amount of $10,5 million from the home purchase assistance program fund established by section 2 of the Home Purchase Assistance Fund Act of 1978, effective September 12, 1978 (D.C. Law 2-103; D.C. Official Code § 42-2601 8) An amount of $913,000 from the Renovation Development Trust Fund established by section 4 of the John A. Wilson Building Foundation Act, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-180; D.C. Official Code § 10-1333 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 13Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 9) An amount of $638,000 from the District of Columbia Department of Public Works’ abandoned vehicle program Other-Type fund 10) An amount of $80,000 from the Recorder of Deeds Automation and Infrastructure Improvement Fund established by section 3 of An Act providing for the expenses of the offices of recorders of deeds and register of wills of the District of Columbia, effective April 12, 1997 (D.C. Law 12-257; D.C. Official Code § 42-1214 and (11) An amount of $486,000 from the District Department of Transportation’s Other-Type fund for the DDOT Administrative Support Fund. SUBTITLE F. CLARIFICATION OF AUTHORITY TO EXAMINE BOOKS AND RECORDS. Sec. 1061. Short title This subtitle may be cited as the “Clarification of Authority to Examine Books and Records Act of 2006”. Sec. 1062. Chapter 43 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding the section designations “47-4313. Examinations of books and records.” and “47-4314. Time and place of examination.” after the section designation “47-4312. Protest of assessment.” b) Section 47-4311 is amended to read as follows: “§ 47-4311. Requirement to maintain books and records. “Every person who is liable for a tax imposed by this title and every owner of real property that is liable for a tax imposed by this title shall maintain sufficient books and records to determine liability for the tax.” c) New sections 47-4313 and 47-4314 are added to read as follows: “§ 47-4313. Examinations of books and records. “For the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any return required to be made by this title, making a return where none has been made, determining the liability of any person or real property for any District of Columbia tax (including any interest, additional amount, addition to the tax, or civil penalty) or the liability at law or equity of any transferee or fiduciary of any person in respect of any District of Columbia revenue tax, collecting any such liability, or inquiring into any offense connected with the administration or endorsement of the District of Columbia revenue law, the Mayor or any authorized officer or employee of the Office of Tax and Revenue may: “(1) Examine any books, papers, records, or other data which may be relevant or material to such inquiry; or “(2) Take such testimony of the person concerned, under oath, as may be relevant to such inquiry. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 14Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “47-4314. Time and place of examination. “(a) The time and place of examination pursuant to § 47-4313 shall be fixed by the Mayor, or any authorized officer or employee of the Office of Tax and Revenue, and shall be reasonable under the circumstances. The time and place for an examination shall be presumed to be reasonable if it is scheduled: “(1) During a normally scheduled work day and normal business hours of the Office of Tax and Revenue; or “(2) Without regard to seasonal fluctuations in the businesses of particular taxpayers or their representatives. “(b)(1) The Mayor, or an authorized officer or employee of the Office of Tax and Revenue, shall determine whether an examination will be an office examination or a field examination. “(2)(A) An office examination of an individual shall take place at the Office of Tax and Revenue. “(B) A field examination shall take place at the location where the taxpayer's original books, records, and source documents pertinent to the examination are maintained, which determination shall be made by the Mayor or an authorized officer or employee of the Office of Tax and Revenue. In the case of a sole proprietorship or taxpayer entity, this will usually be the taxpayer’s principal place of business. “(C) A taxpayer shall not be subjected to unnecessary examinations or investigations.”. SUBTITLE G. FAR SOUTHEAST COMMUNITY ORGANIZATION TAX EXEMPTION AND FORGIVENESS FOR ACCRUED TAXES. Sec. 1071. Short title. This act may be cited as the “Far Southeast Community Organization Tax Exemption and Forgiveness for Accrued Taxes Act of 2006”. Sec. 1072. Chapter 10 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by adding the section designation “47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753.” b) A new section 47-1074 is added to read as follows: “§ 47-1074. Far Southeast Community Organization; lots 73, 74, and 75 in square 5753. “(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “inclusive housing” means a housing development in which all units are rented to occupying households with not more than 80% of area median income (adjusted for household size) for a rent not exceeding 30% of household income as such amounts are determined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 15Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(b) The real property located at lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753, shall be exempt from taxation so long as the property is owned by Far Southeast Community Organization and the property is used for inclusive housing. If the real property is sold or is not used for the purpose of inclusive housing, the exemption shall terminate as of the beginning of the year in which the sale or non-compliant use occurred; provided, that if the real property ceases to be used for the purpose of inclusive housing less than 15 years after the effective date of this section: “(1) The exemption shall terminate as of the effective date of this section and the amount of taxes exempted under this section shall become due; and “(2) This subsection shall constitute a lien against the property to secure the repayment of such amount, plus interest accruing thereon.”. Sec. 1073. Forgiveness of taxes; redemption of real property. The Council orders that all unpaid real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against real property located at lots 73, 74, and 75, square 5753, shall be forgiven, and the amount necessary to redeem the real property under § 47-1316 shall be deposited with the Chief Financial Officer on behalf of Far Southeast Community Organization. If the real property ceases to be used for the purpose of inclusive housing less than 15 years after the effective date of section 1072, the forgiveness under this section shall be rescinded, the amount of taxes forgiven under this section shall become due, and this section shall constitute a lien against the real property to secure the repayment of such amounts.”. SUBTITLE H. UNFOLDMENT, INC. EQUITABLE REAL PROPERTY TAX RELIEF. Sec. 1081. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the "Unfoldment, Inc. Equitable Real Property Tax Relief Act of 2006 Sec. 1082. Real property taxes, interest, penalties, fees, and other related charges assessed against the real property located at 546 Newcomb Street, S.E lot 804, square 5984, and the real property located at 3825 South Capitol Street, S.W lot 826, square 6129, for the period of January 1, 2002 through June 30, 2006, shall be forgiven and any payments made for such period shall be refunded. SUBTITLE I. LOWER INCOME HOMEOWNERSHIP COOPERATIVE HOUSING ASSOCIATION CLARIFICATION. Sec. 1101. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the "Lower Income Homeownership Cooperative Housing Association Clarification Act of 2006”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 16Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 1102. Section 47-3503(c) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new paragraph (5) to read as follows 5) A real property receiving the exemption under this subsection shall be deemed to be receiving the homestead deduction under § 47-850 or § 47-850.01 for purposes of § 47-864; provided, that there is an approved and current homestead application on file applicable to the entire tax year following the expiration of the exemption.”. Sec. 1103. Applicability. Section 1102 shall be applicable to taxable periods beginning after September 30, 2001. SUBTITLE J. REAL PROPERTY TAX SALE NOTICE. Sec. 1111. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Real Property Tax Sale Notice Act of 2006”. Sec. 1112. Section 47-1341(a) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended striking the phrase “The notice of delinquency shall also include the following” and inserting the phrase “The notice of delinquency may also include the following” in its place. SUBTITLE K. NON-DEPARTMENTAL FUNDING. Sec. 1121. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the "Non-Departmental Funding Act of 2006 Sec. 1122. Criteria for spending Non-Departmental funding in fiscal year 2007. Of the Non-Departmental funding for fiscal year 2007 1) The Metropolitan Police Department, up to $7 million for 100 new police officers; provided, that the CFO certify that a hiring plan has been completed, that the funds are necessary to complete the hiring of additional police officers, and that the funds will be used exclusively for the hiring of additional police officers 2) The Department of Corrections, up to $2.8 million for rental costs associated with the Correction Treatment Facility; provided, that the Mayor demonstrates that these costs are not funded elsewhere in the budget and the Chief Financial Officer certifies that the funds are needed 3) The Office of Administrative Hearings, up to $540,000 for rent and administration functions; provided, that OAH has accepted from the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs the adjudication of cases under the Rental Housing Act and that the funds are necessary for OAH to implement the transfer. The amount available to OAH shall be the amount the CFO determines is necessary to carry out the adjudication of cases under the Rental Housing Act. If OAH has not accepted the adjudication of cases under the Rental Housing Act by October 1, 2006, the CFO may transfer any portion of these funds the CFO deems necessary ENROLLED ORIGINAL 17Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. to allow DCRA to continue the adjudication of cases under the Rental Housing Act until acceptance by OAH; and (4) Of the $5.9 million appropriated for educational services to be provided to committed and detained youth who are under the supervision of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services DYRS and are residing in the Oak Hill Youth Center, the Youth Services Center, and any other replacement or new secure facilities operated by or on behalf of DYRS for youth in DYRS custody, the Chief Financial Officer, in consultation with DYRS and the District of Columbia Public Schools DCPS shall make available to DCPS such amounts as are necessary for the provision of these educational services by DCPS for the portion of the fiscal year for which DCPS is providing the services and the Memorandum of Understanding MOU required by Subtitle D of Title IV remains unexecuted, with the remaining amounts and available balances to be allocated consistent with the executed MOU. SUBTITLE L. SCHOOL MODERNIZATION DEED TAX ELIMINATION. Sec. 1131. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “School Modernization Financing Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 1132. The School Modernization Financing Act of 2006, signed by the Mayor on March 30, 2006 (D.C. Act 16-341; 53 DCR 2843 is amended as follows a) Section 141(a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking the phrase “beginning September 2005,” and inserting the phrase “beginning September 2005, through May 2006,” in its place 2) Paragraph (2) is amended as follows A) Strike the phrase “Beginning for” and insert the word “In” in its place B) Strike the phrase “to be applied to the fiscal year 2 years following the audited fiscal year” and insert the phrase “as of the end of fiscal year 2007” in its place 3) Paragraph (3) is repealed b) Section 161 is repealed. SUBTITLE M. COMMERCIAL LINKAGE NEXUS STUDY. Sec. 1141. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Commercial Linkage Nexus Study Act of 2006 Sec. 1142. Nexus study. To quantify the relationship between commercial development and the need for housing for low and moderate-income workers, the District of Columbia Office of Planning shall commission one or more nexus studies. Each study shall determine the appropriate level of a one-time commercial linkage fee, based on square footage, that will generate revenues from new ENROLLED ORIGINAL 18Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. commercial development sufficient to support low and moderate-income housing needs created by the new development. The initial study shall be commissioned not later than October 15, 2006, and shall be completed not later than April 1, 2007. Sec. 1143. Funding for nexus study. The nexus study shall be funded from the Mayor’s Comprehensive Task Force Fund, from which $80,000 shall be allocated from the fiscal year budget as provided in section 2052(b)(7 SUBTITLE N. YOUTH DEVELOPMENT PLAN IMPLEMENTATION STRATEGY. Sec. 1151. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Youth Development Plan Implementation Strategy Act of 2006 Sec. 1152. Youth Development Plan. The Mayor shall oversee the implementation of District’s Youth Development Plan, which has been designed to 1) Increase the quality of coordination and collaboration among all stakeholders to deliver city-funded youth services 2) Advance the positive youth development philosophy and policy approach 3) Effectively implement youth violence prevention and intervention strategies 4) Provide for consistent and sustained investment in the city’s youth guided by positive youth development; and (5) Directly impact upon challenges affecting adolescent youth and disconnected youth. Sec. 1153. Strategy update a) The Mayor, within 30 days of the adoption of the budget, shall disseminate the budget and implementation strategy for the Youth Development Plan for each fiscal year (“youth development report” Copies of the youth development report shall be transmitted to each member of the Council and posted on the District government’s website. This report shall summarize the successes and difficulties of the previous year’s strategy and any new youth development initiatives that are to be included in the plan for the upcoming year b) The youth development report shall also include qualitative and quantitative outcome measures and performance measures (“measures”) for each implemented initiative (“measures” Outcome measures and performance measures for other initiatives shall be developed as soon as practicable. The Deputy Mayor for Children, Youth, Families and Elders and the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and Justice shall develop these measures upon advice from the Youth Development Plan Executive Working Group established under section 1156 of this subtitle. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 19Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 c) For purposes of this section, the term “Qualitative and quantitative outcome measures and performance measures” means indicators of progress toward achieving the citywide goals established in the Children’s Budget Report and ensuring that youth development programs are provided effectively and efficiently. Sec. 1154. Realignment of funding priorities a) Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, any reprogramming of money that relates to the funding of the Youth Development Plan’s budget or the Children’s Budget shall conform with the citywide goals for children and youth identified in the Children’s Budget Report. The city-wide goals for children and youth are 1) Children are ready for school 2) Children and youth succeed in school 3) Children and youth practice healthy behaviors 4) Children and youth engage in meaningful activities 5) Children and youth live in healthy, stable, and supportive families; and (6) All youth make a successful transition to adulthood b) Reprogrammed funds may only be allocated to meet the one of the following specific goals for which such funding was made. Sec. 1155. Funding priorities a) In fiscal year 2007, the youth development plan shall be funded by a $1 million allocation to the Office of the City Administrator to be used as follows 1) An amount of $600,000 for gang intervention services, including the Violence Intervention Partnership to reduce youth violence in communities east of the Anacostia River through innovative law enforcement, conflict resolution, and intervention and prevention strategies through a collaborative effort by community leaders, law enforcement officers, government agencies, faith-based institutions, community-based organizations, educators, and youth outreach workers 2) An amount of $300,000 for girls leadership and violence prevention programs, including a program to study violence among female youth and implement programs to address this issue; and (3) An amount of $100,000 for youth worker training in positive youth development principles and methods b) The Mayor shall designate additional resources for the Youth Development Plan from agencies that will provide services and support for the Plan’s initiatives, subject to the provisions of section 1154 and applicable laws and regulations. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 20Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 1156. Executive Working Group a) There is established a Youth Development Plan Executive Working Group (“Working Group” that shall advise its chair on the youth development plan. The chair of the Working Group shall be the Deputy Mayor for Children, Youth, Families and Elders (“chair” The other members of the Executive working group shall include 1) Current members of the Youth Development Plan’s executive steering committee, including the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety and, the Superintendent of the District of Columbia Public Schools, the City Administrator, and the President of the District of Columbia Children and Youth Investment Trust Corporation 2) The Director of the District of Columbia Department of Employment Services 3) A member of the Council, as designated the Council Chairman 4) Adolescent youths, to be selected by the chair of the Executive Working Group as follows A) A member of the Mayor’s Youth Advisory Council B) A system-involved youth who may be a youth who is legally a ward of, or committed to the care of the District of Columbia, or who is under the care of, the Department of Mental Health, and (C) At least one youth who resides in the District 5) At least one representative from the Department of Parks and Recreation, as selected by the chair 6) At least one representative from the Department of Youth Rehabilitative Services, as selected by the chair 7) At least one representative from the Child and Family Services Agency, as selected by the chair 8) At least one representative from the Metropolitan Police Department, as selected by the Deputy Mayor for Public Safety &amp;amp; Justice 9) Representatives from other governmental agencies and instrumentalities as selected by the chair; and (10) At least 2 District residents who have demonstrated an interest in youth violence or youth development in the District b) The operations of the Working Group shall be subject to the discretion of the chair; provided, that Working Group shall meet at least twice a year. The chair of the Working Group shall work to ensure that the Group receives meaningful, informed feedback and input from its youth members. SUBTITLE O. JUNE RESERVE FUND AND FUND BALANCE ALLOCATION ACT. Sec.1161. Short title This subtitle may be cited as the “June Reserve Fund and Fund Balance Allocation ENROLLED ORIGINAL 21Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec.1162. Twenty-five thousand dollars of the funds appropriated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development in section 2(a)(11) of of the June Reserve Fund and Fund Balance Allocation Emergency Act of 2006, effective July 12, 2006; D.C. Act 16-416 DCR shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution to provide support for the development of an East of the River Business and Community Guide, to be competitively bid subject to the terms and conditions approved by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development. TITLE II. ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT AND REGULATION SUBTITLE A. TAX INCREMENT FINANCING RE-AUTHORIZATION AND INCREASE. Sec. 2001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Retail Incentive and Tax Increment Financing Re- Authorization and Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2002. Section 3(b) of the Tax Increment Financing Authorization Act of 1998, effective September 11, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-143; D.C. Official Code § 2-1217.02(b is amended as follows a) Strike the phrase “$300 million” and insert the phrase “$500 million; provided, that the aggregate amount of TIF bonds for projects in the Central Business District, as defined in Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, shall not exceed $300 million” in its place b) Strike the phrase “January 1, 2003” and insert the phrase “January 1, 2008” in its place. Sec. 2003. Section 3(a) of the Retail Incentive Act of 2004, effective September 8, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-185; D.C. Official Code § 2-1217.72(a is amended by striking the phrase “$300 million” and inserting the phrase “$500 million; provided, that the aggregate amount of TIF bonds for projects in the Central Business District, as defined in Title 11 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations, shall not exceed $300 million” in its place. Sec. 2004. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of August 1, 2006. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 22Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE B. GOVERNMENT EMPLOYER-ASSISTED HOUSING PROGRAM AMENDMENT. Sec. 2011. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Government Employer-Assisted Housing Program Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2012. The Government Employer-Assisted Housing Amendment Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-96; D.C. Official Code § 42-2501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 6(d D.C. Official Code § 42-2505(d is amended by striking the phrase “may not” and inserting the word “may” in its place b) Section 7 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2506) is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended to read as follows: “Sec. 7. Assistance available for District government and public charter school employees.” 2) Subsection (a) is amended as follows A) The lead-in sentence is amended to read as follows: “In addition to the assistance provided in sections 5 and 6, a District of Columbia government employee, an employee of a District of Columbia public charter school, or a person who has accepted an offer to be a District of Columbia police officer, firefighter, emergency medical technician, public school teacher, or a teacher at a District of Columbia public charter school who is a first-time homebuyer in the District shall be eligible for the following assistance:” (B) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the phrase “the officer” wherever it appears and inserting the phrase “the District of Columbia government employee, employee of a District of Columbia public charter school, or person who has accepted an offer to be a District of Columbia police officer, firefighter, emergency medical technician, public school teacher, or teacher at a District of Columbia public charter school” in its place. Sec. 2013. This subtitle is subject to appropriations. SUBTITLE C. DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA TAXICAB COMMISSION FINGERPRINTING FUND. Sec. 2021. Short title This subtitle may be cited as the “District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Fingerprinting Fund Amendment Act of 2006”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 23Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 2022. The District of Columbia Taxicab Commission Establishment Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-97; D.C. Official Code §50-301 et seq is amended by adding a new section 20d to read as follows: “Sec. 20d. Taxicab Commission Fingerprinting Fund. “(a) There is hereby established the Taxicab Commission Fingerprinting Fund which shall be a revolving, nonlapsing fund that shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time but shall be continually available to the Taxicab Commission for the purpose of the fund, subject to authorization by Congress, into which shall be deposited funds from appropriations and from fees from applicants for hacker and limousine licenses to obtain fingerprint records through the Metropolitan Police Department; which funds shall be used to make payment to the Metropolitan Police Department for the cost of obtaining the fingerprint records. “(b) Revenue deposited into the fund shall be specifically designated to be expended by the Taxicab Commission to obtain fingerprint records from the Metropolitan Police Department and shall not be used to provide funding to any other District government agency c) The Metropolitan Police Department shall submit to the Taxicab Commission a voucher, on a periodic basis as agreed to by the Taxicab Commission and the Metropolitan Police Department, to be reimbursed for the cost of producing fingerprint records; which voucher shall include the cost and the number of fingerprint records produced SUBTITLE D. DEED TRANSFER AND RECORDATION TAX INCREASE. Sec. 2051. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Deed Transfer and Recordation Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2052. Mayor’s Comprehensive Housing Task Force Fund a) There is established a special purpose revenue fund designated as the Mayor’s Comprehensive Housing Task Force Fund, which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used solely for the purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section. The Fund shall be administered by the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Economic Development. An amount equal to 39.93% of the funds collected under section 303(a-3) of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 12; to be codified at D.C. Official Code § 42-1103(a-3 and D.C. Official Code § 47-903(a-3 and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in the subsection (b) of this section, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act. Any funds that are transferred through intra-District funding and are not expended in any fiscal year shall revert to ENROLLED ORIGINAL 24Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. the Fund b) The Fund shall be used solely to fund housing strategy recommendations developed by the Mayor’s Comprehensive Housing Task Force; provided, that for fiscal year 2007, the only authorized expenditures are as follows: “(1)(A) An amount of $5 million for the production of workforce housing; provided, that eligibility for purchase or rental of workforce housing shall be limited to households with incomes not exceeding 120% of the area median income as defined in section 2(1) of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7- 22; D.C. Official Code § 42-2801(1 provided further, that all housing units developed under this paragraph shall remain affordable and shall be leased or sold only to eligible households for the life of the unit. “(B) For the purposes of this paragraph, the term “affordable” means housing for which the occupying household will pay no more than 30% of its income for gross housing costs. “(C) The Mayor shall submit to the Council a workforce housing development plan no later than 60 days after the effective date of this paragraph. The implementation of this paragraph shall be subject to the Council’s approval of the plan 2) An amount of $10 million for the Homeless No More program, which shall be transferred to the budget of the Department of Human Services’ Family Services Administration Program through intra-District funds 3) An amount of $4 million for mental health housing, which shall be transferred to the budget of the Department of Mental Health through intra-District funds 4) An amount of $1.8 million for New Communities planning and economic development 5) An amount of $4 million for New Communities human capital 6) An amount of $250,000 for a housing coordinator 7) An amount of $80,000 for a nexus study on commercial linkage, which shall be transferred to the budget of the Office of Planning through intra-District funds 8) An amount of $7.5 million for emergency assistance to prevent eviction 9) An amount of $6 million for energy assistance, which shall be transferred to the budget of the District of Columbia Energy Office for the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program through intra-District funds; and (10) An amount of $1.7 million for homeless initiatives, including 90 beds for youth, educational assistance for homeless youth, and emergency family shelter case management, to include specialized housing, housing-related education, and wrap around services through providers for lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender youth or youth questioning their sexuality or gender identity, which shall be transferred to the budget of the Department of Human Services’ Family Services Administration Program through intra-District funds. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 25Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 2053. Section 303 of the District of Columbia Deed Recordation Tax Act, approved March 2, 1962 (76 Stat. 12; D.C. Official Code § 42-1103 is amended by adding a new subsection (a-3) to read as follows: “(a-3)(1) Beginning October 1, 2006, except for residential properties transferred for a consideration less than $400,000, an additional tax of .35% is imposed upon a deed that is subject to the tax under subsection (a)(1) of this section. An amount equal to 39.93% of the funds collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the Mayor’s Comprehensive Housing Task Force Fund established by section 2052 of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 15% of the funds collected shall be deposited in the Housing Production Trust Fund established by section 3 of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code § 42-2802 and the balance shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.”. Sec. 2054. Section 47-903 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (a-3) to read as follows: “(a-3)(1) Beginning October 1, 2006, except for residential properties transferred for a consideration less than $400,000, an additional tax of .35% is imposed upon a deed that is subject to the tax under subsection (a)(1) of this section. An amount equal to 39.93% of the funds collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the Mayor’s Comprehensive Housing Task Force Fund established by section 2052 of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006, 15% of the funds collected shall be deposited in the Housing Production Trust Fund established by section 3 of the Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code § 42-2802 and the balance shall be deposited in the General Fund of the District of Columbia.”. Sec. 2055. The following programs shall be funded for fiscal year 2007 from the General Fund of the District of Columbia in the following amounts 1) An amount of $15,089,443 to the Office of Unified Communications, which shall be allocated for personnel and nonpersonal costs of the E-911 system 2) An amount of $508,200 to fund the fiscal effect and implementation of the Health Care Benefits Expansion Amendment Act of 2006, effective April 4, 2006 (D.C. Law 16- 82; D.C. Official Code § 32-706 et seq 3) An amount of $379,400 to the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development to be granted to the Tudor Place Historic House and Garden for capital restoration funding 4) An amount of $200,000 to the Commission on Arts and Humanities to be granted to the Washington D.C. Jewish Community Center’s Center for the Arts; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 26Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 5) An amount of $250,000 to the Department of Health to be granted to the Capital Breast Care Center 6) An amount of $50,000 to the Department of Health to be granted to the D.C. Assembly on School-Based Health Care to fund school-based health programs 7) An amount of $400,000 to the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services to be granted to Peaceoholics to assist in providing comprehensive, wrap-around services for at- risk youth and their families in the District of Columbia 8) An amount of $100,000 to the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services to be granted to Positive Choices to provide educational, athletic, emotional, and a socially enriched environment for economically disadvantaged inner-city youth 9) An amount of $50,000 to the Office on Aging to be granted to Saint Mary’s Court Senior Living Facility to assist its Quality of Life Program, which provides support services, classes, community, and social activities for its residents 10) An amount of $50,000 to the Department of Human Services to be granted to Bread for the City to assist in funding programs offered including meals, housing, legal assistance, and job placement 11) An amount of $50,000 to the Department of Human Services to be granted to D.C. Central Kitchen to assist in supplemental food purchases used to provide daily meals to residents at all District of Columbia shelters 12) An amount of $50,000 to the Department of Parks and Recreation to be used as one-time capital funding for the Spanish Steps project 13) An amount of $14 million to the District of Columbia Housing Authority for operations, rent supplements, and emergency assistance 14) An amount of $7 million to the Metropolitan Police Department to hire new police officers; provided, that A) The Metropolitan Police Department maintain equivalent staffing levels as existed on June 11, 2006 in each of the 7 police districts B) The additional police officers shall be allocated evenly across all 7 police districts for patrol duty, shall be in addition to current patrol staffing levels, and shall be assigned to foot patrol, bike patrol, and scooter patrol, mounted patrol, and Segway (or other electric personal assistive mobility device) patrol; and (C) The Chief of Police shall provide to the Council monthly reports on deployment and Metropolitan Police Department strength by the 15th of each month (15) An amount of $257,000 to the fund the fiscal effect and implementation of subtitle B of Title IV 16) An amount of $89,5000 to fund the fiscal effect and implementation of subtitle I of Title I 17) An amount of $143,882 to the Department of Parks and Recreation for Boys and Girls Club programs; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 27Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 18) An amount of $8,780,300 to fund the fiscal effect of subtitle O; and (19) An amount of $150,000 to fund the earned income tax credit community outreach; and (20) An amount of $124,000 to the Board of Real Property Assessments and Appeals to be allocated as follows A) The amount of $9,000 for computer upgrades B) The amount of $45,000 for records management conversion to a web- based system C) The amount of $20,000 for centralized digital recording D) The amount of $35,000 to increase Board member reimbursements to $35 per hour; and (E) The amount of $15,000 for nonlegal administrative support staff. SUBTITLE E. HOUSING PRODUCTION TRUST FUND AND NEW COMMUNITIES FINANCING. Sec. 2061. Short title. This title may be cited as "Housing Production Trust Fund and New Communities Financing Clarification Act of 2006 Sec. 2062. The Housing Production Trust Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-202; D.C. Official Code § 42-2801 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 3 (D.C. Official Code § 42-2802) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended to read as follows: “(a) There is established the Housing Production Trust Fund as a permanent revolving special revenue fund within the Governmental Funds of the District apart from the General Fund consisting of identifiable, renewable, and segregated capital, which shall be administered by the Department to provide assistance in housing production for targeted populations.” 2) Subsection (b-2)(1) and (2) are amended to read as follows: “(1) An amount not to exceed $12 million of the funds deposited into the Fund may be used by the Mayor to secure bonds issued for the benefit of the New Communities Initiative or other purposes consistent with the Housing Production Trust Fund uses and pursuant to subsection (b)(11) of this section 2) Council authorization by act shall be required for any amount above $12 million in the Fund to secure financing for the New Community Initiative or other purposes consistent with the Housing Production Trust Fund uses.” b) Section 203(b D.C. Official Code § 42-2812.03(b is amended by striking the phrase “$6 million” and inserting the phrase “$12 million” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 28Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE F AUTHORIZATION OF NATURAL GAS TRUST FUND ASSESSMENT INCREASE. Sec. 2071. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the "Natural Gas Trust Fund Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2072. Section 101(b)(2)(B) of the Omnibus Utility Amendment Act of 2004, effective April 12, 2005 (D.C. Law 15-342; D.C. Official Code § 34-1651(b)(2)(B is amended by striking the phrase “$.016434 per therm” and inserting the phrase “$.024651 per therm” in its place. SUBTITLE G. MUNICIPAL AGGREGATION FUND ESTABLISHMENT. Sec. 2081. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Municipal Aggregation Fund Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2082. Section 115(a) of the Retail Electric Competition and Consumer Protection Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-107; D.C. Official Code § 34-1515 (a is amended by adding a new paragraph (1A) to read as follows: “(1A)(A) There is established a fund designated as the Municipal Aggregation Fund, which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and shall be used solely to pay the costs of the formation and administration of municipal aggregation contracts of the District. The funds collected under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited into the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress. All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this subparagraph, subject to authorization by Congress. “(B) The Mayor may charge an administrative fee, not to exceed $85,000, under any municipal aggregation contract entered into by the District.”. SUBTITLE H. GREAT STREETS CAPITAL EXPENDITURES. Sec. 2101. Short title. This title may be cited as the “Great Streets Capital Expenditures Act of 2006”. Sec. 2102. Section 47-340.23 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows: “(c)(1) Notwithstanding subsections (a) or (b) of this section, the funds described in the fiscal year 2006 capital budget as the Neighborhood Revitalization Commercial Corridor Redevelopment Project (EB3-04) in the amount of $16.6 million shall be expended in the amount ENROLLED ORIGINAL 29Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. of $4.5 million in accordance with the Great Streets spending plan established by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development in May 2006, including: “(A) The amount of $1 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of acquisition and redevelopment of property in the 3300 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W “(B) The amount of $2 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of gap financing economic assistance for the proposed Radio One development at 7th and S Streets, N.W; “(C) The amount of $500,000 shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for grants to property owners for facade and other improvements along H Street, N.E the 1100 block of Good Hope Road, S.E the 3600 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W, and the 3100 block of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E and “(D) The amount of $1 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of property acquisition and gap financing economic assistance in the 1900 block of Martin Luther King, Jr. Avenue, S.E; “(2) The remaining $12.1 million shall be spent on Great Streets supporting projects in the following manner: “(A) The amount of $1.5 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of issuing a grant to the Lincoln Theater to provide for repairs to the roof and other capital maintenance issues; “(B) The amount of $500,000 shall be allocated to the Anacostia Waterfront Corporation to begin a planning process for the construction of a new pedestrian bridge in Ward 7; “(C) The amount of $950,000 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of issuing a grant to the Historical Society of Washington; “(D) The amount of $450,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of renovating the S and T Street, N.W parks; “(E) The amount of $600,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of a complete playground renovation at the Hearst Recreation Center, 3950 37th Street, N.W “(F) The amount of $100,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of designing and building a new state-of-the-art ADA- compliant recreation center at Ft. Stanton Recreation Park, 1812 Erie Street, S.E “(G) The amount of $100,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of a renovation project at North Michigan Park Recreation Center, 1333 Emerson Street, N.E ENROLLED ORIGINAL 30Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(H) The amount of $150,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of designing and building a new state-of-the-art ADA- compliant recreation center at Douglas Recreation Center, 2100 Stanton Terrace, S.E “(I) The amount of $100,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the Marvin Gaye Recreation Center; “(J) The amount of $1.2 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for purposes of acquisition along with facade and other improvements on Nannie Helen Burroughs Avenue, N.E “(K) The amount of $2 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for purposes of acquisition along with facade and other improvements on Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E from the 2300 block of Pennsylvania Avenue, S.E to Southern Avenue, S.E at the Maryland line; “(L) The amount of $500,000 shall be allocated to begin the planning process and development of an environment education center and other environmental improvements at Kingman Island; “(M) The amount of $200,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for purposes of accelerating the designing and building of a new state-of- the-art ADA-compliant recreation center at Ridge Road Recreation Center at Ridge Road and Burns Street, S.E “(N) The amount of $500,000 shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for purposes of issuing a grant to the Boys and Girls Club of Metropolitan Washington #10 located at 2500 14th Street, N.W for the purpose of capital improvements “(O) The amount of $1 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of gap financing economic assistance for proposed mixed use development in the 3600 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W “(P) The amount of $500,000 shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for purposes of site acquisition and site preparation costs for a sit-down restaurant in the 5800 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W “(Q) The amount of $1.5 million shall be allocated to the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development for the purposes of affordable housing and neighborhood-serving retail assistance for a mixed use development of residential and retail uses in the 6500 block of Georgia Avenue, N.W. “(R) The amount of $100,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of designing and building a new state of the art ADA compliant recreation center at Ft. Greble Recreation Center, Martin Luther King Jr. Ave. and Elmira St, S.W and “(S) The amount of $150,000 shall be allocated to the Department of Parks and Recreation for the purposes of issuing a grant to the Marvin Deal African Heritage ENROLLED ORIGINAL 31Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Dancers for studio/theater build-out expenses on newly acquired property at 1230 Good Hope Road, S.E.”. SUBTITLE I. HOMESTEAD HOUSING AMENDMENT. Sec. 2111. Short title. This title may be cited as the “Homestead Housing Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2112. Section 6 of the Homestead Housing Preservation Act of 1986, effective August 9, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-135; D.C. Official Code § 42-2105 is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows: “(d) The Director of the District of Columbia Department of Housing and Community Development is authorized, at his or her discretion, as deemed necessary to achieve the purposes of this act, and when it serves the District’s interest in producing affordable housing, to transfer real property in the Program inventory to other programs administered by the District government.”. SUBTITLE J. COMPREHENSIVE WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT STRATEGIC PLAN. Sec. 2121. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Comprehensive Workforce Development Strategic Plan Revenue Act of 2006 Sec. 2122. The amount of $100,000 of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Department of Employment Services (“DOES”) shall be used by DOES to support the development of a Comprehensive Workforce Development Strategic Plan for the District of Columbia, to be led by the Workforce Investment Council with the involvement of the Superintendent of the District of Columbia Public Schools, the President of the University of the District of Columbia, the State Education Office, the Office of the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development, and all other District agencies providing services or resources for workforce development. The Comprehensive Workforce Development Strategic Plan shall demonstrate the relation between education, employment, and economic development, and shall include an assessment of all workforce development programs, a comprehensive design of a workforce development system, and a strategic plan for implementation of workforce development. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 32Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE K. LOCAL SMALL AND DISADVANTAGED BUSINESS ENHANCEMENT AMENDMENT ACT. Sec. 2131. Short title This subtitle may be cited as the “Local, Small, and Disadvantaged Businesses Enhancement Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2132. The Small, Local, and Disadvantaged Business Development and Assistance Act of 2005, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 2-218.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2331(a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (2) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end 2) A new paragraph (2A) is added to read as follows: “(2A) Meets 3 of the 4 following standards: “(A) More than 50% of the assets of the business enterprise, excluding bank accounts, are located in the District; “(B) More than 50% of the employees of the business enterprise are residents of the District; “(C) The owners of more than 50% of the business enterprise are residents of the District; or “(D) More than 50% of the total sales or other revenues are derived from transactions of the business enterprise in the District; and” b) Section 2332 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(1) is amended by repealing subparagraph (B 2) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “or a qualified metropolitan area business enterprise” c) Section 2333 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by repealing subparagraph (B 2) Subsection (b)(1) is amended by striking the phrase “or a qualified metropolitan area business enterprise” d) Section 2334 is repealed e) Section 2346 is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended by adding the phrase “and non-construction” after the word “construction” e) Section 2346 is amended as follows 1) The section heading is amended by adding the phrase “and non-construction” after the word “construction” 2) Subsection (a) is amended by adding a new paragraph (3) to read as follows: “(3) All non-construction contracts in which a portion will be subcontracted shall include a requirement that at least 35% of the dollar volume, excluding the cost of materials, ENROLLED ORIGINAL 33Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. goods, and supplies, be subcontracted to local small business enterprises, except that if there are insufficient qualified local small business enterprises to fulfill this requirement, then 35% of the dollar volume, excluding the cost of materials, goods, and supplies, shall be subcontracted to local, small, or disadvantaged business enterprises.” 3) Subsection (e) is amended by striking the phrase “dollar value” and inserting the phrase “dollar volume” in its place 4) A new subsection (h) is added to read as follows: “(h) A prime contractor shall submit to the contracting officer and the Director copies of the executed contracts with the subcontracts identified in the subcontracting plan. Failure to submit copies of the executed contracts shall render the underlying contract voidable by the District.” f) A new section 2349a is added to read as follows: “Sec. 2349a. Equity and development participation. “(a) Local, small, and disadvantaged business enterprises shall receive 20% in equity and development participation in all development projects supported by District funds and in all development projects that take place on District owned property. “(b) The participation requirement shall include all development projects undertaken by government corporations and all development projects resulting from contractual relationships where District owned real property is transferred to a third party. “(c) The Mayor shall promulgate proposed rules to implement the provisions of this section within 90 days of the effective date of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 The Mayor shall submit the proposed rules to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution within the 45-day review period, the proposed rules shall be deemed approved. “(d) This section shall not apply if the entity that controls the development project is an entity tax-exempt under section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, approved August 16, 1954 (68A Stat. 163; 26 U.S.C. §501(c or other not-for-profit entity. “(e) This section shall not apply to any development project for which a contract for purchase of one or more parcels of real property has been executed prior to the effective date of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679).” g) Section 2350(b)(1)(B) is amended by striking the phrase “dollar value” and inserting the phrase “dollar volume” in its place h) Section 2354 is amended as follows 1) The existing language is designated as subsection (a 2) The newly designated subsection (a)(2) as follows A) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the word “and” at the end. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 34Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 B) Subparagraph (D) is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting the phrase “; and” in its place C) A new subparagraph (E) is added to read as follows: “(E) The actual dollar amount expended with each business enterprise.” 3) New subsections (b) and (c) are added to read as follows: “(b) Within 45 days of its receipt of the annual reports required by section 2350(g the Department shall submit to the Council and the Commission a report containing the following information with respect to each government corporation for the current and prior fiscal years: “(1) The expendable budget of the government corporation; “(2) The government corporation's achievement with respect to the requirements of section 2350. “(3) A list of each contract or procurement of the government corporation, which shall include the following information: “(A) A description of the contract or procurement; “(B) The dollar amount of the contract or procurement; “(C) The name of the business enterprise from which the goods or services were contracted or procured; “(D) Whether the business enterprise was a certified local, small, or disadvantaged business enterprise, and, if so: “(i) The category or categories under which the business enterprise is certified; and “(ii) The identification number of the business enterprise assigned by the Department; “(E) The source of funding for the contract (local, federal, other, or capital and “(F) The actual dollar amount expended with each business enterprise. “(c)(1) Beginning with the first full quarter after the effective date of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 “2007 Budget Support Act” the Department shall submit to the Council, within 60 days of the end of each quarter, the quarterly reports of each agency required by section 2353 and the quarterly reports of each government corporation required by section 2350(f “(2) Beginning with the first full quarter after the effective date of the 2007 Budget Support Act, the Department shall submit to the Council the following: “(A) A summary of the information that each agency is required to submit pursuant to section 2353 and the information that each government corporation is required to submit pursuant to section 2350(f in a format that shows the cumulative progress of each agency’s or government corporation’s annual LSDBE contracting and procurement goals to date, and the actual dollar amount expended with each business enterprise for the current fiscal year; and ENROLLED ORIGINAL 35Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(B) A list of all agencies and government corporations that have not submitted a report for that quarter with a detailed explanation of what actions were taken by the Department to effectuate compliance with the reporting requirement.” i) Section 2361 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows: “(e) The Commission shall give first priority in reviewing applications submitted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section to any business enterprises that has received a provisional certification pursuant to section 2362.” j) Section 2362(b) is amended by striking the number “120” and inserting the number “90” in its place k) Section 2363 is amended by adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows: “(e) Any contract awarded to a business enterprise based on the use of a provisional certification issued pursuant the section 2362 shall be voidable by the District if the final disposition of an application for a certificate of registration is denied by the commission pursuant to section 2361.”. Sec. 2133. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Department of Small and Local Business Development, an amount of $200,000 shall be allocated to the additional ramp- up costs and the costs associated with implementing the provisions of this subtitle; provided, that not less than $100,000 of this amount shall be used to complete a disparity study, designed to investigate how the effect of any historic or continuing discriminatory practices impact on the ability of local, small, and disadvantaged business enterprises to participate in procurement and other business opportunities in the District of Columbia; provided further, that not less than $50,000 of this amount shall be used to monitor the implementation of section 2132(e) of this subtitle; and not less than $50,000 shall be used to monitor the implementation of section 2132(f) of this subtitle. SUBTITLE L. D.C. HOUSING AUTHORITY RENT SUPPLEMENT PROGRAM. Sec. 2141. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “D.C. Housing Authority Rent Supplement Act of 2006”. Sec. 2142. The District of Columbia Housing Authority Act of 1999, effective May 9, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-105; D.C. Official Code § 6-201 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 6-201) is amended by adding new paragraphs (3A 19A 23A 36A 39A 42A 43A and (43B) to read, respectively, as follows 1) “(3A) “Area median income” means: “(A) For a household of 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons in the Washington Metropolitan Statistical Area as set forth in the ENROLLED ORIGINAL 36Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. periodic calculation provided by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development; “(B) For a household of 3 persons, 90% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; “(C) For a household of 2 persons, 80% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; “(D) For a household of one person, 70% of the area median income for a household of 4 persons; “(E) For a household of more than 4 persons, the area median income for a household of 4 persons, increased by 10% of the area median income for a family of 4 persons for each household member exceeding 4 persons (e.g the area median income for a family of 5 shall be 110% of the area median income for a family of 4; the area median income for a household of 6 shall be 120% of the area median income for a family of 4).” 2) “(19A) “Extremely-low income” means an individual or family whose gross income does not exceed 30% of the area median income.” 3) “(23A) “Housing Choice Voucher Program” means the federal housing program authorized by section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, approved September 1, 1937 (50 Stat. 888; 42 U.S.C. § 1437(f) et seq and administered in the District of Columbia by the District of Columbia Housing Authority.” 4) “(36A) “Partnership Program for Affordable Housing” means the District of Columbia Housing Authority Program described in Chapter 93 of Title 14 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations.” 5) “(39A) “Project-based voucher assistance” means funds attached to a particular building, or set of buildings, owned and operated by a private or nonprofit housing provider.” 6) “(42A) “Rent Supplement Program” means the program established under section 26a to provide housing assistance to extremely low-income District residents, including those who are homeless and those in need of supportive services, such as elderly individuals or those with disabilities.” 7) “(43A) “Sponsor-based voucher assistance” means funds allocated under contract to a particular private or nonprofit housing provider to subsidize the rent, in units owned and operated by the provider, for a maximum number of households established by contract.” 8) “(43B) “Supportive housing” means housing provided in connection with voluntary services designed primarily to help tenants maintain housing, including coordination or case management, physical and mental health, substance use management and recovery support, job training, literacy and education, youth and children’s programs, and money management.” b) New sections 26a, 26b, and 26c are added to read as follows: “Sec. 26a. Rent Supplement Program: establishment of program and distribution of funds. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 37Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(a) The Rent Supplement Program is established to provide housing assistance to extremely low-income District residents, including those who are homeless and those in need of supportive services, such as elderly individuals or those with disabilities. The funding of this program is subject to appropriation. The Authority shall administer the program and shall promulgate rules for its implementation. The assistance under this section, section 26b, and 26c shall not constitute an entitlement. “(b) The Authority shall allocate the funds appropriated for the program annually toward project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance, as described in section 26b, and tenant- based assistance, as described in section 26c. “(c) The Authority shall promulgate rules, subject to Council approval, as required in sections 26b and 26c, which shall govern the distribution of funds under this program. If federal rules affect local funds, the Authority shall incorporate such rules into the submission to the Council required under this section, section 26b, and section 26c, except if the rules are inconsistent with this section, section 26b, and section 26c. The rules shall provide for allocating project-based, tenant-based, and sponsor-based funds to maintain or create new affordable housing units, including by combining funds under this program with other sources of funds for housing production and development. “(d)(1) There is established a fund designated as the Rent Supplement Fund (“Fund” which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia. All revenues, grants, receipts, or other funds specifically identified or required by any provision of District of Columbia law to be paid into the Fund, and all interest earned on those funds, shall be deposited in the Fund without regard to fiscal year limitation pursuant to an act of Congress and shall be used solely to fund grants and provide assistance as set forth in this section and section 26b. All funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in this section and section 26b, subject to authorization by Congress in an appropriations act. “(2) With regard to project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance, in any given year, the Authority shall spend the specified percentage of its funds that accrues in that year for the purpose of funding grants under this section, unless it provides written justification to the Council for not doing so. “Sec. 26b. Project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance. “(a) The funds allocated under the program for project-based and sponsor-based voucher assistance shall be awarded by the Authority pursuant to its Partnership Program For Affordable Housing, except as otherwise provided herein. “(b) The Authority shall promulgate rules to govern the awarding of rent supplement funds through Partnership Program grants, as described in this section, to providers of sponsor- based housing. The Authority shall designate a portion of these funds to be awarded on a priority basis to sponsors of supportive housing for individuals with special needs. The rules may ENROLLED ORIGINAL 38Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. address eligibility, admission, and occupancy criteria, which serve the supportive housing goals of the housing development. “(c) The Authority shall apply its existing Partnership Program rules to govern the awarding of Partnership Program grants for project-based voucher assistance and the continuing eligibility for such grants under this section, except where such rules are inconsistent with this legislation. The Authority shall also apply its existing Partnership Program and Housing Choice Voucher Program rules to govern eligibility, admission, and continuing occupancy by tenants in units receiving assistance under this section, section 26a, and section 26c, except if the rules are inconsistent with this section, section 26a, and section 26c. The Authority shall promulgate such additional rules as are necessary to ensure that eligibility for tenancy in the units supported by grants under this section is limited to households with gross income at or below 30% of the area median income. “(d) To maintain consistency for households receiving rental housing support, the Authority shall, to the extent possible, given funding resources available in the Rent Supplement Program, continue to fund project-based and sponsor-based grantees at the same level, adjusted for inflation, on an annual basis, unless the Authority determines that a grantee is not meeting the criteria set forth in the rules governing the Partnership Program or is not adhering to other standards set forth by rule by the Authority. “Sec. 26c. Tenant-based assistance. “(a) The funds allocated for tenant-based assistance shall be administered through the Authority’s Housing Choice Voucher Program. Except as provided in this section, tenant-based assistance provided through the Rent Supplement Program shall be subject to the Authority’s existing rules, regulations, policies, and procedures for the Housing Choice Voucher Program. Existing rules, regulations, policies, and procedures affecting the Rent Supplement Program shall be submitted for Council review as required by section 26a. “(b) Eligible families shall be selected from the Authority’s Housing Choice Voucher Program waiting list according to rules established by the Authority for selection and admission, with the following additional limitations: “(1) Eligible families shall be extremely low-income; and “(2) The Authority shall develop rules that give preference in awarding a percentage of the vouchers funded under this program to District residents who are homeless applicants with one or more children under 18 years of age. The percentage shall be determined by the Authority and shall be included in the rules adopted for the program.”. SUBTITLE M. VACANCY CONVERSION FEE CLARIFICATION AMENDMENT ACT OF 2006. Sec. 2161. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Vacancy Conversion Fee Clarification Amendment Act of 2006”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 39Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 2162. The Rental Housing Conversion and Sale Act of 1980, effective September 10, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-86; D.C. Official Code § 42-3401.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 204 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3402.04) is amended as follows 1) Existing subsection (a) is redesignated as subsection (a-1 2) A new subsection (a) is added to read as follows: “(a) Definitions For purposes of this section, the term: “(1) “Low-income individual” means an individual with an annual household income, as determined by the Mayor, of less than 60% of the area median income for the Washington-Arlington-Alexandria Metropolitan area. “(2) “Qualifying tenant-purchasers” means the number of tenants or purchasers who qualify as low-income individuals at the time they enter a 5-year lease, acquire an option to lease, or purchase a unit in the housing accommodation, and whose continued right to remain a tenant is not required by law. “(3) “Declared conversion fee” means the conversion fee required by this section, based on a bona fide estimate of the sales price and number of qualifying tenant-purchasers, as declared by the property owner at the time of application for registration of the housing accommodation as a condominium or cooperative. “(4) “Final conversion fee” means the conversion fee required by this section, based on the number of qualifying tenant-purchasers and the sales price of all sold units and any unsold units that have been assessed a conversion fee by the Mayor, as required by subsection (b- 1) of this section.” 3) Newly designated subsection (a-1) is amended to read as follows: “(a-1) Amount An owner who converts a housing accommodation, including vacant buildings, into a condominium or a cooperative shall pay the Mayor a conversion fee of 5% of the sales price for each condominium unit, or proportionate value of the cooperative residence, within the housing accommodation.” 4) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: “(b) Reduction The Mayor shall reduce the conversion fee of each unit of a condominium, or proportionate value of the cooperative residence, when the owner sells a unit in the housing accommodation, provides a lease, or provides an option to lease for at least 5 years, to current or new qualifying tenant-purchasers. To qualify for this reduction, a lease cannot require monthly payments greater than existing rents, as may be increased by the annual adjustment of general applicability provided in section 206(b or a similar annual adjustment in any successor rent control act, or 30% of gross household income, whichever is greater. The 5% conversion fee shall be reduced by dividing the total number of qualifying tenant-purchasers by the number of units in the building at settlement, and multiplying the quotient by 5 The resulting percentage shall be subtracted from the 5% conversion fee coefficient and shall be used as the basis of the final conversion fee.” 5) Subsection (b-1) is amended to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 40Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(b-1) Payment Upon registration of the housing accommodation as a condominium or a cooperative, the Mayor shall record a lien on the property in the amount of the declared conversion fee. The declared conversion fee shall be apportioned among the individual units or shares according to the percentage that each unit represents of the total estimated sales price and shall be paid at the time of settlement on the individual units or shares. The Recorder of Deeds shall not record a deed for an individual unit or share until the declared conversion fee for that individual unit or share is paid in full. The Mayor shall require payment of the declared conversion fee for any unsold units or shares 2 years after the housing accommodation is registered as a condominium or a cooperative. After payment of the declared conversion fees for all of the units, if the declared conversion fee and the final conversion fees are not the same, any underpayment or overpayment of the conversion fee shall be collected from the owner or refunded to the owner by the Mayor, accordingly. If the final conversion fee is greater that the declared conversion fee, for each 1% that the final conversion fee is greater than the declared conversion fee, a .5 one-half of one percent) surcharge shall be added to the conversion fee paid by the owner. The Mayor shall enforce a lien against any unsold unit of a condominium or proportionate value of a cooperative to collect any underpayment of the final conversion fee.” 6) Subsection (c) is repealed b) Section 210 (D.C. Official Code § 42-3402.10) is amended as follows 1) Strike the sentence “The provisions of this title shall not apply to the conversion of housing accommodations into condominium or cooperative status which are fully vacant as of the date of application to the Mayor for a vacancy exemption.” and insert the sentence “The provisions of this title shall not apply to the conversion of housing accommodations into condominium or cooperative status that are fully vacant as of the date of application to the Mayor for a vacancy exemption; provided, that this exemption shall not apply to section 204.” in its place 2) Strike the sentence “The Mayor shall accept the owner’s certification unless the Mayor has received information which tends to challenge the truthfulness of the certification.” and insert the sentences “The Mayor shall investigate all requests for vacancy exemptions under this section and photographically document the vacant status of at least 25% of the total number of randomly selected units in the housing accommodation. All vacancy exemptions shall expire 90 days after certification. Vacancy exemptions properly certified, and in effect, on the effective date of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 shall expire 90 days after the effective date of the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679)” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 41Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE N. OFFICE OF THE CHIEF TENANT ADVOCATE FUNDING ACT. Sec. 2171. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Office of the Chief Tenant Advocate Funding Act of 2006”. Sec. 2172. Section 401 of the Rental Housing Act of 1985, effective July 17, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-10; D.C. Official Code § 42-3504.01 is amended as follows a) Strike the phrase “$16” and insert the phrase “$17” in its place b) Strike the phrase “tenant ombudsman and a” c) Strike the phrase “liaison.” and insert the phrase “liaison; provided further, that a portion of fees collected shall be deposited in a special account for use by the Office of the Chief Tenant Advocate.” in its place. SUBTITLE O. FREE CLINIC ASSISTANCE PROGRAM COVERAGE AMENDMENT. Sec. 2181. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Free Clinic Assistance Program Coverage Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2182. The Free Clinic Assistance Program Act of 1986, effective September 23, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-155; D.C. Code § l-307.21, et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2(2) is amended as follows 1) The lead-in text is amended by striking the phrase “health clinic or health service” and inserting the phrase “health clinic or community health center” in its place 2) Subparagraph (C) is amended by striking the phrase “and was operating in the District on January 1, 1986 3) Subparagraph (E) is amended to read as follows: “(E) Does not provide intrapartum care, high-risk emergency care, or care requiring the use of anesthesia other than local anesthesia; provided, that intrapartum care may be provided if limited to the management of low-risk women whose labor, delivery, postpartum course, and infant doe not require referral to a physician for medical care.” 4) Subparagraph (F) is amended by striking the phrase “physician,” and inserting the phrase “physician, physician assistant” in its place b) Section 4(a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase “clinic to pay” and inserting the phrase “, or for which payment of the medical insurance premiums would result in a significant reduction of services to low-income patients” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 42Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE P. JOB OPPORTUNITY FUND CLARIFICATION. Sec. 2191. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as “Job Opportunity Fund Clarification Act of 2006 Sec. 2192. Section 203(e) and (f) of the Way to Work Act of 2006, effective June 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-118; 53 DCR 2602 is amended to read as follows: “(e) The funds shall be administered by the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development. “(f) Subject to the availability of funds, the Deputy Mayor for Planning and Economic Development may fund applications for grants or other assistance as may be recommended by the Director under the provisions of this title.”. TITLE III. PUBLIC SAFETY AND JUSTICE SUBTITLE A. INMATE WELFARE FUND. Sec. 3001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Inmate Welfare Fund Establishment Act of 2006 Sec. 3002. Definitions. For the purposes of this subtitle, the term 1) “Commissary” means a system through which inmates in District correctional facilities are able to purchase permitted commodities 2) “Committee” means the Inmate Welfare Fund Committee established by section 3005 3) “Correctional facility” means any building, or group of buildings, and concomitant services, operated as a single management unit by, or under contract with, the Department of Corrections for the purpose of housing and providing services to persons ordered confined pending trial or upon conviction and sentencing for a violation of law 4) “Department” means the Department of Corrections 5) “Director” means the Director of the Department of Corrections 6) “Fund” means the Inmate Welfare Fund established by section 3003. Sec. 3003. Establishment of Inmate Welfare Fund; audit; report a) There is established a nonlapsing fund to be known as the Inmate Welfare Fund and to be used for the purposes set forth in section 3004 b) The Fund shall consist of 1) An initial appropriation in fiscal year 2007; and (2) Monies derived from the sale of goods through the commissary at correctional facilities. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 43Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 c) Except as provided in section 3004(2 funds deposited into the Fund shall not be transferred or revert to the fund balance of the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in section 3004, subject to authorization by Congress d) The Fund shall comply with all financial and procurement statutes, rules, regulations, standards, and systems promulgated by the District of Columbia government e) The Fund shall be subject to annual audits scheduled by the Office of the Chief Financial Officer, which shall be submitted to the Council no later than February 1 of each year. The scope of the audit shall include an examination of the Department’s use of Fund profits, including stocking the commissaries, low-bond releases, providing inmate clothing upon release, and funding transportation costs for inmates after release. The audit reports shall be submitted to the Council and the Mayor. Sec. 3004. Uses of Inmate Welfare Fund. The Fund shall be used for the following purposes, in order of priority 1) To stock the commissaries of District correctional facilities 2) To repay the initial appropriation used to finance the Fund; and (3) To provide goods and services that benefit the general inmate population at District correctional facilities, as determined by the Inmate Welfare Fund Committee established in section 3005. Sec. 3005. Inmate Welfare Fund Committee a) The Inmate Welfare Fund Committee is established for the purpose of administering and supervising the operations of and the expenditures from the Inmate Welfare Fund b) The Committee shall be composed of the following 5 members 1) The Director of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee 2) The General Counsel of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee 3) The Warden of the Central Detention Facility, or his or her designee 4) The Manager of the Office of Internal Controls, Compliance, and Accreditation of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee; and (5) The Director of the Office of Management Information and Technological Services of the Department of Corrections, or his or her designee c) The Committee shall maintain a record of its authorization and approval for all expenditures from the Fund d) The Committee may promulgate regulations governing the use and expenditures of the Fund. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 44Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE B. VICTIMS OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE GRANT-MAKING. Sec. 3021. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Victims of Domestic Violence Grant-Making Act of 2006 Sec. 3022. Grant-making authority for assisting domestic violence victims. Beginning in fiscal year 2007, the Mayor is authorized to issue grants from local funds received for the Office of Victim Services to assist victims of domestic violence. Sec. 3023. Rules. The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this subtitle. SUBTITLE C. NATIONAL GUARD OPERATIONS COORDINATION PLAN. Sec. 3031. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “National Guard Operations Coordination Act of 2006 Sec. 3032. Establishment of a plan to coordinate operations of the National Guard and the Metropolitan Police Department. The Mayor is directed to consult with the Commanding General of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to establish a plan whereby the National Guard Reaction Force provides supplemental manpower to the Special Operations Division of the Metropolitan Police Department to assist it in the performance of its duties. The plan shall be implemented within 180 days of April 26, 2006. SUBTITLE D. CIVIL LEGAL SERVICES. Sec. 3041. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Civil Legal Services Act of 2006 Sec. 3042. Funding for civil legal services. The Office of the Attorney General is hereby authorized to and shall award a grant, with funds appropriated through the fiscal year 2007 budget, of no less than $3.2 million to the District of Columbia Bar Foundation (“Bar Foundation” which shall in turn award grants to nonprofit organizations that deliver civil legal services to low-income people; provided, that no more than $250,000 from the funds granted to the Bar Foundation shall be used to provide funding for a District of Columbia Poverty Lawyer Loan Assistance Repayment Program. The Office of the Attorney General shall permit the Bar Foundation a reasonable amount for administrative expenses, up to 5% of the funds granted under this section. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 45Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. TITLE IV. PUBLIC EDUCATION SYSTEM SUBTITLE A. UNIFORM PER STUDENT FUNDING FORMULA FOR PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND PUBLIC CHARTER SCHOOLS. Sec. 4001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 4002. The Uniform Per Student Funding Formula for Public Schools and Public Charter Schools and Tax Conformity Clarification Amendment Act of 1998, effective March 26, 1999 (D.C. Law 12-207; D.C. Official Code § 38-2901 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102 (D.C. Official Code § 38-2901) is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (1A) is added to read as follows: “(1A) “Alternative program" means specialized instruction for students under court supervision or on short- and long-term suspension, or who have been chronically truant or expelled from a regular District of Columbia Public School or public charter school academic program. To qualify as an alternative program, a school must meet the criteria and rules set by the State Education Office. An alternative program may describe an entire school or a specialized program within a school.” 2) Paragraph (2) is repealed 3) Paragraph (6) is amended to read as follows: “(6) “Full-time equivalent" means student enrollment the equal of: “(A) Five hours or more per school day for a minimum of 180 school days for students enrolled in grades pre-school through 12; or “(B) Three hours per day for a minimum of 4 days per week for 36 weeks per school year for adult enrollment.” 4) Paragraph 13 is amended to read as follows: “(13 Summer school" means an accelerated instructional program provided outside the regular school year of 180 days for students in targeted grades or grade spans pursuant to promotion policies of the District of Columbia Public Schools and public charter schools.” b) Section 104 (D.C. Official Code § 38-2903) is amended by striking the phrase “$7,307.47 per student for FY 2006” and inserting the phrase “$8,002.06 per student for FY 2007” in its place c) Section 105 (D.C. Official Code § 38-2904) is amended to read as follows: “Sec. 105. Weightings applied to counts of students enrolled at certain grade levels. “The student counts at certain grade levels and in certain programs shall be weighted to provide an amount per student differing from the basic foundation level in accordance with the following schedule: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 46Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Grade Level Weighting Per Pupil Allocation in 2007 Pre-School 1.16 $9,2829 Pre-Kindergarten 1.16 $9,2829 Kindergarten 1.16 $9,2829 Grades 1-3 1.03 $8,242.12 Grades 4-5 1.00 $8,002.60 Ungraded ES 1.03 $8,242.12 Grades 6-8 1.00 $8,002.60 Ungraded MS/JHS 1.00 $8,002.60 Grades 9-12 1.17 $9,362.41 Ungraded SHS 1.17 $9,362.41 Alternative Program 1.23 $9,842.53 Special ed schools 1.17 $9,362.41 Adult 0.75 $6,001.55 (d) Section 106 (D.C. Official Code § 38-2905) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows: “(c) These supplemental allocations shall be calculated by applying weightings to the foundation level as follows: Special Needs Add-ons: Level/Program Definition Weighting Supplemental Per Pupil FY 2007 Level 1: Special Eight hours or less 0.54 $4,321 Education per week of specialized services Level 2: Special More than 8 hours and 0.82 $6,562 Education less than or equal to 16 hours per school week of specialized services Level 3: Special More than 16 hours and 1.41 $11,283 Education less than or equal to 24 hours per school week of specialized services ENROLLED ORIGINAL 47Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 Level 4: Special More than 24 hours per 2.47 $19,765 Education week which may include instruction in a self-contained separate school other than residential placement LEP/NEP Limited and non-English 0.40 $3,201 proficient students Summer An instructional program 0.17 $1,360 as defined in section 102(13 including instruction for special education students whose Individual Education Plan requires extended school year or summer school services Residential D.C. Public School or 1.70 $13,604 public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting, in addition to their instructional program Level 1: Special Additional funding to 074 $2,993 Education support the Residential after-hours level 1 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or public charter school that provides students with room ENROLLED ORIGINAL 48Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. and board in a residential setting Level 2: Special Additional funding to 16 $10,883 Education support the Residential after-hours level 2 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting Level 3: Special Additional funding to 2.941 $23,534 Education support the Residential after-hours level 3 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting Level 4: Special Additional funding to 2.924 $23,398 Education support the Residential after-hours level 4 special educational needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or public charter school that provides ENROLLED ORIGINAL 49Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. students with room and board in a residential setting Level 5: Special Residential placement 9.40 $75,219 Education Residential LEP/NEP– Additional funding to 0.68 $5,441 Residential support the after-hours level 3 special education needs of students living in a D.C. Public School or public charter school that provides students with room and board in a residential setting 2) Subsection (e) is amended to read as follows: “(e)(1) The summer school weighting of 0.17 shall apply to DCPS and public charter school students enrolled for at least 6 weeks for the purpose described in section 102(13 Summer school students enrolled for a lesser period shall be funded for the number of days in that period on a pro-rata basis. “(2) To receive funding, a DCPS or public charter school summer school program must offer at least 60 hours of instruction outside the regular school year. “(3) To receive full funding, a summer school program must offer at least 4 hours of instruction per day, 5 days a week, for 6 weeks, or its equivalent, for a total of at least 120 hours of instruction outside the regular school year for the purpose described in section 102(13 “(4) The fully funded summer school weighting of 0.17 shall apply for summer school programs that meet the requirements of paragraph (3) of this subsection. “(5) Summer school programs that enroll students for less than 120 hours but more than 59 hours shall be funded on a pro-rata basis.” e) Section 107(d D.C. Official Code § 38-2906(d is amended to read as follows: “(d)(1) The student counts reported for October 5 of each year shall be verified by an independent contractor commissioned by the State Education Office. The independent contractor ENROLLED ORIGINAL 50Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. shall perform an audit on the student enrollment of each DCPS school and of each public charter school to: “(A) Verify the accuracy of the information contained in the membership report; and “(B) Identify any material weaknesses in the systems, procedures, or methodology used by the DCPS system and public charter schools in: “(i) Determining the number of students, including non-resident students, enrolled in the DCPS and in public charter schools and the number of students whose tuition for enrollment in other school systems is paid for by funds available to the District of Columbia public schools; and “(ii) Assessing and collecting fees and tuition from non-resident students. “(2) The verification process shall begin no later than one week following the day on which the count is taken. The verification shall cover the information required by section 2402 of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321 [257]; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.02 and shall be transmitted by the Mayor to the Council, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the appropriate congressional committees no later than the following December 31. Until the verification is transmitted, the unaudited October count shall serve as the basis for the annual appropriation for the following fiscal year and for quarterly payments.” f) Section 107b (D.C. Official Code § 38-2906.02) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended to read as follows: “(b) Each payment shall be one-fourth of each public charter school's entitlement, determined as follows: “(1) The basis of the July 15 payment to a public charter school shall be the estimate used in the June 30 quarterly reports submitted by the eligible chartering authorities pursuant to section 2402(a) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995, approved April 26, 1996 (110 Stat. 1321 [573]; D.C. Official Code § 38-1804.02(a “(2) The basis of the October 25 and January 15 payments shall be the unaudited October enrollment numbers for that school contained in the reports submitted by the eligible chartering authorities on October 5. “(3) The basis of the April 15 payment shall be the audited October enrollment numbers; provided, that these amounts shall be adjusted in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c) of this section.” 2) New subsections (f) and (g) are added to read as follows: “(f) During any period in which payments to public charter schools become due on a date when District funding is authorized pursuant to a continuing resolution rather than pursuant to an appropriations act, the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia shall provide ENROLLED ORIGINAL 51Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. payments for new public charter schools and increased enrollments in other public charter schools from any unexpended and unobligated funds. “(g) Upon application to the Chief Financial Officer of the District of Columbia, charter schools offering alternative education or special education services may receive payment for eligible students enrolling after October 5, on a pro-rata basis from the date on which the school begins to provide services to that student; provided, that the student represents a net increase to the school’s enrollment as of October 5. The pro-rata payments for special education students enrolling after October 5 based on the public charter school’s predetermined enrollment schedule shall be disbursed in addition to the quarterly payments at the discretion of the Chief Financial Officer.” g) Section 109 (D.C. Official Code § 38-2908) is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows: “(d) For DCPS or Public Charter Schools that provide students with room and board in a residential setting, in addition to their instructional program, the facilities allowance determined pursuant to this section shall be multiplied by 2.7 for those students in residence at the school.” h) Section 111(2 D.C. Official Code § 38-2910(2 is amended to read as follows: “(2) The Mayor, Council, Superintendent/CEO, and Board of Education shall use their best efforts to obtain temporary supplemental funding from other revenue sources.” i) Section 112 (D.C. Official Code § 38-2911) is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows: “(c) The State Education Office shall make recommendations to revise and review the formula as described in subsection (a) of this section for submission to the Mayor and the Council.”. SUBTITLE B. QUALITY TEACHER INCENTIVE. Sec. 4011. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Quality Teacher Incentive Act of 2006 Sec. 4012. Section 47-1803.03 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new subsection (b-2) to read as follows: “(b-2) An individual who has been a classroom teacher in a public school or public charter school in the District of Columbia for the entire year for which the individual is filing or for the entire year prior to the year for which the individual is filing and has a professional certificate for teaching may deduct from gross income: “(1) The amount the individual paid during the year for basic classroom materials and supplies necessary for teaching; provided, that the deduction shall not exceed $500 per year, per individual, whether the individual files individually or jointly; and “(2) The amount the individual paid during the year as tuition and fees for post- graduate education, professional development, or state licensing examination and testing required ENROLLED ORIGINAL 52Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. for or related to improving teacher credentials or maintaining professional certification; provided, that the deduction shall not exceed $1,500 per year, per individual, whether the individual files individually or jointly.”. Sec. 4013. Section 4012 is subject to the availability of appropriations. SUBTITLE C. HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE. Sec. 4021. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Higher Education Financial Aid Assistance Act of 2006”. Sec. 4022. Definitions. For the purposes of this subtitle, the term 1) “Academic year” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 481 of the Higher Education Act 2) “DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program” means the college financial assistance program administered by the State Education Office pursuant to Subpart 4 of Title IV of the Higher Education Act 3) “Eligible institution” means an institution that A) Is an institution of higher education, either public or private, with its principal campus in the District of Columbia; and (B) Is eligible to receive Student Aid Program funds under Title IV of the Higher Education Act 4) “Eligible student” means a District resident who meets the eligibility criteria for the DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program administered by the State Education Office 5) “Higher Education Act” means the Higher Education Act of 1965, approved November 8, 1965 (79 Stat. 1219; 20 U.S.C. § 1001 et seq 6) “Institution of higher education” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 101 of the Higher Education Act 7) “Qualified higher education expenses” means A) Tuition, fees, and the cost of books, supplies, and equipment required for the enrollment or attendance of a qualified beneficiary at an eligible institution B) The costs of room and board of a qualified beneficiary incurred while attending an eligible institution; provided, that the amount of room and board shall not exceed the minimum room and board allowance determined in calculating costs of attendance for federal financial aid programs under section 472 of the Higher Education Act, or any subsequent legislation and implementing regulations; and (C) Additional living expenses. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 53Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4023. DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program. The State Education Office shall administer the DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program. Sec. 4024. Grant awards for DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program a) From local funds appropriated annually for the DC Leveraging Educational Assistance Partnership Program, the State Education Office shall make available grant awards to pay for qualified higher education expenses for no fewer than 800 eligible students attending eligible institutions. If fewer than 800 eligible students from eligible institutions apply, the funds may be used to grant awards to eligible students attending eligible institutions of higher education outside of the District of Columbia b) An eligible student attending an eligible institution shall have paid on the student’s behalf under this section A) Not more than $5,000 for any one academic year; and (B) A total of not more than $25,000 over 5 years c) Payments under this section shall be prorated for eligible students who attend an eligible institution on less than a full-time basis. Sec. 4025. Annual reports a) The Mayor shall report to the Council annually regarding 1) The number of eligible students attending each eligible institution and the amount of the grant awards paid to those institutions on behalf of eligible students 2) The extent, if any, to which a ratable reduction was made in the amount of higher education assistance payments made on behalf of eligible students; and (3) The progress made by eligible students each year in obtaining recognized academic credentials b) The State Education Office shall annually make available the following information, to be solicited by the State Education Office and collected from participating institutions 1) The enrollment status and graduation rates of students on whose behalf funding from this program has been paid to eligible institutions; and (2) The enrollment status and graduation rates of students on whose behalf funding has been paid from the DC Tuition Assistance Grant Program, established by the District of Columbia College Access Act of 1999, approved November 12, 1999 (113 Stat. 1329; D.C. Official Code § 38-2701 et seq ENROLLED ORIGINAL 54Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE D. EDUCATIONAL SERVICES FOR DETAINED AND COMMITTED YOUTH UNDER THE SUPERVISION OF THE DEPARTMENT OF YOUTH REHABILITATION SERVICES. Sec. 4031. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Educational Services for Detained and Committed Youth Act of 2006 Sec. 4032. Educational services for detained and committed youth under the supervision of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services. The District of Columbia Board of Education shall enter into a Memorandum of Understanding (“MOU”) with the Mayor that shall specify how educational services shall be provided to committed and detained youth who are under the supervision of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services (“DYRS”) and are residing in the Oak Hill Youth Center, the Youth Services Center, and any other replacement or new secure facilities operated by or on behalf of DYRS for youth in DYRS custody. The MOU shall specify in detail how an appropriate educational program shall be delivered to children under the supervision of DYRS and how operating funds, allocations, and other funds that support the provision of these services will be utilized. TITLE V. HUMAN SUPPORT SERVICE SUBTITLE A. MEDICAL HOMES GRANT-MAKING. Sec. 5001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Medical Homes Grant-Making Act of 2006”. Sec. 5002. Grant-making authority a) In addition to any contract for services authorized by the Health Care Privatization Amendment Act of 2001, effective July 12, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-18; D.C. Official Code § 7-1401 et seq “Act” subject to any necessary appropriation and the legal availability of funding, the Office of the City Administrator shall award, through a grant to the District of Columbia Primary Care Association 1) If the grant meets the criteria for a sole source award, from capital funds available to the Department of Health outside of the funding for any contract authorized by the Act, an amount not to exceed $8.2 million during fiscal year 2007,which amount is in addition to the $7 million authorized by the Medical Homes Grant-Making Act of 2004, effective August 2, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-205; D.C. Official Code § 7-1401, note and $2.8 million fiscal year 2009 to support Medical Homes DC provided that A) Of the fiscal year 2007 funding 6 million shall be directed to the Northwest One Community Health Center project, as part of the Mayor’s New Communities Initiative; which funds shall be managed according to the general rules of Medical Homes DC, as ENROLLED ORIGINAL 55Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. described in the Medical Homes Grant Agreement between the District and the DC Primary Care Association; provided, that any portion of the $6 million not used for the Northwest One Health Center shall be used for any other Medical Homes capital project B) Of the remainder of the grant 2.2 million in fiscal year 2007 and $2.8 in fiscal year 2009, shall be used to develop an electronic health record system for community health centers to promote higher quality of care, improved coordination of services among providers, and more accurate reporting of health statistics to the Department of Health; provided, that of the $2.2 million allocated for fiscal year 2007 200,000 shall be used to support information technology needs for District of Columbia public and charter school nurse suites 2) From operating funds available to the Department of Health not including funding for any contract authorized by the Act, an amount not to exceed $1.9 million during fiscal year 2007 to support and stimulate the Medical Homes DC’s public purpose of health improvement by ensuring that all residents of the District of Columbia, especially low-income residents and indigent residents, have a medical home where a primary care provider knows each patient’s health history, where each patient can be seen regardless of ability to pay, and where each patient can routinely seek non-emergency medical care in the community where the patient resides b) The grant amounts and grant authority provided for in this act are in addition to any grant amounts and authority provided by the Medical Homes Grant-Making Act of 2004 effective August 2, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-205; D.C. Official Code § 7-1401, note Sec. 5003. Rulemaking authority. The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204, D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this act. SUBTITLE B. HEALTH INSURANCE OPEN ENROLLMENT PROGRAM AMENDMENT AND HEALTHY DC PROGRAM. Sec. 5011. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Amendment Act of 2006 Sec. 5012. The Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-245; D.C. Official Code § 31-3501 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 2 (D.C. Official Code § 31-3501) is amended by adding a new paragraph (3A) and (7A) to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 56Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(3A) “Healthy DC Fund” means the Healthy DC Fund established by section 15b. “(7A) “RS Fund” means the rate stabilization fund established by section 15(j).” b) Section 15 (D.C. Official Code § 31-3514) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (f) is repealed 2) Subsection (j) is amended to read as follows: “(j)(1) A corporation shall maintain a separately established rate stabilization fund (“RS Fund”) to be used solely to subsidize open enrollment subscribers pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of this section. A corporation shall deposit an amount necessary and appropriate to maintain the open enrollment program of the corporation pursuant to subsection (k)(1) of this section; provided, that the corporation shall not deduct an aggregate amount exceeding $550,000 of its payment to the RS Fund from the amount otherwise due by the corporation under section 650(b) of the Life Insurance Act, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1291; D.C. Official Code § 31-205 or D.C. Official Code § 47-2608(a The RS Fund shall not be used to pay marketing or promotional expenses associated with the program. Unless the corporation elects to terminate the RS Fund pursuant to subsection (k)(3) of this section, the corporation shall carry over from year to year all unexpended funds in the RS Fund, including interest earned on investment of the funds in the RS Fund. “(2) In the rate filings for the open enrollment program required by section 9, a corporation shall provide documentation to the Mayor confirming the existence of the RS Fund, identifying the amounts paid from the RS Fund to subsidize open enrollment rates, and specifying the RS Fund balance at year end and as of the date of the corporation’s filing. The Mayor may order an independent audit of the RS Fund, the expenses of which shall be paid by the corporation. If the Mayor determines, with or without an audit, that all or any portion of the money in the RS Fund is not being used to subsidize open enrollment rates or is not being reasonably set aside in anticipation of projected subsidies of open enrollment rates in future years, the Mayor may order the corporation to pay the revenue not being so used or set aside to the Healthy DC Fund established by section 15b.” 3) Subsection (k) is amended to read as follows: “(k)(1) A corporation shall maintain its open enrollment program for subscribers who are enrolled in the program as of the effective date of the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 and shall, subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, continue to offer the program to each such subscriber for as long as the subscriber renews his or her coverage under the program. “(2) The corporation shall not be required to offer or maintain an open enrollment program for persons who are not subscribers enrolled in the program as of the effective date of the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 The corporation shall not use any ENROLLED ORIGINAL 57Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. money in the RS Fund to subsidize the open enrollment rate of any person who was not a subscriber to the open enrollment program as of the effective date of the Hospital and Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 “(3) The obligation of the corporation to maintain an open enrollment program under paragraph (1) of this subsection may terminate on December 31, 2010. If the corporation thereafter elects to terminate the open enrollment program, the corporation shall submit a plan for termination to the Commissioner for approval, and immediately upon receipt of the Commissioner’s written approval, the corporation shall promptly pay to the District of Columbia Treasurer, as a payment otherwise due under section 15a, all amounts remaining in the RS Fund, and such amounts shall be credited to the Healthy DC Fund. Upon termination of the open enrollment program, the Mayor shall ensure that subscribers who are enrolled in the program at the time of its termination are provided with an opportunity to enroll in a comparable individual line of health coverage at no additional cost to the subscriber.” c) New sections 15a and 15b are added to read as follows: “Section 15a. Tax and related payments. “A corporation shall be subject to D.C. Official Code § 47-2608. “Section 15b. Establishment of Healthy DC Fund and Program a) There is established among the funds of the District a segregated nonlapsing enterprise fund designated as the Healthy DC Fund, the funds of which shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available without fiscal limitation for the purposes described in this section, subject to authorization by Congress. All tax revenue derived from hospital and medical services corporations pursuant to D.C. Official Code § 47-2608, except for taxes upon real estate and fees and charges provided for by the insurance laws of the District shall be deposited into the fund b) On or before January 1, 2007, the Mayor shall establish the Healthy DC Program (“Program”) to finance health care and medical services for qualifying individuals in the District of Columbia. The program shall be part of the Medicaid Managed Care Program established under section 1 of An Act To enable the District of Columbia to receive federal assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act for a medical assistance program and for other purposes, approved December 27, 1967 (81 Stat. 744; D.C. Official Code § 1-307.02(1 c)(1) For the purposes of this section, the term “qualifying individual” means a person: “(A) Who resides in a household having a net household income no greater than $35,000 or a net household income between 200% and 300% of the federal poverty guidelines B) Who does not have and has not had health insurance with benefits on an expense reimbursed or prepaid basis during the 12-month period prior to the individual's application for health care service coverage under the program; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 58Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 C) Whose employer has not provided or contributed an amount that exceeds 5% of the individual’s gross household income toward the cost of group health insurance with benefits on an expense reimbursed or prepaid basis in effect during the 12-month period prior to the individual's application for health care service coverage insurance under the program D) Who is ineligible for Medicare, Medicaid, or the District of Columbia Health Care Alliance; and E) Who is a resident of the District of Columbia 2) A qualifying individual whose household income increases beyond the limitation prescribed in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be eligible to continue participating in the program for a period of up to 2 years 3) The requirements set forth in paragraph (1)(B) and (C) of this subsection shall not be applicable if an individual had health insurance coverage during the previous 12 months and the coverage was terminated due to A) Loss of employment due to factors other than voluntary separation B) Death of a family member resulting in termination of coverage under a health insurance contract under which the individual was covered C) Change to a new employer who does not provide group health insurance with benefits on an expense reimbursed or prepaid basis or does not contribute an amount that exceeds 5% of the individual’s gross household income toward the cost of group health insurance with benefits on an expense reimbursed or prepaid basis D) Discontinuation of a group health insurance contract with benefits on an expense reimbursed or prepaid basis covering the qualifying individual as an employee or dependent E) Expiration of the coverage periods established by the Continuation Coverage Under Group Health Plans provisions in part 6 of the Employment Security Act of 1975, approved April 7, 1986 (100 Stat. 227; 29 U.S.C. §1161 et seq F) Legal separation, divorce, or annulment resulting in termination of coverage under a health insurance contract under which the individual was covered G) Loss of eligibility under a group health plan; or H) Loss of coverage under Medicaid or the District of Columbia Health Care Alliance as a result of income exceeding eligibility requirements 4) The Mayor may adjust the time period set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection from 12 months to 18 months if the Mayor determines that an adjustment is necessary to prevent inappropriate substitution of the program for other public or private health insurance coverage d) The program shall provide only in-plan benefits, except for emergency care if these services are not available through a plan provider. Covered services are the following 1) Inpatient hospital services consisting of daily room and board, general nursing care, special diets, and miscellaneous hospital services and supplies; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 59Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 2) Outpatient hospital services consisting of diagnostic and treatment services 3) Physician services consisting of diagnostic and treatment services, consultant and referral services, surgical services (including breast reconstruction surgery after a mastectomy anesthesia services, a second surgical opinion, and a second opinion for cancer treatment 4) Outpatient surgical facility charges related to a covered surgical procedure 5) Pre-admission testing 6) Maternity care 7) Adult preventive health services consisting of mammography screening, cervical cytology screening, periodic physical examinations no more than once every 3 years, and adult immunizations 8) Equipment, supplies, and self-management education for the treatment of diabetes 9) Diagnostic X-ray and laboratory services 10) Emergency services 11) Therapeutic services consisting of radiologic services, chemotherapy, or hemodialysis 12) Blood and blood products furnished in connection with surgery or inpatient hospital services 13) Mental health services; and 14) Prescription drugs obtained at a participating pharmacy or a health maintenance organization, which may utilize a mail order prescription drug program and may provide prescription drugs pursuant to a drug formulary; provided, that the health maintenance organization implements an appeals process so that the use of non-formulary prescription drugs may be requested by a physician e)(1) The benefits described in subsection (d) of this section shall be subject to the following co-payments, deductible, and maximums A) A $500 co-payment for each continuous hospital confinement for in- patient hospital services B) A $200 co-payment per occurrence or the lesser of 20% of the total cost for surgical services C) A $75 co-payment per occurrence for outpatient surgical facility charges D) A $50 co-payment for emergency services, which shall be waived if hospital admission results from the emergency room visit E) A $10 co-payment for prenatal care services F) A $10 co-payment for each 34-day supply of a generic prescription drug; provided, that the co-payment shall not exceed the cost of the prescribed drug; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 60Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 G) A $20 co-payment for each 34-day supply of a brand name prescription drug plus the difference in cost between the brand name drug and the equivalent generic drug; provided, that the co-payment shall not exceed the cost of the prescribed drug H) A $20 co-payment for each 90-day supply of a generic prescription drug; provided, that the co-payment shall not exceed the cost of the prescribed drug I) A $40 co-payment for each 90-day supply of a brand name prescription drug, plus the difference in cost between the brand name drug and the equivalent generic drug; provided, that the co-payment shall not exceed the cost of the prescribed drug J) A $20 co-payment for all other services K) For prescription drug coverage provided by the program, a $100 deductible per individual per calendar year; and L) A maximum of $500 per qualifying individual in a calendar year for prescription drugs, and a maximum of $500 per qualifying individual in a calendar year for mental health services 2) The Mayor may, by regulation, modify the copayment and deductible amounts or the maximum coverage amount set forth in this section if the Mayor determines a modification is necessary to implement this subtitle f) Applications for the program shall be accepted at all times throughout the year g) Eligibility for the program may be subject to a pre-existing condition limitation h) Nothing in this act shall be construed to create an entitlement to health care and medical services during any fiscal year if no funds are available to the District government under a District or federal appropriation that has been enacted for the specific purpose of the program Sec. 5013. Conforming amendments a) Section 650 of the Life Insurance Act, approved March 3, 1901 (31 Stat. 1291; D.C. Official Code § 31-205 is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b) is amended by striking the phrase “and nonprofit hospital and medical service corporations” 2) Subsection (c) is amended to read as follows: “(c) A hospital service corporation or medical service corporation may deduct, up to $550,000, the corporation’s payment to the rate stabilization fund under section 15 of the Hospital Medical Services Corporation Regulatory Act of 1996, effective April 9, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-245; D.C. Official Code § 31-3514 from the amount otherwise due by the corporation under subsection (b) of this section.” b) Chapter 26 of Title 47 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows 1) The table of contents is added by striking the section designation “47-2608.01. Health service corporations.” and inserting the section designation “47-2608.01. Repealed.” in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 61Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 2) Section 47-2608 is amended by adding a new subsection (a-1) to read as follows: “(a-1) A hospital service corporation or medical service corporation may deduct, in an amount not to exceed $550,000, the corporation’s payment to the rate stabilization fund under § 31-3514 from the amount otherwise due by the corporation under subsection (a) of this section.” 3) Section 47-2608.01 is repealed. Sec. 5014. Report and recommendation on extending health insurance coverage. Within 60 days of the effective date of this subtitle, the Mayor shall submit a report and recommendation on extending health insurance coverage to individuals that, but for this subtitle, would otherwise be eligible for health insurance coverage under the open enrollment program, but do not otherwise meet the income requirements for health insurance coverage under this subtitle. SUBTITLE C. DEPARTMENT OF MENTAL HEALTH ESTABLISHMENT AMENDMENT. Sec. 5021. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Department of Mental Health Establishment Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 5022. The Department of Mental Health Establishment Amendment Act of 2001, effective December 18, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-56; D.C. Official Code § 7-1131.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102 (D.C. Official Code § 7-1131.02) is amended as follows 1) A new paragraph (10A) is added to read as follows: “(10A) “DYRS” means the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services.” 2) A new paragraph (19A) is added to read as follows: “(19A) “Oak Hill Youth Center” means the secure juvenile facility currently operated by DYRS in Laurel, Maryland.” 3) A new paragraph (29A) is added to read as follows: “(29A) “Secure Facilities” means Oak Hill Youth Center, the Youth Services Center, and any successor facilities or new secure facilities operated by or on behalf of DYRS for youth in DYRS custody.” 4) A new paragraph (32) is added to read as follows: “(32) “Youth Services Center” means the secure juvenile facility currently operated by DYRS in the District of Columbia.”. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 62Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) Section 104(2 D.C. Official Code § 7-1131.04(2 is amended by adding the phrase “except that DYRS shall be responsible for the provision of mental health services for youth in custody in DYRS secure facilities;” after the word “Department” c) A new section 115a is added to read as follows: “Sec. 115a. Transfers to Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services. Effective October 1, 2006, the Department shall transfer to DYRS all full-time equivalent positions and funding, real and personal property leased or assigned to the Department, assets, records, ongoing obligations, unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available relating to the Department’s powers, duties, functions and administration of the operations of the mental health units at the Oak Hill Youth Center and the Youth Services Center Sec. 5023. The transfer of funding and authority authorized in section 115a of the Department of Mental Health Establishment Amendment Act of 2001, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 does not require the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services to employ any persons employed by the Department of Mental Health who are providing mental health or related services to youth in the care and custody of the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services, and the Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services shall not inherit, recognize, or be bound by any collective bargaining agreement involving those persons and negotiated and entered into by Department of Mental Health. SUBTITLE D. HEALTH PROFESSIONAL RECRUITMENT AMENDMENT ACT. Sec. 5041. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Health Professional Recruitment Program Amendment Act of 2006 Sec. 5042. The District of Columbia Health Professionals Recruitment Program Act of 2005, effective March 8, 2006 (D.C. Law 16-71; 53 DCR 2521 is amended by adding a new section 16a to read as follows: “Sec. 16a. Establishment of the Health Professional Recruitment Fund. “(a)(1) There is hereby established within the General Fund of the District of Columbia a segregated, nonlapsing fund to be known as the Health Professional Recruitment Fund (“Fund” the funds of which shall not revert to the General Fund at the end of any fiscal year, or at any other time, but shall be continually available without fiscal limitation for the sole purpose of making direct payments to Program participants, subject to authorization by Congress, shall be deposited into the Fund. “(2) All fees and penalties generated pursuant to the Program and all general revenue funds appropriated by a line item in the budget submitted pursuant to section 446 of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 801; D.C. Official ENROLLED ORIGINAL 63Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Code § 1-204.46 and authorized by Congress for the purpose of the Program, and any other funds received on behalf of the Fund for the purpose of the Program. “(3) The Department of Health shall administer the Fund from its appropriated operating budget SUBTITLE E. HEALTH CARE PRIVATIZATION BENEFIT AMENDMENT ACT. Sec. 5051. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Health Care Privatization Benefit Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 5052. Section 7 of the Health Care Privatization Amendment Act of 2001, effective July 12, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-18; D.C. Official Code § 7-1405 is amended by adding new subsections (c) and (d) to read as follows: “(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of the District’s health insurance laws, a health maintenance organization that has a contractual obligation to provide health care services to persons enrolled in the D.C. HealthCare Alliance Alliance shall be required to provide to persons enrolled in the Alliance only those health benefits specified in its contract with the District of Columbia. “(d) A health maintenance organization or health insurer under contract to the District to deliver services to persons enrolled in the Alliance is not required to reimburse non-participating hospitals for services provided to Alliance enrollees.”. SUBTITLE F. ACCESSRx CLARIFICATION AMENDMENT ACT. Sec. 5061. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “AccessRx Clarification Amendment Act of 2006 Sec. 5062. The AccessRx Act of 2004, effective May 18, 2004 (D.C. Law 15-164; D.C. Official Code § 48-831.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 102 (D.C. Official Code § 48-831.02) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (4)(A)(iii) is amended by striking the phrase “for its employees or members” and inserting the phrase “for its employees or members who are employed or reside in the District of Columbia” in its place 2) Paragraph (16) is amended by striking the phrase “to covered individuals” and inserting the phrase “to covered individuals for dispensation within the District of Columbia” in its place b) Section 141 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official § 48-831.41) is amended by striking the phrase “in the amount of $1.956 million” and inserting the phrase “in an amount up to $1.956 million" in its place. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 64Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 c) Section 201 (D.C. Official Code § 48-832.01) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b)(1) is amended as follows A) Subparagraph (A) is amended by striking the phrase “aims;” and inserting the phrase “aims; and” in its place B) Subparagraph (B) is repealed 2) Subsection (d) is amended as follows A) Paragraph (1) is repealed B) Paragraph (2) is amended to read as follows: “(2) If the substitute drug costs more than the prescribed drug, the pharmacy benefits manager shall disclose to the covered entity the cost of both drugs and any benefit or payment directly or indirectly accruing to the pharmacy benefits manager as a result of the substitution.” d) Section 202 (D.C. Official Code § 48-832.02) is amended by striking the phrase “and a covered entity” and inserting the phrase “and a covered entity entered into in the District of Columbia or by a covered entity in the District of Columbia” in its place. SUBTITLE G. TIMELY DISBURSEMENT ACT. Sec. 5071. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Timely Disbursement of Grants Act of 2006 Sec. 5072. Disbursement of funds a) By the 1st day of fiscal year 2007, the District shall issue a Notice of Grant Award, containing a signed grant agreement and scope of work, to each entity designated in this title to be awarded a grant by the District of Columbia b)(1) By February 1, 2007, the Mayor shall disburse to each entity designated in this title to be awarded a grant by District of Columbia at least 25% of the total grant award, unless otherwise agreed upon in the signed grant agreement 2) If the District fails to make the 25% disbursement by February 1, 2007, the District shall disburse 50% of the total grant amount to the designated entity by February 15, 2007 c) By March 1, 2007, the Mayor shall disburse to each entity designated in this title to be awarded a grant by District of Columbia all outstanding grant funding, unless otherwise agreed upon in the signed grant agreement d) By December 1, 2007, the Mayor shall conduct an audit and reconciliation of all funding disbursed to entities designated in this title to be awarded a grant by District of Columbia. SUBTITLE H. NURSING FACILITY QUALITY OF CARE FUND AMENDMENT. Sec. 5081. Short title. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 65Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. This subtitle may be cited as the "Nursing Facility Quality of Care Fund Act of 2006 Sec. 5082. Section 47-1262(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended to read as follows: ‘(b) “No less than ninety 90% of the Fund shall be used solely to fund quality of care initiatives.”. SUBTITLE I. MEDICAID ENROLLMENT AND EXPANSION. Sec. 5091. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Medicaid Enrollment and Expansion Act of 2006”. Sec. 5092. Within 30 days of the effective date of this subtitle, the Mayor shall submit Medicaid State Plan Amendments to the Council pursuant to section (1)(a) of An Act To enable the District of Columbia to receive Federal financial assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act for a medical assistance program, and for other purposes, approved December 27, 1967 (81 Stat. 744; D.C. Official Code § 1-307.02(a to achieve the following 1) Increase the maximum eligibility standards of the State Children’s Health Insurance Program from 200% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines to 300% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines 2) Increase the maximum eligibility standards for Qualified Medicare Beneficiaries and Special Low-Income Medicare Beneficiaries to 300% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines 3) Establish a comprehensive adult dental program; and (4) Draw down an additional $9,750,000 in presently uncaptured federal matching funds for the purpose of expanding school health services. Sec. 5093. Penalties. An agency head, deputy agency head, agency chief financial officer, agency budget director, agency controller, manager, or other employee may be subject to adverse personnel action, including removal, for not submitting the plan in accordance with this subtitle. SUBTITLE J. MEDICAL ASSISTANCE ADMINISTRATION REPORTING REQUIREMENTS. Sec. 5101. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Medical Assistance Administration Reporting Requirements Act of 2006 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 66Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5102. Non-Emergency Transportation Reform Report. The Medical Assistance Administration (“MAA”) within the Department of Health shall provide a report to the Council by October 1, 2006, on the status of its efforts to reform the Medicaid Non-Emergency Transportation (“NEMT”) Program. The report shall 1) Describe MAA’s plans and proposed timelines to A) Verify that all Medicaid NEMT services are provided to clients that have been certified as medically necessary and make such certifications subject to renewal B) Institute a prior-authorization system that maintains public transportation as the default method of NEMT C) Require transportation vendors to submit documentation of services provided, including purpose of trip, pick-up location, drop-off location, and times; and (D) Increase MAA oversight of NEMT abnormalities and high usage; and (2) Quantify the potential savings from the measures described in paragraph (1) of this section. Sec. 5103. Out-of-state reimbursement report. The MAA within the Department of Health shall provide a report to the Council by October 1, 2006, on the status of its efforts to decrease payments to providers located outside the District of Columbia. The report shall 1) Describe MAA’s plans and proposed timelines to A) Transition the residency of individuals in nursing facilities located outside the District to the state where the nursing facility is located; and (B) Implement fraud protections and increasing oversight of payments made to non-District providers for Medicaid services, including reimbursements to physicians, hospitals, nursing facilities, pharmacies, Intermediate Care Facilities for the Mentally Retarded, and day treatment centers; and (2) Quantify the potential savings from the measures described in paragraph (1) of this section. Sec. 5104. Penalties. An agency head, deputy agency head, agency chief financial officer, agency budget director, agency controller, manager, or other employee may be subject to adverse personnel action, including removal, for not submitting the report required by section 5102 or by 5103. SUBTITLE K. DESIGNATED APPROPRIATION ALLOCATIONS. Sec. 5121. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Designated Appropriation Allocation Act of 2006 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 67Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5122. Funding of the diabetes program. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration of the Department of Health 250,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Howard University Hospital to expand diabetes prevention, screening, and treatment for low-income and uninsured District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5123. Funding of the prostate cancer program. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration of the Department of Health 250,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Howard University Hospital to provide prostate cancer screening for low-income and uninsured District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5124. Funding of the Breast, Cervical, and Ovarian early detection program. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 250,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Greater Southeast Community Hospital to provide screening and treatment for breast, cervical, and ovarian cancer for low-income and uninsured District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5125. Funding of the tobacco control and cancer prevention program. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 500,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the American Lung Association of DC for tobacco cessation initiatives for District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5126. Funding for pre-school immunization program. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 300,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the Children’s National Medical Center for pre- school immunization programs for District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5127. Funds for health professional training. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 600,000, which shall be a one-time, ENROLLED ORIGINAL 68Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the District of Columbia Area Health Education Center for health professional training programs and supplemental services, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5128. Funds for allied health training programs. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in Department of Health 1 million, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Southeastern University to work in partnership with the Service Employees International Union to develop training programs for allied health services, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5129. Funds for organ and tissue donor awareness campaign. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 100,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the Washington Regional Transplant Consortium for purposes of an organ and tissue donor awareness campaign for the District of Columbia, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5130. Funds for kidney screening. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 250,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the National Kidney Foundation to provide kidney screening for low-income and uninsured District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5131. Funds for poison control. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 200,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the National Capital Poison Control Center to provide operational support for poison control activities, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5132. Funds for implementation of comprehensive cancer plan. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 150,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the DC Cancer Consortium for planning support for implementation of the comprehensive cancer plan, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 69Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5133. Funds for Latino health services. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 170,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Mary’s Center and La Clinica del Pueblo for a joint program to enhance primary, health, education, and outreach services for the Latino population in the District of Columbia, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5134. Funds for dental services. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 225,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Howard University School of Dentistry and So Others Might Eat for a joint dental program for low-income or homeless District residents, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5135. Riggs Park health assessment. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 300,000 shall be made available to contract with a qualified provider to conduct an health assessment of the residents of the area in the District known as Riggs Park where a gas leak occurred, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5136. Funds for health professional loan repayment program. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 300,000 shall be made available for direct payments to Health Professional Loan-Repayment Program participants, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5137. Funds for National Legislative Association on Prescription Drug Prices. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Primary Care and Prevention Administration in the Department of Health 20,000 shall be directed to the budget of the Council of the District of Columbia for membership dues in the National Legislative Association on Prescription Drug Prices, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5138. Funds for nutritional support. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 500,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Food &amp;amp; Friends for supplemental services, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 70Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5139. Funds for HIV/AIDS prevention services. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $400,000, shall be made available to partner with qualified District providers for prevention services, outreach, and education programs that target youth of color at-risk of, or living with HIV/AIDS, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5140. Funds for HIV/AIDS prevention services. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $400,000, shall be made available to partner with qualified District providers for prevention services, outreach, and education programs that target women of color at-risk of, or living with HIV/AIDS, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5141. Funds for Medical Assistance Administration Management Assistance. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Medical Assistance Administration within the Department of Health, up to $3 million, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be made available exclusively for the Department of Health to contract with the School of Public Health at George Washington University. The Department of Health shall have the ability to negotiate for rates and services and the contract shall be used at the discretion of the Director of the Department of Health to conduct federally reimbursable management and administrative projects on an as needed basis. Sec. 5142. Funds for HIV/AIDS prevention services. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $400,000, shall be made available to partner with qualified District providers for prevention services, outreach, and education programs that target men of color at-risk of, or living with HIV/AIDS, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5143. Funds for burial assistance. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $250,000, shall be made available for burial assistance, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5144. Funds for Oak Hill Juvenile Detention Center and D.C. Jail HIV/AIDS counseling. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 300,000 shall be made available for pre- release and post-release HIV/AIDS counseling, testing, and referral services for individuals at Oak Hill Juvenile Detention Center and the D.C. Jail, subject to appropriations. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 71Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5145. Funds for the East of the River HIV/AIDS Initiative. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $550,000 shall be made available for the East of the River HIV/AIDS Initiative, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5146. Funds for transgender community HIV/AIDS prevention education. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 100,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Transgender Health Empowerment, Inc for HIV/AIDS support services and prevention education for transgendered individuals, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5147. Funds for HIV/AIDS primary care, treatment, and support services. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 1.525 million, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the Whitman Walker Clinic to provide HIV/AIDS primary care, treatment, and support services, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5148. Funds for HIV/AIDS client services and prevention education. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 145,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to Angels and Associates, Inc for organizational capacity-building, client support services, and prevention education for women living with HIV/AIDS, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5149. Funds for HIV/AIDS prevention. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 50,000 shall be made available for the purchase and distribution of condoms at the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration Detoxification Facility, the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration methadone maintenance sites, other substance abuse treatment sites, and the D.C. Jail, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5150. Funds for clinician training. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health 50,000, shall be made available for culturally-based training for clinicians providing services to Latino and other immigrant populations, subject to appropriations. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 72Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5151. Funds for volunteer responders database. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Emergency Health and Medical Services Administration in the Department of Health 50,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be provided to Greater DC Cares for the maintenance of a first responders volunteer database, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5152. Funds for emergency preparedness. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Emergency Health and Medical Services Administration in the Department of Health 150,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be provided to the District of Columbia Hospital Association for the hospitals’ Terrorism Response Planning Coordination Services, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5153. Funding for State Children’s Health Insurance Program expansion. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Office of Managed Care in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health 3.943 million shall be made available to increase the maximum eligibility standards of the State Children’s Health Insurance Program from 200% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines to 300% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5154. Funding for Medicare Part D assistance. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Office of Managed Care in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health 120,000 shall be made available to increase the maximum eligibility standards for Qualified Medicare Beneficiaries and Special Low-Income Medicare Beneficiaries to 300% of the Federal Poverty Guidelines, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5155. Funding for Medicaid adult dental benefit expansion. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Office of Disabilities and Aging in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health 12.96 million shall be made available for comprehensive adult dental services, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5156. Funding for school-health program expansion a) Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Office of Support Services in the Medical Assistance Administration in the Department of Health 4.25 million shall be made available for the local share of Disproportionate Share Hospital funds, subject to appropriations. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 73Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 b) All federal revenues generated as a result of this section shall be allocated to enhance school-health services. Sec. 5157. Funds for substance abuse prevention. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration in the Department of Health 100,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the Crystal Meth Working Group for expanded substance abuse prevention programs, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. Sec. 5158. Funds for school-based health. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Maternal and Family Health Administration in the Department of Health 50,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the D.C. Assembly on School Based Health Care to provide operational support for school health policies and programs for the District of Columbia, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Health. This distribution is in addition to the $50,000 grant as authorized in the Deed Transfer and Recordation Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 for a total grant award of $100,000 to the D.C. Assembly on School Based Health Care. Sec. 5159. Mental health substance abuse detoxification facility funds. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for Core Community Providers in the Department of Mental Health 100,000 shall be allocated for mental health services at the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration Detoxification Facility, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5160. Mental health parental support funding. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for Core Community Providers in the Department of Mental Health 200,000, which shall be a one-time, nonrecurring distribution, shall be granted to the District of Columbia Birth Center, Inc to support their critical community work, which includes parental education and postpartum counseling, subject to terms and conditions approved by the Department of Mental Health. Sec. 5161. Funds for Choice in Drug Treatment Vouchers. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Department of Mental Health 824,000 shall be made available for substance abuse vouchers utilizing the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration Choice in Drug Treatment Program to provide comprehensive treatment and support to substance abusers with mental illness, subject to appropriations. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 74Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 5162. School-based Mental Health Services Funds. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Department of Mental Health 4.1 million shall be allocated to school-based mental health services, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5163. Funds for jail diversion. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Department of Mental Health 1.5 million shall be allocated to the Department to expand jail diversion programs for persons with mental health illness, to provide mental health services at the D.C. Jail, and to provide services for persons with mental illness being released from jail, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5164. Mental health substance abuse detoxification facility funds. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Department of Mental Health 100,000 shall be allocated to mental health services at the Addiction Prevention and Recovery Administration Detoxification Facility, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5165. Funds for housing resources. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $2 million of Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS program resources shall be made available to sub-grantees for capital, rehabilitative construction, and acquisition costs to strengthen the development of facilities and units in facilities to expand the housing stock available to eligible persons living with HIV/AIDS in the District of Columbia, subject to appropriations. Sec. 5166. Funds for housing resources. Of the funds appropriated in fiscal year 2007 for the Administration for HIV/AIDS Policy and Planning in the Department of Health, no less than $300,000 of Housing Opportunities for Persons with AIDS program resources shall be made available for the establishment of a long- term mortgage assistance program for eligible persons living with HIV/AIDS in the District of Columbia. Long-term mortgage assistance shall consist of at least 45% of monthly mortgage obligations, subject to appropriations. SUBTITLE L. DAY CARE GRANT-MAKING AND RULEMAKING. Sec. 5181. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Day Care Improvement Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 5182. Section 14 of the Day Care Policy Act of 1979, effective September 19, 1979 (D.C. Law 3-16; D.C. Official Code § 4-413 is amended by adding a new subsection (d) to read as follows: ENROLLED ORIGINAL 75Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(d) The Mayor, pursuant to Title I of the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; D.C. Official Code § 2-501 et seq may issue rules to implement the provisions of this act.”. Sec. 5183. Section 3(a) of the Child Care Services Assistance Fund Act of 1988, effective March 16, 1989 (D.C. Law 7-220; D.C. Official Code § 7-2002(a is amended by striking the phrase “up to $10,000” and inserting the phrase “up to $500,000” in its place. SUBTITLE M. ASSESSMENT OF DISTRICT PROGRAMS TO PREVENT ABUSE AND NEGLECT IN THE DISTRICT. Sec. 5191. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Assessment of District Programs to Prevent Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 2006”. Sec. 5192. Definitions. For the purposes of this subtitle, the term 1) “Primary prevention” means activities and services provided to families that are designed to prevent or reduce the prevalence of child abuse and neglect before signs of abuse or neglect may be present 2) “Secondary prevention” means activities and services provided to persons identified by etiological studies because of their propensity to abuse or neglect children in their care. Secondary prevention strategies target children who are identified as being at risk of abuse or neglect and are designed to intervene at the earliest warning signs of abuse or neglect. Sec. 5193. Status of abuse and neglect prevention programs a) The Mayor shall convene a working group to assess child abuse and neglect prevention programs in the District. The working group shall 1) Take an inventory of all current public and private programs for the prevention of child abuse and neglect, including A) All primary prevention programs servicing the District B) All secondary prevention programs servicing the District C) All sources of local, federal, and private funding for each program; and (D) A determination of whether each program’s services are evaluated for effectiveness; and (2) Perform a gap analysis to identify where these programs are A) Meeting, or failing to meet, the primary prevention needs of the District; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 76Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 B) Meeting, or failing to meet, the secondary prevention needs of the District; and (C) Duplicating services identified in the inventory b) The inventory and gap analysis shall be completed, submitted to the Council, and made available to the public no later than December 31, 2006. SUBTITLE N. INTEGRATED FUNDING AND SERVICES FOR AT-RISK CHILDREN, YOUTH, AND FAMILIES. Sec. 5201. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Integrated Funding and Services for At-Risk Children, Youth, and Families Act of 2006 Sec. 5202. Definitions. For the purposes of this subtitle, the term 1) “At-risk child or youth” means an individual who is less than 18 years of age and exhibits, is characterized by, or is subject to one or more of the following conditions A) Abuse or neglect, as described in D.C. Official Code § 16-2301(9) and (23 B) Developmental disability, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 21-1201(3 C) Delinquency, as described in D.C. Official Code § 16-2301(6 D) Homelessness, as described in section 2(18) of the Homeless Services Reform Act of 2005, effective October 22, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-35; D.C. Official Code § 4- 751.01(18 “Homeless Reform Act” E) Mental illness, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 21- 501(5 F) Mental retardation, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 21- 1201(7 G) Poverty, as defined by the income eligibility guidelines set by the United States Department of Agriculture for the school lunch and school breakfast programs H) Probation, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 16- 2301(18 I) School dropout, defined as not attending school without graduating from high school or completing an approved education program J) Substance abuse, as that term is defined in section 3(12) of the Choice in Drug Treatment Act of 2000, effective July 18, 2000 (D.C. Law 13-146; D.C. Official Code § 7-3002(12 “Drug Treatment Act” K) Teenage pregnancy; or ENROLLED ORIGINAL 77Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 L) Truancy, defined as 10 or more unexcused absences during a school semester 2) “At-risk family” means a family that exhibits, is characterized by, or is subject to one or more of the following conditions A) Abuse or neglect, as described in D.C. Official Code § 16-2301(9) and (23 B) Homelessness, as described in section 2(18) of the Homeless Reform Act C) Incarceration of a parent D) Intrafamily violence, as described in D.C. Official Code § 16-1031 E) Mental illness, as that term is defined in D.C. Official Code § 21- 501(5 of a parent or caregiver F) Poverty, as defined by the income eligibility guidelines set by the United States Department of Agriculture for the school lunch and school breakfast programs G) Substance abuse, as that term is defined in section 3(12) of the Drug Treatment Act, of a parent or caregiver; or (H) Teenage parenthood 3) “Child” means an individual who is less than 18 years of age 4) “Domestic partnership” shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2(4) of the Health Care Benefits Expansion Act of 1992, effective June 11, 1992 (D.C. Law 9- 114; D.C. Official Code § 32-701(4 5) “Family” means an adult or adults who share a residence with at least one child and are related by blood, legal custody, marriage, or domestic partnership 6) “Fund” means the Integrated Services Fund for At-Risk Children, Youth, and Families 7) “Local funding” means funding appropriated from tax and non-tax revenue raised by the District of Columbia government and not earmarked for a particular purpose 8) “Youth” means an individual who is at least 13 years of age and less than 18 years of age. Sec. 5203. Integrated Services Fund for At-Risk Children, Youth, and Families a) There is established the Integrated Services Fund for At-Risk Children, Youth, and Families, which shall be a nonlapsing fund separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia and used to implement initiatives, programs, and services to meet the needs of at-risk children, youth, and their families in a holistic, interdisciplinary manner pursuant to section 5204 b) The Mayor, or his or her designee, may transfer to the Fund up to one percent of the local funding appropriated in the District of Columbia’s annual financial plan and budget for each of the following agencies, or any successor agencies 1) The Child and Family Services Agency; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 78Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 2) The Department of Employment Services 3) The Department of Health, excluding local funding appropriated or authorized for the Medicaid program authorized by Title XIX of the Social Security Act, approved July 30, 1965 (79 Stat. 343; 42 U.S.C. § 1396 et seq 4) The Department of Human Services 5) The Department of Mental Health; and (6) The Department of Youth Rehabilitation Services c) The Mayor may also designate federal or private grant funds to be deposited into the Fund if the designation of funds is consistent with the terms of the federal or private grant d) Funds deposited into the Fund shall not revert to the General Fund of the District of Columbia at the end of any fiscal year or at any other time, but shall be continually available for the uses and purposes set forth in section 5204, subject to authorization by Congress e) The Chief Financial Officer shall provide the necessary administrative and management support to pool the funds described in subsections (a) and (b) of this section into the Fund, and shall maintain systems of accounting and control that provide the Mayor with financial information needed for management purposes and ensure accountability for the use of the Fund’s resources f) The Mayor shall submit a budget and spending plan for the Fund as part of the annual budget that he or she transmits to the Council. The plan shall include 1) The amount proposed to be transferred from each agency 2) The effect, if any, on programs in the agencies from which the funds are being transferred; and (3) A listing of each program and its financing through the Fund. Sec. 5204. Scope and design of programs and services a) The Mayor shall use the funds described in section 5203 to support policies, programs, and services for at-risk children, youth, and families that 1) Offer a broad spectrum of assistance and support tailored to the needs of at- risk children, youth, and families, such as child abuse prevention, child care, domestic violence prevention, job training, maternal and child health, mental health counseling, mentoring, parent education, respite care, and substance abuse treatment 2) Cross agency and professional boundaries, using an interdisciplinary approach and employing techniques such as case management, co-location of programs and staff, and inter-agency case conferences to ensure that services are coordinated and accessible to at-risk children, youth, and families 3) Build on family strengths and view the needs of the child or youth in the context of his or her family 4) Respect cultural diversity and promote family involvement; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 79Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 5) Adopt flexible approaches to service delivery, such as home visits, and ensure that essential supports, such as transportation, are in place so that at-risk children, youth, and families can use available services 6) Promote access and continuity by offering assistance, when possible, in non- traditional settings such as the home, school, or community, and at convenient times, including evening and weekend hours, and by reducing complex eligibility and paperwork requirements 7) Reduce barriers to essential programs and services by reducing complex eligibility and paperwork requirements and providing referrals to programs and services offered by private organizations 8) Are of sufficient intensity and duration to help children, youth, and families who are most at risk or in need, as reflected by multiple risk factors or chronic poverty 9) Are provided by skilled and committed individuals with experience and demonstrated effectiveness in serving at-risk children, youth, and families; and (10) Support, to the greatest extent possible, in-home and community care for children and youth in the child welfare or juvenile justice systems, or at risk of referral to those systems, while reducing reliance on out-of-home or institutional care b) The Mayor shall establish performance measures and goals for the programs and services financed by the Fund. The measures and goals shall focus on high-priority outcomes for at-risk children, youth, and families, and shall reflect the impact, effectiveness, and quality of the programs and services. The Mayor shall include the measures and goals in the performance plans and reports required by the Government Managers Accountability Amendment Act of 1995, effective May 16, 1995 (D.C. Law 11-16; D.C. Official Code § 1-614.11 et seq TITLE VI. PUBLIC WORKS SUBTITLE A. DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS’ BRYANT STREET FACILITY. Sec. 6001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Bryant Street Facility Renovation Funding Act of 2006 Sec. 6002. The amount of $6.5 million in pay-go capital shall be allocated for the Department of Public Works to repair the Bryant Street facility. SUBTITLE B. PUBLIC SPACE RENTAL FEES. Sec. 6011. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Public Space Rental Fees Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 6012. The Sub-Surface Space Rental Rate Resolution of the District of Columbia City Council, effective September 16, 1969 (Res. No. 69-71; 16 DCR 72 is repealed. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 80Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 6013. The District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act, approved October 17, 1968 (82 Stat. 1156; D.C. Official Code § 10-1101.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 103(8 D.C. Official Code § 10-1101.01(8 is amended by striking the phrase “the United States or the District of Columbia, or of any governmental entity or foreign government, or” and inserting the phrase “the District of Columbia or ” in its place b) Section 104 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1101.02) is amended by striking the phrase "the government of the United States, the government of the District of Columbia, or any foreign government, for the use in accordance with the provisions of titles I and III" and inserting the phrase "the government of the District of Columbia for the use, in accordance with the provisions of title II" in its place c) Section 305 (D.C. Official Code § 10-1103.04) is amended by adding a new subsection (c) to read as follows: “(c) Each level of a vault shall be treated as a separate vault for purposes of computing annual rent. Fuel oil tanks shall be considered as single level vaults. Annual rental shall be computed on the basis of the assessed value A.V per square foot of the abutting land multiplied by the area of the vault level in square feet Area multiplied by a utilization factor U.F otherwise expressed as (A.V x (Area) x (U.F The utilization factors shall be 1) First Level: One and eight-tenths percent (1.8 2) Each Level Thereafter: Forty-fifth of one percent (0.45 ”. Sec. 6014. Section 9b of the Department of Transportation Establishment Act of 2002, effective October 20, 2005 (D.C. Law 16-33; D.C. Official Code § 50-921.10 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a)(2) is amended by striking the phrase "General Fund of the District of District of Columbia” and inserting the phrase "District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund” in its place b) Subsection (b)(1)(A) is amended by striking the phrase "public space and inserting the phrase “public space; provided, that as of July 1, 2006, any incremental revenue generated by section 305(c) of the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act, approved October 17, 1968 (82 Stat. 1156; D.C. Official Code § 10-1103.04 that pertains to the public space rental fees for vaults as established by section 305(c) of the District of Columbia Public Space Rental Act shall be deposited in the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund;” in its place. Sec. 6015. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of July 1, 2006. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 81Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE C. PUBLIC RIGHTS-OF-WAY OCCUPANCY FEES. Sec. 6021. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Public Rights-of-Way Occupancy Fees Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 6022 a) Chapter 3302 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations is amended as follows 1) Section 3302.8 is amended by striking the phrase “$0.88 per linear foot” and inserting the phrase “$1.06 per linear foot” in its place 2) Section 3302.9 is amended by striking the phrase “$1.32 per linear foot” and inserting the phrase “$1.59 per linear foot” in its place 3) Section 3302.10 is amended by striking the phrase “$1.32 per linear foot” and inserting the phrase “$1.59 per linear foot” in its place 4) Section 3302.14 is amended as follows A) Strike “At the time of each quarterly payment” and insert “On April 1, July 1, October 1, and the first business day of January of each year” in its place B) Strike the phrase "quarterly report" and insert the phrase “quarterly report on the past quarter’s financial performance” in its place b) The amendments made by this section to the public rights-of-way occupancy fees do not preclude the Mayor from further amending these same fees, through rulemaking; provided, that the amended rates, when taken together with the other user fees, charges, and penalties collected pursuant to this section and D.C. Official Code § 47-2718 do not adversely impact the positive fiscal impact as set forth in the committee report for this subtitle. Sec. 6023. Section 102a(a) of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1996 is amended to read as follows a)(1) There is established the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund Maintenance Fund which shall be separate from the General Fund of the District of Columbia, into which shall be deposited without regard to fiscal year limitation, pursuant to an act of Congress A) All revenue derived from the collection of the public rights-of-way user fees, charges, and penalties established pursuant to 24 DCMR §§ 3302.8 through 3302.10, or any other regulations; provided, that any incremental revenue derived from the collection of the public rights-of-way user fees, charges, and penalties pursuant to sections 3302.8 through 3302.10 of Title 24 of the District of Columbia Municipal Regulations as increased in accordance with section 6022 of the Public Rights-of-Way Occupancy Fees Amendment Act of 2006, passed on 2nd reading on July 11, 2006 (Enrolled version of Bill 16-679 shall be deposited in the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund B) Except for dedicated sales tax described in D.C. Official Code ENROLLED ORIGINAL 82Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. §47-2002.05(d)(4) and any dedicated taxes or fees on parking, as that term is described in section 490(n)(5) of the Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 809; D.C. Official Code § 1-204.90(n)(5 that were dedicated prior to the Highway Trust Fund and District Department of Transportation Emergency Amendment Act of 2005, effective November 17, 2005 (D.C. Act 16-206; 52 DCR 10524 i) One hundred percent of the sales and use taxes up to $30 million collected by the District for parking and storing vehicles to source funds for the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund; provided, that any such revenues in excess of $30 million shall be deposited into the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund ii) One hundred percent of the revenues collected by the District for the rental of public space that is not derived from I) Sidewalk cafes II) Surface and subsurface fuel oil space; or III) Vaults; and C) All excess monies remaining in the District of Columbia Highway Trust Fund pursuant to section 101(e 2)(A) Up to 50% of the revenue collected pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(i) of this subsection from parking and storing vehicle taxes to source funds for the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund may be used for debt servicing and the remaining balance used for local roads construction and maintenance; and B) All or any portion of the revenue collected pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(ii) of this subsection for the rental of public space may be used for debt servicing Sec. 6024. Certification of expenditures a) During fiscal year 2007, the Chief Financial Officer CFO shall not make available for expenditure by the District Department of Transportation DDOT 2,426,349 of DDOT’s fiscal year 2007 appropriation for Highway Trust Fund matching funds eligibility unless, from time to time, the CFO, certifies to the Council and the Mayor that he or she has identified that all or a portion of such amount is available for such purposes from local funds b) For fiscal years 2008 through 2012, the $4,126,349 annual local match requirement to the Highway Trust Fund shall be made available for expenditure by DDOT subject to any necessary appropriation and the legal availability of funding. Sec. 6025. Applicability. This subtitle shall apply as of July 1, 2006. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 83Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. SUBTITLE D. LOCAL ROADS CONSTRUCTION AND MAINTENANCE FUND EXPENDITURE PLAN APPROVAL. Sec. 6031. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the “Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund Expenditure Plan Approval Act of 2006”. Sec. 6032. Pursuant to the requirement of section 102a of the Highway Trust Fund Establishment Act of 1996, effective October 3, 2001 (D.C. Law 14-28; D.C. Official Code § 9- 111.01a the Mayor submitted on May 8, 2006, a proposed plan for the use of all monies in the Local Roads Construction and Maintenance Fund for fiscal year 2007 to the Council for approval. The Council hereby approves the proposed plan dated May 8, 2006. TITLE VII. GENERAL PROVISIONS SUBTITLE A. INCORPORATION OF COMMITTEE REPORT RECOMMENDATIONS Sec. 7001. Short title. This subtitle may be cited as the "Report Authority Act of 2006 Sec. 7002. The allocations and recommendations set forth in the committee report of the Committee of the Whole, which includes the reports of all committees, are hereby incorporated into the Fiscal Year 2007 Budget Support Act of 2006. TITLE VIII. FISCAL IMPACT STATEMENT Sec. 8001. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602 (c 3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 TITLE IX. EFFECTIVE DATE Sec. 9001. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 84Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>1152</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1581"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>1153</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1582"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>1154</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1583"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>1155</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1584"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>1156</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1585"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3002</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-281"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3003</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-282"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3004</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-283"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3005</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-284"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4022</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2731"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4023</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2732"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4024</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2733"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4025</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-2734"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4032</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§38-3301"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5202</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1345.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5203</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1345.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5204</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1345.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>2052</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2855.01"/>
  </section>
</document>
