<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-197">
  <num type="law">16-197</num>
  <heading type="short">Library Procurement Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-02</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-197.pdf">D.C. Law 16-197</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 8827</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0562">
      <narrative>Law 16-197, the “Library Procurement Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-562, which was referred to the Committee on Education, Libraries and Recreation. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 6, 2006, and October 3, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on October 23, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-492 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-197 became effective on March 2, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend An Act To establish and provide for the maintenance of a free public library and reading room in the District of Columbia to grant the Board of Library Trustees the authority to procure goods and services independent of the Office of Contracting and Procurement and the requirements of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985 PPA except for provisions of the PPA pertaining to contract protests, appeals, and claims, and to make the independent procurement authority of the Board of Library Trustees contingent upon it issuing procurement regulations that have been approved by the Council; and to amend the PPA to exempt the Board of Library Trustees from the provisions of the act except for those provisions pertaining to contract protests, appeals, and claims. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Library Procurement Amendment Act of 2006 Sec. 2. Section 5 of An Act To establish and provide for the maintenance of a free public library and reading room in the District of Columbia, approved June 3, 1896 (29 Stat. 244; D.C. Official Code § 39-105 is amended as follows a) Subsection (a) is amended as follows 1) Paragraph (1) is amended by striking all text after the semicolon 2) Paragraph (3) is amended to read as follows: “(3) Have the authority to procure all goods and services necessary to operate the library system, independent of the Office of Contracting and Procurement and the requirements of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective February 21, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-85; D.C. Official Code § 2-301.01 et seq “Act” except as specified in section 320 of the Act, and in accordance with subsection (c) of this section;” b) A new subsection (c) is added to read as follows: “(c)(1) The Board shall not exercise the procurement authority granted to it under subsection (a)(3) of this section until the Council has approved rules governing the procurement of goods and services submitted by the Board pursuant to this subsection. “(2) The proposed rules shall be submitted to the Council for a 45-day period of review, excluding Saturdays, Sundays, legal holidays, and days of Council recess. If the Council does not approve or disapprove the proposed rules, in whole or in part, by resolution, within the 45-day period, the proposed rules shall be deemed disapproved.”. Sec. 3. Section 320 of the District of Columbia Procurement Practices Act of 1985, effective April 12, 1997 (D.C. Law 11-259; D.C. Official Code § 2-303.20 is amended by adding a new subsection (s) to read as follows: Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 39-105 Amend § 2-303.20 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. “(s) Nothing in this act shall affect the authority of the Board of Library Trustees, except that Title IX shall apply to contract protests, appeals, and claims arising from procurements of the Board of Library Trustees.”. Sec. 4. Sunset. This act shall expire 2 years after its effective date. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D. C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
