<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-235">
  <num type="law">16-235</num>
  <heading type="short">Mental Health Civil Commitment Extension Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-235.pdf">D.C. Law 16-235</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 389</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0778">
      <narrative>Law 16-235, the “Mental Health Civil Commitment Extension Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-778, which was referred to Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-591 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-235 became effective on March 8, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend Chapter 5 of Title 21 of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide that the commitment of a person for an indeterminate period under section 21-545 of the District of Columbia Official Code shall expire 548 days after the effective date of a federal law enacting provisions of the Mental Health Civil Commitment Act of 2002 that will make all subsequent commitments for a one-year period, unless the chief clinical officer of the Department, facility, hospital, or mental health provider has petitioned for recommitment of the person. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Mental Health Civil Commitment Extension Act of 2006 Sec. 2. Chapter 5 of Title 21 of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended as follows a) The table of contents is amended by striking the phrase “21-589.01. Interim provisions for term of commitment for persons committed prior to January 1, 2003.” and inserting the phrase “21-589.01. Interim provisions for term of commitment.” in its place b) Section 21-589.01 is amended to read as follows: “§ 21-589.01. Interim provisions for term of commitment. “(a) The commitment of a person committed under section 21-545 for an indeterminate period of time shall expire 548 days after December 10, 2004, unless the chief clinical officer of the Department, facility, hospital, or mental health provider has petitioned for recommitment of the person. “(b) A petition for recommitment under this section shall be subject to the provisions for a petition for renewal of commitment brought under section 21-545.01 unless the provision is inconsistent with this section. “(c) A petition for recommitment may be filed at any time during the 548-day period, but not later than 60 days prior to the expiration of the 548-day period. For good cause shown, a petition for recommitment may be filed within the last 60 days of the 548-day period. “(d) If a petition for recommitment is pending at the expiration of the 548-day period, the period of commitment shall be extended pending resolution of the petition. “(e) This section shall apply as of July 20, 2005.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher Amend § 21-589.01 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 788; D.C. Official Code § 206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
