<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-23">
  <num type="law">16-23</num>
  <heading type="short">Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform Amendment Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2005-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-23.pdf">D.C. Law 16-23</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 8078</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0030">
      <narrative>Law 16-23, the “Nuisance Properties Abatement Reform Amendment Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-30 which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 21, 2005, and July 6, 2005, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 14, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 16-132 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-23 became effective on October 18, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend AN ACT to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes to limit the exemption from registering under the vacant properties registry where the owner has a valid building permit for construction, renovation, rehabilitation, or repair, or is actively seeking to rent or sell the property; and to provide for civil fines for failure to comply with the Act. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may cited as the ANuisance Properties Abatement Reform Amendment Act of 2005@. Sec. 2. AN ACT to provide for the abatement of nuisances in the District of Columbia by the Commissioners of said District, and for other purposes, approved April 14, 1906 (34 Stat. 115; D.C. Official Code 42-3131.01 et seq is amended as follows a) Section 6 (D.C. Official Code 42-3131.06) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (b)(3) is amended by striking the phrase Aand if there is a valid building permit that was issued within 60 days of the required registration date;@ and inserting the phrase Aand if there is a valid building permit that was issued within 60 days of the required registration date; provided, that the scope of the permit is not limited to electrical or plumbing work; provided further, that this exemption shall not exceed one year from the date of issuance of the first building permit for rehabilitation, renovation or repair;@ in its place 2) Subsection (b)(4) is amended by striking the phrase Athe owner or his agent has been actively seeking to rent or sell it;@ and inserting the phrase Athe owner or his agent has been actively seeking to rent or sell it; provided, that the time period for sale or rent shall not exceed one year from the initial listing, offer, or advertisement of sale, or 90 days from the initial listing, offer, or advertisement to rent;@ in its place b) Section 10 (D.C. Official Code 42-3131.10) is amended as follows 1) Subsection (a) is amended by adding a new sentence to read as follows: AThe Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs shall provide the Office Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2005 Fall Supp. West Group Publisher Amend 42-3131.06 Amend 42-3131.10 ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 2 of the Attorney General with a list of all owners who fail to register and pay the required fee after notice.@ 2) A new subsection (c) is added to read as follows: A(c) In addition to the penalties provided in subsection (a) of this section, and other available remedies, the failure of the owner of a vacant building to register and pay all the required fees under section 6(a) or 9 within 10 days after receipt of the mailing of a delinquency and determination notice under section 11 shall be punishable by a civil fine not to exceed $1,000 for each instance of inclusion of each property in the semiannual list under section 11. The Mayor shall provide for such fines in accordance with the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs Civil Infractions Act of 1985, effective October 5, 1985 (D.C. Law 6-42; D.C. Official Code 2-1801-01 et seq @. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813 D.C. Official Code 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia ENROLLED ORIGINAL Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 3</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
