<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-243">
  <num type="law">16-243</num>
  <heading type="short">Office on Ex-Offender Affairs and Commission on Re-entry and Ex-Offender Affairs Establishment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2007-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-243.pdf">D.C. Law 16-243</citation>
      <citation type="register">54 DCR 605</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0910">
      <narrative>Law 16-243, the “Office on Ex-Offender Affairs and Commission on Re-entry and Ex-Offender Affairs Establishment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-910, which was referred to Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 28 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-599 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-243 became effective on March 8, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish the Office on Ex-Offender Affairs and the Commission on Re-Entry and Ex-Offender Affairs. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Office on Ex-Offender Affairs and Commission on Re-Entry and Ex-Offender Affairs Establishment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1) “Commission means the Commission on Re-entry and Ex-Offender Affairs established by section 4(a 2) “Director” means the Executive Director of the Office on Ex-Offender Affairs 3) “Ex-offenders” means persons who were previously incarcerated 4) “Office” means the Office on Ex-Offender Affairs established by section 3(a Sec. 3. Establishment of the Office on Ex-Offender Affairs a) There is established the Office on Ex-Offender Affairs. The Office shall coordinate and monitor service delivery to ex-offenders. The Office shall make recommendations to the Mayor to promote the general welfare, empowerment, and reintegration of ex-offenders in the areas of employment and career development, health care, education, housing, and social services b)(1) The Office shall be headed by an Executive Director, who shall be appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to section 2(a) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code §1-523.01(a The Director shall be a full-time employee, for whom annual compensation shall be fixed in accordance with Title X-A of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective June 10, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-124; D.C. Official Code § 1-610.51 et seq 2) The Director shall A) Serve as principal advisor to the Mayor on matters related to the Codification Di s t r ic t o f Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. reintegration of ex-offenders into the general population B) Serve as an advocate for the ex-offenders C) Respond to recommendations and policy statements from the Commission D) Identify areas for service improvement and policy development and implementation for presentation to the Mayor and the Commission by funding research, hosting symposia, and undertaking other projects E) Coordinate efforts of District government agencies targeted toward ex-offenders F) Accept volunteer services and funding from public and private sources to supplement the budget in carrying out the duties and responsibilities of the Office G) Apply for, receive, and expend any gift or grant to further the purposes of the Office; and (H) File an annual report on the operations of the Office with the Mayor and the Council 3) The Office shall have staff as funded by appropriations and federal or private grants. Sec. 4. Establishment of the Commission on Re-Entry and Ex-Offender Affairs a) There is established the Commission on Re-entry and Ex-Offender Affairs to advise the Mayor, the Council, and the Director on the process, issues, and consequences of the reintegration of ex-offenders into the general population b)(1) The Commission shall consist of 15 public voting members appointed by the Mayor with the advice and consent of the Council pursuant to section 2(a) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(a There shall also be 11 ex-officio non-voting members, including the following officials or their designees A) Attorney General B) Director of the Department of Human Services C) Director of the Department of Health D) Director of the Department of Housing and Community Development E) Director of the Department of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs F) Superintendent of Education of the District of Columbia G) President of the University of the District of Columbia H) Chief of the Metropolitan Police Department I) Director of the Department of Youth Rehabilitative Services J) Director of the Department of Employment Services; and (K) Director of the Office of Human Rights 2) Ex-officio members or their designees shall develop and implement policies ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. and programs in their respective agencies that will ensure that the purposes of this act are accomplished. Ex-officio members or their designees shall meet with the Director, at a minimum, once per quarter in planning and coordinating policies and programs to assist in the successful reintegration of ex-offenders into the general population 3)(A) Voting members shall be appointed with due consideration for significant representation from the ex-offenders community and established District-based public, private, nonprofit, and volunteer community organizations involved with the provision of services for ex-offenders, the incarcerated, and their families B) Voting members of the Commission shall serve terms of 3 years except, that of the initial members, 5 shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, 5 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, and 5 shall be appointed for a term of one year. Members may be reappointed, but shall not serve more than 3 consecutive full terms. Terms for the initial Commission members shall begin on the date that a majority of the members are sworn in, which date shall become the anniversary date for all subsequent appointments C) If a vacancy occurs on the Commission, the Mayor shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Council, a successor to fill the unexpired portion of the term in accordance with section 2(a) of the Confirmation Act of 1978, effective March 3, 1979 (D.C. Law 2-142; D.C. Official Code § 1-523.01(a 4) The Mayor shall appoint the Chairperson of the Commission 5) All members of the Commission shall serve without compensation. Expenses incurred by the Commission or by its individual members, when authorized by the Chairperson, shall become an obligation to the extent of appropriated District of Columbia and federal funds designated for that purpose 6) The Commission shall adopt rules of procedure 7) The Commission shall meet monthly. The meetings shall be held in space provided by the District government and shall be open to the public. A quorum to transact business shall consist of a majority, plus one, of the voting members c) The Commission shall 1) Serve as an advocate for ex-offenders 2) Review and submit to the Mayor, the Council, and the Office an annual report, made available to the public, that includes a comprehensive analysis of the needs of ex-offender 3) Develop sustainable relationships and coordinate with federal, state and private agencies working with ex-offenders 4) Participate in public hearings and promote community dialogue concerning the issues confronting ex-offenders 5) Review and comment on proposed legislation and regulations, policies, and programs and make policy recommendations on issues affecting ex-offenders; ENROLLED ORIGINAL 4Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378 6) Develop policy and provide continuing review of the planning undertaken by the Office; and (7) Make reasonable requests for information necessary to effectuate the discharge of its responsibilities. Sec. 5. Inclusion in the budget and financial plan. This act shall take effect subject to the inclusion of its fiscal effect in an approved budget and financial plan. Sec. 6. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(3 Sec. 7. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1301"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1302"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1303"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§24-1304"/>
  </section>
</document>
