<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-22">
  <num type="law">16-22</num>
  <heading type="short">Summer Youth Employment Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2005-10-18</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-22.pdf">D.C. Law 16-22</citation>
      <citation type="register">52 DCR 8076</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0023">
      <narrative>Law 16-22, the “Summer Youth Employment Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-23 which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 7, 2005, and July 6, 2005, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 14, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 16-131 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-22 became effective on October 18, 2005.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1 AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the Youth Employment Act of 1979 to authorize the Department of Employment Services to enter into public-private partnerships with District businesses to fund the summer youth jobs program, and to require the District of Columbia to provide employment for 10,000 youth between 14 and 21 years of age. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Summer Youth Employment Act of 2005”. Sec. 2. Section 2(a)(1) of the Youth Employment Act of 1979, effective January 5, 1980 (D.C. Law 3-46; D.C. Official Code § 32-241(a)(1 is amended to read as follows: “(1)(A) Summer youth jobs—A summer youth jobs program to provide for the employment each summer of 10,000 youth between 14 and 21 years of age on the date of enrollment in the program, at a rate at least equal to the federal minimum wage established by section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, approved June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. 1062; 29 U.S. C. § 206 B) The weekly number of hours of employment under the summer youth jobs program shall be established according to the age of the youth to be employed and the nature and requirements of the job, but shall not be less than 20 nor more than 40 hours per week. Participants in this program shall be employed for a minimum of 6 weeks C) Employment may include an appropriate number of supervisory positions at a wage not to exceed the federal minimum wage by more than 12 provided, that these positions shall not be subject to the requirements under this paragraph regarding the number of hours and weeks of employment c) The Department of Employment Services shall implement the summer youth jobs program subject to the appropriation of funds or availability of funds through public-private partnerships between the District government and a District business that has the ability to employ youth under this program; provided, that these partnerships shall be subject to all federal and District laws, rules, and regulations relating to the procurement and award of contracts, grants, or other government assistance. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “District Business” means a corporation or any entity carrying on any trade or business in the District of Columbia that is subject to taxation under sections 47-1807.02 or 47-1808.03 of the District of Columbia Official Code.”. Sec. 3. Rules. The Mayor shall issue rules to implement this act. The proposed rules and regulations shall be submitted by the Mayor to the Council for review and approval. ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2 Sec. 4. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D. C. Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 5. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
