<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-222">
  <num type="law">16-222</num>
  <heading type="short">Licensed Health Professional Criminal Background Check Amendment Act of 2006</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2007-03-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-222.pdf">D.C. Law 16-222</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 10219</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0438">
      <narrative>Law 16-222, the “Licensed Health Professional Criminal Background Check Amendment Act of 2006”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-438, which was referred to Committee on Human Services. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 14, 2006, and December 5, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 19, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-551 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-222 became effective on March 6, 2007.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend the District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985 to require persons licensed under this act to undergo a criminal background check. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Licensed Health Professional Criminal Background Check Amendment Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. The District of Columbia Health Occupations Revision Act of 1985, effective March 25, 1986 (D.C. Law 6-99; D.C. Official Code § 3-1201.01, et seq is amended by adding a new section 522 to read as follows: “Sec. 522. Criminal background check. “(a) No license or registration shall be issued to a health professional before a criminal background check has been conducted for that person. The applicant for a license or registration shall pay the fee established by the Department of Health for the criminal background check. “(b) The criminal background check shall be obtained by the Department of Health from the U.S. Department of Justice, or from a private agency determined by the Department of Health. The results of the criminal background check shall be forwarded directly to the appropriate health licensing board.”. Sec. 3. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02 (c)(3 Sec. 4. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2007 Winter Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
