<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-53">
  <num type="law">16-53</num>
  <heading type="short">Full Service Grocery Store Alcohol License Exception Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>2006-03-08</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-53.pdf">D.C. Law 16-53</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 3</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0160">
      <narrative>Law 16-53, the “Full Service Grocery Store Alcohol License Exception Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-160 which was referred to the Committee on Consumer and Regulatory Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 1, 2005, and December 6, 2005, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 22, 2005, it was assigned Act No. 16-215 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-53 became effective on March 8, 2006.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To amend section 25-314(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code to provide for an exception from the distance-to-a-school requirement for certain full service grocery stores that apply for an off-premises retailer’s license, Class B. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Full Service Grocery Store Alcohol License Exception Act of 2005”. Sec. 2. Section 25-314(b) of the District of Columbia Official Code is amended by adding a new paragraph (4) to read as follows: “(4) The 400-foot restriction shall not apply if: “(A) The applicant applies for an off-premises retailer’s license, Class B; “(B) The primary business and purpose of the establishment is the sale of a full range of fresh, canned, and frozen food items, and the sale of alcoholic beverages is incidental to the primary purpose; “(C) The sale of alcoholic beverages constitutes no more than 15% of the total volume of gross receipts on an annual basis; “(D) The establishment is located in a C-l, C-2, C-3, C-4, or C-5 zone; “(E) The establishment is a full service grocery store which is newly constructed with a certificate of occupancy issued after January l, 2000, or is an existing store which has undergone renovations in excess of $500,000 (i) after January 1, 2000 and prior to the effective date of this paragraph, or (ii) during the preceding 12 months in which an application is made; “(F) The opinion of the ANC in which the establishment is located has been given great weight as specified in Chapter 4; and “(G) The applicant does not hold a manufacturer’s or wholesaler’s license.”. Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Spring Supp. West Group Publisher New § 25-314 ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. Sec. 3. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 4. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
