<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 16-89">
  <num type="law">16-89</num>
  <heading type="short">Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Affairs Act of 2005</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>2006-04-04</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/16-89.pdf">D.C. Law 16-89</citation>
      <citation type="register">53 DCR 1084</citation>
    </citations>
    <history url="http://lims.dccouncil.us/Legislation/B16-0235">
      <narrative>Law 16-89, the “Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Affairs Act of 2005”, was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 16-235 which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on December 6, 2005, and January 4, 2006, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on January 30, 2006, it was assigned Act No. 16-275 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review. D.C. Law 16-89 became effective on April 4, 2006.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>ENROLLED ORIGINAL 1Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. AN ACT IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To establish the Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Affairs and an Advisory Committee to the Office. BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, That this act may be cited as the “Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Affairs Act of 2006”. Sec. 2. Definitions. For the purposes of this act, the term 1) ”Advisory Committee” means the Advisory Committee to the Office Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Affairs 2) “Gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender” means individuals who identify themselves as gay, lesbian, bisexual, or transgender and who are residents of the District of Columbia 3) “Office” means the Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Affairs established in section 3. Sec. 3. Establishment of the Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Affairs; Advisory Committee a) There is established within the Executive Office of the Mayor, the Office of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, and Transgender Affairs (“Office The Office shall administer such programs as shall be delegated to it by the Mayor and the Council to promote the welfare of the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community b) The Mayor shall establish an Advisory Committee, consisting of not more than 25 public members, whose members shall be representative of the diversity of people and ideas within the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community. The Advisory Committee shall include, at a minimum, representation from gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community organizations representing health, social service, religious, and human rights issues and its members shall be representative of the diversity in the community with regard to socio- economic status, religion, race, ethnicity, gender identification, age, and families. The Advisory Committee shall advise the Director and the Mayor on issues relating to the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community and on issues relating to the mission of the Office. Sec. 4. Appointment of Director; compensation; staff a)(1) The Office shall be administered by the Director, who shall be appointed by the Mayor. The Director shall devote his or her full-time to the duties of the Office. His or Codification District of Columbia Official Code 2001 Edition 2006 Spring Supp. West Group Publisher ENROLLED ORIGINAL 2Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. her annual compensation shall not be lower than a DS-15, step one, or equivalent compensation pursuant to sections 1051 through 1063 of the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978, effective June 10, 1998 (D.C. Law 12-124; D.C. Official Code § § 1-610.51 through 1-610.63 2) The Office shall have 2 full-time employees, plus any temporary staff approved by the Office of Budget and Planning b) The Director shall 1) Serve as an advocate for the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community in the District of Columbia 2) Assist community organizations in developing and submitting grant applications 3) Provide information and technical assistance with respect to programs and services for the Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender community to the Mayor, the Council, other District of Columbia agencies and departments, and the community 4) File an annual report on the operation of the Office with the Mayor and the Council 5) Identify areas of need for service or improvement of services and bring them to the attention of the Mayor, with suggestions for satisfying such needs, including conducting or funding research and demonstration projects to test the suggestions 6) Assure necessary control, evaluation, audit, and reporting on programs funded through the Office 7) Accept volunteer services and funds from the public and private sectors to supplement the budget in carrying out the planning duties and responsibilities of the Office 8) Meet with the Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Program Coordinators within each department and agency of the District government as a group, at least once a month to coordinate activities within the government involving the gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender community 9) Meet with each department and agency director to establish a Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgender Coordinator 10) Work with the Department of Health’s Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual and Transgendered program coordinator to ensure that the Department’s annual report on the status of gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender health in the District of Columbia is comprehensive and receives an appropriate response. Sec. 5. Fiscal impact statement. The Council adopts the fiscal impact statement in the committee report as the fiscal impact statement required by section 602(c)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(3 Sec. 6. Effective date. This act shall take effect following approval by the Mayor (or in the event of veto by the Mayor, action by the Council to override the veto a 30-day period of Congressional review as provided in section 602(c)(1) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, approved December ENROLLED ORIGINAL 3Codification District of Columbia Official Code, 2001 Edition West Group Publisher, 1-800-328-9378. 24, 1973 (87 Stat. 813; D.C. Official Code § 1-206.02(c)(1 and publication in the District of Columbia Register. Chairman Council of the District of Columbia Mayor District of Columbia</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1381"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1382"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1383"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§2-1384"/>
  </section>
</document>
