<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-103">
  <codified:at doc="D.C. Code" path="42|26|I"/>
  <num type="law">2-103</num>
  <heading type="short">Home Purchase Assistance Fund Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1978-09-12</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-103.pdf">D.C. Law 2-103</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1977</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-103, the “Home Purchase Assistance Fund Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-316, which was referred to the Committee on Housing and Urban Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 13, 1978, and June 27, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 1, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-214 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> O. c. Law IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU"BIA To establish a h09e purchase assistance fund in the District of Columbia• and for otner purposes. BE IT ENACTED 8Y THE COUNCIL OF THE OlSTrtICT OF COLU'48lA• Tnat tnis act tte cited as the •Ho Purc:n•se Assistance Fund let of 1~78 Sec z. Tnere is hereby established in tne District of ColulllOia and ti'lere Is autnori~•d• to b• appropriated out o f the revenues of the District of Colu.Cia• funds not to revo~vin9 fund to be known as tne Hoae Purcnase Assi5tance Fund (nereinafter referred to as tne •fund to provide financial as5istance to residents of tne District of ColulllOia of lower incomes for the purpose of enaolin9 tne~ to purchase decent. safe and sa.ni tary ho-s in the Distr ict of Col umo i a. Sec. 3. T~re snail be deposited to tne credit of tne fun&amp;lt;I suc:n aMounts as •ay be appropriated pursuant. to this act; grants an~ gifts from public and private sources to tne fund or to the District of Colu•Oia for the purposes of the fund; repayments or principal and any inte rest on l oans Drolled Original -z rovided fro• t he fund; proceeds realized from tn liquidation of any security interests held by the Distr ict f tolu•bia under tne ter•s of any assistance provided fr om tne fund; interest earned fro• the deposit or investment of 110nies of tne fund; and all other revenues. receipts and fees of whatever nature derived fro• the operation of tne f und. sec. 4. The fund snall be a:vailaole• without f i scal year limitation. for •aking loans; for providing other forms of financial assistance under terms and conditions prescribed Dy the Mayo r of the District of Columoia (herei nafter referred to as the •Mayor and for the principal purpose o f e nabling a recipient thereof to mak e a down payment toward the purchase of a ho111e i n the Oistri ct of Columbia as his principal place of r e sidence Such f i nanci a l assistance may De used in conjunction with othe r availaol e home purchase assistance proyrams nere t ne applicable law or regulations of such otner programs prohibit assistance in the for• of loans. the Mayor i s autnorized to provide other for•s of financial assistance. Sec. 5 a) The Mayor i s authorized to pro•ulgate rules and regulations to govern tne operation of the fund, inc l uding but not limited toe rules and regul a tions es tabl; sh ing s~andards for determi ning the eli gib il i ty a nd -3 election of applicants; procedures for Ssistance and for notifying applicants tiro11ed Origiaal applying fc&amp;gt;« I including the de-topment of appropriate for•s and criteria for deter•ining the terlllS and conditions under •hich loans or other forms of financial assistance may be •ade from the fund •hiCh• a•ong other things. shall reflect the ability of the recipient to pay and •aY provide for the deferred pay•ent or forgiveness of loans. The rules and regulations issued by the Kayor for the purpose of i•ple111enting the provisions of this act shall be suo•itted by tile Mayor t o the Council o f the District of ColumDia for a forty-five SI ca lendar day rewie• peri,do eluding days of Counc i l recess. No such rules or regulations shall take effect until the end of the forty-five SJ calendar day peri od beginning on the day such rules or regu lations are transeitted by th• Mayor to the Chairman of the Counci l and then only if during such period. the Council does not adopt a resolution disapproving such rules and r egulations i n •hole or in part b) Any loan agreement entered into pursuant to sucn rules and regulations shall provide that ll all applic ations for and recipients of financial assistance froe the fund shall be res idents of the District of tolulllbla and a member of a nousenolo consi sting of two (Zl or 110re persons wno are related by blood° r r i age; and 2) if the ho111e purcnased ceases to be the pri•ary residence of tne recipient of financial assistance from the fund• the payments to such fund by the recipient snall be accelerated on ter111s and conditions prescribed by the IMyor: PR~VIOEO. That such obligation snail not be inconsistent with the applicable law or regulations of any federa l ho:11e purc:nase assistance program made available to the recipient. Sec 6 a) An annual audit of the operations of t he fund sh~ll be conducted by the District of Colu111oia Offi ce of Internal Audits a •1d Inspections O) Not later than si 6 ontns after the end of each f i scal year. the Mayor shall sub~it to the Congress of the United States and to tne Council of the District of Colu1111&amp;gt;ia a report of the financial condition of the fund and the results of the operations for such fiscal year c) The Mayor shall inc lude in tne budget esti~ates of the District of Colullt&amp;gt;ia for each fisc~l year and there is authorized. to be appropriated annually, such amounts out of the revenues of the District of Colu•bia as .way be required to co~pensate any deficiency in the working capita lizati on of one ~ill ion dolla~s cs 1. ooo.0001 for the funds s- Sec. 7. This act shall take effect as Of the Council of the Distr ict of Colu•bi J!!arolled Origii:ial provi for 1 n sect 1-on acts OZ(.c)(l) of the District of Colullbia Self-Govern-nt itn&amp;lt;J Govern~ental Reorganization Act. 11.SCOIUt or crFltC:LL ccccr.:cn a.c tc t o: Bill Z- 316 Flnt 11..eMll.zll A&amp;lt;:doa: June 13, 1978 @ VOICJ: VOTE; LJ JlOU. CAU VOTE 1 t I I l111 l t1 J l r l 4 a. I T'C'&amp;lt a.3. I I o~ I I I Si'Ali CIO"C 1 I I I lUJt.DY I ~oou. D. I I Wll.SON I I I I I :a.u,iy I l )o(OOJI 1 I I ~TL' I I I r 1 C1 •PK7 I 1 I I I.OLA.IX I I I I I i l DO:CC'I I Sl'.A.OUZ 0 1 I I I I I I s ed'C'° Ao I a I ta tile c c:il A d Fl.Z'1t a d.tD.c A.c1:loa L I vou:i: VOTE; Q 10CJ. CA.tl. VOTJ:1 111C1t I I I a" t I t 4ltt&amp;amp;o'le t 1 I r oco. I I I I I MA.SON I I I I p A.in.OOIG 1 l 1 ~y; I I I M I J I I P.'ti.SON I I I i I :a~Ut I I I I WOOll.ii 1. I I 1· I 3WtN~ I I I c lt;Z I I j 1 q ll.Ot..1..U I I I I N J I I i I n i::ON I I I I I 5'AC 1 I I I I I I I L I s d L l'I Xet 7 I Adopted Unanimously Za.b a Barry, Dixon t:-rs.a4.t f l LJ ltOU VOTJ I t I 1 I I I j &amp;amp;.a I I I T'l&amp;lt CZ~ I I I I 8 M..l.SON I I I 1 IP u 1 i c I I I 1 1 H l.!l'r i l I I llMOOIU c. I I I r lt;nUON I I I I 5A.U I I I I MCC:llU J. I r I I I I I I I Ct..\3 tZ I I 1 I 'i!.01..A.1U: I I I I I f I J I Dl::tON I I I 1 S!.G&amp;lt;:Z I I I I I I I I l T Jo L amp;'ea tf q I Ac o J:;U:;L l ma L I C t r,&amp;gt d: L I ~t:l?j&amp;gt;=ove JA a!e:en Do ­ •31 stt Ac o s ecu::ive S..c:eta 1. 0 C ctu! wi~ot&amp;amp;J: May~•s Sl1:o.a.:re See-eca b Cat Cl LI VO!cz von 0 'il.0!.1. C:.U.X. VOT I ~t.e•C 1 f I :0-4? f f r H c:.i c c I I I c v C'lo amp;Jo•C• I n I I -z \ t. I I I I MASCN \ gt I I I I I C03.Z 3.A I I I I I MCOU i cu I I I l I :tOI \ I Z)l:(CN t I I I R s c ;c.z x rd I 3 Ac!ian esi~•e.c: I I Reuaa c A?~rcrved. If :1.Cayor' a Velo $uat&amp;amp;t#ri .UH 1 3 \9?8 .D. C o le e.ti.Ye 0..ce I I I I I I I 'is U4 I J I 1 Vt SC X I I i I I I 1 l J I I 4 I I I :c t-"ifu y F.CT&amp;lt;Ue Acdo leso\u.:icu ~u te I I I J I I I I</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>2</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2601"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>3</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2602"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>4</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2603"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2604"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>6</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2605"/>
  </section>
</document>
