<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-111">
  <num type="law">2-111</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1978-09-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-111.pdf">D.C. Law 2-111</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1462</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-111 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-334, which was referred to the Committee of the Whole. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 13, 1978 and June 27, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 17, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-232 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COu"'NCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE D. C Law Z-111 Official Pu_rposes Funds Act of 197811 Pur suant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Goverrunent and Goverrunen:al Reorganization Act, P. L 93-198 the Ac the Council of the District of Coluinbia adopted Bill No. 2- 334, on first a nd second readings June 13, 1978 and June 27, 1978, respectively. F ollowing the signature of the May or on July 17, 197.8, this legislation was assigned Act No. 2-232, published in the August ll, 1978, edition of the D, C Register and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in ac:cord.ance with Section 602 (c)(l) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period lias expired and, therefore, cites the follo~g legislation as D. C. Law 2 -lll, effec tive Septe=be 23 1978 STERLG TUC~ER Chairman of the Council (VoL 25, N gt 6, D. C. Register, 1462 August 11, 1978 J 2 o. c. La w 2-111 I N THE COUNClL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA Septe mber 23 1978 To auth orize the e~penoiture o f f unds by Coun cil Members for off ici a l purposes BE IT E~ACTEO SY THE COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF CJLUMBIA, That t h is act may be cited a s tne Dff ic i a 'I Purpose Fun o s Act of 1'178 Sec. 2 The fir s t s e ntence of section Zb of An Ac t to authori-ze certain programs and acti-vities of the go vernment of the Di stri c t of Col u bi a app roved Oq;nbe r Z6 1.973 (87 Stat. 509 u. c. Code. sec. l -2b2a. and se 31- 1122 is amended to r.ead as f ol l o ws The Mayor of the Di s trict of Columbia the Cha irman and Members o f the Council of the Dis tri ct of C~l umbia. t he Supei,intendent of Schools• and the Ch ief Executi ve Off icer of the University o f the Di stri c t of Co lumbia are eac n hereby authoriz ed to provide fo r the e Kpend it u r e wi thin the l i mits of s pecified annual appropr i ation of f u nds f or approoriat e purposes rel~ted t o the ir of f icial c a pac ity a s they may res.pect ive'l y deem necessar y 2- Sec 3 Section 30l(b) The District of Columola Puol ic Postseconoar·y EOucat ion Reor ganization Ac t Amendments• effective Novemoer l• 197 5 (D.C. La~ 1-36: o.c. Code. sec 31- l 7Zl(DI J is nereoy repeal ea Se·C· 4 This act shall take effect as provided for acts o f the Councii of the District of Columbia in section 602( C l) of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental \ tlocMc No: Bill 2-334 Z_I VOICZ VO r j ca~-c-c• I r r 1 j a t n i 1 nrc:z::i I I I I I M SON I I I I 4 s gt u p;c; I I I l I iiA.3-0 I I f I MC&amp;lt;n'.Z. o. I I I W SCN J f I s.A.i!.3 I I I I ,l MOOR.I 1. I I I I a I 1 c r I I 1 I .I ROJ U c I I J J 4 I I i I I f 4 Ac I; i :t I I T I v jr 1 \ it I L I VOIC:C: VOTZ l f I c• I l I I C~U•O\ 4-&amp;amp;11- t I 1 Ttrc::s:z I i l i MASON' I I I t :is ca c I I I I I I J J I w•coaz gt I I I I l .rz so I I I I !I~ I 1 I I ~Mee 1. I I 1- I 1 I I I C D r I I I R £.1:1c a I J I I &amp;gt j I I 1 1 Dt N' f ·1 I I 1 1 I I I l I l I I P \. v I « j r j i I I C.CV 0 I .ir-C I J c a 1 i I 1 M.,\.SCN I I I I f \IC I I I I ·V &amp;amp I f I I I MCCAZ gt I 1 I I qw-~CN I I I 3A.U I I I I «:1caz, I I i i ij'fT!N I I I I I Cl.A U I f j I t.o.i I I I 1 I 1 I I !JCC:N I I I I U S&amp;lt;J lt Z-:O::N l I I I ;1 I I f I a v r a, I L I ti=e e el c.C c.!\:e Ooc s~r \_c Z:ci1tc:C gt;c:t• d w i.L&amp;amp;ya Si s e ca I 3.C VOTZ T::C I I I I Li.SON I I I J !I cc u a i I I I l MC03.Z c I OJ z I I -r I tO L o=ccN I I I I II s.;c e Ac on gt e s-!C e Q :M.a A;l;i evet! LJ a.yr Vdo S.u::r.i lt Se:ate Ac ll awoi Nc-•e I i f I :ts z z I I i Vl SC X I I t-:o I I I I I I I i I I I lt £ c &amp;gt c:o 3.ascl-.J Xe i 1 l l i I I I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
