<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-119">
  <num type="law">2-119</num>
  <heading type="short">Property Tax Deferral Reform Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1978-10-13</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-119.pdf">D.C. Law 2-119</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 1514</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-119, the “Property Tax Deferral Reform Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-324, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 27, 1978 and July 11, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 1, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-249 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> \ COUNCIL OF THE DiSTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTI CE D. C. Law 2- 119 P r operty Tax Deferral Reform Act of 1978" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Seli- Government and Governmental Reor ganization Ac t P L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Dis tric t of Colr.unbia adopted Bill No. 2 324, on first and second ea.dings June 27, 1978 and July 11, 1978, respectively. Following the signature of the Mayor on August 1, 1978, thi s legislation was assigned Ac t No. 2 249, published in the August 11, 1978, edition of the D. C. Register Vol. 25, page 1514} and transmitted to Congress on August 14, 1978 !or a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c){l of the Ac t. The C ou.ocil o f t le Dist:-ic: of Columbia h ereby gives nocice that the 30 day Congress ional Review Period has e:&amp;lt;pired and, therefore, cites the following l egislation as D. C. Law 2 119 effective October 13, 1978 Chairman fr the Council Dates Counted During the 30-Da.v Con11r es s ior.al Review Per iod: 14, l5, 16, 17 S E PTENlBER 6 7 8 ll 12, 13, 14, 18, 19, 20, 25, Zb, 27, 28, 27 OCTOBER 2, 3, 4, S, 6 10, 11, 12 F o.c. Law 2- 11 q IN THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA To ame nd the property tax deferral 111&amp;amp;chanis and for other pu r po ses BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCI L OF THE OI ST~ICT OF COLUMBIA T~at t his act may be cited as t he Property Ta x Def e r ral Refor Act o f 1 ~78 Sec 2. Sect i on 425 o f the District of Columbia Real Prope r ty Ta~ Revisi on Act of 1974, appr o ved Septe~ber 3 1974 (88 Stat 1055 o. c. Code, s ac 47-645) is amended as fo ll ows a) Subs ect ion (9) is a :nended to reacJ as follows 9) an e xp lanati on of al l s pec i a l ben e fits incen t i ves l i mita tions or credit s hicn rel a te t o real p r ooer ty taxes as a result of this o r any other ac t Included in said exp l anati on sha ll be an easily understood descri pti on o f t~e Prooerty rax Oeferral Prog r am. the Property fax Cr ed it. t he Homestead Exemption and t~e Incenti~es fo r the Preservat ion of Hi storic Pr oper ties Each descr i?tion s hall incl ude but not be 1 imited t o applic ati o n p r ocedu r es a nd qualifying reouir em~nts The ti t le o f each prooerty tax 2- relief program shall oe capital i zea. un er1 i!"lea anc printed in bold type Sec. 3. Section 435 of the District of Columoia ~eal Property Tax Revision ~ct of 1974, approved Se~ternber 3. 1974 (38 Stat 105a; o c Code, sec. 47-655) is a~ended as follows al oy amending suosection (a ll o reao as fol lows L) have owned for at least one (l) year the resic:ential real property for which the deferral is clat~e D) Dy amenoing subsection {a)(3) to read as follows 3 file a written application for deferral on a form provided by the Mayor n application for re.;il oroperty ta&amp;gt;&amp;lt; deferral may oe f ilea tn ene "layor any time ~rior to tne last da~e an i nst~llment paymenc of tne real property ta&amp;gt;&amp;lt;es whicn are tote defer~ed is due Cl by amending suosection (a)(4J to read as fo:lows 4) certify tnat such resiaenti.31 real prooerty is currently the principal place cf residence of the tax~ayer and that such resioential real oraoer~y for tne twelve (12) montn period immeoi tely precaaing t:ie aopl feat ion for deferral 0 3 d) oy redesignating subsections (OJ c) and (d) as (Cl d) and (e respectively. and adding a new suosection (o) to read as follows 0) If a taxpayer suomits a timely application for deferral of real property taxes• the amount of real property tax owed in excess of llJ per centurn of the prior year s tax bill shall not constitute delinquent ta~es nor shall the taxpayer be assessej any interest for the period said application is pending A taxpayer shall be eligible to start deferring portions of the increas ed property tax liability i~~e:liately after nis or her application has been approved by tne ~ayor. If t:ne aopl ication for deferral is disa;ioroved. the taxpayer shall De ~otified. in ~riting. of said disapproval and the reasons therefcr anc &amp;gt;ranted an additional tnirty (30) days to pay said ~axes witnout interest e) oy a~ending suosection (d as reoesignated. to rea.:1 as follows ll No fur\.her deferrals of real prooerty tax shall be gran\.ed a taxpayer ~r.en the :lef~rre~ tax ~1&amp;lt s assessed valt.:e of t he proper::y for whic:i t:ie cef-:r;-al i s r2oue~:eC J i Sec. 4. Section 436 of tne District of Columbia ~eal Property Tax Revision Act of 1974, approved September 3, L97&amp;lt caa Stat. 1059; o.c. Coc::e. sec. c.7-o56l is amended as fol lows a) oy reoesignating suosections (o CJ d) and (e) as (c Cll e) and (f resoectively, and adding a new subsection (b) to read as follows 0) If a taxpayer suo~its a timely apolicacion for deferral of real property taxes. tnc amount cf said taxes attrioutaole co an increase by more than 25 ~er centum over the prior year's cax bill snail not constitute delinquent ~axes nor snail tne taxoayer be assessed any interest for the period said application i s pending A t ixpayer snall oe el igiole to start def~rring portions of the increased pro~erty tax liability immediately after his or her ap;:ilica ion i is been aporoved by the ~ayor. Cf the application for deferral is disapproved• the taxpayer sn.;ill :e notifleo, in writ ing of said disapproval and cne r•asons tnerefor and grantee an a~ditional thirty (30) cays to pay sai d :axes wit~out in~ares as fol low 5 d) No further deferrals of real property tax snail be granted a taxpayer ~hen the deferred tax plus inter~st equals ~ore than 20 per centum of the current assessed value of the pro~erty for wh icn the deferral is reQuested.•1 C) cy deleting sucsection &amp;lt;fl• as redesignated. Sec. 5. The Mayor may promulgate rules and regulations for tne proper administration of the provisions of this act. Sec. 6. This act shall take effect as provicea for ac:s of the Council of the Oistrict of Co lumbia in section 602(c)(ll of the District of Columbia Self-Governmen~ and Governmental Reorganization Act J I:«ltoc :io: 3ill No. 2-324 JU.L I s (iJ Ac ticio. o! e 14Ter 1 AUG 1578 ~° 0 !l amp;p;o cd1 0 auppra~ i:&amp;gt gt;&amp;amp t ere Br.qec Ac i o_M l:,x;e~v. S•ceta y, C.C. Z cuc! wi~aou U.y Sir-a::an Se e e l:a r to :lie C~o=cil I I YOtCZ •rcn. LJ O.U u VC Z: 1 AVG ms 1 lt;m•c P f I. t c-s amp;Joo•O I 9'!111 f l ccx""a f I I I j lt;.\SON l l gs o~J:Nc 1 l I I I I I J ii o!CC:.Z l I :1w~ox I f I I I I 3.11 t I I l d MCC I I i r I I I I u l 'f il.O U I I I 1 i I I I I I i!Xc.'f I 1 I ii st NI I I I 1 I I i I I 1 req !f lat "lc f' I Scc:.Q.:y to t C l 1 \ I I loc.lcec No Sill No Z~324 s e:.c os: Ju.n~ Z7, 1978 00 VOI!:Z VCT:t llOU von C l •a•l 1 t c C I I ~J I n I i 1l~3 I I t l l M.&amp;gt;.SOi'l I r.A lt;.i:r I I I I j MOOl Z o. I 3~&amp;lt 1 I I I MCC S I C.t..o Z I I I l tCt.A { I CC:C.'f I I J I j c ii i 1 u•F cl.C t_I era vo I I l s::i u rnv 1 I j I I I I iwtUoN I I I I I I I il W!N'!Z I I I I J I I I I I I T I I I l I I I I I Y. T f• t ·r ar I m'il I I t C.:\otJo 4 I 1 C-AW,.c:\o CJI I I 1' I v 1 I lt;:C Z MCC II L Acio lted !Jr.an!.mouslv {2abs) Rola:-k, Har~y ¢ r- 1 C4'U t lt.t i.-f C I I e 7C7 I aaat u I I lt c I av c I c I I 7":iC Z~ I :l L SCN JJF i l c </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
