<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-135">
  <num type="law">2-135</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-135.pdf">D.C. Law 2-135</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 5008</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-135, the “District of Columbia Housing Finance Agency Act,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-161, which was referred to the committee on Housing and Urban Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 25, 1978, and September 19, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 1, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-291 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>com~C! L OF TH2 DISTRICT OF COLL"'M 3IA NOTICE D. C. LAW 2-135 "District of Co lw11bia Beus i ng Finance Asen cy Act" Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government anci Governmental Reorgani:3tion Act L. 93-198 the Act the Council of the Dist=ict of Colur.i.bia adcpted 3ill io. 2-161, on first and second eacings, JtJly 25, 1978 ar.d Sep- tember 19, 1978 respectively. Following the signature of the :1a7o:c on ~ovember 2 197 8, this legislation was ass isied Ac re. 2-:Z n, 9u.blished in the Decem:ier l, 13i3, ecition of the D.C egist.er Vol. 25, page 5008) and transmitted to Congress on Jar.ua::y 18 19i9 :er a 30-day ri in accordance with Section 60 c 1 of the rtCt. T~e Counc l ct e e :Jistrict of Cokuibia he eey gi•Jes not.ice that the 30-day ConS't'essicnal Review Pe.d.od has ex;:irec, ar.d, t~erefo:-e, cit~s the :cl.lcwi:1g legislation as D.C. Law 2 33, ef feet i•Je March 3, 1979. Cates Cc~n:ed Ourina the 30-~av Concressional ~eview icd: Ja::ua 1 8, 19, 22, 23, 24, 25, 25, 29, 30, 3 1 s f 0 I 1 8, 9, 13 l.4, l.5, 16, 20, 21 23, 26, 2i, 28 D.C. L 12a 1 3 5 AN ~CT 2-291 I~ THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLU~9 To estacl ish a housing finance agency in t~e District of Columcia to proviae safe and sanitary housing within the financial ineans of f~mil ies and ~ersons of low ana ~oderate incomes. ae rr ENACTED av THE CDUNCIL OF THE OtST~!CT OF COLU~BIA. Thac chis act may be cited as tMe "District of :olumoia ~ousing Finance lgancy Act TABLE OF ~ONTENTS TIT~E I OlICY ANO uEFIN!TIJNS Sec. tOl. Declaration of Pol icy Sec. 102. Oefini~ions TITLE II ESTAdLISHMENT OF T~E AGE~Cv Sec. 201. Craa~ion of tne Agency Sec. 202. codr~ of Directors Sec. Z03. Emoloyees Sec. 204. Confl ic~ of Interest Sec. 205 equirement for Sure~y 3onding TITLE III QPE~ATIJNS OF r~e AG~NC1 Sec. 3JL neral Powers 2 Sec 302. Loans to Sponsors Sec. 303. Purcnase of .lol!ortgage Loans Sec. 304. Loans to Mort.gage Lenders Sec. 305. Supporti'le Programs Sec. 306 ules and ~egula-tions Sec. 307. rec:nnical ~ssistance :iec. 308. C:.xemption from R~nt Control TITLE IV F!NANC!AL AFFAIRS uF r E A GE 'iC 'f Sec. 4Ql. Sources of Funds Sec. 402. Issuance of aonds and Not.es I Sec. 403. Terms for Sa 1 e of Bonds and ~otes Sec. 404. Trust Indenture Sec. 405 gency Purchase of It.s o~n 3on~s and Notes Sec. 406. Special or Reserve Fun~s Sec. 407. Non-alteration of ~i~hts of 3o~cnolders and Notenolders Sec. 408. Credit of Qi strict Not Ple ec Sec. 409. 8onds and otes as Legal Inves::nents Sec. 4tO. District Tax Exe!'ltption Sec. 411 Jeoos its and l'lon i es in Trust. TITLE v PUSL AC:OUNfASILITY Sec 5 iJ l. Administrati'le Proce~ure J&amp;amp; c 1: Sec. 5J2. Advisory 5oard 3 Sec. 503 \nnua l Report Sec 504 \nnual Audit T!Tt.E V ISCELLANEOUS PROVISIO~S Sec. 601. Lioeral :onstruct)on Sec. 602. Sever ab i 1 i ty Sec. 603. Effective Date TITLE I ?Qt.ICY ANO OEFI~IrIONS Sec. l l Q Si.9 l-2L {a) ihe :aunci1 of tne Oistrict of Columoia hereoy fi nas: tha~ a decline in the number of housing units in tne ~istrict of Columoia. togetner itn the existing numoer of s~ostandaro dwellings. has produced a critical snor~age of ~dequace housing for low and modera income families; that tnis s~ort~se of affordable housing and tne ina~il ity of resiae~ts to ootain aporopri~te financing :o~cels J suostantial numoer of Oistr~c~ resiaants t~ 1 ive in unsanitary. overcrowdea and unsafe condi ti~ns ~nd to expend ~disproportionate portion of their incomes on housing; tnat t.tiese conaitions are oetril'llental to t.tie neal tn and el fare of Distr i ct residen~s and ad~ersely affec~ t~e economy of tne Oistri:t; t~at a major cause of tnis housinq crisis is tne :ost of Funes ~ade a~ailable oy ~ort;age l anders in tMe Jistric f i n~nc2 nousing for lo~ and ~odera~e income fami l ies; and further that tnis situation nas frustrated tne :onstruction. lease. sale and ~urcnase of ~ousing units for to~ and moderate income families b) The Council determines tn~t a corporate instrumentality of the Oistrict snat I be created and given authority to generate funds from private and puol ic sources to increase tne supply and lower the cost of funds available for residen~ial mortgages and construction l oans and tnerecy nelp al l eviate tne snortage of adequate nousing. rne Counc i 1 furt~er ae!ermines t~at this pur~ose can be acco~pl isned througn programs ~hereby ~ort;age l~nders 1c/or tne Agency ~aKe mortgage. construction and renaoi l itation 19ans for single and ~ultifamily rental and no~e O•nership units on terms cesigned to exoand availaole nousin~ opportunities. rhe :ouncil furtner determines tnat t Me goals of nei~hCorhood and fisca l staoil ity can oe acMieved tnrougn a pol icv of residential economic d i ~ers i tv c) The :ouncil hereoy declares that tne enac~~ent of ~nis act i s i n tne puClic interest and for t~e DuQ t i c ~enef i t• and tnat the authority and powers conf~rrea oy tnis act and tne exoenditure of monies oursuan~ to this act are to serve vd l id public ~urposes J s The fol l owing ~erms as used in tnis act shall nave tne fo1lo•ing meanings unless a different iseaning clear ly apoedrs fro~ tne context a act" means tnis Housing Financ2 ~gency Act l:l Agency" neans trie Jistric:t of Colu:noia Housing Finance Agency C 3oara" means tne 2oard of Directors of tne Clistrict of :oluiuoia Housing Finance Aqencv d bonds notes" and "otner 001 igations~ refer to ~ny conas, notas. jeoentures. interi~ cert i ficates or otner ev i::ances of financial indebtedness of t~e A ency dut::iorized to ~e issued under the provisions of tnis act et ouncil" means tne Council oF tne District of Colu~oia. {f onstruc~ion loan" means a snort tar~ aavanca of ~onias fo r tne pur~ose of constructing or renaoi 1; tating residential nousing g District eans the District of Columoia hJ "el igiole ~ersons~ means indi~i~uals and families .no qualify for nousing under a given progra~ according to tMa requiremen~s of tne progra~ as aut~orized oy is act ~nd rules and regulat i ~ns prumul~ated oy the Agency oursuant to sue~ recuirements i For~ard Commit~ent Mortgage ?urc~ase Programn ~eans a progra~ pursuant to Nhicn the ~gen:y commits to ourcnas~ from nortgage lenders mortgage loans committed to dnd ~riginated by tne ~ortgage lender after the date of the ~gency•s commitment ~nare tne loans are to low or moderate income persons for financing housing units to oe ONner- oc:upiad or are loans ~nicn ~eet the require~ents of section 302(0) or section 302(c) of this act j homeownership or~gram" means any type of program through .nicn a cerson can achieve an owners~ i os iti on in 3 residential unit including, Out not li~itec co, Jperatives and condominums K nousing project" means a numoer ~f dwelling units located in tne District of Columoia assis~~d ~Y cne Agency under the pr~visions of tnis act includi ~g Du~ not 1 i~ited to. units ac~uirad. financed• refinanced ons~ructed• renaoi1 itatej and/or conv@rtad to a concominiu~ or a :ooperative ~itn tne assistance of the A;enc1 r~j~ct ~ay incorporate anc ill ary Facilities .ni may include l) necessary or desiraole aopurtenancas to residential ,ousing such as, cut not 1 imi tac to. streets• s.e ers Jtil ities, parks and stores• as the .1.gcncy ~eter~ines to ~e approoriate; 7 (2) such c:om111unity facil it:ies in=ludingJ Out not limited to. nealth• recreational, educational and ~e1fare \ t J ci Cl \.J facilities. as t~e ~gency determines to oe approoriate; and (3) ancillary commercial facilities to11hicn t.he Agency deter~ines to be necessary to make the renainder of the proje&amp;lt;:t financiall1 feasicle: P~OV!DEa. HOWEVER. Tha~ the pr i mary use of the projec~ shall oe for residential housing 1 10--income persons• means persons and families nose annual income as det:er11i ne-j oy the Agency does not exceed tne fol lowing percentages of the ~edian Standard ~ecropol itan Sta~istic:al Area (S~S fa~ily income for t~e Jist:ric:t of :olumoia. as such SMSA family income may oe re~ised from ~ime to ti~e. F-3'1'1 i l v S i l 9.1 Fam i 1 v r r l. 2 3 72 0% 5 7 35. 5~ a 8 The ~gency snall adjust upward from 90.o: tne perc~nt of SA Median Family Income by 4.5~ for e~erv additional family memoer o~er eight (8} persons m) Nrnoderate income ~ersons" means persons and fame lies wnose annual inco~e as determined oy the ~gency does not e~ceed one nunared t~enty percent (lZO~} of tne ,edian Standard Metropolitan Statistical Area (S~S family income (as sue~ S~S~ family income may be revised from time to time) aopl iad to an eight (8) or nore person housenolj and ddJUS~ed downwarj for household size in ac:ordance witn formula adopted oy tne Agency n mortgaqe eans an interest in real property locacea ~itnin the District of Colu~oia wnicn is inprovea or to be imoroved by one or m~re housing units• whicn in~erest s~cures a ~ortgage loan or par~icication in a mortgage l oan and cons~itutes alien on tne fee simple intarest in sucn real prooerty or on a leasenold interest tnerein navi~g an unex~ire er~ longer tnan tne tarm in ~nich cne mortgage l oan secured is to Ce amortized o} or~gage lender• means any oanK. mortgage oanKin; company. trust company. savings oank. savings and loan assoc i ation. crecit union. national ~ankin; association. feceral sav i ngs and loan associati~n or feaeral cra~i~ union ,inc~ining an offica in Che ~istrict. er any i nsuranca 9 company authorized to do business in tne District and deemed eligible by the ~gency to participate in any of its orograns O ortgage l oanu means an ool iga~ion secured Cy a ~ortgage issued for the ourposes of financing residentia l housing a sponsor" means a sole propri~tor. joint ventura. oartners:iip. limH:ea partnerstiip. trust. c~rporation. cooperative. or condominum he~ner nonprofit or organized for orofi hich Owns a housing project pursuant to the orovis i ons of tnis act r) Nsuosidy" means any resources gener~ted tnrough aoprooriation oy the f~deral or Oistric~ government. or donated oy a puc l i: or private sour~a~ tne resources must ~e ~esi~na~ed for meeting nousi~g exoense and may oe payments to tne occupant of a housing unit as rei~oursement for noni:s expended. pay~en~ mad~ for suoplementing housi ng or rent p3yments ~ace by an occupant. or payments made ~o ~ffect a reduction in rnort;age interest rates paid Oy the 10rtgagor of a nousin9 unit. TITLE Ir ESTA6LISHMENT QF THE AGE~CY I lO The Distri:t of Columbia Housing Finance Agency is :raated as a c~rporate b~dy ~nich nas a l egal existenca separate fro~ tne government of the District but which is an i nstrumentality of the government of tne District created to effectuate cartain public ~urposes. Sec. 202. ooard of Directors a) The ency shall oe governed oy a aoard of J i rectors. wnicn snall oe _comprised of nine (9) memoers as follows 1) thre 3J ax officio memoers ~no sha ll be the Director of tne Oe~artment of Housing d Community Jevelopmenti (a) the Oiractor of tne Cff i ca of nicipal 1 anni ng and (C) t~e Oirector of t~e Off i ca of audget 3nd ~anage~en~ Systems 2) six (o gt;uol ic. memoers, oeing resijents of ti'1e Q istr i of wnom AJ t~o (2) sna l l hava ex~eriance in ~ortgage lend ing or finance; ca&amp;gt; t~o (2 snall have exoer i ence in nome ~ui 1 jing. real est3te• architecture or planning; and (C} two (2) snal l represen~ community or ll (O) The six (6) puolic nemoers of tne aoard snail be apoointed Oy tne Mayor on or after February l• 1~7~9 ~ith the ~dv i ce and consent of the Council ct nor~ tnan five (5) of the public ne~oers shall belong to the same political oarty. Each ex officio memoer may designate a reoresentati~e to perfor~ nis respective duties ana cowers un~er this ac including the power :o vote. Not~ithstanding the provisions of any otner law. no officer or employee of tne District sna11 oe deemed to nave forfeitej or s;iall f:lrfeit his office or e11playmeni: by re~son of his acceotance of ~emoersnip on tne Boarj or his service thereon c) Of the six (6 uol ic memcers first aopoint~d to ~ne 3oarj, tnree (3) sna11 be acpointed to ter~s of office ex~•ring in one (ll year and t~e ~emaining tnree (3 to terms of office ex~iring in three (3) yearsp aftar ~nicn tneir successors shall be apooineed to ~arTIS of office of four years each. Th ayer or tne ooard ~ay remove ~ny of t~e si puol ic nemoers of tne ooard f~r ineff i ciency. neglact of d~~Y or misconduct in office~ after giving such ~emoer a copy of t~e cnarges against nim and an oooor~unity to oe :ie~rd in person or t&amp;gt;y counse 1 in his defense uoon not less tnan ten 10) days no~ice emo~al of a puol ic ~emoer :iv ac-:ion of t:ie 3oar~ snall r~quire t:ie aff i r-nae.i11e 11oi::a f 12 si b e~oers. If any public memoer snal 1 be re~oved oy ~ne 3oard. t~e Board sha l l promptly notify ~ne Mayor of sucn ac t ·i on. Vacancies in the public memoershi~ of t~e Board shall oe filled for the unexpired term of the vacanc member by appointmen~ by tne Mayor and approval by the Council acn cuol ic ~emoer s nall hold office for t~e ter~ of his aooointment and ~nt i l nis successor snal l nave oeen aopointea and qualified. Any pub1ic memoer sna ll oe ~1 i;iole f~r raaopoincrnent d) The Board sna l 1 e l ect from among cneir nu~oer a irperson. vice-chairperson and such otner officers as 1ey may aetar~;n rhe cnairperson shall be el~cted from among tne puol ic memoers e) Tne powers of t~e Agency shall oe vested in t~e 3oar:1. F i ve 5 emoers of the aoaro sMal 1 constitute a ouorum for t~e transact i on of ousiness. and an affir~ative "oce o f at l east f i ve (5) me~oars shal l ~e necessary for val id Agency action o vacancy in t~e membership of t~e 3.oar::1 sha l l i moair tne rignt of a ~uorum t::i exercisa a ll r ·i qnts and perform al l duties of tne ~gency oard snall oe reimoursed for actual and necessary excenses i ncurred ~nile engageo in services for t he lgency e~oers of t le Boar d no~ otner~ise employed oy ~ne Ci strict nay a l so cei "e i e l i em c~moensation .3t: i::ie ra a ac ial r o t le cai 1 y 13 eQuivalent of Grade lS -0f the General Scneaule established under section 5332 of ritle 5 of tne United States Coce. with a 1 i mit of sa,ooa p?.r annum. Sec. 203. s?2l.2 a) The Board of Directors shall appoint an Executive ~irector wno snall be an employee of the Agency. but ~ho snal 1 not Je a memoer of tne Soard. and "no shall serve 3t tne ~l:asure of the Soard and receive sucn compensation as s~al l oe fixed b1 the aoard. Tne Executive Ji rector sna1 1 admin i ster anage and dir:ct tne affairs an~ act i vit i es of the ~gency i~ accordance ~itn tne ool icies. control and direction of the Board. The Executive Oirector shall aoorjve all accounts f~r salaries. allowab l e expenses of t~e ~gency or of any enployee or consultant tnereof, and xoenses incidental to t~e operat i on of th se~cy. He SMdll oerfor~ such o~ ier duties as may be jirectea oy tMe ~odr~ i n carr~ing out the ourposes of this act Tne E~ecuei~e Ci rector shall oe Secretar y t~ tne 3cara e s~al 1 attend the meetings of the 3oard• Shdll ~eeo a r~c~r1 of the proceedings of tne Board. ana snall ~aintain a~d be custodian of all boo~s. docu~ents and pacers f il ed 4itn t~e Soard• of the minutes booK or journdl of the 3odrd and ~f its officia l seal. I l 't (c) The Agency may employ on a permanent or temoorary ~asis technical advisors. accountants. legal counsel. appraisers and sucn ot~er officers. agents and employees it ce~ms necess3ry to operate tne Agency efficiently. and snall jetermine their qualifications. juties and compensation ~ithout regard to federal or Cistrict Civil Service or cl3ssificati~n l~ws. Federal or District :mo1oyees emoloyed oy t~e ~gency mdy retain all righ~s and ~rivi1eqes under tMe federal or District emcloyees• retirement systems oointments. jromotions and separations may oe oasea on :nerit only. Title s. cnapter 53• suoc~aot:r rtt of the itao States Code aopl ies to tne Boarj and employees of the ~ency to tr.e same extent as to District employees ny ~emoer. officer or employee of tne ~gency wno is interested eitner jirectly or indirectly. or ~no is 3n officer or e~ployee of. or has an owners~i~ interest in any fir~ or agency int:rested oirectly or indirec~ly in any ~r3nsaction ~itn t~e Agency including. but not 1 imited tO• any loan to any sponsor. builder or develooer, snall ~f:sclose tnis interest to tne Agency. This interest shall ~e sat forth i~ tne ~inutes of the &amp;amp;;ency, anc tne memoer. officer. or emoloyee having tne interest snall not •art icipata or. Oenalf of tne Agency in tne autnoriza t i~n or 0 11ed Origi~al \ 15 implamentation of any such transaction. The aoard by t~o- tnirds (2/3 majority vote may allow a waiver of a memoer•s. officer's or e~ployee•s inability to particijate in circums~ances ~nere the interest falls within guidelines adopted as ru l es promulgat2d by the ooard. Eacn memoer of tne Board snall execute a surety oond in the penal sum of szs.ooa. and the Exacutive Direc~or of the ~gency sna ll execute a surety oond in the penal sum of ~50,;JOO acn surety oond shall be conditioned upon tne fai~nful performance of tne official duties of the person oondedr issued by a surety company autnorized to transact ousiness as a surety in tne ~istrict. approved Oy the Corporation :ounsal of tne Oistrict~ and filea in cne office of ~he J i strict Deoart~ent of Insurance. All costs of the surety bonds snail be ~orne oy the ~gency. r!TLE Irr rne Agency is nereoy gran~ed all po~ers necessary or :onvenient to effectuate its corpora~e pur~oses. inc l uding ~ut not 1 i ~ited tO• tne fo l lo•inq a t~ na~e perjeeual succession t~ sue ana oe sued in i ~s o~n name ell ed. or lo (c) to nave an official seal and po~er to alter that s~a l at. will d) to ~aintain an office at such place or places ~ithin the Oistr i c:t as it ~ay designate e) to adopt, amend and repeal ~ytaws, rules and regu l ations ~o carry out its purposes under this act fl to ~a~e and execute contracts and all other instruments for the perfor:nance of its cut.i.es under t.hi s ac:t fncluding ut not 1 imit.ed to, contracts or ~greemencs for tne servicing 3nd originating of mortgage loans g) to emo l oy acvisars, consultants. and agents e l uding. out not 1 imitad to. financial advisers ppr~isers. 3c:ountants and legal counsel, and to fi~ their o«tpensati ~n hi to o l lect reasonaole interestt faes and char~es in connec:i~n wit aKin9 and servicing its loans. not.est oondS• oo l igations ommit.~ents and ot~er evidences of in aeotadness. 3nd in connection with providing tecnnical. consu l tative and project assistance serv i ces i) to procure insurance or sel f-rnsure agains~ any Toss in connection with its oroperty and other assets• including ~ortgage loans, in such amounts and from sue~ insurers as it de~~s desiraole; 17 (jJ to oorrow money and to issue bonds• notes or otner evidences of inoeotedness and to give security tnerefor to enter into agreements ~itn tne United Stat~s or ~ny agency, jeoart:nent. instrumentality or political suodi~ision thereof. to orovide that interest on any bonas. notes or otMer evidences of indeotedness of the Agency will gt;e suo jec t to federal income taxes 1) to contract for and to receive contribut ions of :noney roperty, l ~bor or ot~er thin~s of walue from any source. to Ce used for tne pur~oses of this act and suo j~ct to t~e conjitions upon ~h i cn t~e contributions are made. Sucri contributions may include gt;ut are lOt l i:nited tO• g i fts or grants from any aapar~ment• agenc y or instrument3l ity of the United States or of t~e Qi strict m) to enter into agrae~e~ts ~itn any de partment• a~ency or in strumen~a l ity of tne Unite~ St3tas or ~ne Jistr i a nd w i e~ sponsors and mortgaga lenders f o r tne ur~ osa of olanning. rasu lating and ~rovid ing for tne financing and refi~anc i ng. construc~ion. raconst ruct i on or renaoi l itation. leasing. managemenc. m~int~nance. ooeration. acu isition. sale or o~ner aispositian of any hous ing pro j ect n ~ertaKen i t~ tne 3ssistance of tne Agency under t ~i s act; I l8 (n) to proceed ~ith foreclosure ac~ion. to take 3ssignments of leases and rentals. to acquire property in lieu of foreclosure o) to own, lease. clear. reconstruc renaoilitate. repair aintain anage, operate. assign. encumoer, sell or ~cnerwise dispose of any real or personal property i f (l) tne prooerty was ootained oy tne ~gency due tc tne oefault of any ool iga~ion held by the Agency; and {2) the ~gency•s actions. as orovided in this subsection• are in preparation for ~isposition of sucn properties p) to invest any funds no~ required for immediate scursement• including funds neld in reserve, in invest~ents; tne income derived from tne investment snal 1 oe deoos i ted ~s provided in section ~ll of this act q) to provide technical assistance to profit and nonprofit entities in the development or ooeration of nousing for lo~ and ~oderate income persons in accor~ance •itn saction 307 of this act; to gatner and distribute data and informa~ion concerning tne housing needs of lo• ana ~oderate income oersons within tne District r) to the extent per~itted under i ts contr~ct ~iin tne ~olaers of bonds. notes and otner obligations of ~ne Agency. to consent t~ any ~odifi:ation with resoect to r3t~ of in terest. ti~e and pay~ent of any insta l lment of pri~cipal 19 or interast. secur i ty or any other terTI of any contract ortgage, mort~age loan, mortgage loan commitment• or contract or agreement of any kind to whicn t~e ~gency is a s to sell. ac puol ic ar pri~ate sale, witn or witnout ouol i c oicaing. any ~ortgage or other 001 i;ation hel j oy the agency pursuant to regulations pro~ulgated by the ~gency t to ~aKe construction loans in keeo i ng ~itn the ouo l ic purposes af tnis ace; and (u to jO any act necessary or convenient to the xer i ~e of the po-.ers granted t&amp;gt;y or reasonao 1 y imp l i ed fr:lm t!"l is act 11 The agency mdy make. partici~ate in naking. and undertak~ commit~ents to make or parti~ioate in Tiaking Tiortqage loans to sponsors for tne financi,g of nousing Such housi~g projects must ~eet tne r~quirements of section 3C2(b) or 302 (c of tnis act 2) The ~gencv may make. oarticioat~ in ~aking. anc uncertake commicmen~s to make or part i i Jace in maki,g construct ion l:J.ans to sponsors for. cons~ruc.o:ion. l"'eccnstruct i Jn or ri:riao il itation of nousin iro J acts for 20 al igible persons. Such housing projects must meet the requirements of section 302(0) or 302(c) of tnis act o &amp;gt; 8 L112~SL m!l ll Cl l S.!ll-1U.S2 L A) With respect to eacn rental housing project• the soonsor snall sub~it a tenant selection clan -nicn nust oe reviawed and aoproved oy tne ency orior to tMe final commitment to assist tne project. The plan wust provide that a minimum of fifte@n percent (15 of tne units ~re initially rentea to low-income persons. I dd::l i i on. the plan ~use orovide For a Metero~eneous nixture of low. del"'ate and aoove inoaef"ate income persons to tne extent atr in tne discl"'ation of tne Agency. sucn 3 mixtul"'e is ~ade possiola oy tne availaoil ity of celo~ mdrKet financing and ren~al mar-e onditions. The Agency is not pronioited from financing a rantal housing project in ~nich all tenants ~r all units are e l i giola for one or more subsid i es nen the economic feasioil ity of tne nousinq pr~JeCt or conditions in tne rental market and in the o~nd ~ar~et orevent the Agency fro ee~ing it~ oojective of financing nousing servin~ a balanced mixcure of inco~e groups Bl itn respe&amp;lt;:c to al l ref'lt.al nousing ~r~je&amp;lt;:ts for wnicn tne Aqency nas ~rovid~d commitments for fina~cing jur i ng edc~ t~o-yedr perio the aggregate numoer C J 21 of un i ts rented to low-inc~me persons9 as ~rovided in the tenant selection plans aoproved by tne Agency9 must not oe less tnan twenty-five oercent (25%}• rhe first two-year ~eriod concludes at tne end of tMe Agency's second full fiscal year follo~ing the date of the lgency's first rental nousing loan commitment. tf tne Agency fails to meet the tAenty-five ~ercant (25 requirement for any given two-year period9 the ~gency. in its annual repor~ for t~e sacond year of t~e suojec~ period• must submit explanation and ~ocu~entation to justify its failure to neet tn i s requirement ithin sixty (60) days from tne ~ate tne :ounci 1 receives the annual report the C:ounc:i 1 by r~solution ay relieve the Agency of furt~er requ i rements aganc:y to finance a spacified ~umber of lo~-income renta l ~nits in addition to tne t~enty-five perc:en 2 5 req uirement for the succaedi~g t~o-year ceri~d. T~e reso l ution may not require a greater numoer ~f additional lo·-income rental :Jnits trian ould have gt;een sufficient to te-at t e :werity-fiye per::ent (25 raquire11ent for t:ie suoject per i od. In the event the Council ~oes not act by reso l ut i on ~itnin sixty (oO) days fr~m t~e data of recai~t of e annua l r~oort• t~e ~gency s~a ll be re l i2vea of any I i 22 f u rtner obl i;ation to ~eet the requirements of the suO JeCt (C) Eacn sponsor shall continue to rent to 10~-income persons no less tnan fifteen percent (15 of tne oroject•s total units: PROVIOEO• HO~EVER~ That this requirement shall not apoly ~hen subsidies available to the sconsor at the time of initial rental ~ra no l onger availaola. Imolementation of this provision does not require or sanction eviction of any tenant Soonsors sna l l not har;e i o i ncome rs~ns annual rent •hicn exceeds twenty-fi perc~nt (25 of annua l incone except ~here the ~gency makes a determ i nation t~at t~e lack of adequate suosid i es or otner Fina nc i a l considerations make fulfillment of tnis requirement unattainaole B) The annu.al income of oersons in i tia ll y selec~ed for re~tal of a unit not rented to lo"-income iersons sl"lal 1 not exceed six o) t i mes tne annual rent cnarge~ curing tne initial leasing period C nere feasiole pursuan~ to rules ~romu1;ated ~Y tne ~gency. t~e Agency snal 1 require tnat rents of nonsuosid i Zad units are afforaao l e to persons of ~o ~erate i ncome ~t rant l evels not econo ica l ly ouraenso me 23 in prooortion to t~eir incomes. The rules promulgated oy tne ~gency to implement such rent levels for nonsuosidize~ units snall take irtto 3ccount i the av a i 1 a o i 1 i t y o f ~ortgage finance race reductions for projects in •hicn s ue~ u n i ts are 1 o c: a t e d i i the c e cent age o f to ta 1 u n i ts i n sucn pro j ects ~nich is ranted to tenants of aoove noderate income and the rents cnarge~ sucn tenants; and (ii i relevant housing mar~et conditions including. jut not limite~ to. tha extent of demand for nonsuosidizea units i n rel a t i on to avai l ~o l e suooly of sue~ units. For t:ie Jurposes of tnis suooaragrapn~ tne t~r mortgage financ; rac~ r~duction~ means tne different i al Oetween prevai l ing Tiortgage intarest rates ano a lo~er rate wnicn is ~aid Oy a ~µonsor of a pro j ect for •nicn financing nas ceen ~ade avai l ac l a. dire~tly Oy ~he ~gency or tnrou9n a mortgage l end~r, from tne proceeds of a oona or oonds issued ov t~e J. genc y 3 sponsor nay not iai&amp;lt;e aistrioutions in :iny one year itM ras~ecc ~o a rental nousing pro j ect financed ~Y the ~ge~CY• in excess of eignt percent (8 of the sponsor•s equity i~ sucn housing project. Tne soonsor•s ecui t y i a project s~a11 consisc of t~e difference oet•ee n ie ort-;ac;e 1 oan and t~e total proje~t :ost as estaol i sned l ith respect to eacn homeownership project. the sponsor shall submit a buyer selection plan ~nich shall ce reviewed 3nj approved oy the 4gency ~rior to the final ~ommit~ent ta assist the project. The plan ~ust provide tna~ at least fifty percant (50 of the units are to oe initially set aside for sale to lo~ or moderat; income oersons. Ta t~e extent ~ade possiole by t~e availaoil ity of Del ow ~arket financing. nousing market conji tions. and tne Jrooortion of unrestricted units• the ~lan must orovide for 3 ne~ero~eneous mixture of lo~ and moderate incone persons. i ces of all units shall oe acceptable to tne ~gencv. { 2} The! sponsor sttal l sec the sale price of indivi:ual units so that total profit joes not excaed t~enty ~ercent (20 of total housing pro j ect costs as originally orojectej oy the sponsor and accepted oy t~e ~gency at tne tine of its co~mit~ent t~ assist tne project d 2 l.UtiQ The Agency ay invest in. purctiase ake commitments t~ purcnase. and take assignments from ~ortgage lenders of ~ortgage loans made for the financing of resiaent i a l ~ousing locaced in the Oistricc. E.x::ept for loans ~urc~asea under the Forward Commit~ent ~ortgage gt;u~c:iase ?ro;r3m, a :nort;age loan i s not e l i;i::ile for 25 ~urcnase or coTimitnent to purcnase by i~e Agency hereunder u~less t~e mortgage lender first certifies that the proceeds of sale or its equivalent ~ill be reinvested in Tiortgage loans or not~s in accordance with section 303(0) {1 of tnis act. The ~gency s~all provije. by contract or regu l ation or ~oth• aporopriat~ Tiethocs of enforce~ent of tne Tiortgage l encer•s o~l i gation to reinvest tne orocee~s of sa l e O or tq~L 29 2 L.3 l ith respect to the ourcnasa of l oans ot~er cnan und~r t~e For~arc Commitment ~ortga;e Purchasa ~rogram. t~e ~ge~cy s~al l raquire tne mortgage lender to re i nvest tne oroceecs as follo~s. including any comcination tnereof: {A) in ac:orjance wit~ the requiremen~s of section 302(0 of tnis act SI in ac:or iance •it 1 the re';luirements of section 302 C=l of this act C} i~ mort;age l oans for lo~ or ~oderate income o ~rsons .nere t~e housing units are or ara ta oe owner-oc::uo i ed. r he ~gency s nal l. tnrougn rulemak i ng. promul;ate proceaures neretl y i nousing orojects financed under su~car 3g raon or (S) acove are develope~ and operatec so as to comply wi tn t.h'e program requirements of sec~ion 302 or 30Z(C respectively; and i i loans made under suoparagraph c:&amp;gt cove are assured of complying witn the requirements of suoparagraon {C 2 ortgage loans purchased under tne For#ard :ommit:nen-t art.gage ?urcnase Program must oe made as follo s in accordance with the requirements of s~c~ion 3C2 of this act 6) in accordance witn tne reouirements of ,ct i on 302 c) of this act or {C) in ~ortgage loans to l ow or moderate i ncome persons where tne housing units are or are to oe owner-occuoiec 3) rne Agency snall reQuire tnat l oans ~ade in fu l f i l lmenc of tne r~invest~ent requiremen~s of sect i on 3 0 3 l) of t~ i s act are at i nterest rates wnicn insure that tMe oorrower ~ill oenefit to the ~axi~u~ extent feasible from tne ~elo arket interest cost of Agency bond and note proceeds used to purcnase mortgage loans from the l ender uncer sac~ion 303(a) of ~nis act. z. 7 Tne Agency snall purcnase nortgage loans at a ourcnase price not in excess of the unoaia principal balance olus ac:c:rued interest thereon. Sec. 304 2.2 S2-~tl9..2 a (a t!£ l.~U2 T:ie Agency may ,11a1&amp;lt;e loans to mortgage lenders pursuant to an agreement Oy t~e recipient to reinvest an amount aqual to or greater tnan tne proceeds in accoraance ~i:h tne provisions of section 304{0) of tnis act. C o l 2U E n 11 The Agency ~ill reouire tnat tMe racipient reinves"t t:ne proc:e~ds as follows• including any c:omoination tnereo f A) in ac:ordanc:e •it t:ie requ i r ernent s of section 302 of tnis act a J in accordance i th t~e requirements of sect io n 302 of this act C) in loans to individual lo or moaerate income persons for mortgage loans. wnere t,e housing units are or are to oe o~ner-o:cupied. The ~gency s~all, t~rougn rulemaxing. pr~mulgate proce~ures ri;eraoy i) nousing projects financed under suooar3gra~n or (S) aoove ar evelooed and ocerated so 28 as to comply ~itn the program requiremants of section 302(0 or 302(C respectivelyi and (ii) loans made under sub~aragrapn (C) acove are assured of complying witn the requ i rements of suoparagraon Z) The Agency shall require that loans ~ade in f u lfillment of t~e reinvestment requiraments of sect i on ~O~{ L) of tnis act• are at interest rates which insure that t ne oorro~er •ill oenefit. to tne maximum extant feas i ole. from the belo~ mar~et interest cost of t~e Agency ~and and note oroc~eds used to make the loans to or to Jrcnase tMe securities from the lender under section· 304{a) of t:i i s act. Sec. 305 g_aQ il 9.gr a lL l~il The Ag~ncy may establ i sh or ~dminister anv rent subsidy or nom@owners~ip ~ortgage interest suos i jy program to the extent t~at funds are ~ace availaole for that purpose oy tnis act or ~Y any other source wnere. oy reason of other income or payment by any department, agency or instru~entality of t~e United States ~r of the District. tne Agency nas ~eter~ined the pr~gram can u~ uti l ized without jeopardizing t~e economic staoi l i ty of hous i ng pro j ects be i ng f i nancad. 29 or aaminister a housing renaoil itation program for tne ;lUl";JOSe of pl'"OYiding foans to eligible persons for renaoi l i cation of residential nousrng. These loans sha 1 1 be secured to tne satisfaction of tne Agency. or administer a noITTe ourcnase assistance program from any excess monies 3enerated from the operation of tne ~gency. aporopr i ated fro~ any source. or other~ise mdde availao l a to assist crospective name ~urcnasers to ~eet co~n oayment requiram~nts f~r ootaining ~ortgage fina~c i ng for (C Q.l~.l.!2~ Tne ~gency may est30l ish or nay =ontract wic rivat r pu01ic groups ana organizations t~ Jrovide :ounse l ing orograms for lo• ana ~caerate income fa~i I ies .no may ~e ~articipating in ranta l ~r nomeo.nersn i~ asiistance activities. escaolisn anj ~ainta4n a s ecia l fund catl~a t:ie "11or1:qage loan guarante-e fund• into ti i ch shall oe 0200s i tea monies (l} as ~ay o~ 3ppropriat~d oy tne District f~r tne purpose of t:ie fund; ana (2) as t:ie A~ency det~r~ines co c~oosit onias i the ~or~;age loan guar3ntee func may oe us2c by \ I 30 tha ~gency to guarantee or insure ~ortgage loans according to criter i established ~Y- tne Agency. Sec 306. E 1-S LE lllls a) rhe ~gency shall ~ake rules and r~gulations governing al l au~norized activities including. but not limited tO• ttie fol l owing l) orocaduras for tne submission of req uests or tne in~itation of ~roposals for tne purcnase and sale of loans and the ~aking of loans 2) the nu~cer of 1~ell i ng units. l ocat i on of cn e units and ot~er characterist i cs of resident i al housing to oe nanced oy tne ~gency 3) rates. cnarges and other ter~s and conditions of originating or servic i ng loans. in order to protect against real iza~ion of an excessive f i nancial return or oenef i t oy t~e or i ginator or servicer 4) the rent leve l s and ttie sa l es ~rices. inc l ua i nq do~noayment requirements. and tna a l lo~ao l e ad j ust~ents in rent levels and sales pr i ces• of res i dentia l ~nits financad by the Agency, i n accordance ~itn ~ne program requirements of this ac S) t~e type and amounc of col lacera l or sec~ri~y to oe ~ro~ided by ~orro.ers to assura recayment of loans ua ae or ourcnase Y ~ne Agenc y 3t (o) tne tyoe of colla~eral ayment ~onds• perfor~~nce oonds. or ~ther security to oe prov i dea for construction l~ans 7) tne nature and amounts of fees to oe ctiargad oy the ~gency to provide for expenses and reserves o f t~e lgeric:y; and 9) anv otner mat~ers relatej to tn~ d u t i es or exercise of oo~ers under tnis ac b) The Agency's rules and regulations sna l 1 ~e consisten i tn tne following: {l) L.oans ;nade .for resie12nt i 3l housing may oe orepaid only wit~ tne consent of tne ~gency nicn may i mpose a penalty for prepayment. In tne case of nousi ng gt;roj~ts assisted oy the Agenc 1· refinancing sna il oe 3 l lo~ed oy the Agency on l y wnere refinanc i ng wi l l not 30rogate tne rignts of bone1nolders or ~otenolaers 3nd ~i 1 I ~ot c~ange tne matarial ourpose for ~n i cn the 'r~ j ect 40$ o r i ginal l y assisted 2) Preferen:e for assistanc~ ynaer tM i s ac~ snall oe given to e l igiole persons diso1aced as a result of ~gency 3ction. Such preference snail i~cluje inaiv i aual ot.ificacion and t.ne right. of first refusa l a reni: or ~urcnase t~e unit oreviously occucie~ J y e aisol3ceo ollsC. I 32 ~erson or a co~parable unit i n other housing ~rejects assisted ~Y the Agency 3) Specific loan terms for eacn program of assistance Shall oe adopted oy the Agency i~ its rules and regulations. pursuant to the provisions of tnis act A) Suen terms snall oe cons i stent ~ith tne ocject i ~e of maximizing the availaoil ity of housing opcortunities to l~w and moderate income persons. The 4qency sna1 1 insur~ that sucn terms ara properly ino l ementeo oy ~artici~at i ng mortgage l enders, and sna il prov i je and implement a ~r~cadure oy •nicn loan de~isions canoe ~ni~ored. reviewed. or appealed. {6 nere a mortgage lender makes rasidantial loans to l ow or moderate income persons ~itM funds received tnrougn ~or~ar~ Co~mit~ent ~ortgage ~urcnase ortgage ourcnase, security purchase and loan to l enoer programs under :nis ac the Agency s~a1l reauire t~at tne loans ara ~ade ~itn terms ~nicn ~eet conditions set ouc Oy !ne Agency. inc luding the f ol l ~wing i oan ter~s. criteria and re~uirements snall oe consistent witn the oojective of ~rov i aing ;raater oppor~~nit i es for nome own~rsnip for low ana ~oaerate income oers~ns to wno ort;age fina~ci n g nas qenera l ly not ~een availao l e tnrough pr i vate l anders; ana 33 i i hen the orojected ratio of month l y jayments t~ family income of a loan apol icant exceeds twenty- f ive ~ercent (2Si the mortgage lender shal 1 not 1isqual i fy tne loan application on that gt;asis alone tn the case of federal or District programs in ~nicn the Agencv may particioate• the ~rovisions of this act and 'gency rules snall aoply unless there is a conf li ct ~itn sucn a federa l or District program 5) The Agency sna11 reauire tnac oc:uoancy of al l nousinq f i nanc~d or otMer~ise assisted undar tn i s ac: oe ~pen to dl I ~ersons. and that such mortgag~rs. c~ntractors anc suocontractors engaged in the construc:ion. renaoil itation. sale or rental of such housing. snal 1 provi~e eaual opportunity for emoloy~ent i t~out jiscr i ~ination. in ~cc~r~anca with aool icaole District and federa l la s including, Out not 1 i111i ted co J.C. Law 2-a3. Al 1 c:&amp;gt;nt:r3ct.irig and ~rac~rament of tne ~gency and of housing f in3ncea or erwis~ assisted under tnis act. sr.a l 1 ~e i n accordance itn aoi: l i::aole Distric:t and federal laws incluaing. t)ut not l i~itej to• o Law 1-95. the inority Contracting ~ct of (a) Tne Agency ITTay ~roviae sponsors ~i technical assistance or loans for consultant services ~nich nay oe required in the organization• planning or operation of residential ~ousing projects for eligiole persons. The Agency may require tne soonsor to provide a jOrtion of the value of tecnnical assistance and consultant services in latc:i i ng fiJnds b) The Agency ~a1• in its discretion, convert a loan co a nonprofit soonsor. or any portion tnereof, co a nonool ig3~ory ;rant, or ~ay consiaar t~e v~l~e of tr.e loan s a aev~ l op~en~ cost suosumed i~ anv ~ort;age financin rov i ded t.o t.ne nonprof i c sponsor. Sec. 308. § l.S!!L.i!.£ f:2!!Ull a} Housing projects assisted by ~he ~gency or through tne auspices of th~ Agency under cne orovisions of t~is act shal 1 oe exe~pt From o.c. La~ 2-54. the "Rental ~ou ng ~ct of 1 77 bl Tne Agency sl"lall estaolisn Y rule~ak i ng rocedures for evic~ions and protections frow reta l iatory 3ct i on for tenants of r.ousing ~rojects eAempted from o.c Law 2-54. the ental Housing ~ct of 1?77 unoer suose~tion 303(a of tnis act. Sue~ procadures and procec~ions sna l 1 :ie i accord3nca i n t.:ie aoolicaole provisi ins of o.c. La 54 ne ental ~ousing ~ct of 1?77 r~lled Origi~~l 3 5 {cl The Agency snall estaol isn. by rule~aking. conditions and procedures for relocation assistance to tenants jisplacea from housing projects wnicn are exemoted from O.C. La~ 2-54. the •Rental ~ousing ~c~ of 1977 under s~ction 308{a) of this act. Such conditions and procedures snoll be in accordance with apol icacle provisions of o.c. La~ Z-54. the "Ran~al ~ousing Ac: of 1977 dl Eac~ o~ner of a rental accommodation suoject to t~e oravisions of tnis act snall fi1e. simultaneously #ith the ~gency and ~itn ~he ~ental Accommouations Jffice. dn axamption statement ~nic~ snall contain tne following inf ormation t) tne actual rent for eacn rental unit in tne ~ccommodation e services included and t~e facil i ties and c~arges therafor 2) tne nu,,cer of bedr-ooms in tne ren-cal ~c=o~moda~ion: and 3) a list of any outstanding ~io l ations of t~a rlousing ~egulations cf t~e Distric-c of Columoia (est~cl isneo and 3utnorizad ~Y Commissioner•s Or-der No. 55-1503• dated ~ugus~ ll• 1~55 3policaole to such accommodation a Tanants of housing orojects exemote~ oy tnis 3Ct from o.c. La~ 2-54. tne n~a l rlousing Act of 1~77 no x:eo~ f~r sue~ a~ema~ion ou l d oe al igi~le for rant 36 supplements under Tit l a III of o.c. Law 2-54. shall nave t~e same rignts to such suppJements as tenants residing in a ~roject suoject to o.c. La• 2-54 f) Prior to the execution of a laase or other rental agreement, a prospective t~nant of any unit shall receive notice in •riting ad~ising him or her that rent increases for tne ac=ommodation are not regulated oy the Rent Stael izacion Program of o.c. Law 2-54. tne ~Rent31 Housing ~c:t of 1977 TITLE IV FI~A~CIAL AFFAIRS OF THE AGE~CY The ~gency may r~ceive and soend gifts rants• aooropriations ond or ,ote proceeds. prooerty or other assistanca fro ny federal, District or priv~te source in ~rder to e~ercise the po~ers delegatad by th i s act. au~horize tne issuance of bonds and notes r other ool igat•ons (hereinafter ~bonds or notes for undertaKings authorized by this act. In addition. the ~gency may i ssue noces :o renew not:s and ~onas to pay notes~ including tne in terest there~n rolle~ c 01 4 I 37 oonds oy tne issuance of new oonjs. regardless of ~netner tne oonds to oe refunded have ~atured. rhe Agency may also issue oonds for 3 comoination of refund. rene~al ana financing programs au~nor~zed oy this act. provided otner~ise by tne ~gency. oonas and notes of tne ~gency are 001 igations payable solely from revenues cerived from t~e resoective or~jec~s which sucn ool igations are issued to finance. The ~gency may excressly provide 3djitional sacurity oy pledge or contriOution from any source in ac:ordance ~ith the Oistrict of :olumbia Self- Jvernrnent and Governmental ~eorganization Act (37 Stat. or cnarac~er. Oonds and notes of tne ~gency ~re ~egociaole instruments For all purposes of tne Uni for ommercial Code of t,e District of Columoia (77 St3 30; o oae. sec. 28:l-l0lr e~ seq suojec~ only to tne ~rovisions of tne conds and no~es for registration. agent of tne Agency is personally 1 iacle solely oecause a oon~ or note is issued. Sec 03. Ter for Sale of Bonos an o~~s 38 l a) g.fill Tne Agency 11ay stipulate 1y resolution tne terms for sale of its oonds and notes in accordance •itn tnis ac includin; the following l) tne date a oond or note oears 2) the oate a bond or note matures: PRJV!DEO• That no~es snall not ma~ure later cnan ten ~10) years from t:"ll date of original issuance and oonds sna l I not 11acure l ater tnan fifty (50) years from t:ie oate of original issuance 3 Met.Mer oonds are issued as serial bonds. as t.ef'm oonels• or as a i::omcination of tne t o 4 the c:eno:nination 5 tne interest ra"t.e ti ene r-egistration pri ileges 7) the iedium and met.nod for oe1vrnent; ano d) tne terms of redemotion 0) The A gene may s 2 l 1 its oonds or notes at ~uolic or oriva't.e sale ana may deter11ine t.:ie pric~ for sale c f t.ne resolution aucnorizing tne sale of ooncs or ,ates contains ~ny of t~e pro~isions 1 isted oel~w. the pr~visions ~ust also oe part of cne c~nt.ract #ith nolcers of cne ~onos or not~s. r~e ~rovisions i~ c~e resolution mav incluce t~e fol l o~ing l l"'o 1 ec Or i a o 39 (l) the custody, security• expenditure or ap~lic3tion of proceeds of tne sale of bonds or notes of tne Agency hereinafter "proceeds a pledge of tne proceeds to secure payment. and the rank or priority of the pledge. suoject to preexisting aqreemen~s ~ith holders of bonds or no c.es 2) a o l edge of revenue from projects of t.ne ~qency to secure payment and tne rank or pr i ority of t~e J l edge. suo j a&amp;lt;:t to preexisting agreements 1th holjers of oonds or notes 3) a cl edge of assets of t.ne .lgency. inc l ud i ng ~or~gages anc 00 1 igat.ions securing mort;ages. to seeure oayment• and t~e rank or priority of the plecge, s~oject to ore~xisting agreements witn nolders of conds or notes se of gross income from rnortg~ges O•ned Oy tne ~gency and pay~en~ on orincioal of mortgages ownea Oy the ~gancy 5 use of reserves or sinking f~n~s o use of proceeds from sale of Oonds or notes and a ~l~age of pr~ceeds t~ secure payment 7 li~itati~n of issuance of additional oonds o r notes, incl uding ter~s of issuance ana sec~ritY• ano t~e ref undi ng of outstanding or otMer oonds ~r no~es; 40 (3) procedure for amendment or aorogation of a contract w~t~ holders of bonds or notes. the amount of bonds or notas, the holders of which must consent to the amenjment• and tne manner in which consent may ce ~iven 9} vesting in a trustee property• power and duties nicn ~ay include the po~er and duties of a trustee aooointed Oy holders of oonds or notes uncer this act la&amp;gt; 1 imitation or acrogation of the rignt of nolders of conds or notes to appoint a trustee under tnis 3Ct; { 1 l defining the nature of default in tne Jl igations of tne Agency to the nolders of oonds or notes -3nd orovidin9 rignts and remedies of holders in cne event of jefault. includi~g tne rignt to apoointment of a receiver. in acc~rdance •itn tne general laws of t~e District and tnis l z) any otner provi~ions of 1 ike or different 3rac:er ~nicn affect t~e se~urity of holders of oonds or notes. oinding from the time it is nade. Any funds or property l adged ara suojact to t~e 1 ien of a ple~ge •itnout ohysical rne lien of a plertge is binding as against ~ar~ies ~aving any tort, con~ract or ot~er claim against t~e 41 1gency regardless of notice. Neitner tne resolution nor an~ otner instrumen~ creating a pledge need oe recoraed e) il,g 2§ The signature of any officer of tne Agency wnicn appears on a bond or note remains val ic if that uerson ceases to nold tnat office a) ± 1!2.tl The Agency ;nay s.acure bonds or notes oy trust indenture oetween the Agency and a corporate trustee wnich has tne ~ewer of a trust company ~itnin tne uistri:t b rus~ indenture of the Agency ~ay contain orovisions for protecting and enforcing tne riqncs and remedies cf holders of oonds or notes in acc~rdance with cne pr~visions of the resolution authorizing tne sale of gt;onds or notes. The lgency may treat expenses incurre~ i n carrying out a trust indenture as ooerating expenses. S.ac. 4·J s. Suoject to preexisting aqreements witn t~e holders of ~onds ?r notas. tne Agency may purchase its own ~onas or n~tes ~nicn nay tnen oe cancelled. The price canno~ exceeo che fo ll ing 1 imits l) if tne ooncs or notes are r~aeemao l e. t~e orice canno~ exceed tne rede~pti~n ~ri:e tnen aoc1 icaole olus accrued interest to t:ie next interest ~ayme n t; or 2) if t:ie oonds or notes are not: redee!1'1ao 1 e tne or ice cannot exceed tne rede~ption price app l icaole on tne first cate after tne purchase upon ~nicn tne oonds or notes become subject to redemotion plus accrued interest to tnat date. fhe ~gency may estaol isn special or reserve funds in furtnerance of its autnority under tMis act ot~itMstanding otMer orovisions of ~istrict 13~ ana SJOject to agre-e:nents •i th holders of oonas and notes. 4=:ie .A;enc:y snall ~anage its ow~ funds• and ~av inv~st fun~s not required for disoursement in a manner tne ~gency decer~ines oruaent. rr.e ~iscrict pledges to tne nolcars of any oonds or notes isiued under tnis act cnat tne District ~il l not limit or alt~r rignts vested in tne agency t~ fulfi 11 agreements ~ade wi~n tne "elders t~ereof• or in anyway imoair tne ri~nts ~na remedies of suc:n nolders unt i l cne oonas and notes, toget~er •itn tne interest tnereon. witn interest on any unJaia installrnen~s of inter~st, and all costs and ax~enses in :onnection ~i~n any acti~n or ~roc:~eoings ov or on benalf of sucn nolders are fullv ~et ana ~iscnar;ac. The 43 Agency is authorized to include this p1edge of the Oistrict in any agree~ent witn tha holders of bonds or notes. Jbl igations issuea under tne provisions of tnis act do not constitute an obligation of tne District. out are )ayaote solely fro~ tne revenues or assets of tne ~gency. EacM 001 igation issued under tnis 3Ct ~ust contain on its face a state~ent tnat tne ~gency is not ool igated to pay ~rinci~al or interest exceot from tne revenues or assets ~l~aged 3na tnat naitner the fa~cn and crejit nor tne taxing :Jo~er of tn~ District is pledge&amp;lt;j to the oaymen: of tne or i n c i o a I i n t er es t on an o gt; l i g at i on Sec. 409 2 S~.2i~il~L~s.2~~ll~nt rhe gt;onds and notes of tne Agency are I ega 1 i nvest:nents in ~nicn puclic officers ana oubl ic oodies of cne Oistr i =t• insurance co~panies and associations and oc~er parsons carry i ng on an insurance Ousiness. t&amp;gt;on11es gt;ankers. o.ani&amp;lt; i ng instit~tions including savings and loan assoc i atons. oui l a i ng and l oan associatons. trust comoani~s. savings oanks and savings 3ssociations. invest~en~ companies and otner ~er-sons carrying on a banking ousiness aa~inistrators. guarjians. executors. trustees. and otner f i duciar i es and otner cers~ns autnorized to invest in gt;ones \ olled Origi~~t 44 funds. includinq caoital. in tneir con~rol. rne bonds and notes are also securities ~nich legally ~ay oe deposited •ith and receive~ oy public officers and public oodies of tne ~istrict or ~ny agency of the Distr i ct for any purpose for •hicn cna deoosit of bonds or other obligations of the Jistrict is authorized oy law. Sec. 410. Qilll.i.£Lil j_Q a) Assets and income of tne Agency are exe~pt from Oistrict taxation. The Agency may maKe. at i~s discretion. jayment in 1 ieu of taxation b) aonds and notes issued ~Y t~e ~gency and tne interest t~ereon are exe~pt from District taxation exceot ~states• inherit3nce and gift taxes. Sec. 4 l l. Q!.9.~L~1 11~-i a) All monies of ~ne Agency. e~c~o~ as otner~ise autnorizgd i~ this act• snall ~e aeQ isitea as soon as oracticaola in -one or 11ore seoar a te ac iun~ s in financ ial institutions r~qulatea or insured oy a f~c2 r~l or Jis~rict agency. Monies in t:iese acc:Junts sti-3 1 l oe paid out on cnec signed oy the Executive Oirec~or or o~ner authorized officers or emoloyees of the Agency 0) No~•itnscanding tne provis i ons of t~ i s sec~ion• tne ~gency sna ll Mave oo•er to c~ntracc i tn t~e Moljers of its ~otes or oonds as to the custody. collec~ i on. se~~ring z i 45 i n vest~ent. 30d payment of any monies of tne ~genc y ~nd o f any mon i es Me 1d in trust or otner~ise for the payment o f notes or bonds onies neld in trust pursuant to a contract •ith no lcters of notes or bonds may ca secured in tne same manner as monies of tne Agency. TITL: Ii PU8LI: ACCOUNfAS!LITY All actions of t ne Agency snal l oe conju ctea in accorcance i t~ t e Oistric~ of Co l umoia Aam i n i strati~e Procedure ~Ct• as amendeo (32 S~at. 12:4; o Coae. sec. 1- 15 al et seq The 3oarj of Oirectors of tne Agency s~all i tnin s i xty cu l cays o f i ts first meeting. apcornt an advisory ooar~ of t~enty-five (25) persons ~nicn must include i ndivi ~uals i t n ax er i ~nee i :i el"!e areas of mortgage oanl&amp;lt; i ng. rea l estate• fi na nce. arc::i i tect u·e· federa l and District housin g ogra~s. construct i on and renaoil itation. consumer affa i rs ommuni~y organiza~ion. small ~usiness programs and :ommercia1 deve l oo~ene. The Advisory 3oarj nust include a nemoar f ro~ eac ar~ select~d Oy the ~cvisory Ne i snoornoo d o mm i s s i oner s. The 1av i sory Board snall ad v i s e t~e ~gen c y 46 •itM rgspect to t~e develooment of its rulas and regulations. its plans and programs and any otner ~4tters d~signated oy tn~ Soard. rne ~gency shall itnin ninety (90) days of tne end of eacn fiscal year. submit an annual report of its activities for cne preceding year to tne ~ayor. tne Council nd tne ~dvisory aoard. The report snall set fortn a complete operating financial statement of tne Agency ~uri~g tne Fiscal year it covers. its housing program ooerations 3nd 3cco~pl isnments. its plans for tne succeeding fiscal year 1d its recommendations for ne~de&amp;lt;l action on tne part of tne \ ~ayor or Council ith respect to tne purposes of the J.gency. rhe Agency shall contract at least one~ eacM year •itn an ind~pendent certifiad public accountant to audit tne oook~ an~ dccounts of the Agency. The Agency snall transmit the audit eo tne ~ayor and Council witnin ten (lJ) cays of receipt. TITLE 'II ~ISC2L~ANEOUS OV!SIO~S Libar3l C~nstruction J I The provisions of t~is act are to be 1 io~ral ly construed so as to effectuata thosa powers which are specifically enumerated f any saction, suosection. subdivision. parasraoh• sentance. clause. or provision of this act snall be unconsc i tutional or ineffective. in ~nola or in oart• to tne axtent tnat it is not unconstitutional or ineffec~ive it snail ~@val ia and effective• and no ot~er section. suosaction. suodivision. paragraoh, sentence. c l ause. or ~revision shall on account tnereof be de~meo inval ia or i nef feet i ve. This act s~all take effect as ~rovidec i, sect i on ~02(c Ll of the Oistrict of Columoia Se l F-Government ana :overn~en~al R~organiza~ion ~ct. t:oc..ur ic: Bill 2- 161 ­ u~ Ac Ju.lv 25, 1978 'fO!C:Z ·t 7 Adopted Unanin:ously (all present} -L I ce cn c 1 i 1 I lt v111c c c a c:n c•cc 1 r 1 L I 0 VC:&amp;lt z VC Z: i Septe~be 19, 1978 Ado~teti U'naci.mous l Sab s au c lt C t w..c C••CJI .a 1 a'P 1.,C amp C;9 r 1 r 0 c:r e N'o: Bill 2-16 1 OCi l 8 i97d u.J Sec:-e i L I sa veC. i ci i: Occ a SW c Ac ac ve Sec:c~J C L I a \ ve L I U.y s e Si s i Se a.:e a:sol~c e E e e:sc:l i e </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>101</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2701.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>102</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2701.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>201</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>202</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>203</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>204</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>205</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>206</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>207</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2702.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>301</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>302</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>303</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>304</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>305</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>306</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>307</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>308</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2703.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>401</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>401a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.01a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>402</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>403</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>404</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>405</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>406</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>407</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>408</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>409</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.09"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>410</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>411</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>413</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2704.13"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>501</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2705.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>502</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2705.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>503</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2705.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>504</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2705.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>601</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2706.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>602</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2706.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>603</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2706.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>604</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2706.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>605</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§42-2706.05"/>
  </section>
</document>
