<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-137">
  <num type="law">2-137</num>
  <heading type="short">Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-137.pdf">D.C. Law 2-137</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 5094</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-137, the “Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Rights and Dignity Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-108, which was referred to the Committee on Human Resources and Aging. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on September 19, 1978 and October 3, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on November 8, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-297 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> 2·136 I r or tlU5 ac I 60) daJ• I ll { LAWS OF THE OISTRtCT OF COlUMBIA jflZ2 u 2.tl7 D.C. t.Alf 2:137 IC!llTALLT IS'l'AJIDBI&amp;gt; crrxua OJ1iS tl-?UTIOllAL l.lc:B'rS AND OIGl'IITT AC'l l.978 Ill THE COUNCIL OP THE DISTRICT 01' COLOMBIA NOVEMBER 8, 1978 ?o secure constitutional rights to mentally retarded persons; to provide and define rights of procedural due p:ocess and rights to habilitation and care for such persons; to ass~re t be fullest normalization which is possible; and for other purposes. BE IT ENACTED BY 1'B1 COUNCIL OF THE DISTltICT OF COLOMBIA, That tbis act may be cit*&amp;lt as tbe "Mentally Retarded Citizens constitutional Rights and Dignity Ac: of 1978 See a) Columbia Tl LE I STA!l'EMENT 01' PORPOS2 AND DEFINITIONS 102. Statuient of Purpose. I t is tbe intent of the Council of the District of toi (lJ aeaure that mentally retarded persons shall have all tbe civil and legal rights enjoyed by all other citizens of the Dis t rict ot Colwabia and the Onited States 2) secure of each pe rson. who may be mentally retarded, r ega rdles s of ability to pay, such babilitation as will be suited to the needs of tbe person, and to assure that such habilitation is skillfully and hWDanely provided with full respect for the person's dignity and personal integrity and in a setting l ease restrictive of personal liberty 3) encourage and promote the development of t he ability ~nd potential of each mentally retarded person in t he Distr i ct to the fullese-poasible extent, no matter how severe his or her degree of disaoility1 (4) pra.ote the economic security, standard of l ivi ng and Meaningful eaploY11ent of mentally r•tarded pers ons S aximi:e the assimilation of mentally retarded pe rsons into the ordinary life of the cO!Olllunity in which they live; and (6) provide a JOechanism for the identification of persons with mental retardation at the earliest age poss i ble bl To accomplish these purposes, the Counci l of the District of Colwabia finds and declares that the des i qn and delive ry of care and habilitati on services for mental l y retarded persons shall be directed by the princi ples of normal i zat i on, and therefore: Ill community- based services and res i dent i al fac il itie$ that are l east restrictive to the personal liberty of the individual shall be establi shed for menta l ly retarded person at each stage of life development 2) the use or tnot l tutionalitat i on shall be a Da,ed o t he g~eatest extent poos 1ble; DISTR ICT OF C-:lUJMetA STAt\ITES Al j,.ARGE 3) vhene•e~ c-ire 1n ar. 1ns&amp;lt;;1~ut1 or •1u 1dential cil1ty 1s re~uired, it shall be in the l~ast re~ trictive :1et':ing d (4) i ndiYidual:I placed in institutions .ohall be transferred to com11unity or home enviroll.lllents whenever possible, c~as~stent vlth protessioaal diagnoses and recommendations. Sec. 103. D•!inHions. As u•ed in this act a dmiss ioo• mea.cs the voluntary entrance by an lnd!vic~a l vbo i s at lease moderately mentally retar~ed :n:o an J st1t~tion o~ resident1a acility bl •st l ease moderately mentally retarded• ceans a perso ho i s r~und, following a comprehensive etaluatl?n. to ~e i mpa i red lo adapt i ve behavior to a moderate, severe or profound degree and t unc tion1n1 a t tbe moderate, seve r e or prof ound lcteUec1.ual l eYel in accordance 1tltn s tandard mea3ure=ents as recorded i o the Hanual or TeMlinologv and Class trlcat ton ~n Ment~l 8etardat1on, 197 Amer ican Associat ion on ~enta..J. De ei-:1 ency cl "Chi er Program Director• means an individual with special training and experience in the diagnosis an and habilitatlon or mentalJ.y retarded persons, and who l s a Quali i ed Hental Retardat1on Progessional appointed ~r des1g~ated by ~he Director or a tacil i~y tor mentally retarded persona to provide or su~el"t"lse habilitation and care tor residents or the racil1ty d ooanitaent• means the placement in rac1l1ty, pursuant to a cu.•t order, or aa n&amp;lt;!l•idual vbo is at l eas t moderately mentally retarded at the request or the individual's parent or guardian vitbout. the consant ot the individu&amp;amp;l~ exc ep t it shall not include placement tor respite care e co unity-based .serYices• means non-resident i al s pec1a l1=ed or generic 3ervices ror the valuation, care and habilitation or menta lly r e tarded persons, ln a community ~etting, direc ted ~oward th intell~etual, 5oc1al. pe r5ona pnys l~l emot iona l or economic d evelopment or a mentally retarded per3on. Such s erv ices shal l include, but not ~e :i~ited to, diagon 13, e'laluation treatm e nt, day c are, tra intng, education sheltered employment, recreation, counsell~g o f the mentally r9tarded l)erso.n and h1s or her ramily, protectlvl! and other 5oc1a l and s oc 1o legal ~erYice intormatlon and ra(arra and transportat ion t o a ssure delivery or services t o persons or all ages who are mentally retarded comprehensive evaluation• means a study i nc luding a sequence or observat1ons and examinatl'ons or a person leading to conclusions and recommendations ton11ulated jointly, wi th d1ssent1ng opln1ons or any by a group or persons with opeclal training an experience ln the diagnosis and habilltation o~ mentally retarded pe rsons. the evaluation s hall Include, but no t be limited to, a phys ical examination, and educational and/ or voeat i ona l evalua tion, psychological evaluation, a social and r ecreational evaluatlon, and a s peech and he aring evaluat ion g council" means the Council or t ne Dis trict or Columbia h Cour t Cleans the Superior Court or tne Di s trict or Colu o: bla 1 Department o f numan Resourzes• means the Department or Human Resour es ot :he Dl st~ lct or Columb~a l I den ti al ctlve J. be possible tlon:s. an ed lt;'Ito an e a gt;erson .o be r profound round ·ement3: a~ ion 1n .tal with .nd a Qualified ed by :he to prov!de he raclli :y pursuant .erately parent or t it shall t!.al re and ni:y r~onal. a y t be li:oi ~ed 1 g, ni; or the ct!.v~ and d r-erer~al, per-$ons o luding a lea~ing to ·1 :h h .special Ion or ude, bu: not l and/or cla: and luation; of Colucibia; rict or l?artment oe I LAWS OF THE OISTRICT OF COlUMBlil 1982 {j Director• means the administrative hePd or a tacility, or community-based servioe and includes superintendents k District• means the District of Columbia government 1 education• me&amp;amp;lUI a systematic proc~ss or training, Instruction artd babllitatioa to facilitate the intellectual hysieal, social and emotional d••elopment or a mentally ~etarded oerson ml •facility• means a public or private residence, or pa thereat, which is licensed by the Dlst~lct as a skilled or inte,.mediate care facility or a community esidenua: r~cili:y (as defined in D.C. Regulation 74-15, as amended) and also includes and supervised group residence tor mental ly retarded pe.-sons under eighteen (18} years or age n habilitation• means the process by which a person is assisted to acquire and maintain those life skills which enable him O her to cope more ertectiYely with the deMands or his o her own person and or his tor her ovn enYironJ11ent and to raise tbe level ot his or her physical, intellectual, social, emotional and economic ett1clenoy. ffab1litat1on includes, but !s not limited to, the provision or oommunity-based services o informed consent• means consent voluntartlr given in writing with sufficient knowledge and comprehension f the subject matter involved to enable th• person giving consent to nake an understanding and enlightened decision, without any element or force, fraud, deceit, duress or other r.-om ot constraint or coet"'clon p least estricti•e .alternative• means that living and/or habitation arrangement vntch least inhibits an individual's independence and right to liberty. It shall include, but not be limited to, arrangements which move an larger to smaller facilities 3) larger to smaller living unitst (4) group to lndi•idual residenoes 5) segregated trom the commun!tr to integrated vith community living and programming; and/or 96) dependent to independent llv!ng q Mayor• meanll the Mayor of :he Oi:itrlct or Columbia Mental Reta.-dation Advocate• means the g~oup or advocated created purlluant to :iectlon 413 of this act ll} •mentally retarded" meanll a significantly llUb-average general intellectual level determined ln acco.-dance with standard measurementll ·u recorded in the Manual or Ter&amp;lt;0lnology and Classlr!cation in Mental Retardation, 19;3, American Association o Mental Deficiency, exillting concurrently with 1mpariment In adaptive behavior, which o.-1ginateo during the development period t normali:ation principal" meanll the principle aiding mentally retarded persons to obtain a lifestyle as close to normal as possible, making available to them pa:terns and conditions or every day lite which are as close as possible to the patterns or mainstream society u Qualified Mental Retardation Progressiona means a psychologist wlth at leallt a master's degree from an accredited p!'ogram and with specialized training or one (1) year or experience in ental retardation; or a phyllician licensed by the Commission on llcenllure to Practice the Hea!lng A.-ts to ?ractlce medicine in the Olstr!ct and with specialized training in mental etardatlon with one (1) year ot experience !n treating the mentally retarded; or an educa:or with a degr~e in education r~o 4JS DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 5TATl#TES AT 1.AAGE an accredi;ed pr~gram and with sp~~ialized training or one :ll year of experience in working wit~ mentally.retarded persons or a social worker w1tb (i) a master's degree from a school of social work accredited by th• Council on Social Work ~ducation (New York, New York and with specialized training in menta l retardation or with one (1 year of experience lo work ing wi•h mentally retarded persons; or (11) with a ~achelor degree om an ucdergraduata social work program acc,.edited ~Y tne Counc on Social \ irk Zducat1011 '4bO is currently worki·ng and continue• to work undar the SC?ervt~ion of a social worker as de~ined in :1 abo':e, and who has specialize&amp;lt;i tr-aining 1 i mental etar"a t m o~ one (1} yua~ of experience in working with mental:y retar-ded persons; or a reh?bil!tatlon couns&amp;amp;lor who l:s .o~rtH~ed ~y :ne Colll!Oi~sion on R~h~bill~atioo Counselor Certific~tlon Chicago Illinois od who bas specialized tra1ni~g in mental retar-~a~ion or one year or experience in working wi th mentally reta:-ded per$ons; or a physio&amp;amp;l or occupational therapist vith a bachelor degree from an aocredited program in physical or oooupatiocal tbere1py and who haa specialized training or- one 1 year- or experience in working with mentally retarded ?ersono; or a tberapeutlo recreation specialist who is a graduate of an accredited program and who has •peeialized tr-aining or one {1) year of experieoce in &amp;gt;:orking wi ~h mentally reta:-ded per•on v resident ans a person ;1.dmitted or eommttt-.d to a tacillty pursuant to title Ill O( this act for habil~tation servicesl (w reapitd care• means temporary overnight care prov~ded to a mentally retardeJ person in a hospital or :acillty, upon application or a parent, guardian or fami lr me~ber, ror the temporary relier of such parent, guardian &amp;lt;•r family member, who normally pro•ides tor the care of the person x) ft~e5pondene~ mean~ the pe~5on vho~e commi~ment or continued commitment i• being sought ln any proceedi~g under thi3 act y time out~ means tim~ out from po~it.ve r~i~forcement behavior ~od1fieat1on procedure in which, con~inge~t upon unde•ired behavior, the resident i removed from the •l~uation in which positive reinforcement I• available. Tl LE I! DETERKINATIOH OF THE NEED FOR MENTAL RETARDATION FACILITIES AND SERVICES IN the DISTRICT Sec. 201. Determination for the Need ror Mental Retardation Fac1lit1es and Services 1n the District. The Hayor shall determine and report to the Council within one (1) year- or the enactment or this act the cur~ent and projected needs in the Diotrict Cor racilltieo and oervlces ror mentally retarded peroon, giving due consideration to the Statement of Purpose as noted in section 102 or thi s act, and a timetable Cor establishing ouch Cacllltie• or ervlceo. the report 3hall be de•eloped with the a~~istance, a~ nece~~ary, rro= the Department or Human Resources, the District of Columola Developmental D1oab1l1ties Council, the Diotrict of Columbia State Health Coordinatlng Council, the Board o~ Edu~atlon or the District of Columbia, the Oepar-tment of Recreation, the Department of Housing and Community Development, the Department J6 one 1 l r:son:s; or l or llca:ion Hlltal og with ~ree rr'om :ou.nc 11 on lnues to l in 1) latlon or u·ded by the cage ardation tarded l or )r one 1 l sons; or an &amp;gt;ne 1 Jons; I to a 'ion &amp;gt;rovided upon the )et who or 1nder thh e:nent, a cuation 1'l :CT iardatlon witl'lin Id es ror- 1e 1.nd a le .ary. rrom 11:&amp;gt;ia obla n of the lart:oent Uw2·137 LAWS OF lllE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 1982 u 2.1::11 or transportation aDd the Department or General· Ser"vices. It shall be ~ased OD a deteMllinatiOll O( the projected incidence or mental retardation in tbe District, and on comprehensive evaluations conducted vith in eight (8) months or the enactment or tbis act or all residents in the facility tour the mentally retarded knovn as Forest Rave. lt shall also be ~ased on evaluativns or the needs or mentally retarded per•on who present themselves ror services within six (6) months or the enactment or this aet, by tbe D1r"eetor or such services. the report shal include, but not be limited to, an in-depth analysi• or the need for- and CO$t of infant st!mulation programs acil fes1 ork and program recreation programs ran3parta~ion serviees and ~c~er com:r:unity-based oervice• as set forth in subsection e or section 103 or this act tor mildly, moderately, oeverely and profoundly mentally retarded persons. TITt.E III ADH!SSION, COHMIT!f€NT, DISCHARGE, TRANSFER, RESPITE CARE SEC 301. No individual fourteen 1 years of age or older' who is Or' is believed to be mentally retarded shall ~e committed to a tac111ty if the 1nd1~idual is determined by the court to be committed to facility if tbe individual ls determined by the cour't to be competent to refuse such commitment. For purposes of this act, person fourteen (14) years of ago and older shall ~e proaumod competent to r.eruse commitment. See. 320 a) Aoy indi•idual fourteen 14·} years of age or older vbo ls, may be or' has been diagnosed mentally retarded may apply to a Director or a Cac111ty tor habilitation and care. the D1r'ector may admit the individual: PROVIDED, that the Director has determined that the individual is at least fourteen (14) year or age b) Wiihin three (3) days or the admission, t~e Director •hall not notify the court .or the adcisslon and snail cert~~y to the court that comprehensive evaluation shall be condue~ed and an Individual habilitation plan developed within ten (10) day• of the admission e) The court shall promptly appoint an approprlate officer to detel"llline wnetber the individual ls competent to admit himsel~ or herself to the facility and whether the admission I• voluntary. The determinatlon or competency shall consider, but not be limited to, an inquiry lnto the individual understanding of what hab111tat1on and care will provided in tne ~acillty and what alternative means of habilltatlon and care available ~ro~ community-based services.It the officer determines that there Is a substantial question regarding either the voluntariness or ~he admlssion or the competency or the 1nd1v1dual, the of~icer shall so advlse the court, and the court shall promptly conduct a hearing in accordance with the procedure• established in title IV of this act to resolve the issues of competency and/or voluntariness Ir the cour't determines that he adml•s!ons not voluntary, the court ~hall o~de~ that the individual be discharged rrom the facility f the court finds that the indlvidua! ls not 437 OIS"TT:IC'l OF COLUMBIA STA ruies AT 1..ARGE competent to admit him..selt or'horselt, it &amp;amp;ay order that person be discbargod t r 1~ dotol'!llines tbat dischar;o would be in the 111diTidual's best interest, O it may appoint a guardian ac em to represent. tho ina.i•idual in a subsequent hearing to be he:d promptly to detoMlline tho appropriate placement, Lr any, ot the individual. the 1nd1Tidual may remain in the facility unt!l the court bearing unlos~ tho court decides that nis would not ~e ~n the indi•1dual' s C~$t. interest. Soc. 303. Any indi•!dual ~our~oen (14) years ot age or olde r who 1 may b" or as been diagnosed mentally retarded :Day app:y to any hospital, clinic or t'acili ty, or otr.er communiey-l&amp;gt;ased serTice owned or ~perated by r under contr~ct with, the District ror out-patient nonresidential ha~llit3tion. Applications shall t~ mad~ to the Director or the hospital, clinic, facility or servine, or to tho Depart:Dent r llu:Dan Resources. It an application is f1led with a Director and the Director dotorwlnes that th• part1cular hospital, clinic, facility or commW11ty-~ased service cannot ?rovld~ the necessary h&amp;amp;bilitat1on, he er she shall retar the individual to the Department ot RWllan Resources, and the Department o: Human Resources shall assist the indi•idual 1n locating a ~acillty, hospital, clinic or service which can provide t~e necessary hab1l1tatio11. See. 304. A w-1tten petition by a pareat or guar1ian may be tiled with the coui•t to have an individual ourteen 14) year• or age or older, who 1s or 1s belioTed to be mentally retarded, co1111itted to a racility. Upon the tiling or such petition, tne oourt shall promptly conduct a hearing in accordance with :he procedures set rorth in title IV or th1s act. It the court daterm1nes that tho individual is competent to r efuse such commitment and tho indivldual so refuses, the court shall dismiss t~e pet1tion and order that he !nd!vtdual not be comm~tted to a facility. It the court determines that th~ individual 1s not competen: to refuse commitment, the court shall determine whetner to order the commitment the court shall o~der tho commitment on~y i~ lt determi11es beyond a reasona~le doubt that a) based on a comprehensive evaluation or the Individual per!oM11ed within six (6) months prior to the hearing the individual i s at least moderately mentally retarded and require hab 1l 1ta ti on b) commitment to a facility is necessary in order ~or in the individual to receive the habil1tation indicated by the indi•ldual habil1tat1on plan required and detlned under section 403 or th 1:s act cl the racility to which commitment is sought, Its ~pon3orlng agency, or the Department or Human Re~ource s capable or providing the required habilitation: and (d) commitment to that facility would be the lease restrictive means or providing the habilitation. tne ~acility, It a sponsoring agency, or the Department or Human Resources shall provide a written certification to t~e court, before commitment to the raclllty s ordered hat ~he habilitatlon plan will be lmplemented 38 ttiat pers on be ln the rd1an ad item to be he ld any, ot the ity untU tie ld not be l n r age or old1tr ded may appl y nity-based h e os p1 tal, r llWDan .tor and :he ;linic 1 ~he nece5~ary .r Hum-an faclll ty, aeCf ary 'ar ·H an may ~It 1 1 yearo ot retarded, oetit lon, the 'e wl th t he :he court i-Se ~uch shall ~lsmios z:un i ed to a r.ot competent ethe~ to Or'der ent onl y 1t it 1odlvldua l tg, t.he i and require )rde r o r- 1n •d y :he snder ~ection s l!"C t L~ l Lea.Se ar:ment or Lon o the :l a the 1.Al'IS OF TME DISTRICT OF C'JL.llll01A. 1982 Sec. 305 ny parent or guardian mar app: y on behal f of an lodi d~al under f ourt een (T years ot age ~ho i s or i s oe lieved to be ntally retarded to any hospital. clinic, tacil i :y or co1111unity-based service ovned or op&amp;amp;rated by, or unde r contrac: with, the Olstriot ror aoa-residantal babll i tat lor App:ications sha ll be made to the Director or the gt;opit1 l clinic, or s•r• l c o~ to the Department o f ffwaa.n sour~~s. I t an applict.tion h riled vi :b a Di r ector and tbe· Dl ~ec gt;r dete~:oines :hat tbe partlcular hospital, clinic, r 1lity o~ coi:m.unity ~ased service c&amp;amp;nnot provide the nec essary habllitation e or she shall re ter the parent or guardian to :he Depart:oent or H"man ~e•ources and the Depar tment or Human Resources •hall ass :st t~e parent or guardian in locating a tacillty spital, c!in!c or servloe which can provide the r equired habilita tion. Sec. 306. A parent or guardian may ri le a wri~:en petition vith tte court to have an individua l under fourt een (1 4} yea or age vho l s or l s beli eved to b• mentally r etarded co=ml :ted to a rac!llty. the cour t s ha ll proeptly conduct a hearing ln accordance vltb the procedures set torth la tltle rv ot this ac t to de teMl1ne whether tbe court shall or d&amp;amp;r tbe coOIA itment. the court shall order such co 1taent only lt 1t d eter:ln~ beyond a reasonable doubt tha t1 (el based on a comprehens ive evaluatlon of t he lnd1v1dual pertoruaed vithin s ix (6) months prier to the bear i ng the !ndlv1dual i s at least moderate ly mentally retar ded and requires h• bill tatioa b) commitment to a fac ility is a&amp;amp;cesoary lD orde r ror tbe 1nd1T1dual to receive the habllitatlon 1ndlcated by the lndiYidual h&amp;amp;bilitatlon pl an requ1~ed under sect!on 403 o! tbls act c) tbe facility to vbich comaitment t s s ought, Its s ponsor l ng agency or the Oepart.men t or llu111an Resource l s capable ot providing t he required habilltat ion; and { d) commitment to tha: faci li ty would e the least res trlctlve means o! prov iding the hab!litation. the taclllty, its sponsoring a gency, or the Departme~t or Human Resources shall pr ovide a written s tatement o :he court, before commitment to th• facility ls ordered, t hat the habillta tion plan wlll be i mplemented. Sec. 307. Any individual rourteen (lq) yearo o f age or older who l s adaitted to a ~aclllty s hal.l have the right to i mmediate discbarge from t he tacl l lty upon vri t:en request t o the 'l~ector of the facil ity. Sec. 308 esidents committed purs uant to section JD~ or .section 306 of thls act llall be dlscharged tr the parent or guardian who petitioned ror tho comml!ment reque~t3 the r eo1dent r elease in writing to the court and t he court determines, ba~ed on con3ulta~1on wi~h the resldent, his ne~ couns el and the re•ident' s mental retardat1on advo~ate, i one ba.s been appoint e d, that t he r"e~ident consent-:s to 3uch relea.se. Such reoidents also s hall be dl .scharged upon the i r own que•t when they have ga i="ed cocape~ence t o m:ake .such a d ec1.s ion and have reached the l r tourteentn IUtl\e oirthday hearing z ay be conducted pursuan~ to provi s ions of title ~V of t~l act to de t erslne the que5tlon or competence J9 OJS&amp;lt;Rt::T Oi COlUMSIA STATVTES Jct 1.AR'IE s ec 309. {al the Di rec tor or a t'ac111ty Y recom::ie nd tb..i court thllt a rcs1deut co-1tted to the fac 111ty 'oe orans.'arl"ed to another r:.c111•y l t' the :Hrec t or deter min,.s that it vould b• benet'icial and c &amp;gt;nshtent vi t h t he h.a b I li ta~ ion leed3 ot' tbe r eside nt to do s o. Notice or t h• r eccmmenda lon s hal e s o ed on the re:1dent, the r esident' s counsel, the es ident 's parsn t or g-~ard1ar. who 9etHicned r r th com: it:oen t ~no ~h e sideat s mental retardat i on ad·;o·:a r. e i t one t1.s b11t appo inted tr t he propose1 rans~dr 1s de t en11ined b e cour~ to be a trans t'er to a core P~strietlve rac! l lty, a manda:orr h•ar iog shall be conduct ed pro:nptl in accordar.ct wt :h :he pro~edures es tablis hed 1n tttl~ Ii ot' the l r act. If e ccur: de t er nes that the proposed tran~rer w• u: d be a l e e nrtcti raaU!~y court hearing sn"ll be he ld only 1f :h6 r e:s lden t or hU or her parent O guardia r; r equests a ng ~y pet i t i oni ns tbe court 1D writing withi j t en (10) days ~r be ing n~t1tied by t h• court ot lta determi nation th~ hearing shall be h• l d promptly following t h• r equest t or t~e hearing. In decid ~ng vh ther to .lut~or ze ie tr ns t er the cc-Jr t s ha ll oor de r whe ther the proposed tactlity call p!"oYide the ne~essary habllitatlan &amp;amp;nd vhe tner it vould be :he l ease restr!:t~ve mean• ot p!"o•iding such habilitation Due cons ideration shal• be i've n t o tbe re l at ions hi p ot t he r esiden t to hls or h er ramily guardian or t'rl end :so as to mainta i n rela~1cnsh1ps ar.d e ncourage v 1s lts b•ne t iai1l t o t he rel a tionship b r esident admitted to a r acillty can be t,.ansferr ed to another raoill ty it' t he r eside nt consent to the t r a11:1 re r c Wotbing in this section s ha l l b• cons trued tu prohibit transfer or a r es ident to a health care t'aeillty without prior court approval in an em•r gency s lt~atlon when ~he tl te or the r es i dent Is i n danger. I n :1uch c i r cums t anc es consent o f the resident or parent or ·guardian who s ought the com.mi tment 5hall be obtained prior to he transfer n the eve nt :he res ldent cannot con~ent and the r e 13 o ?e r-son ho c an ~e rea3 onab 1 contacted, such t f"an:sfl may be made upon t.'h.e au~hor i zat on r t !le Director or the ~acll1ty, with notice prompt ly g iven to the pa.r e nt. o r guard lan Sec 31 0. the Direc t or s hal l d 1s ohar ge any realdent admitted to OOOllllited pur.5 uant t o this ti t l e if In the Judgment or the Chie f ProgTam Director, t he r esults o r a comprehensi ve e•al~ation which s ha ll be pe rt'ormed at l eas annually Indica te tha t residential care l s no longer advisable. If the r es ident, the resident parent or g·uard1an, the res 1dent counsel, or t he menta l re t a rdation advocate objects to the di s charge, he or she may f ile a pe t1tion with the cour t r equesting a bearing tn accor danc e with t he procedures se t ~orth ln title I V or thi• a ct. the r esident shall not be di s charged prior to the hear ing. Sec. 31 1. Ho mentally r e t a rded pers on who r es ides ln the Dl.:1trict s ha ll be deni ed habili t a tion 1n faci liti es or from communtty- bas ed !ervice~ o vnttd or operate d by, or unde~ cont~act With, the 015trlct beeauae or 1nabll1ty tO pa y f or 5UCh habll1 tat Ion. Sec. 3 12 Not mentally reta rded pers on shall be comml:ted to a ~ae ll!ty under this act prior to the court hea,.lng r equired unde~ thl t le 440 mend to nes that Uon needs shall l&amp;gt;e !dent's d the :ie cour atory t he e ccurt y If th6 arlng by r oeing g shall be n dec ~ding id er 1ve means l be given 'I' encourage ferred t:&amp;gt; proh1l&amp;gt;it t prior or t.he or ttle nt sh.a!l ident. bly .t ion f he tne I t adOli tted the i ndicate ·es ident, el or t he e or he i n this hearing. In t he f~oro cont~ac t om ed t o qu :re&amp;lt L.AWS OF THE OISTRIC! OF COLUMBIA 1982 Sec. 313. A d"ter::inat1on by the court under t h! s tle that i~dividual tourtaen 14) years ot age or older is in~·Jmpetent to refuse commitment :shall not be relevant to a determ \ nation f the bdi idual's competency vith _respect to other matter~ not considered by the court.Sec. 314 a) the Oepartme~t or Human socrees shall promulgate Illes and ~egulations go~erning the pr?v1$ion respite care ~or mentally retarded persons. these 3nal! prov!de the period~ or ~e~p!te care shall -not exceed rorty wo 2) days i.1 a twelve (12 month period wtthout s;:ieei:I authorization by the court after a hearing conducted in ace~rdanee with tltle IV or th1s act b) Should any person be detained for resp i te care :er a ~e~iod exe~eding forty-two (42) days in a twelve (1 2 month pe~iod without speeir1e authorization by the court ar~er hearing conducted in a::oordance with the t1tle IV, he or she shal~ be rromptly discharged. TITtE IV HEARING ~NO REVIEW PROCEODRES See 01. Proceedings tor the commitment or a.n individual pursuant to title III of this act shall be commenced by tne filing ot a written petition with the court in the manner and rorm presc~ibed by the court. the petition may be tiled by a parent or guardian with respect. to an individual who t s or l s believed to be mentally retarded. tr f1led by the parent or guard1an, a copy or the petition shall be served on the ~espondent and on his or her eounsel1 retained or appointed pursu&amp;amp;At to section 402 of this act See 402. Individuals whose admission to a raeility under section 302 or this act has been questioned on grounds or their competency or the voluntariness ot the admission, have the right to be represented by counsel, retained or appointed by the court, in any procee~ing held before the court in acco~dance wi th see:~on 302(c or this act, and they sha~l be informed by the oourt of this r!ght. Respondents shall be represented by counse l ln any ?receeding ~erore the court, and shall be so informed by the court. tr an Individual whose admission i s questioned requests the appointment ot counsel or tr a respondent rails or refuses to obtain counsel, tho court shall appoint counsel to represent the indlv1dual or ~espondent. Whenever possible, counsel snal l be appointed who has had experience in the mental retardation area. Counsel appo!nted to represent respondents, and counsel appointed to represent Individuals Whose admiss!on has been questioned but two are unable to pay for such counsel, shall be awarded compensation ~Y the court for his or her services In an amount determined by the court to be ratr and reasonable. Sec 03 a) If a petition filed in accordance with section 40 1 ts not accompanied by a comprehensive evaluation report based on an evaluation which has been perr~rmed within six (5) months Prior to the hearing and an Individual habilitation plan which has been prepared thin thirty (30) days or the f ling or the petition he eourt 'hal l cuaediately order that a com~rehen3ive ~valuation ~e conducted and an indlv!dual habilitation plan be wrl en CISTRICT OF GOl.UMBIA STAJ\!TU AT LARGE (b l A 11ritten r e port sett ing rortb the r esul :s o( the cou-prehens i n e ~aluation and a copy o the hal&amp;gt; i li :1t Lon plan s!lall be sut&amp;gt;isitteo to tb• court the report shall ~ndicate &amp;lt l i whether or to what degree the I ndividual or respobdent 1• mentally retarded1 (2) what habilitatlon Is needed; and J l the record or hab111ta..t1on and care Ir any cl the individual nabllltation plan s11al: be .deve loped by the ~ame prrso o.:s wt conduct tbe compre bens i ve evaluat i on exee where t he cc-mpre~ensive eva!uation has been perron:~c gt;y ;iersc &amp;lt;&amp;gt; not geog·raph lcal l y accessible to the Dls t r !ot worlc i ng jo i l t r ~Ith t he pe~s~n who l s the s ubject or the pla n, and such persco par~nt or gu.~rd ~an who pe titioned ror t he mm i tmen I:'l case 1bere tne co,.preheos l ve evalaatlon bas been per~ormed by perso»" not geogra i l'l.ally accessibl e to the Di s tr i ct the cour t s ha ll de~ig1'at e t be appropri at e and protess io!Ul~ l7 quailtl pe rson t o develop the plllJl. the pl an •ball conta in t he rol l c 1ng 1) a statement or tbe nature o f t~e specl~ l c trengtl:s limi ta tions &amp;amp;nd s pecir lc need oi' t he per t Jn vho i s ubject to ~he plan 2) a descriptlon or lnteMlledlate and long-range habilitatlon goals with a projected time table ror ~he i r z.tta1nmgnt; Ol a statement ot, and an explanatlo" ror, the plan habilltatior. designed to achieve these lntermedlate and long• r-ange goals II a stat e•ent or the objective cri t e r l a, and an evaluation proc edure and schedule for deteM11!ni ng wnether the goals ar e be ing achieved 5) a stat ement or the l east res trictive set~ lng ror habi l l t a t ion necessa17 t o achieve the hablll tatlon goal s: and 6) cri t eri a ror r el ell!le t o l ess r as t r lct l ve sett i ng~ f or habllltat loo and 11-r lng, I nc ludi ng c r l t eda f gt;r d: s cha rge a a pr o j ec t ed date o r discharge H commi tment s r t!com.,ended y tht gt;lan d) A copy or t he rt!port and t he pl a.n sha ll be provi ded t o t be l nd l vldual or r eopondent and his o r her counsel a nd to he parent or guardlan 1r the petition was rl l ed undt! rsection JO~ or section 306 or this act, at l eas t ten 10 days pr i or to the hearing. t r the petition was accompanied by a cO$prehensive eYaluation and ·plan, copi es or the r eport and pl an shal l be proYided to t he respondent and his or he r counse l wlthln there (3) dayo or the r iling or the petition. Sec. 3oq, Responde nts and the ir counsel shal l be informed ~Y the court or the rlght to have an i ndependen t comprehensive evaluation and habll ltation plan developed and, t r unable to pay ror it, a~ p~oved t o the sat1~r1cat1on or t h e c ourt t o ~ave .sue~ eva luation conduc ted an plan deve loped a t t he e xpense or t~e Oi.s t r lct. See QOS The hearl:'lg In co ltment proceed ~ngs s ha ll be conducted prompt ly a ft er r iling ot the pet! tlon Sec. 406. Mear l ngs oha ll be conducted l n as t nrorma l a =anner as may be c on 3 3tent w1th order l y grooedur Indlv 1dua 3 ~ho3e ada ~o5 ton ha3 been que~t l on e d o~ r t5 ponCen he plan ?ate gt;r lY oped iy ln except r per,,on j o b!ly :i p e r-~on to &amp;lt a 3 e f gt;e rsons t "hall ~enon to wbo L• ngf! he ;il an o f Long- d an er tbe i ng f or anti. settings cba,.ge and nded y vid ed o d ~o the on 30~ or o he nsive l be n thert! nrormed by .slve 0 Le t o pay ave 3UOh .r e 1all be tal a sondent.s 1.AWS OF TltE DISTRICT OF COLVMSIA 198? Llw 2-137 have the r i ght to preaent during hearing and t o :est Hy but s~all not be co&amp;amp;pelled t a t est i ry, alld shall be s o adTlsed by t he court. Tboty shall h;ne the d gtlt to call vitnesse:s and present evidencg, and to cross-exa.aine appo,,log witnes,,e:s. The presence or the respondent aay be waiTed onl y it the court finds tha t t he respondent bas ~nowingly and voluntarily waived hi or her lght :o be pre:sent, or if the court dete1"121ine:s that .the responden t i s unable to be present by virtue o r hi s or her physlcal ly h~nd!capping condit ion. Secti on. UQ7. tr t he peti tion was filed pursuant t o sec: i on 30~ or th! s act, t h• parent or guardian or or her cou~~el i r s o re preseot ?d, shall present evidence wh!ch s hows beyond a reuonable doubt. tttat he respondent s noc ccmy:e t ent t o r e r•Jse co1111 1. t men t Sec OS Hearlngs s hall be clo"ed to the public unless the !llentally retarded person o r hi s o r her coun.oel, reques t s that a heari 03 be open t o tbe public. Sec. UQ9 a Qpon compl etion or the hearin1, the court shall order that a res ponden t shall net ~e committed to a fac ility 1r the court finds that 1) the respondent i s not at least modera t e ly mental ly r-etarded; or (2) a respondent fourteen (14) years of age or older i s cc!Dpetent to re.ruse co- 1tment b) Only If tbe cur t detel"'lllines that the conditions se t f orth in section 304 sec t ion 306 are satisfied shal l l t order comaitment to a rac ll ity consistent with the comprehens ive e•a l uat lon and i nd t l dual habllltation plan or t he me nt ally retarded person c) t r t he court deten1ines t ha t respondent should not be comm i tt~ to a tacil1ty, the court may orde~ tha t ~he r espondent undergo such nonresidential habil!tat ~on and care as may ie appropria~e a.nd neces3~ry, or lt ~ay o~de~ no habilttat~on and c ar e d) Por persons whose ad!Di ssion to racilit!es has ~een questioned under section 302, the court shall ent e r an appropriate order as set f or t h under that sect ion. Sec. 410 Any c ommi t ment order of the court may be appea l ed in a like manner as other clvll actions. Sec. 411 a Any dec ision or the court ordering conmlt!Dent or a mentally retarded person to a rac i lity shall be rev iewed n a court hearing every s l x (6) months tor two (2) years and once a year thereaf t er. t he men t al ly retarded l ndlv \dual •hall be diseharsed unless there 1• a f ind ing or t he rollowlr.g1 (1) t he cour t det ermines t ha t t he menta l ly retarded lndi vidual has bener lted f ros the hablli ta t!on; a nd 2 the rac1l1 t y, I ts sponso r lng agency or the Depa~tment o r Human Resources demo n3trates that cont i ~ued r es ident i al ba bllltatlcn l s necessary ~or the habl lltat lon progra11 b f a mentaily r e t a rded l nd lvidual l s discharged I n accordance with t he provis i ons or section ~ll a l abov~ bu t 2·117 OISTRlc;f OF COLUMBIA STATV'ra ,1H a GE coati.lUU o e• 1denc e the need tor hab1l 1 v.~1on and care, t shail ~e th~ responslbllity ot the Depal"tm•nt f Human Aesour~es to arr age tor u1tabl~ services ror the ~er4on. Sec 12. Cost and expenses or all proceedings held under ;his act shall be paid as ~ollovst :1 o "XP.Jr t w i nesses designated by ~hl ~ourt and amount d~t~Mlli~ad by the court to attc:-11e y appointed under this aot rees a~ aut:;odzed under the Criminal Ju~tice Act (O.C. Code, s~c l 2SCI c to ot her vi ~ness, the same fees and ~tle~g r~r attend,.nce at co.:rt tc be paid upon the appr&amp;gt;Va or t he cvurt. Sec 13 a entally r e tarde&amp;lt person.s i.o .zdml t t he,.s e lv"s to a :actl1ty 1:.nder section 302 of tll.l s a ct, and me a~ly r etarded persons vhose co..Ut:oents sough~ unde r sec~ion ~1q or section 306 of tll.is ~ot, sh~ have the a ss i s tance o a ~e~tal retardation advocate in proceeding end at tage ln such ?roceedi ng:s •1nde1 this act J pon recaipt of tbe petition fo r comm!tment or not1r1cation r admission as provided in :section 302 s ection 30~ and •ection 306 o f t his act, the court s hall appoint a qual!r! ed mental re:ardation advocate selected rrom a lis or such advoc~tes Lt maintains c) H~ntal retar1at1oa advocates shal l l'!a e the f ol owing povers an~ duties 1) to lnfOMI persons subj ect to the ~rocedure~ set rorth in this ac~ of their r1ghts1 (2 to consul t vitb the person, his or her ~amily and ether concerned vlth his or ber habilitation and well- be ing to ens ure by all means, Including ca se referra: to l egal services, agencie:s and other practic ing lawyer, that the per son i s affor ded a ll rigbt:s under the l aw; and ij) to guide and a s s !st the pe r son ls such a manner as to e neou ra&amp;amp;e Ael r ellanc~ ond e nable t~e e r 3on to pa r ticipa t e to h~ gr~at~3 t ex t e nt po~3 lble l o dec13ion3 concerning hl o~ her habilltation pl an and the services to be provide d unde r thi :s plan d the menta l r etardation advocate shall rec e ive notice and shall have the r i ght to participate in a ll meet ings conrerences or other pr~cee~1ngo relating to any matter af rect l ng provis ion ot services to the person includlng, but not limi ted to comprehenolve ova luatlon, hab1litat1on plan, petition and hearing• t or comm i tment and ror periodic review or t he commitment e the mental retardation advocate s hall have acceso to all ~ecords eport3 and docu.ments artect1ng h!3 or her client t the mental r etardation advocate s hal l have access a ll personnel and racillties r~pons!ble ror providing are or servioe:s to hl s or her client and shall be pe rmit t ed to v tot~ and cammun! e a t e wi th hia or her c l i en t l n pr ivate, and at any reasonab l e time wi"hout prior no t ice: PROVIDED, That he or she shows ~easonable cause ror V~3 l t!ng a t tlmes o t her than vt 3 l~i~g hours g the men t al retardation advocate shall be a person wit~ rain ing and exper i ence In the ie ld or »enta l r etarcat lon sou.rues under a.mouot t orized ·or- vurt amp; or 1en.t.al 111 ;ion 30~ 1allfl" d owing set 'ly and lng rral to t the :inner- a.s ccipate il 3 or &amp;gt;der h t!ee and e,.enee:5 ovteion d e s to all nt. eee to e or v1 3 1t. and y or she •11 e l ti og on "Ith n u 2-137 L.AW!i OF THE DISTRICT OF COW MBIA 111§2 u Z-ll1 h Advocates shall be provided directly by the oour~ or by a contract vith indiTidual s or organi:atioos including local ass ociations tor consUAers of mental retardat ion services however the court shall ensure that the cootracts and ot~er arrangements ror se l ection and provision or adTOcates provi de that each mental retardation advocate -shall be i ndependent of any public or private agency which provides services to persons subject to this act Io the selection, training and deve lopme nt or the advocacy provision o f t l'lh section, the curt shall ex plo a nd •eek out pot nt!al s ources or rundlng at the rede~a! and Dlstr!ct l evele j) Advocates shal l be provided with rac!llt l es, s uppl i es and secretarial and the support se rv1e s urr!e! ent to enabh tbem to carry out the i r dut i es under :his act k) All o° unica t ioo be t ween ad• oca t es and :be lr cli ents sh~ rema1a cooCident i a l ;uid pr 1• 1leged as a i t ~etween a:tor ney and cl1..at 1 tl'le court sha ll promulgate such rul a.m~ li fying and clarifying this section as it deems necessary ml Mental.ly retarded pe r sons subjec t to thi s act may knowingly r e j ect the ser-•1aes or a mental retardation advocate and shall be so advised by tl'le court. Advocates vbose ser vices have been rejected by the mentally retar-ded person shall not have the r i ghts set torth in subsect ions (e d e t and (J) or tllh section, TITL! V RIORTS OP MENTALLY RETARDED PERSONS See. 501 a All mentally r e t a rded per•ons have r i ght o habllltat!oo and 1Uare su tt"d to tl'le ir needs egardless o r age, deg r ee o~ retar;lat lon or handicapping condition b) Each r "s!dent bas a lght to a ha bllitatlon pr-osram vhicb vlll maxim hi s or her ~UAan abiliti es enhance hi s or her ability to cope vl tb h!s or her envi r oru11.,nt and c reate a r easonable opportunity t or progress toward t he goal o r indap ndent community living Sec. 502. Residents s hall be provided vith th" least r estrictive and most noneai living condition• possible. This standard shall apply eo dr ss, grooming, movement, use o r rree time, and contact and communication wi th the collllllunL t y, including access to services outside or the 1ns tltutlon or r es idential racili ty. Res idents sl'lall be taught s~!l ls that he lp them l"arn how to errect !vely ut!li~e the i r- env !rooment and how to make choices nece ary ror dally living. s e. 503. Res idents Shall ha•e a right to the l eas t re3t r ictive condlt 1on3 nec essary to achieve the puroo~es o r hab!lltat ion. To t bi• end, the ln• t i tutloo or r es ldent!a l racility shall move r s!dents from a } mo to l ess st~uctured l!v!ng {bl l arger to smaller rac!llt s o} large r to •maller l!vlng units d) group to I ndividual r e•idenc e~r-ega~ed to i ntegrated com.m.unlty llvingi or { r de~endent to ~ndepe" dent 44S DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA STl&amp;lt;TVTI:S AT LARGE l1v1ng. I at any time, t!oe Director decide~ that res ident should be trdnsterred out or tho facility to a le:s res:r1c:ive enviroiu:eot, he or she shall ill!Jlledtately notify the court pursuant to section 309 ot this act. Notice shall ~e provi~ec ~he e~ident. the rasident•s eoun~el. the ~e~iden men~al retardation advocate, it one has been apoointec, ar.j :neir ~esident'3 parent or guard who pet1~i0ned ~or cocm e See. 50 a) All e!Sidents eoll!Jlli~.ted pursua:!t to this ac s'iall have ecei ed prior tc their com i t1r:ont ?Ursu;.nt :o sec 403, and annually thereafter, a comprehensive eva a:ion al'&amp;lt;l a individual hab1l1tation plan. Residents admitted ~o a :acil!ty s~all h~ve, W&amp;lt;thin ten {iO dnys ot the admiosion nd a~nual. th~rea!ter, a comprehensive evaluation and an inc~v~jual habilitation plan b} Within ten O} days or admission or comm.tment prcressionals ~r staff m•~bers responsible ro~ impl~:nen:i or O'l'ersedng th• implementa·,ion or t ·he residen 1 indi vidua! hab1litation plsn shall be designated by the faci)1ty, it sponsoring agency, or the Department ot Human Resvurces ach District or other agency or serv ice responsible ror providing h.abilitation indicated by the plan shall also be designated Within ten (10) days, and implementation Of the plan Shall be within ten (10) days. the plan shall specify the role and objectives with respect to the plan of all ucb agencies or services e) All resideots shall receive habilitatlon and Care consistent with the hab1litat1on plan. ttie Department or Hu:nan Resources shall set standards for habilitation and care provide~ to such residents, oonsistent with standards set by the Accreditat ion Council tor Services tor the Mentally Retarded ao&amp;lt; other Developmentally Disabled Persons, including s:att-~eside ~1 and progessional-res1dent ratios. In the lnterests or contlnui ot care, one qualified mental retardation protessi~nal shall oe responsible tor informing the Chier Program Director, or the Director, when the resident should be r eleased to a l ess restrictive ·satting and tor continually reviewing the plan. Sec. 505 a) Subject to restrictions by a physician for good cause, each resident has the ~ight to receive vis1tor' or his or her own choosing daily. Hours during which visitors may be received shall be limited only in the interest or errectlve treatment and rea3onable errtc i ency or the facility, and ~hal~ b sutt1eiently flexible to aceomodate the individual ~eeds o r the resident and his or her visitors. Notwithstanding the above, each resident has the right to receive visits trom hi• or her attorney, physician, psychologist, clergyman, social worke parents or guardians. or mental ~eta~dation advocate i~ pr1vate at any reasonable time, irrespective or visiting hours, provide~ the visitor snows reasonable cause for visiting at times other than nor~al visiting hours b) Writing material and postage stamps shall be reasonabiy available for the ~esident'3 u3e in wrlting letter and the communications. Reasonable assistance shall be provided for ~riting, addre~~ing and posting lette~s and other doc~ments upon ~equest. the ~esident 3hall have the right ~o sent and rece~ ve dent lctlve ided to tal nt act section and an ~illty nnua y 1 or Each ding the ed .1 begin Ld or ·e Human 1rovided •ded and ·esident &amp;gt;nt~nu1 ty 'a:l be ~he 1n. l ror rs of )rs may !Ct! V&amp;amp hall tie or ~he gt;ove, r her &amp;lt;er, private provided other a•onably he or nt.s upon ece1 ve LAWS OF' Tl!E DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 1 uw2·137 Sbaled and uncensored mail. the resident has the r-!ght to reasooable private access to telephones and, in case of pe~sonal aaergencies wben other means or communication are not satisfactory, be or she shall· be afforded reasona~le use of long distance calh A resiclent Who is unable to pay :shall be furnish such writing, postage and telephone tanilities w1:hout eharse c) Eacb resident shall have the right to tollov or absta!n from the practice or religion. the facility shall provide appropriate assistance in thi:s connection inclucling rea:sona~le accomodations tor religious workshop and/or transpor~ation ~o nearby religious services. Residents who do not ~tsh to P•riicipate in religious practice shall be ~ree rrom pressu~e to do so or to accept religious beliefs d ach resident shall nave the right to a humane sychological and physical environment. Ke or she snall be provided a comrortable bed and adequate changes or linen and r-easonable storage space, including locked space, or his or ner personal posses:s1ons. A record shall be kept or each resident's personal possess1on:s. Except when curtailed for r-ea:son or :safety or therapy as documented in his or her reoord by a phy:sician, he or she shall ~e afforded reasonable privacy in bis sleeping and personal hygiene practices e) Each resiclent shall have reasonable dally opportunities ~or physical exercise and outdoor exercise and shall have reasonable acoess to recreational areas and equipment f) Each resident has the right to a nourishing, well- balanoed, Taried and appetizing diet, and where order-ed ·by a physician and/or nutritionist, to a special diet g) Eaoh resident shall ha•e the right to prompt and adequate medical attention tor any physical ailment:s and shall r-eoeive a complete physical examination upon admission ancl at lea:st once a year thereafter h) All residents have a right to be ~ree ~rom unnecessary or excessive medication. No medication shall be administered unless at the written or ver~al o•der of a :icensed physician oted promptly in the patient's medical recor-d and signed by the phy:stcian within twenty-four (24)hours. Medication shall be administered only by a licensed physician, registered nurse or licensed practical nur:se, or by a medical or nursing student under the direct supervision of licensed physician or registered nurse, or by a Director acting upon a licen:sed physician's instruet1ons. the attending physician shall review on a regular basis the drug regiaen of each resident under his or her care. All prescriptions tor psychotropic medication:s·:shall be written with te ination date, which shall not exc~ed thirty (30 days edication shall not be used as a punishment, tor the convenience or starr, a:s a substitute ror programs or in quantities that interfere with the resident's habilltation program. Sec. 506. No psychosurgery, convulsive therapy, experimental treatment or benavior modit1cations program Involving adversive stimuli or deprivation of rights ~et ~or-th in title V of this ac shall ~e administered to any re:sldent. Sec. 507. tr, in a medical emergency, it ls the Judgment oC one licensed physician vlth the concurring judgment or another licensed physician that delay 1n obtaining coose~t for surgery I.ow 2·137 DISTRICT CF COLUMe•A ST:,ll{JTeS AT L.ARG~ would create a ga·.s 1 al'ger to the t- ea h or t!le r-~s i den nsenUal :nrge ur b4 ado.ini3t el"'9d 1 t hout the consent of th~ reai dent r t b• ne essn 1ntorma•ion i s pr~v1d~d to the r esident amp; parent guard i an spouse or nezt o r kin to enable sue~ person to g1 Ye informed, knowing and inte llige nt consen~ a nd sue: consent i s gi•en pr ior to the s urg i cal procedur e n t he ~vent tha t there 11' no person vho can be r-~asonl\t:y conta::ed, 3uch surgery ~y be pe r f ormed upon the au"hori:ation o! t he ch1e medica l orrioe r or the r~cility. Seo. 5C3 o reos idene or a rae1ltty shaJ e s t er l :ed y any empl oyee or a fac ili ty or by ac1 oeber person ao t ~ng he di r ection o or under tbe author iza~ion or, the D i rec~or or an y other employe or a 111ty Se c 09 Res i de:lts s hall have a r ight n t to le s ub,!eo :ed t.&amp;lt;o e xper1.ment.a.l e.aear-c h without the irp re:i:i a nd 1 ntor:ied con3ent o tbe r esident, or l~ tbe r~sident c&amp;amp;nnot g l v~ i nformed consen t, ot tbe resident 's parent o~ suardian Sucb pruprsed resea.rch ~ha~l f irst ha•e been r e•teJed and approve~ by the Oe~artment or Human Resources b~tore ~uch consen t shall be s ou:ht. Prior t o s uch approval, the Depa r t ment shal l det ermi ne that such research complies with th• princ1plas o f the ot a t ement on the u e or hu~~n subj ects t or research ot the American Ass oci at i on on Mental Deticiency ~nd wi t h the principles for r esearch involving human subjects req~ired bv the United Sta t es Department or Health, Education and We l fare :or projects s uppor t ed b that agency. Sec. 510 a M i s~reatment neglect or abus e in any r orm of Y resident sba l l be prohibited. The rout1n~ use or a ll f orms ot res traint shall be elimi nated Physica l or chemica l e tra i nt s ha ll be •m~loyed onl y whe n absolutely nec essary to prevent a r esident rrem seriously injuring hi mself or hersel f or others Restraint ha ll not be employed as a puni s hment or the con•eni eoce of ~tarr or as a subs titute t or program In any event, res t raint" ma y only be appl i ed l a l ternative t eehn!que s hav~ geen attempted and ~ailed such rai:ure eo ~e docu~ented i~ the r es i dent reco rd) and only lf such ~estraints i mpo,.ed the leas t po ssi r estriction cons istent with t heir ?Urpo,,es. Each facility s hall have a wri tten policy defi ning (1) the use o r res era 1nt 3 t he proCess lonal~ vho may author l %e 3ueh u~e ar.d 3} the mechanism tor monitoring and controlling such use b) Only professi ona l s des ignated by the O!rector ma y orde r t he use o f res t ra!nts. Such orde r s s ha ll be in wrltlng and shall not be in fo r c e tor o•er t we l ve (12) hours A r es iden t plac ed in res traint s hall be checked at l east e very t hi rty (301 m !nu~es by s t a tr tra i n ed i n tbe ase or r estraints and a written record or s uch checks s ha l l be kept c) Hechan1cal re traints s nall be des igned t or minimum d iscomfor t and used s o as not t o cause physical in j ury to tne r es ident. Opportunity t or motion and exe rc i se s hall be provide or a period or not l e s s t han ten (10} minutes during eac wo (Z) hour" in which r estraint 1 employe d d) Se clus ion, defined as the placement or a resident alone In a locked r~om, s ha ll no t be employed Legit!mate time out• procedure~ may ~e ut11L:ed under clo3e 4 nd dlrec t pro(e~~l ona! 3upe rv 13 1on a3 a technique 1n behav1or 3hap l ng p r o1ram3 Each rac111ty ~ha!l have a wr it ten pol icy regar~lng ~t tme-out~ pt"ocedure:s of the le such .nd such ent uch. ef :d l::y e O any ieted to 1sent of 'ent, or hall Human $UC!\ :h &amp;gt hum.an •l human l t :y rorm or forms estraint :it a the~s any nique=t nted 1n d the Each of u'e, and y order :nd shall &amp;gt;laced 1n iutes by &amp;gt;rd of :mum the )rov ide :h two it alone ~e out gt;ional a ch 1.A\'IS OF TliE 0:5TR&amp;gt;CT OF COLUMBIA 191!:f e) Alleged instaLces or mistreatment, neglect or abuse or any reaidant shall be reported immediately to the Director ~nd ~he Di~ector shall iator-m the resident's coun~el, parent or guardian who petitioe~d tor the commi~ent and the re1ldent's mental ret3rdat ion ad ocate or any such instances here 'hall be a written report that the allegation has been thor~ughJy an romptly investigated (with the findings stated· therein Employees ot ~acilities who report such instances of mistreatment, neg!ect or abuse shall not be subjected :o adverse act ion by the facility because or the report.(f)A resident couns£l, parent or guardian who petitioned for co11UDi~ment and a ~esident•s mental retardation advocate shall be noti! ied in writing whenever restraints are used and whenever an instance o! mistreatment, neglect or abuse occurs. Sac. 511 a) No resident shall be compelled to pertorm l abor wbich involYes the operaoion, support or maintenance or the facility or tor which the facility is under contract with an outsi~e organization. Privileges or release from the !acility shall not be conditional upon the perfor111ance o~ such labor. The Mayor shall promulgate rules and regulations governing compensation or resldents who volunteer to perform such labor, which rules and regulations shall be consistent with U.S. Department of Labor regulations governing employment of ~atient workers in boapitals and institutions at subminimum wages b) A rest.dent may be required to perform. hab111tative tasks which do not iqvolve tbe operation, support or maintenance of the :acility if tbose tasks are an integrated part of the resident's habilitation plan and superYised by a qualified mental retardation professional designated by the Director. {c) A resident may be required to perfor111 tasks or a housekeeping nature for his or her own person only. Sec 512. Complete records tor each resident shall be ~aintained and shall be readily available to professional persons and to the starr workers who are directlv involved ~1th ~he particular resldent and to the Department or Kuman Resources without divulging the identity of the resident. All infor-mation contained in a resident's records shall be considered privileged and con!ident1al. The resident's parent or guardian who petitioned (or the commitment, the resident's counsel, the resident's mental retardation advocate and any person properly authorized in writing by the resident, 1! such resident is capable or giving such authorization, shall be permitted access to tne resident's records. These records shall Include statu.s; to: {1) identification data, including ~he resident's legal (2) the resident's history, including but not 11~1ted (A} .family data, educational bacl&amp;lt;grounC: and employment ~ecord Bl prior medical history, both physical and mental, including prlor institutlonalization 3) the resident's grievances, tf any 4) an inventory or the resident's li~e s1&amp;lt;i:ls 5) a record or each physical examination whic~ Cesc~ibe$ the re~ult~ o( the ~xamination; 449 OISTR'CT Or CC~UMBIA ST-'T.JTeS AT 0.Al&amp;gt;GE 6) a copy or the indi~idual habil'.tation gt;!ar ar.d mod1t'1ct.t1on• therei:o and ac ppropr ate uuary wh!ch wil l gu a.nd a~sist the prore~31onc.l and stat: uplcyee• 1n icplement·~r. the resident prograta 7) the rinding• made in periodic reviews or the habilltaticn plan which ~1ndings shall include an analy•i• or 'ueces~ and failure of the hab111t~tion pr~bram and ~hall r~ vhatever modif!cation3 are necessary 8) a me,ieation history and stzt~s 9) a summ~ry of •ach •ignificant contact ~Y a professional ?er~on •i:h a si~ent 10) a summary of the re!:ide e5?0n!te t; hi ­ program, prepa ed ai1d recot at least mon ly gt;y he professional per•on 1esignated pursuant to :ec:!on 50ij t~ superv1.1e the resident's rehabilltat!on 11} a monthly summary or the extent and nature o re•iden work activities and the e:reet or such activity upor the resident's progress along the habllitati~n plan 12) a signed order by a pro!esslona: person. as set rorth ln ~eotlon 510(b) or thi.s act, for any physical restrait&amp;gt;f (13) a description of any extraordinary inci~ent or accident in the !ac1lity involving the resldent; to be ente~ed a starr member noting personal knowledge of :he incident or accident or other source or lnformat1on, including any repor investigations ot resident•s mistreatment 14) a •ummary or f;uiily visits and contact 15) a summary of attendance and leave• rrom the raeility; and (16) a record or any seizures, Illnesses, treatments thereor, and im.munizatlons. Sec. 513 a} Any ioterested party ha!l l'lave tl'le l"ight t.t· initiate an action ln the court to compel tl'le ~lghts afforded mentally retarded per•ons under thl act b) Any re•ldents •l'lall have the rlgh~ to a civil reoedy an amount ~ot les han twen~y-~lve collars 25) pe~ day r~co the Director or the ~1st~lct or Colu~bia. separately o jointly tor each day !n which said r~sident at a facility is no: provie a program adequate ro habl!itation and moralization pursuant t the resident's indiv!dual habilitation plan c) Sovereign im.munlty shall not bar an act ion under thl ection d) The good faith belief that a hab1lltation program was proressionally Indicated shall be a derense to an aetlon unde~ subsection (b) or this section, despite the prog~am apparent lnerrectlveness. In such circumstances the nabilltatlon progr&amp;lt; shall be modiried to. one appropriate tor the residen ithln fi 5) days or a court's decision that the program is inappro?riate e) Reasonable atto~ney•s rees and cour~ costs shal l be available ror ac~ions brought under th13 ~ect ton. See. 514 a) No person shall be deprived of any clvil right, or puDlic or private employment, solely by reason or his or her having received 3ervicest vo luntar i ly or involuntari:y, ror menta l ~etardation b) Any pe~son ~ho has be~n ad~i~ted er co~mitted to a facility under the provisions or thl• act retains a rights not speclrlcally denied hlm or her ~nder th i s act, inc!udl~g r ght a; and any viU guide amen ting the s l s o! the 1 d1r~c s or her c) to ot the ?tty upon a~ s et restraint ent. or entered gt;y nt or eport.s or a t :zient s r 1gl\t t o ,rrorded a:e dy t n day ~roe Jr jo 1n:ly, 1ot provided 1u.rsuant to ~gram WIU ion und e r apparent c.~on program w1:hLn five approprla te gt;a ll be c1v son o r his untarlly d o a r ght not ng r lg ts 2·1J7 \.AWS OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA 9112 7.1 37 of hap~~s eorpu c toy persoo vbo yiolates or abuses any r gnts or ~ri•l~•ges protecte&amp;lt;j by this act shall be l l ao l e tor dam.ages a~ deteMlined by l av, for court costs and for reasonable attorney s fees. Any person who acts in good faith compliance with the p~ovisions of this act shall be immune from c ivil or criminal liability tor actions lo connection with eva~uation, admission commitment, habllitative programming, educat ion or di s charge or a re3 ide~t. Rowe•er this ectlcn ~ha!l not re eve any pera on rrom loabil!ty or acts or negligence misfeasance, n¢nfea sance or maltea~at\ce T:TLE VI MISCEL~ANEOUS PROVISIONS; EFFECTIVE DATE Sec. 601. The respoa:!l1ble party must be provided with notice and a reasonable opportunity f or a hearing before increased tlnanicd r e:!lponsibility, resul ting r~o.m a change In the oourt s comm.i tment ord•r may be charged for the support or a me ntaJ.ly r et.artled person. Sec. 602 Should any pro•is 1on of this act be declared o be unconstitutional or beyond the s tatutory ~uthority Qf the Council, the remaining provisions or this act shall ~emain in errect. Sec. 603. There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such District funds as may be necessary to implement the provisions of this act, including funds tor th• development, and the support, o r co unlt7-based services f or mentally retarded persons Sec. 60Q a The act •ntltled "An Act to e~act Part III ot the D 1str1ct or Columbia Code, ent1 tled Dec eden t s states and Fiduc Rolatlons, cod i fy i ng tl\e general and permanent laws relating to decedent:!I estates and t1duciary relations i n the District o: Columbia approved September 1U 1965 (79 Stat. 766; O.C ode sec. 21- 1101 et 2!!1 l 1-'l amended a.o rol!ows 1) The following sections are hereby repea~ed sec. 21 110~ tllrough a.nd including .sec. 21 1108A sec. 21 111 1ec 2 1-1116 tllrough and includtng .sec. 21-11 18 lee. 1120 through and 1nclad1ng sec. 21- 1123 2 O.C. Code sea, 2 1- 111q 1:1 he reby a~ended a3 rollows: delete •substantially retarded within the meaning or th chapter Insert •at l east moderately mentally retarded as defined in the Mentally Retarded Citizens Constitutional Right:&amp;gt; and Dignity 4c t delete •and direct a sui table orrlcer under this chapter Insert •and di rect the child's parent or a guardian appointed by the court to file a petit ion under that act 3) D.C. Code sec 21 1115( a J l s her.,by amended as follows: del ete •substantially retarded v itl\1n the mea ning o C thl .s chapte r insert •at l east modera t ely mentally retarded a.s de! lned In the Mentally Retarded Citizens Con.stltutional Rights and Dignity Act delete "peti t!on be rtled purs uant to thi.s chapter Insert "parent or guardian appoin t ed by the court riie a Petition under that act D.C. Code oec. 21-11 lS( c 1.s hereby amended a s follows de lete •substantially retarded n~er at lea t moderately mentally retarde d 5) D.C. Code, sec 21-1101 Is hereby amended by del etLng rrom ubstantlally r etarded• to the end of that •51 t w 7-137 sect on. Dls IUCT OF CC v'M81A Si A TIJTES Ai' L.AAGE b) The follovtng j&amp;amp;Ct~cos o the aot entitled n Act ~ro;1de for COlllll l~11ents tO, maintenance ln, and d ischarges f~ th• 01str1et Treinin~ School, and tor other ,urposes approv Hareb 3, 1925 3 .ltat 1135: D.C. Code s 32·601 S ar~ hereby repeal ed: section 2, 3 and q (D.C. Code, see. 32 through and inclu:!ing 32'-0:05 See. 605. Nothln~ htreic ~hair be constructed to e xte nd dimi nish the authorH~ or r e pons lbillty of the D.C. 9oar o Eduec t.1on ves t.e J ur:sua.nt to title 3 \ or the O!.st r !ct or Code and appllca~le fe, e ra\ 3ws and re~ulationa. Sec. 606. Th i s act shall tak~ effect pursuant to the pro~tsiuns or section 6r2 ll o f the Dl s t~Lct o! Columb Se~-Govern:en~ and Cove~nme~tal Reorgan i ~atia~ le op~ov Decnber 2 1973 \ 87 St~t. 8 1Q D.C. Code sec. 1- 1u7 e With respect to p~rsons who a~e res idents in racili t l es on the errective date or tht ct, t~e provlolons or the act wtll tak etrect l 111mejiat ely, vltb t he e~c•ptlon or the ~dmJ so ions and coL'lliblen t beal'1ng p.-ocedur"3 e:stabl1:sbed In t t ~les I: a nd IV The court shall ~egin bearings UDder titles III and rv to rev i the co1111itment ot :such persons and •ball appoln t appropriate ot!1ce rs to ~evi&amp;amp;w the admi~~ion or ~uch per~on, as ~oon a~ po s:s i~l e but not l ater tbllll one hundred e ighty 180 days a the ~ttect1v~ date or t~1~ act. All court hear n to revie~ admi~:sion or commltment or persons res iding !n ractlitle:s on etrecti ve date or tbh act :shall be compj.e t ed wi ~hie. t hree 3 1 years Of the er1'eot1Ve a ate or th! S •act Illa f ua ac o S.c:t.J.aa c of t.be 0Ut.r1« oC Coli-.Di t•lt ta• Act Ul• CO\l'\C il ct u Ola t.rin O! Col ad.cpt d I t ao. 1-1~1~ o.n !lr• t •rid .t•C'Ol'd r ad l."llf Se;ic I 1111 r Qcmoe r J, Lt t r P1:t L1.,1e l y. rollO lft(f t t t ot 'tll ror a.a :t r 1 lt7 1. u u l~ Ls1 4 t&amp;amp;o1' Wi 9t:i.-d .\ct "°• 2-111. pWUa b.ed 10 tb C.c-•r 1'71 d&amp;amp;t.i.o" ot Ut• D.C l•t.•C Vol. 23 P 30t4 J tnd t.f'•n.9.J.t.i:.S t..o :on!J r 01t J t"T 11 U'19 Dr lCl•Uy r YL lA •ccor• ac 1. t-1'1 sensoa CO:l t ctll 1 ot U \c:r fl• ComcLl ot t.b• ot ac1'1C:t ~t Colii•ll b• C f 9iv ftOt:Lc u ac Ull• 10-day Cofl91'H l.cU'l• l h -rtod qi i red. an4 U t fote cSt U tollC.Vlt!I; l91J l.JIJ.&amp;amp;t-lO D.C 1• Ll7 lt;S2</search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>102</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1301.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>103</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1301.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>201</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1302.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>301</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>302</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>303</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>304</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>305</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>306</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>307</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>308</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>309</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.09"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>310</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>311</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>312</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.12"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>312a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.12a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>313</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.13"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>314</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1303.14"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>401</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>402</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>403</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>404</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>405</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>406</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>406a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.06a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>407</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>408</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>409</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.09"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>410</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>411</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>412</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.12"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>413</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1304.13"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>501</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>502</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>503</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>504</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>505</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.05"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>506</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.06"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>506a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.06a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>506b</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.06b"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>506c</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.06c"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>507</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.07"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>507a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.07a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>508</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.08"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>509</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.09"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>510</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.10"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>511</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.11"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>512</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.12"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>513</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.13"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>514</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.14"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>515</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1305.15"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>601</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1306.01"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>602</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1306.02"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>603</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1306.03"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>603a</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1306.03a"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>605</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1306.04"/>
  </section>
  <section>
    <num>696</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§7-1306.05"/>
  </section>
</document>
