<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-147">
  <num type="law">2-147</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Charitable Organizations Conformity Tax Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-147.pdf">D.C. Law 2-147</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 6987</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-147, the “District of Columbia Charitable Organizations Conformity Tax Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-377, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 28, 1978 and December 12, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-324 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COOHCZ: L Of EE STRICT CF COL\ M3IA ~OTIC~ 0, C. LAl1 2-1 47 "District o: Columbia Chari t able Organi za&amp;lt;;ions Conforrr.i';y Tax Act of 1978" Purs uant t o Section 412 of the Distric: of Columbia Self- Goverr.ment ar.C Gove r rniental Reorsanizatior. Act, P. L. 93- 198 the Act t:ie Council of the District of Ccl:im~ia adcpted Bill No. 2- 377, on f i rsi: ane second readi:igs, Nove l gt;er 28 979 and December 12, 1978 respe ctively Fol!owing the signa tur e of the Mayor o n December 29, 1979 th ~s legislation was ass igned Act No. 2- 32 published in the January 26, 1979, edition of the C Register Vol. 25 pa9e 6987) ax transmitted to Congress on January 18, 1979 for a 30- day c-eview, in accordance with Sect !on 602 c l 1 of t he Act. The Council cf the District of Columbia here gt;y gives notice c.ha the 3 0-day Congress ion al Review Pe iod has expiz:-ed, and, t:terefore, cites the :ollowin9 legisla tion as o.c. Law 2-!47, e ect ve i~a 0 3, 1979 r ·\ 1 AR.'U ~GTON "DIXON O!ait'T.lan of the Council Dates Counted Durinc the 3C-dav Co noressional Review Pe z i o d: Januar1 19 t 19 f 2 2 f 2 J r 2 2 5 I 2 6 t 2 9 f J Q f 31 t'eb c-ua ry 1 2, s, 6, 7 a, 9, lJ, 14, 15, 16, 20 231 26, 27 t 28 l, 2 I \ O.C. LA.W 2 14 7 M~.R 0 3 1979 A)I 4CT 2-324 I)I THE COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT ~F COLUMS IA DECEMBER 29, 1978 To amend t ne Distr ict of Columbia In:one a nd Frdncn i se Tax Act of 1~47 eo provi de for conformity ~ith federal t3x laws as they concern l e~islat l ve activities o f charitable organizat ions and operations ithin the Di strict of Columbia. 3E IT ENACTED ~y T~E CDU~C IL OF T~E JIST~ICT OF COLU~BIA That t~is act nay oe cited as t he NOis trict of Col umo i a :naritao le Organizations Conformity raK Act of 1~7a Sec 2 Sect ion l(d) of Title 11 of the District of Co l unbia Income and Fr ancnise TaK ~ct of 1947. aoprove~ July lb 1'147 1 Sta t• 334; D. c Code, sac 47 155 4 is a'Tlenaad to raad as follows d) Corporations. and any co nmunity ches t funj or f ounoat ion organized and ooerated to a subst ant ial extent wi thin the Distri ct, e xclusi vely f o r re l i~ious cnarltat&amp;gt;le scientific. li ter ary or ·eaucatlonal ourposes or for the prevention of c r ualty to chil~ren or a n i mals no part of tne net e arnings of wnich inures to t~e oenefit of any ~rivate i ndividual or s n arenol der no sut&amp;gt;stantia l part of t ne activities of "ni cn is carr ying on propaganda or otherwise att~mptin9 to -2- influence legislation (except as otherwise provided in su:isecti on 50l.(h) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954) and hicn ooes not particioate in or intervene in (including tne oubl isning or oistributing of statements) any ool itical campaign on oehalf of any canoioate for puol ic office Sec 3 AO~inistration The ~ayor of tne Cistrict of Colu~oia is authorize~ to oromul;ate regulations to carry out the ourposes of this act and ~ay amend. by regulation the aporopriate provisions of Title lq of the District of :olumbia Rules ano Regulations. Sec 4 Effective Oate a) Th is act snail aoply to toxaole years beginninq after Decemoer 3lt 1977 i) This act snall take effect as orovioed for acts of the Council of the District of Columoia in section 602(cl(ll of tne Dis trict of Co1umoia Self-Gov~rnment and Governnental Reorganization Act. Bill 2-377 vc1ez vo-:z: Adopted Unar.icourl y 2 abs) Di:i:on amp;.kiid1 S•C 4 Cou=il Wilson 0 I C!llflil•c,:J I •T&amp;amp 1' t Sll\O CD c i t T \ 1 1,11 lt;11o I •rt t 1" 1 v t c I I l I !I t,~CN I I l .l S Ul O I I I I I !I ¥CO;&amp;gt l. I f 11 sc~ I j t I il ccc I v I t I I :1 cl..\ I I I vaa vc-:z: If amp;ge ?l Bill 2- 377 ii~t, I I S1:;o i i amp C-cc e \ o s. L:x.1t c! c C l i r Z:.taet ive See::a 1. i C Sec:-eca r Scc:-1 I I as amp;.c=.e \ rer </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
