<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-146">
  <num type="law">2-146</num>
  <heading type="short">District of Columbia Resident Tax Credit Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1979-03-03</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-146.pdf">D.C. Law 2-146</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 6987</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-146, the “District of Columbia Resident Tax Credit Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-370, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 28, 1978 and December 12, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-323 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCIL O? THE DISTRICT OF COLU.lBIA NOTICE D. C. LAW 2- 146 "District of. Columbia Resident Tax Credit Act of 19 78 Pu~suant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governrrental Reo r ganization Act, P. L. 93 198 th e Act the Council of the District of Columbia ad opted Bill tlo. 2-370, on first anc second re adi ngs Noven:ber 28, 1978 and Decem- ber 12, 1978 respectively. Follcwing t he signature of the Mayor on December 29, 1978, t hi s legi slation was assigned Act No 2-3 23 published in the Janua y 26, 1979 edition of the D. C Resister Vol 25, page 698 7) and transmitted t o Congress on January 18, 19 79 fo r a 30-aay review in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of th e Act. The Council of t he District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has e xpired, and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 2- 146, effective March 3, 1979. Dates Counted Durina the 30-dav Conor essional Rev i ew Period: January 18 19 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 29, 30, 31 February 1, 2, 5, 6 7, 8 9, 13, 14, 15 16, 20 21 22 23 26, 27 28 March l, 2 J t D.C. LAW 2 146 Alll ACT 11 t'A" 0 O°''lf ft iJ 1!79 IN THE COJNC IL JF THE DISTRI CT JF COLUMgIA DECEMBER 29, 1978 To prov i de an income tax credit to District of Columbi a residents for taxes paid to other states BE IT ENACTED BY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA That tnis ac t ~ay oe cited as the "Di s trict o f Columbi a Resident Tax Credit Act of 1970 Sec. 2 Section S(a) of title VI of the Di str ict of Co l u mbia I ncome ano Francnise Tax •ct of 1947 aoproved July lo 1947 (bl Stat. 345 n. r Code, s ec 47-1 567d( a is amended t o rea~ as follows: COLU~~JA~~lQ~TS The amount of tax payable unde r this title by a resident of the Di strict in respect to the taxable year snall be reduced oy a credi t equal to the amount of individual income tax such indiv idual is required to pay and. in fact has oa id to any State territor y or p~ssession of the u~ i ted States. or oolitical subdivision the reof uoon inco~e attrioutaole to such State territory or possession of the Jnited States or politi cal s ubdi vision t nereof, fo r such taxaol e year or portion thereof -h ile concurrently a -2 resident of t he Distr ic t Tne credit provi ded under this subsecti o n shall not exceeo t ne proportion of tne tax otnerwise due under this article t nat the amount of the i nd ividu3l 's adjusted g ross income rec eived by him. or accrued to h im if o n an accrual basi s subject to tax in tne o ther juri s~i ct ion oears to his entir e adjusted gross inco~e rece ived by him. or accrued to hi mt wnile ne was concurrently a res ident of the Di s tri ct The ~ayor may require s ati sfactory pr oof of t he payme nt of such income taxes to a nother Jur isdi ction. The credit provided b y th is s ubsect ion shall not be all owed against any tax imposed under t i tle VIII of th is article Sec 3 This act snail take effe ct in accordance wltn the Jrovisions of section 602(Cl(l) of the District o f Co lumoia Self overnment and Government aeo rganization Act and s hall apply to taxable years beg i nn ing after Decemoer 31. 1976. Bl 11 2- 370 !lac.ket ~o j November 28 1978 VOIC VOTZ: AdgpteC Onanimouslv 92 abs Dixon, Wilson I O L C.A.W VOTZ: fa~'il~t{ Sec: c.ta y :o thu Co~~l ii lt;~u C it I 1 I i I u,.cu re I t a,tf CQU Ch, io-l C:l'I i j I C I I I I t soN I I I I ij S lJ'T oL c I I I I l a.D I I I I M: O?.Z l. I I I 1 Wu.502 1 I I I 3 I l I ll tCO Z i I l l ll \V!N~'O I I I I i c u I I I ·13.0 L I I I I i I I I ] I i 1 I s CXI I I 1 I I I J I :C-1 o A at. X 1 101 •tau I I 1 lt; v G vozc VCT Adopted Unanimously (1 abs) Shackleton· {01fs.e L I OL.t. C..u.l JOT I lt;° lt c 1 c I c ¢1o r j ot,:o,i lt;ei c I 1 1 1 1 M.&amp;gt SON I r I I fi i I r i I I ic z. o. 11 r so I c z cu I t I r ir c::c.z T::N I ii I i ua v 7 t lt ll 2-370 Dcd:c \e e se eci te ~e Y.a ye OEC 15 1978 I 8 DEC 1978 c Col a v i C-E: i971 { i Cout o xecU vt Sec:eU:o&amp;gt;+f, t. C c~t:C wit ct t ~layc-r1 .s S!g::i.a J I fClCZ: VC:-Z: 1 c c:or C amp I i 1 c:i~c 1 T''C I l c.1h,1,.t Pl I T J I ~I I c j LAS~~i I iS u t i MOC?.Z </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
