<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-156">
  <num type="law">2-156</num>
  <heading type="short">Amendments to an Act to Provide for Voluntary Apprenticeship in the District of Columbia Act of 1978</heading>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1979-03-06</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-156.pdf">D.C. Law 2-156</citation>
      <citation type="register">25 DCR 6991</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-156, the “Amendments to an Act to Provide for Voluntary Apprenticeship in the District of Columbia Act of 1978,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-325, which was referred to the Committee on Employment and Economic Development. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on November 28, 1978 and December 12, 1978, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on December 29, 1978, it was assigned Act No. 2-325 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COU!'ICIL Of THE DISTRICT Of CO LUMBIA NOTICE O. C. LAW 2-156 "Arnendrrents to An Act To Provide o r Volun tary Apprentice sh LP I n The Dist r ict of Cobmbi.a Act of 1978 u rsuant to Sect io n 41 2 o f the District of Columbi a Self- Gove rnme n t and Governmental Reo-cganiza t ion \ct, P L. 93- 19 8 the Act the Co unc il of the District o f Col umbia adopted Bill No. 2- 325, on fi rst and second -cel!ldings, November 28,197 a:'ld December 12, 1973 r espectively follo wi ng the s i gnac. ure oc the layer on December 29, 1978, t:-tis leg i.sl11tion was assigned Act No. 2-325, published i:'l the Januacy 26, l979, edition of the O. C lt;egister, {Vol. 2 5 page 6991) and transnit t ed t gt; Co ngre s s on January 19, 1979 for a 30-day re·1i ew, i n accordance with Se ction 60 2 (c 1) o~ the Act. The Council of the Distric t of Colu~bia hereby gives notice tha t t he 30- day Congressional Review Per iod ha s expi-ced, a nd therefore, c ites t he fo l l ow i ng legisla tion a s o. c. Law 2- 156 e ffe ctive March 6, 1979 Oa t es Coun ted Our inq the 30- d a y Congr essional Review Per iod: Janu ary 19, 22, 23 2 4 2 5, 26 29 3 0 31 Februa ry 1, 2, s, 6 7, 8 9, 1 3 1 4 15, 16, 20, 21, 22, 23, 26 27 t 2 8 March 1 2 I 5 "1 C lA 1 io AR 0 b 1!?79 l'-5 I~ THE :OUNCIL JF T~E OtSTRICT OF CJLUMS!A To eKpand aporenticeship programs in tne Oistrict of Co lumoi a by reducing the minimum numoer of hours of apprenticeship; to increase the nembership of the Apprenticeship Council of the Ois~rict of Columbia, and for other related purposes. 8E [T ENACTEj SY THE COU~CIL OF THE DIST~ICT OF COLU~5I A, That tnis act may be cited as the nAmendments to An Ac t To Prov ide for Voluntary Apprenticeship in the District of :olumbia Act of 1978 Sec. z. Section Z of the Act entitled "An •ct To provide for voluntary aporenticeship in the District of Columbian, approved ~ay 21. 1946 (6J Stat. 204; o.c. Code• sec. lb- 122 is amended to read as follows Sec. z. Without regard for any other provision of law •ith respect to the appointment of officers and employees of the United States or the Oistrict of Columt&amp;gt;ia. the ~ayor of the District of Columbia shall appoint and the council shall confir~ an Apprenticeship Council• to be composed of eleven (lll members• as follows: three (3) representatives from employer organizations, three (3) representatives fro~ empl oyee z- organizations. and t~ree (3 ucl ic reoresentatives. who are not nenbers of either employee or emoloyer organizations. cnosen to make the Apprenticeship Council better reflect the composition of the District of Columb ia labor force. including •omen ancr minorities who are tr~aitionally under-representeo in tne trades; and two (2) representatives of government, who snail be the Mayor of tne District of Columbia and the Suoer inten~ent of Schools or their respective d~legates. The terns of office of the members of the Apprenticesnip Council first apoointej Dy the ~ayor shall expire as designated by tne Mayor at the time of naking t he appointnent: One (l) representative each of enployers. employees and tne public being appointed for one (l) year; one (lJ reoresentative eacn of enployers mployees and the puolic aopointed for two (2) years; and one (1) representative each of enployers• employees and the public for three (3) years. Thereafter. each nember shall be appointed for a term of tnree (3) years. Any me·nber appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of nis predecessor shall be apoointed for the re~ainder of sa id ter The compensation of each memoer not otherwisa co~pensated bY ~uolic money. shall oe paid not "ore than t~enty-five -3- dollars (S25) per day for each day soent in attendunce 3t meetings of the Apprenticesni~ Council: PR JV I OED HOWEVE T~at ~ny applicable Jaws pdssed by the Council of the District of Columbia shall supersede the provisions of this section Sec. 3. The terms of members presently serving on the Aporenticeship Council shall not be affecteo by the orovisions of section 2 above. Sec. 4. Section 7 of the Act entitled "An Act To provide for voluntary aporenticeship in the District of Columbia ap~roved ~ay 21. 194b (bO Stat. ZD5; o.c. Cooe. sec. 3b-127) is amended by striking out •four tnousand• and inserting in ieu thereof •two thousand Sec. 5. Ninety (90) days after the effective date of this act, all orime contractors anj subcontractors who contract witn the District of :olumbia government to perform construction or renovation work with a single contract or cumulative contracts of at least s50D.ooo, let within a twelve (12) month period. shall be required to register an apprenticeship program with the District of Columoia Apprenticeship Council. Sec. 6. This act shall become effective at the end of the period pro~ided for Congressional review of acts of the ounci l in sec tion b02(C) of the Oist ric:t of Col umo i a Se lf overnment and Go v e rnmental ~eor qanizati on Act l&amp;lt;1c!cet fo: Bill "2 325 c.l Ac:!ec.i: No vember 2 8 L978 Adooted UnanimousL l Dixon 7@U;it I f lt e 11.4 c I I c:;a 1 1 J cu 4 1 1 r r 3 CO?.Z I I I Ot CA CT S• c=e:a r :o t!:a e C~c:;il a.I. a tt,c n- Em.e:i~cr .1.c1:1oc Dec: embe r l2, 1978 i£.j Vai:C VOT Ado ted Una.nimousl L I 11.ou. CA..U von 1 I ca11 amp;A II I r I i &amp;lt ° I I I I Occ~e: N"o: OE.C 1 5 '978 j c Se~:et.:L:-l, I I c I I c A t I I ~t s i :s ·1 tcc:.z v(CC Z O L I c t A c! I f Ma.yo V e lo S a~ Se:.a.ta. Ac oa a e1 0U;Coc. N l. I I n o i &amp;lt;i.o oi fJ. s. E o\:.2• Ac~o:i s ol icz: i'ic ° </search-text>
  </meta>
  <section>
    <num>5</num>
    <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§32-1431"/>
  </section>
</document>
