<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-20">
  <num type="law">2-20</num>
  <heading type="short">Revenue Recovery Act of 1977</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-09-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-20.pdf">D.C. Law 2-20</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3339</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-20, the “Revenue Recovery Act of 1977,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-21, which was referred to the Committee on Finance and Revenue. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 3, 1977 and June 14, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 5, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-51 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>• COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE October 4, 1977 D.C LAW 2-20 "District of Columbia Revenue Recovery Act of 1977 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District o f Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-21 on first and second readings May 31, 1977, and June 14, 1 977, respectively. Following the s i gnature o f the Mayor on July 5, 1977, this legis lation was assigned Act No. 2-51, p ublished in the July 15, 1977, edition of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602(c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following legislation as D. C. Law 2-20, effective September 23, 1977 j/ J-i- STERLING UCKER Chairman f the Council (Vol. 24, D.C. Regis ter, 414, July 15, 19 77 J.C. LAf\ 2-20 IN THE COUNCIL OF T~E DISTRICT OF CJLU~ S IA Septe~b?.r 23, 1~77 Tu provi far t he mo netary µaymo nt of r e~ards t c c 2rta in ~e rsJns ~ho prov id~ infor ~atio n r elAt i ng to vi~l J tions of the Dis tr ict of Colum~i3 reven u la~ s anj for ot~er u rpOS S. JE IT E~~C TE J y THE C ~U\C I L 8F TH~ J I ST~ ICT J CCLU~BIA That this act ~ay be cited as th e "9istrict of Co lu mbia J r t he purooses of t nis act t~e f) l lo in 9 o r a s, t r ms phr3ses and t~eir d~ riv a tions sh~ll n~v 0 the ~c1n i n3s r e s~ective l y ascri bed t a them in this s ection unle ss the context clearly indicates other~ise a Co llect ion or "collecte·j" means the a ct ual r ece i pt b y or oay&amp;lt;!lent to the Oist ric t o f Co l ·J11 j i i o f a s 1J r.1 f ·Tl ney r ~p r esen ti n~ t axes ena lti e s a r in r st a r any corn~ i nation thereof whic~ has ~e e n f i n&amp;lt;l lly de tEr~ine1 ~s he i n l o lt;'Io. d to th~ D i s t r i c t o f C o 1 um b i a o r h i c h t-1 a s been 'a i j pu rsu ~nt to a se tt l .ement b n et tax e s, pe n i lti e s, and i ntere-st 11eans t t1e taxes panalt i~s, anj int erest co llect2d by the J i st ric t of Colu~bia l~ss the costs incurred b y th~ Qi st r ict of Co l u~tia i ri co l 1 c t i n s u c i t J x s De ri a l t i e s an J i i t r e s t d ri c Enrolled Original 2 (c revenue .laws" means the· District cf Columbia Income aAd Franchise Tax Act cf 1947, as amended, the District of Columbia Revenue Act of 1937, as amended, any ether tax or revenue la v of the District of Columbia, and any. rule or regulation adopted pursuant thereto. Sec. 3. The !ayor of the District cf Colum~ia, or his or her duly authorized representative or representatives, is authorized to make such monetary payments as he or she may deem suitable to any person or persons who furnish information leading to the collecticn cf taxes, penalties, or interest, or a combination thereof, cved to the District of .Columbia by any per son, partnership, corFora ti on, unincorporated associatj.on, trust, or estate violating the re~enue laws of the District of Columtia. The determinations of the ~ayor as to whether such payments shall be made and as tc the amount thereof shall be final and conclusive and shall not be subject to review in any court. The amount of any such payment shall not exceed ten (10) percent of the net taxes, penalties, and interest or any combina tio1i thereof collected by the District of Columbia as a result of the information furnished. Such payments shall be based on the collecticn cf taxes, penalties, and interest, or any combination thereof, only for the periods an~ the types of taxes for which the 3 information vas providEd. In no event shall any such payment be made prior to the expiration of all appeal periods applicable to the assessments involved. Enrolled Original Sec. 4. The Mayor may enter into ccntracts for the payment of such sums of money as he or she may deem suitable for information subject to the provi~icns cf this act. No person, in the absence of express authcrity from the Mayor, is authorized to make any offer, promise, er contract or otherwise bind the ~ayer with respect tc such payments or the amount thereof. Sec. S. The following persons shall be ineligible to file a claim for any mcnetary payment aat~crized by this act a) Federal, District of Columbia, and Cther Governmental Employees No person vhc was an officer or emp.loyee of the United States .Department of the Treasury, the District of Columbia Department of Finacce and Revenue, or any other state or local government department, agency, or office with similar functions, duties, or cbligations at the time he or she came into possession cf infcrmation relating to violations of the revenue laws, OF at the time he or she divu.lqed such i.nforma tion, shall l:e eligil:le to file a claim for any payment authorized by this act. lny other Ped iTistrict of Columbia, or other state or local Enrolled Original 4 government employee, or former em~lcyee, shall be eligible to file a claim for any payment authorized ky this act if the information submitted came to his er her kno~ledge other than in the course of his or her duties, except as otherwise ~rovtded in this section b) Attorneys Ho person vho was emplcyed by, retained by, or appointed to represent any ether perscn as an attorney or who was otherwise involved in a~ attorney-client privileged relationshi~ with such ether ~erscn at the time he or she came into possession of informaticn relating to violations of a revenue law, or connivaDce at the same, by such other person shall be eligible to file a claim for any payment authorized by this act c) Legal Representatives No perscn who was an executor, administrator, or other legal representative of a deceased person at the ti~e he or she came iDto possession of information relating to violations cf a. revenue law_b_y such deceased person shall ke eligible to file a claim for any payment authorized by this act d) Other Persons Ho person vho derived, either directly or indirectly, information relatiDq te violations of a. revenue lav from a person ineligitle tc file a. claim for ~ny payment authorized by this act shall te eligible to file a claim for such ~ayment 1nro11ea Original 5 Sec. 6. The Mayor shall promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this act. Sec. 7. This act shall take effect as ~rcvided in section 602(c) of the District of Columtia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act JLECC!l.D CF CFFlIC.U.Jt. CCGCitlI a.C71Ci!I' Docket No: 2-21 rust Reading ktion: May 31, 1977 @ VOICE VOT:C Adopted Unanimously Secretary to the ·cowicil 0 ROLL CA.LL VOTE: COClllCI C•Hll I •TC I 1 c::v.,cu C c.11 I C I l lf. v. I amp I c:o cu c ec.11 A1'C I I j TUCX R. I I I I II MASON I I I I !I S?.J..UUiL\;G I I I I KA:.ltDY I I I II MOOP..Z. D. I I I II i~11..SON I I I lU.R Y I I I ll MOORE. J. I I I I II WL'l'TI I I CI.A I I I I !I ROLA I I I I II I I DIXON I I I !I Q'T I I I I II I I x-l11dlca1ft Vol 3 H. V-:toc V~fiNJ Seaetary to the Ccuncil Amended Fi:st Rea.ding Ac:tian LI VOICE VOTE: Secretary to. the Counc:il ll ROLL CA.LL VOTE lt oi I t: I I l a. 11 11.~c:i c,.oc• I •tt I I I j c c lt Vt 1't: j I l TUCXZ I I I I If MASON I I I I i1S \.CJ DDiC I i.A I I I I II MOOR o I I I I f ;v-u..soN I v I I MCOiU I CI 1 I I I I R.OL 1 I I II I DIXON I I I I H S:.AC~n I I I I 11 I X-tac•a:tt •t•t 1 U1•11U :r. v foc ·1.c Fmal Aeadinc or Emerrency Action: Secretary to the Caunc:il June 14, 1977 VOICE VOTE: Adopted Unanimously ~tau) i.te wa Secretary to the Ccw:ic:il LI ROLL CALL VOTE: TtJCKZ IM.ASON HA I II MCO?-i i. BA l 1·MCO?-i J. I 11 I I I I I I I I I I I I I I I i I I I JlECCZD CF CFFIClIA.lt. ccau~CitlI amp;CTIIO Pa.ge 2) Docket No: Presented to the Mayor JUN 21 'm S JUL r!11 Action o! the Mavor pproved: Q Disapproved: Q Disappraved in p&amp;amp;rt Re!erenc:e Document Budget Actions LI Returned Without Ac:tioc 2-21 £IV Secretary to Executive Sec:eta.ry, D. C. l:n&amp;amp;c:tecl without Mayor's Signature Secretary to the Counc:il Council Reenac:t:nent: 0 VOICE VOTE: Secretary to the Co1::icil I I ROLL CALL VOTE: cou"Cl c c 1 11: I 1 N.v. J f c=u i C c" I u: I I v. I c::u:oc c c I 11: I I I TUC~.a. I I I I .11 ~L.\.SON I I HAR.DY I I I I II MOC:U o. I I B.A y I I I I ii too I. I I CI..A T.G: I I I I II ROLA K I I ·DIXON I I I I II !r Kt o"N I I c ·o~'a Uft Vote 3 C Presented to the President: Action o! the P!-esident: LI Reen.a.c:tment Approved Mayor Veto Sustained Submitted to the Ccngreu Senate Action llHolution. Number Secretary ol the Sena.te I I IS?A~l..l:lL'iG I I I t I 11wu..scx I I I I I L.a V1N I I I I I a I I I t I I I !I I I I !f Cos Secretary to the Cou.nc:il Secretary to t!:ie Council Presic ent ol the tJ S S•creta.ry to the Counc:il House Action Resolution Numlar Clerk of the House I I I I I ~JUL 1977 I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
