<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-22">
  <num type="law">2-22</num>
  <heading type="short">Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-09-23</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-22.pdf">D.C. Law 2-22</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3341</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-22, the “Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect Act of 1977,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-48, which was referred to the Committee on Human Resources and Aging and the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on May 17, 1977, and May 31, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 6, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-53 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>j i COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA NOTICE D.C LAW 2-22 "Prevention of Child Abuse anei Neqlect Act of 1977 October 4, 1977 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Colwnbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorqanization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-48 on first and second .readinqs May 17, 1977, and May 31, 1977, respectively. Followinq the siqnature of the Mayor on July 6, 1977, th~s leqislation was assiqned Act No. 2-53, published in the July 22; l9i7;-edition-of the D.C. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c l of the Act. The Council of the Di.strict of Colu nbia hereby g i ves notice that the 30-day Cong=essional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the followin; legislation as D. c. Law 2-22 I effective s·eptember 23 I 1977. jt LL I ST!:RL!NG 'm,JCKER Chair.nan of the Cou lcil (VOl. 24, O.C.Regis~er, 72 7 July 22, l97 i ailed. Orig 2-53 IN TRE COONCI~ OF tHE DISTRICT OP COtO~Sil July 6, 1977 To amend existinq Distti.ct of Columbia lav with regar~ to c:asas of c:!l.ild ne&amp;lt;;lect and a.busa, tc establish procedures for the term.ination of parental rights in certain situations, and for other ~urpc~es. BE IT ?BACTED BY TR? COO?ICJ:.t O li! JlIS!BIC! 01 COltl~Bil, That th.is act ~ay be cited as th&amp;amp; npreventicn of CAi1d lbnse and Neglect let of 1977 TI!rl.Z I e%PO~G-l.BOS? ASD J!Gi!CT sec. 102. pefinitious Por the pu.r~cses of this act a Child Protection Reqister means the con'fidentia.l inde~ of a.l1 reports esta.b1ished FUrsuant tc s&amp;amp;c ion 201 of Title II of this ·act b credi.ble evidence" means any evidence wllich indicates that a child is an abused er teglected chi1d, including the statement of any person worthy cf be.lief. {c) e cept where used in Tit.le rv cf this act Division" means t~e Chi1d ~rotective s~rvices Division of t~e Dist=ict cf Columbia Depart~ent of aaman Eesources i \ Enrolled original. 2 d) n q11ardian ad litem" means an atto.rney a t:Poi.nted by the superior court of the District of Columtia to represent the ch.i.ld's best interests in neqleet ~roceedings e Eolice" means the aettopol.ita.n Police Department 0£ the District of Columhia f report" means a report to the iolice or the Division of a StlSl)ected or known neq~~cted child q solll'ce" means the ~arson or i~~ituticn from whom a repo.rt oriqillates h supported repc:rt" means a report, made pursuant to section 103(d) of 'ti.tl.e I of this act, vhich is sup~orted by credible evidence. {.i unsupported report" means a re~o:t, made pursuant to sect.ion 103(d) of Title I of this act, which is ~ct supported by credil:.le evide~ce. Sec 103. Amendments to t~a Act cf November 6, 1966 ?he act entitled "ln let to provide !er t.lle mandator7 reporting by pnys:icians and i.n.stitatic~s in thE Dist=ict of Columbia of cert a.in ph ysi ca.l a.base of child.re n" r approved November 6r 1966 (80 Stat. 1354; O.C. Cede, secs. 2-161 t~rouq~ 2-166) is amended as follows a) Sal:chapter Ir is rei:.itled "Eei;:crts cf Neg.lected C!:i.i.ldre.n El:lrolled Original. 3 {b) Section 1 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-1e1) is amended to read as foliovs: n (1) It is the purpose of this subchapter to require a report of a suspected neglected child in order to identify neglected ch~ldren; to assm:e that ~rotective services will be made available to a neglected child to protect t~e cl:iild and his or her siblings and tc ~revent further abuse or neqlect; and to preserve the fa:ily life of the parents and children, to the ma.xi~um extent possible, by enh.a.ncinq the pa renta.l capac:i for ad equatE c.h.ild care c Section 2 (D.C Code, sec. 2-162) is amended to read as f ollovs: 11 2 fot'iithst:ud.inq section 14-307 cf the Oist:ict of Colwn.bia Code, any person speci£ied in subsection (b) 0£ t~is section who knows or has reasonaQl e cause to suspect that a child known to him or her in hi~ or her frofessional or of£icial capacity has bee.a or is in i=imed.iate danger of :bei.nq a ~entall y or pl:t. ysica.lly ai:l ased er neg lee ted child, as def.i.D.ed i.n D. c. Code, sec 16-2301 (9 shall i::imedia.tely report or have a report made of such k~C"iledge er suspicion to either the aetropol itan Police Department of the District of Columbia. or the Chi.ld rotecti ve service~ ti vision of ue oepartmen t of au::an ae~ou.rces \ \ clleci Origil2al b) Persons reqlliJ:ed to reFcrt such abuse or neglect shall i~clade every physician, psychologist, medical e%a.:iner, dentist, chiropractor, registered narse, licensed. prac:tic:al nurse, person involved in the care and treat~ent of patients, la.w enforcement officer, schocl c£ficia.l, teacher, social. service worker, day care worker, and mental b.eal th professional. Whenever a parse z: is re qui.red to report i.u his or her capacity as a memtEr of the staff of a hospi ta.l, school social agency or similar ins1:i t ation, he or she shall immediately noti.fy the person in charge of the institution or his or her designated agent vhc shall then be required to make the repo=t- The fact that such a notification has been made does not re l ieve the person who vas orgina.lly required to repor~ from his er her datr ttnder subsec~ion (a) of this section of ~aving a re~o=t made promptly 'to th.e et:opclitan ?olice O.epart:n.ent of the District of Columbia or the Child P~otective Services Division o! the Department of aaman aescurce c) In addition to those perscns vhc are required to aaxe a report, any ct~er person 2ay make a report to the ~etropolita.n Pol.ice Department of 't.le tistrict cf Colombia or the Child Protective Serv~ces Oivisicn cf th~ Oepart~ent of Human Re so ore: es ol1ed Original 5 (d) Section 3 (D.C. Code, sec. 2-163) is amended to read a.s follows: n (3 a) Each person required tc make a :report of a k.llovu or suspected neglected chi.la slial.l: 0 (1) im~ediateJ.y make an cl:al report of the case to the Child Protective services Division of the Department 0£ au::ian aesotll'c:es or the !e~o~clitan Police De pa.rt men t of the District of Columbia and n (2) 111.ake a. vritten report of the case i requested by sa.id Di vision or. Police b) Xhe report shal.l inc.lade, but need not be limited to, tlle follow inq_ in£oaa tion i£ it is kllovn to the person making the report 1) the name a.qe, sex, and address of the fol1owing iJldiVidaa.ls: n (A) the cllild wtto is the ~ub j ect of the report a) each ot the child's sib liJlg and "CC) eac h of th~ child's ~areuts or other persons respon.s:ib.le for tlle chi.ld's care; n(2) the nature and extent of the abuse or neglect of the child aDd any previous abuse er neglect, if k.novn \ 6 3) all other information vhich the person ma.kinq~the report belie~es mar be hel~ful in est.ablishinq the cause of the abuse or neqlect a..tid the ide~tity of the pe.I:Son responsible for the a.bllSe or neglect. w Q) If the source was required tc report a..nder this su.bchapter, the identity and occupation of the source, how to contact the source and a statement of the actions taken br the soa.rce concerning the child e) section D.C. Code, sec. 2-16Q) is amended to read as follows q) lny person, hospital, or instituticn participat.i.nq in qood fait~ in the maki~q cf a report pursuant to t!:l..is subchapter shall have i:mu~ity fro~ lia.:ility, civil or c::im.inal, that might otherwise be inc:i:red or imposed •ith respect to the maki~g of the report. Any sach participation shall have the same immunity vit.h. respect tc participa~ion in an7 judicial ~rocscding involving the report. I~ all civil er cri%iDal proceedi.:lgs concerning the child or resulting frcm the reFcrt good faith shall .be presumed unless re.butted f section 5 (D.C. Code, sec 16 is amended to r:ad as follows 5 lo1:~ithstand.ing the xcvisic:ns cf D.C. Code, secs. 1~-106 a 1~-307, nei~h.er tbe hustand-~i!e privil~ge l!:zll"olled Original. 7 nor tb.e physician-patient privilege shall te g~onnds fer exc.ludinq evidence in any pJ:oceed.ing i~ the Family Division of the Superior Court of the District cf Colam.tia. concerninq the ve.lfare of a neqlected chi1d: PBOVIt?D, That a judge of tlle. Family Division of tb.e Sa.perior Cea.rt cf the .Cisttict of Columbia determines such privilege should =e waived in the interest of jllStice q) l new section 7 is added to read as follows: 11 (7) ln! persoa. req llil: ed to make a report ll.Ilder t.his subchapter wh.o villfu.l.l.Y fails to make sach a report shall be fined not more tlla~ one hundred dclla.rs (S1001 or impi:isoned fer not more than thirty (30) days or both. Violations 0£ th.is subc~apte:c shall be FTc~ecuted by the Coqoration co11:1seJ. of t.b.e District of coJ.um.l:ia or his or her agent in the name cf the Distric~ cf Cclumbia SEC. 104 aandlinq of aeoorts: The Divi.:icn (a) Opon the :eceipt of an orai reFcrt, the Division shal.l i:mediateJ.y inform the Police of the ccntents of the report, if it alleges a child is or ~ay have teen an abased ch.ild b} The Division sha.l..l comce.nce an investigation of al.l reports alleginq ueqlec~ ot~er than a~nse within tventy-four (2 ow:s oi t~e :eceipt cf the repor~ except that when Etirolled Original. 8 (1) a report al.leqes that a chi.ld is left alone or with .inadequate supervision, tbe Divisicn shal1 ccmmence an investigation immediately. If the Division is unable to dispatch a worker to the child forthwith~ it shal..l inform the Po.lice of the report 2) a report indicates the e:istet:ce of an immediate danger to a child and the immediate removal. of the child- from bis or her surroundings appears i:ece ~a:y despite tb.e availa.ble nsources, the Division sha.ll inform the Police of the co.ntellts of the report and request the Police to investigate. The Division sha1l immediatel1 commence a social investigation c) In a.ll cases o ccurrillg after ncrmal vcr.king ho a.rs or vhen it is otherwise deemed necessary, the Oivisicn may request the assistance oi the Police. Sec. 105. Handling of Recor-ts oliee (a) The ?olice shall, as soon as pessitle a!ter the receipt of a report of a neglec~ed child ether than an abused child, inform the Di.vision of its cout en ts and a.ny action the Police are taking or have taken b) The Poiice =ay, upon the recei~t cf a report of an aha.sed c~ild, info:i::m the Division of its con~ents and shali, as soon as possible v~en the repor-t is a su~~er~ed report, Enrolled Orig1oal 9 inform the Division of its contents and any action they a.re taki~q!or have taken c he ~olice shall immediately after a report is received comJ1ence an investiqat.ion of the circumstances al.l.eged in the report d) The Police shal.l immediately azter a report is received commence an investigation of a case cf a neglected child in immediate danger vhich case was referred from the Division or reported directly to the Pclice e) crpon t~e receipt of a report alleqi~g a ch..ild is or b.as been left alone or vithout adequate supervision, tlle Po.lice shall. respond to t~e report im~ediateJ.y a.nd shal.l take such steps as are necessary to sazequa=d the child until a Division staff mem~er arrives: kiOV!'D!t, aoqEv That i.f t.he Division does not ao:i ve vithii: a reasonable time, the Police may transport the c..hild tc the Division. The tra.nsportinq of a cl:Uld to tb.e tivi.:tioo parsuant to this subsection sha.ll net be considered a taki~g ioto custodJ as described in D.C. Code, sec. 16-2309, as amended by this act. Sec. 106 llvestiqation (a) The primary responsibi1ity !or the initial investiqation is with the Police in cases cf an a.l.leqedly abused chi1d a~d with the Division .i.:i ct~er cases of an 10 al leqed1y neglected chiJ.d: PROVIDED, Bc~ever, That the investiqation of a report in.volvinq acts or omissions of either the Department of R~ma.n Resources or the Police shal.l be conducted by the Depa.rt~ent vhich is not involved b) The pw:-pose 0£ the .initia1 invertigaticn shall be to determi.tle 1) the nature, e%tent, and cause of the abuse or .11eqlect 2) the identity of the person res ~onsib le for the a..b11se or neg1ect 3} the name, age, sex, and cc~dition cf the abused or neg1ected chi1d and a..11 other children in the home 4) the eondi ti.ens i.n the home at the ti.:ie of the in vestiqa ti on 5) whether there is any child in t.b.e home •hose hea1t.b safet_y, or welfare is in jeopardy t:ecaase ot b.is or her treat=ent in the heme or ~is or her home environment; an.d (6) vhethe.r any child vho is i.n jecpardy because of treatment in the home c: his or her heme environment should be removed f:om the ho=e or can be prctected by the provisio~ of resoarces sac~ as those listed in section 30~ of !itle !1! of t~is act. s,ec. 107 noval c= c i ili=e.n Enrolled Origi::al 11 ca) In cases in which a. cb.ild is a lleqed to be a ueqiected, but not an abused, chiid the Division sha..ll determine whether. the child should 1:2 removed fZ'om the home or can be protected by t.he provision of serVices or resources If in the cpinion of the Divisicn the available services or resourees are insufficient tc otect the child and there is insUf£icient ti.me to petiticn for remova.l, the Division snail request the Police to remove tbe cbild pursuant to o.c. Code, sec. 16-2309 (3) er (4 each as amended by this act b) In a.ii cases for vb..ich the Police u:e responsible for the initial investiga:;ion but which do not involve an immediate danger to a child, the Police shall seek f.rom t~e Division and the Division shall prov1de assistance in the deteri:inatiou of whether tbe child can l:e protected by the provision of services er resources or vhethEr remcval is necessary. ihenever pcssi~le the Divisicn shal1 di~patch a worker to t~e scene to provide a.ssis~ance in this determination c) In al1 cases for which the Folice axe responsible !or the initial in'Testiqa.tiOll and vb.ic.l:l do illvclve a.n i :mediate danger to a c:hiid and require remcval pursuant to n. c. Code, sec. 16-230 9 (3 as a:iecded y tti act. the ?olice shall immediately notify tbe Divisicn cf the removal \ 12 and the latter shall investigate a.lternative ~lacements for the child d} ihen, prior to a s~elte~ care hearing, the tivision locat~s a suitable aiternative placement pursuant to subsection (c} of this section, the Pelice may release the child pursuant to o c. Code, sec. i6-i31i (a 1 sec. 108. Photograchs and I-Rays r f there is a su ~ported report, a.ny person res,:onsible for the investigation under section 106 of this act may take, or have taken, color photographs cf each area of tiauma visible on the child or photog=a~hs cf the conditions surroundinq the neglect o~ the c:.hiid and, iz medica.l.ly i.ndicated, have radiolcgical e%ami.naticns perfcrmed on the c i.i.ld. Sec. 109. Social Investiaation and S€rvices (a) If the initial investigation results i~ a supported report, t~e information from the initial i"7eEtigation shall be i~mediataly referred ~o tha Police er the Division, as appropriate. 1 social inves~igation shall be ccmme~ced immedia taly .by t.he Intnfa::iily Sr an ch cf t.he Socia.J. Services Division of t~e Superio Coar~ of the tistrict of Columbia in al.l cases of a:.n. allegedly a.btlSed child ii b.ich are refarrad for petition to the Family Division of the supericr Court of th.e Oist:ic~ of Colu:=ia a.11d by t Div-i.sic i.:l all ot..har Enrolled Origi:u 13 cases, except tha.t cases vhich are or vere recenUy active vit.h the Division may l:e in vestiqated by the ti vision. The iurpose of the social investigation shall te to determine what services a.re required the family tc re:edy the conditions of a.h tlSe or neq.lect b) If there is a supported report, the agency responsible for the social investigatict shall as soon a.s possible prepare a plan for eac~ child and family fc~ vhom services are required en more ~han an emergency basis and sha.l.l forthwith take sac!i ste.~s to ensure the protection of the chil.d. a~d the preservation, rehabilitation and. when appropriate, reunification of the faMily as may be necessary to achieve the purposes of this act. Sach steps may include out need not be limited to 1) arranging for necessary ~rctective, rehabi.litative, and financial services tc be ~rcv~ded to the child and the child's family in a manner vhich maintains the c~ild in his or her home 2) referring the child and the child's fa~ily for placement in a family shelter or other a~~rcpriate faci.lit7 3) sacurinq services ai~ed at reulliting ith his or he: family) a ch ld ta~en in~o custody Enrolled Orig1paJ 14 (4) providing or making specific atrangements for the case management cf each case vhen child protective services are required o the maximum extent possible, the resources of the community (public and ~rivate) shall =e utilized fo~ the provision of services and case managei:ect c) l report of the social investigaticn required ander subsection (a) of this section and the pla~ required under subsection b) shall be submitted to all cctlll~l at least five (5) days prior to the da~e of the fact-finding hearing i~ cases in which a petition vas filed pursuant to o.c. Code, section 16-2305: P~OV~ZD, That ncthing added ~o the report or t~e pla.n subsequent to either an initial appea:a.nce or shelter care hearillg shall be considered by the court prior to the completion of the fact-findinq hearing unless the parent, guardian, or custodian alleged to be responsible for the neglect consents to such consideration. Sec. 110. l!llend::ien'ts to the AC'tS cf Decr:111.ber 23, 1963 and .July 29, 1970 Title 16 of tha District of Colambia Cede is amended as follows a} Section 2301 is amended as icllc•.1s: EnrolJ.ed Origi:lal. 15 (1) subpuagraph (9) is amended to read as followii 9 e term •neglected child' means a chi1d: nc1&amp;gt; who has =een abandoned er abused by ~is or her pa.rent, qua.rdian, or other castod.ian: or B) vtio is without prcpeJ: pa.renta.l care or control, subsistence, education as required by lav, or other cara or cont l necessary for his or he: physical, mental, or emotional health, and the deprivaticn is not due to the lade of financial means of lli.s or her pa.rent, guardian, or othe.r custodian; or C) vhose _pa.rent, guardian er other custodian is unable to discharge his or her responsibilities to and for the ctt.i.ld because of i~ca:ceraticn, b.ospita.lizati.on, or othe.r physical er a:ental incapacity; or O) whose paren guardian, er custodian refuses or is unable to assume the res pons i~ili ty for the child's care, control er subsistence and the Ferscn or institution vhich is providing for the child states an intention to discontinue such ca.re; or n (E) vho is in im.mi.nent danger cf being abased and 11 'll.ose si:c ling has teen a.b llsed o ci:i.ild who in qood fait~ is ander treatment solely by spuitual mea..c..s tb..roagh p:ayer in a·-c=ord-ance i t.:i t~e enets Ezlrolled Original. 16 and practices of a recognized church or religious denom.ination by a duly accredited practitic:er thereof shal.l for that reason alone be considered a neglected chiid for the purposes of this subch.apter 2) subparaqraph (12) is a~ended tc read as follows 12) The term 'custodian' 2eans a person or agency, other than a parent or legal guardian, to vhom the legal custcdy of a child has been granted ~y the order of a cou.rt or who is acting i.n 10~9 parentis and (3 by add.i.ng to the secticll the f cllcving new subparagraph (23 M(23) the term 'abused when usad with reterence to a child, means a c:hiJ.d vhose parent, guardian, or cu~odian inflicts or fails to make reasonatle efforts to prevent the infliction of physical or mental i.njury upon t~e child, including e~cessive corporal punish3ent er an act of sa.:cua.l ab use or molesta tioc b) section 2305 is a.mended by adding a new last santence to read as follows Complaints a.l.legi~g c.eglact submitted by the Child PTctective services Divisio~ of the tepartment cf Bamac esources sl a..l.l be re£errad directly tc the Ccrporation Co.ans el o.f t::le .0 ist ic o C.01. um bi.a 17 (C) Section 2309(3 is a.mended as fcilcvs 1} subpa.raqn.ph (3) is amended to read as follows: EnrolJ.ed Origi:le.J 3) by a lav enfcrceme.nt officer when he or she has reasonable qrounds to oeiieve that the child is in immediate danger from his or her surrcundinqs and that the removal of the ch.ild from his or her surroaudinqs is necessary and (2) subparagraph (4) is re.aum~ered as subparagraph (5) and t~e following new sub.paragraph (4) is added to read as follows 4) by a law en£orcement officer after he or she has consulted with the Chief of the Child Protective Services Di~ision of the Depar~~ent cf Buman EesotU:ces, or hi.s or her desiqnee, pursuant to section 107(c) of the Prevention of Child Abusa and Neglect Act of 1977 vhen the officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the child is suffering from illness or injur7 or othe.r~isa is endangered and that the child's removal from his er her surroundings is uece ssary d) Section 2311 is a.mended as follcvs 1) subsecticn (a) is amended as fcllcws l) su.bparagrapb 2) is a:iended tc J:ead as follo•s 18 2) brinq a ch.i1d al1eged in need cf supervision or dell.nqaent before the Director of Sccial Services; or B) subparagraph (3) is amended by acding to the end thereof the fol.loving la.nquaqe and may order the cl:Lild retailled at the ·hos pi ta.1 subject to a further order of the i!etropoli tan Po1ice Department of the District of Columtia,.the Ch.ie~ of the Cl:Li.ld Protective Services Division cf the Department of auman Resources, or the Superior court cf the District of Columbia; or and (C) a new subparagraph is added to read as fo.1.lovs 4) brinq a c:hi..ld alleged tc be a neglected chi.ld to the Cb..ief of the Chi1d Protective Services Division of the Department of auman Resources i (2) subsection (b) is amended as f cllcws 1) the present su~secticn is redesiqnated as subsection b 1 and (B} a new subsection 2) is added to read as follows 2} vhen a child is l::rcu gh t l:lefore t!le Chief of the Cilild Protective Servic:2s tivisicu of the Depart:nent of a11ma.n Re~ources, tb.e Cllief shall re view -the ~eed !or shelter ca:e ior ~o the adwissicn to shelter Enrolled Origi.nJ 19 care. If shelter .care is required the Chief shall select the most appropriate placement for the child. If the Chief determines that shelter care is not reqai.red the Ch.ief may recommend to the etropolita.n Police Det:a:rt11e.nt of the District of Colnmbia the release of the child to his or her parent. guardian or custodian. ihen a child is being held in a hospital the c::ase sha..l..l be reviewed by the Ch..iet. I.f th.e Chief deter:nines t .ha t sh.el ter care is net required, he or she sna.11 recommend to said Pol.ice the relea~e of the child to his or her parent. qua.rdian, or custcd..ian. If the Ch..ief determines there is a need for shelter ca=e but there is not a medical need r~uiring hospital.i%aticn, the Chief shall secure the approt:riate shelter care alld (3) a nev subsection (d) is added to read as follovs Cd) a person taking a child into custody or a pnblic agency having temporari care pendiAg a detention or shelter care hearing may bring the child tc a medical facility if the c~ild appears require prcm~t treatment or to require prompt diagnosis for medical, p~7chiatric, or evidentiary pa:~oses and may authorize such diaguosis or emergency treatment EoutiAe medical treat~ent shall not be authorized un.less a parent cazi.not be consulted \. \ Etl:rolled Original. 20 (e) Section 2316 is amended by redesignating subsections (cJ a.nd (d) as subsections {e) and (f) a~d inserting new subsections (c) and (d) to read as follcvs: n (c) iihe.re- the petition al.leqes a child is a neglected chiid :y reason ·of abase, evidence cf illness or injury to a c~ild who was i..n the custcdy of b.is or her parent, qua.rdiaA, or custod.i.an for which the ~a.rent, guardian or custodian can give no satisfactcry explanation shall. be su££icient to j~stify an inferencE ot neglect d) iihere the peti~~on al.leges a c!lil.d is abandoned as refer.red to in D. C. Code, sec. 16-2301 (9 1 is amended by this act, the following evidence shall be sufficient to justify a.n inference ct teglec n(1) tb.e child is a foandli.ng vhose parents have made no effort to ~ailltain a parental relationship vith the chil.d and reasonable effor~s have been :ade tc identify the chi.ld a.Dd to loca~e t.lle pare..nts !or a pericd of at least four (4) weeks slice the cllild was found, er 2) the child's p_a.=ent gave a false identity at t~e time of the c:.h.ild's b~.r"tb since tten has made no ef£ort to maintaiA a parental relationship wit~ the child and reasonable effor~s have ~ean ~ade to lccate the pa.rent for a period of at least four eeks since his or her d.i.sappearance; or El:rolled Origiilal 21 3} the chi.ld's parent, guardian c-r custodia.n is knovn but has abandoned the child in that he er she has made no reasonable effort to ~aintain.a pare:nt.al relaticnship vith the chiJ.d for a period of at least four mcnt.hs tt shall not be necessary to prove that the pa.rent, qua.rdian or custodian intended to abandon the child or that he or she is nov dead. However, if the judge is satisfied that there was a sat.is factory explanaticll fer the abandonment he or she need not enter a finding of neg1ect f) Section 2319 is amended by redesiguatinq the present language as sul:section (a) and cy adding at the end thereof a. new sn.bsecticn b) to read as follows b) the social investigation and plan for the fa:ily prepared pursuant to section 109 cf the Prevention of Child Abuse and Ne9lect •ct of 1977 shall satisfy the requirements of subsection (a) of this section. Sach investigation and plan sha.l.l be ~ade availatl~ to all counsel iA the proceedings at laas~ five (5) days prior to the date cf tra.i.l: PROVD&amp;gt;ZD, ac zv::R I.hat. the investigation and plan sha.ll net be furnished t.o or ccnsice:ed by t!J.e co11rt prior to the ccmple"t:ion of t!:i.e fact-findi.ag hearing 9 Section 233 i (b) is a.mended by adding the following nev subparagraph (6 Enrol1ed Original 22 6) p~ofessional employees of th~ Social Re.habi~itation Administration of the Depart~ent of Buman Resoarces when necessary for the discharge cf their of!icial duties h) section 2332(b) is amended bT deleting the period after subparagraph (7 inserting in lieu thereo and a..nd adding a ne~ subparagraph (8) to read as follovs 8) professicnal employees of the Sccial Rehabilitation Administration of the De~azt:ent of Buman Resources vhen necessary fer he discha~ge cf their official duties l L.E ll CR:tI..D pao?ZC~10N REGIST!B Sec. 201. Establish2eot and Pur~cse (a) There is hereby established a Child Protection Register to be maintained by the Divisicn b) The pu..rposes of the Register are to 1) maintain a confidential i~dex ct cases of a~used and neglected children 2) assist in the id~ntificaticn and treatment of abused and neglected children and their fa~ilies; and (3) se~ve as a resource for the evaloaticn, llla.nageme.nt, and planning o! progra:ns and services fc: abused and !leglsctad c.:i.ildJ:e!l. Etlrol.led OrigiJ::ial 23 {c) The staff of the Department ·of Buman Besou~ces assigned to ~ailltain the Child Protecticn Eeqister shal.l maintain twen ty-fotir 24) hour, seven (7) day a week telephone l.ines which mar be combined vith the tventy-four (24) hottr intake components described in Title III of this a d) Said stall shall {1) receive reports and infcrmatio~ necessary for the operation of the Child Protection Se9ister and ake appropd..ate entries ill such Beqister as requ.ired by section 202(a) of this act; and (2) release info~mation contai~ed in the Child l'rotection Re gi.ster in a mallller consistellt with this act. Sec. 202. In for?!lation to be Ret a.ined (a) There shall be retained in the chiid Protection Register the followi~g ill!or~aticn concerning eac~ s~pported report 1) the recipient of the repcrt, the date and the time· of the receipt cf t.he .re port 2) the ill:formation required in the report pursuant to the Act of &amp;amp;ovembe.r 6, 1966, as amended l:y this ac:t (80 Stat. 13Sq; o.c. Code, sec. 2-163} m-olled Origi:lal. 24 (3) the census tract and vard in which the chiid lives and other demoqraphic :iJl..forma tic~ concernill g t.!ie incident refe~ed to in the repcrt the agencies to which the repcrt vas refer:ed and the date and the time of the referral 5) the a9ency or agencies making t!lE initial investiqation, the sum~a.ry of the results cf the initial investiqation and the dates and the times the investigati~ns •ere begun and terminated 6) th.e agency or agencies taakinq the social inve~iqation, the sum::ary cf the resalts cf tbe social investigation~ the dates- and the t.i=es said i~vestigation was begun and terminated, the services c!!ered and vhen they were offered 7) the agency or agencies tc wh.ich the referrals were made and t!le services z:equested, vit.h the dates of the opening and t~e c.losing oi the case 8) t~e placement~ o! the child and the dates of each. placement 9) court actions concerni.ng the child and the dates thereof: and (10) the date the case ila.s clcsed b he.re may :e reta..i..ned in t!le c.~i.ld P:ctectiou aegi.ster ot.lle r in.£ c.r~a ti on reqo.ired !er res ea rc:h, platini.ng I Em-olled OriginaJ. 25 evaluation and management purposes pur~uant to ru.les adopted accord±nq tQ the District of Columbia Administrative Procedure Act, approved October 21, 1962 (e2 Stat. 1203; D.C. code, sec. 1-1501 c) In£ormation in an tl.Il.SUpported report sha.ll be retained in a separate i.nde: in which all i~fcrmaticn that coa.ld identify any person rafe.rred to in the unsupported report shall be destroyed d) The staff which maintains the Child Frotection Register shall reviaw all op~n cases every six (6) months to assure that information in said Register is current and shall request updated i.nformatiou from the aF;ropriate agencies as indicated e) The public agencies responsible fer receiving reports. making investiqations and providing or securing case management shall te ~esponsible f cr supplying the in£or~ation req~ired under tllis secticn to the Child Protection aegis~ez on a ~izely basis. See. 203. Access to t~e Reaister (a) The staff which maintains the Child P~ctection aeqi.ster shall g ra.n·t access to informaticn co otai!led in said Register only to t~e f cl.lowi.Ilg persons 1) officers of the iol..ice fer the par?ose of an i.nvestigat~~n of a :epcrt \ EJ:lrclled Original 26 (2) the Corporation Coa.nsel cf the District of colnm~a or his or her agent fer the p~~ose cf fuifill.inq his or aer of£icial duties concerning cases of an allegedly neqlected chi.ld 3} the personnel of the Division and the Social Services Diti.sion ot the Superior court of the District of Columbia for the purpose of investigating a repcrt or providi.llq services to a family or ch.iid whc is the subject of a report the guardia.n ad litem of a cilild vho is the subject of a report 51 each perscn identified in a rercr-t as a person re.spo.c.si!lie for the neglect of the child or that person 1 s attorney; and (6) the pa.rent, guard.ianr castcdian c= attorney of the child ~b.o is the subject of the repcrt b) The investiqatcrs of a report may divulge the infor:ation obtained from t~e Ch.ild ~rctection Eegister to medical professionals tor the purpose cf ottaining a diagnosis of the child who is the su~ject cf the report c) Each person seeking access to the Child ~rotection Register sh.a..11 show iden"t:ifica tion sa ti~fac tor}" to t!le staff 11.b..ic h iai n tai ns said gegister before access is allowed. Enroll.ad OriginSl I 27 (d} ?he staff whicb ~a.intains the Child Protection Reqist~r shall not rel•ase to those pErsons identified in subparaqraphs (5) and (6) of subsection (a) of this section any information that iden~es the source ct a repcrt or the witnesses to the incident referred tc i~ a :eport un1ess said staff first obtains pe01ission f~cm the source of the ~eport and/or from the vitnesses named in the report e he staff vhich maintains the Child Prctection Register sha..ll release only that informaticn vhic~ is necessary for the purpose of the request and vhich does net' violate the confidentiality of t.b.e per sens identified in the report f) Tne staff v~ich mai.D.tains the Child Protection Register sha.l.l not release the inior~aticD contained in said aegister to aoother jurisdiction unles 1) that jurisdiction tia.s com~arable safeguards for ensuring the confidentiality of information ~egarding persons identifi~d in the report and fer withholding the identity of the source of the report; er (2) the staff obtains per;nissicn fc-r the release of the iAformatiou fiom aac~ person ideDtified in the report a~d f=om the source cf t~e report g) T~e staff which main~ains the Child Protection Register shail maintain a recor~ of eac~ release cf \ 28 information, which record shall ccntai~ the fellowing infor1:1.ation: E2:lrolled Origil::al 1) the date o£ the release of the iDfcrmation 2) to vhom the i.n.formation vas released and the address of that person or institution; and (3} the purpose for which tb.e information was released h) The information in the Child Prctecticn Register shtll be released cral.ly only to the Police and to personnel of the Division and of the Socia.l Services tivi~on of ·the s~perior coart of the Dist:ict cf Colum~ia vb.en they are investigating a report. Ally release of i.nfcrmation to other pel:Sons listed in subsection (a) of this secticn or pursuant to section 204 of this act sha.ll be p:eceded b7 a written request froai the person requestug the inf cr::11.a tion. Sec. 204. Release for Bes~arch and ivaluaticns The staff which ~aintains the Child ~rctection Begister may release illf ormation from said Register for research and eval~ation only upon an orde.r of the su~ericr Ccurt of the District of Columbia P.OVIDED, ao~ZVIS hat no information ·identi.f7iDg the persons na~ed in a repcrt shall ~e made avai.lable to the researcher or evaluate Sec. 205. Noti£icatioo of ?ersons Iden~i!ic.d in a ~e~ort ] rolled Original 29 (a) The sta ff which maintains the Child ~tc ioti. aegi.st'r shall, within seven (7) days trom the that a report is entered in said Heqister, give notic ach person identified in the report of the fact tha repo r t identifies him or her as responsible fer the 31 j aDuse or neglect of the child who is the subject c or {b) This 11otice shall inc.lude t.ne fcllc i ation 1) the date that the report identi!7 e person was ent~ed in the Child irctection 3egister 2) the riqht of the pe.rscn tc revie!O ti.re report, e -xcept i.nfor::iation Yhicb. identifies c rsoc.s mentioned in the report; and (3} the admin.istrative procedures t ollich the person may seek the ccuection of i nfor11a-ticn le or she alleges i s incorrect. Sec. 206. Challenges to !nfor~aticn i Protec o n aeaister The aayor s hali establish, by rnles adc~~a! the District of Columbia Administrative ~r o c sc approved Oc"tober 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 120 i c sec. 1-1501) procedures to i::ermit a ?ersc.:i iden'ti the Child Protection Register to c.1:1.alienge ic c h. ic b. lie or she alleges is incorrect Enrolled original 30 (a) The staff vb.ich maintains the Child Protection Reqiste.r sha.ll E!xt&amp;gt;anqe from each report all infcna tion that identifies any person il1 the report ~pen 1) the eight·eenth birthday of the child, if there is no reasonable suspicion or evidence that a ycwiger sibling is beinq abused or neglected; or (2) the eud of the fifth year after the termination of the social rehabilitation services directed toward the a.b~e a..nd neglect, wh.ichever occurs first b) The staff vhich maintains the Child Protection ieqister shall erpunqe, p~rsuant to -the rule~ adopted u~der sectiou 206 of th.is act, material successfully challenged as incorrect. Sec. 208. P~nalties for UnauthoLi%ed Oissemi~ation of I.n.tormation from the Child ~rotection ~eqister Any staff member of the Child Protection Begister vho willfully relsases i.n..f cr:ation obtained frc: the geqister in violation of this act sha.ll be fined ~ct mc~e than one thousand dcllars (S1,000 Sec. 209. Prosecution all ~io.lations of t!lis act shall be prc~ecuted cy the CorpQration Counsel of the District of Ccla:hia or ll.is or lier designee i.D. the name of the Oist:ict of Colum.i:ia. Sec. 2 10 ffec~i7e ~ate Enrolled Orig1 naJ 31 (a) This title shal.l uot become effective until funds su£fic::ient to meet the e:r::penses of sta.ffin9 and opera ting the child Protection aeqistar are available and the rules implementing this title are adopted by the ~ayor parsuant to the Distric't of Colnmbia 1dministrative Erccedare Act, approved October 21, 1968 (82 Stat. 1204; o.c. Code, sec. 1- 1501 b) No later that ten (10) days after the date the requirements of this section have been ~et, the ~ayor shal.l publish in the District of ColQmhia Register a notice that this tit.le is in ef£ect TIT III CHII.D PBO CTIV S'E!R VJ:CZS DIV I SI C'N sec. 301 Establishment and Purpose (a) There shall be maintained within the te~artment o! euman Resources a separate and distinct Divisicn. The Division shall have as its purposes and futcticns 1) safeguarding the rights and prctectj.ng the welfare of children v~cse ~arents are unable to do so 2} offering highly specialized diag~cstic and tJ:eat~ent services to fami1ies when there i~ speci£ic har: to t~e child's p~ysical or emotional vell-te:ing 32 (3) ensuring that neglected and ato.sed children are proteqted from further experiences and ecnditicns detrimental to their heaithy growth and development; and (q) providing services cu behalf of the child designed to help parents recogni%e and remedy the conditions harmful to the child and to f ll.lfill their ~arental roles more adequately b) The Division sha.l.l have no other function which is not directly related to its child protective service purpose, except that the tve~ty-four (24) hcu~ i.ntake unit may on an emergency basis, after nor~al o£fice hours, of:fer crisis assistance to adults c) The Department of auman Resources shall. support the purpose and function of the Division ty chtaininq suhstitate care for a child whose parents are unatle, even with ava.i.la.ble help, to meet the child's :inimum needs and, where appropriate, by providing to the family of such child services which ara ai~ed at reuni~ing the family as guickly as possi.ble. Sec. 302. Oraanization (a} The Division sha.J.l be administered ty a f u.ll-time Chief vho shal.l be qualified by reason c! training and ex~erience to further the purposes of this ac E:lrolled Origil:lal 33 (b) The Ch.ie.f of the Division shall be respcnsible for all c.hild protectiTe services provided ty the Department of auman Resources, for mc:nitorinq child ~rctective services provided by compact er cont.:act with the De~a~tment of Buman Resources and for coordinatinq activl.ties with the Social services Division of the superior Court cf the District of Coltimbia c) The Division sha.ll have sufficient ~taff, supervisory personnel, alld resources to acccmplish the purposes of this act, including the capacity to pro tide emergency and cont.inuinq service resoarces to atused and neglected children and thei.r families d) Staff qua.lifications, caseload levels, and supervision requirements shal.l be guided by standards set by the Child iel.fare league of America or ether child w@lfare organizations, sha.l.l be published in tbe District of Col~~bia Register for ~u~lic comments. and shall be reviewed by the ~ayor•s Interaqe.ncy !llterdepart~ental CcMmittee on .lb \1Se and Beg lect e} There shall be within the Divisicn a tventy-four (24) hoar intake component staffed by wcrkers s~ecial.ly trained in intake and c:isis· interventicn be unit shall be staf£ed at ali ti:~s, twenty-four (2 bcurs a day, seven (7 da7s a week. This component sb.a.ll maintai:i. the capacity Ezlrolled Origittel. for receivinq reports and fc~ respcnding prcm~tly vith i.nvestiqation and emergency services. This component shalJ. maintain a widely public:i:ed telephone ~umhe~ for receiving reports at a.ll times and sha.J.1 maintain suf~cient telephone lines and qualified staff so that all calJ.s vi.ll be answered immediately by a trained worker. sec. 303. Duties and Hesconsibil.ities (a) The Chief of the Division shall have the following de.ties and responsibilities, a.ny of which may be contracted for with private or other pub).ic agencies 1) to receive and investigate re~crts of neglect as provided in. sections 103 104 and 106 of t.:is act and to assist in t~e deter~ination of the ·need for the removal of an abused child as provided in sec:tion 107 cf this act 2} within ninety (90) days cf taking a child into custody pursuant to sutparagraph (i} of su~secticn (c) of section 304 of this act, to return the child tc the home or to request the filing c£ a neglec~ petitio~ in e Fa~ily Division of the Saperior Coart of the District cf Co1a.mbia 3) to maintain a program of treatment and services for fa.mi1ies of neglected and abused children to prepare annua.lly a plan for chi1d protecti7e se.rvices whic~ shall be revieved a~d cc~mented en by t~e E rolled OrigiJ::al 35 ~ayor•s Interagency Interdepartmental CcmmitteE on Abuse and Heqiect. The plan shall 1) describe the Division's itplementation of this act, including its orqa.ni.%ation, staf£inq, method of operations and fi.Iland.ng, and programs and Frccedares for the receipt, investigation and verification of ~eports B) describe .the provisions fer the determina tio11 of protective and the t=eatment of amel.iorative service needs, and the provisicn of such services C) state the quidelj..nes fer referrals to t.he Pami.ly Division of the Superior Court c£ the tistrict of Columbia; and CD) state the provisions fer mcnitcrillg, eval.uation and planning he first plan shall be made available to the public ~ithin ninety (90) days of the effective date of this act 5) to encourage and assist in the fcr:iaticn of c~ild abuse/neglect teams in hospitals, health and mental heal.th clinics and other appropriate !aciliti~s in the Dist=ict of Colu.mbia; and (6) to take whatever additional acticns a.re necessary to accomplish the purposes of this a l) The Dire~or of the Depa.rtmeDt cf aaman e.esotll:ces, in additio11 toll.is ar bar other re.s;onsi::iiliti~s, s.ha.11 :iave El:lrolled Origi:laJ. 36 the followinq duties and responsibi.lities, any 0£ which may be con:tracted for vith p~ivate or other pa~lic agencies 1) when a child has been adjudicated a neglected c.hild and committed to the Department cf Human Resources, to o£fer rehabilitative services to the child's famil1 2) when reha:C..litative services have fai1ed to reunite a committed c~ild and his or her fai:.ily within a reasona~le time, to prepare a per~ane~t ~lan fer the c~ild 3) to establish or a~tampt to secure ~riority access for protective service. clients, by ccntnc't or agreement vith p:i~~te organizations, other public agencies, or other Department of Euman Resoarcas units tor services necessary for t~e preserTation er reuni.ficaticn of faaiiies. These se~vicas may include bat sha11 net be li:ited to 1) emergency fina.ncia.l aid B) emergency caretakers C) homemakers D) fam:i.ly shelters E) emergency foster homes } facilities providing :11edieal, psychiatric or other therapeutic services G) day ca.re; CH) parent aides/lay thera~ists; Enrol.led Original 37 (ti) to monitor and evalna.te services tc and needs of neglected children and their fa2ilies 5) to compile and publish training materials and provide technical assistance on neglect prevention, identification and treatment; and (6) to prepare and submit tc the aayo the Coancil of the District of Columbia and the public an anneal report which shall inclwie a description of the s~ecific actions take.n to i~plement this act and an evaluaticn of the Division's perfor:ance he .report sha.il include a ful.l statistical analysis of case reports received, an evaluation of services offered, reco~mendations fer additicnal legislaticn or services needed to ful.fi1l the purposes of this act and tlie comments submitted by the aayor•s Interagency !nterdepa.J:t:entai Committee en Al:la~e and ~eglect. T~e first re~ort shall. be submitted not later than one (1) year and ninety (90) days a!ter the effective date of this act. Sec. 304. Authority of the Child Prctective Services Division (a) ihen an investigation made pursuant tc sections 104 or 105 of this act indicates that a child i~ an abu~ed or neglected chiid and in need of services, the Chief of t~e I I \ Enrolled Origi:lal 3S Division is authori%ed to provide or secure any necessar1 servic~s which may include 1) emergency financial aid 2) temporary third-party placement with responsible neighbors c:r relatives for the child and his or her siblings: P:eoVID!D, That the perscn wi·th vhom the child is placed shall not be considered an agent cf the Department of Human aeso lll:ces 3) emergency caretaker (s) vhc enter the home and provide temporary care for the child and b.is er her siblii:iq·s in appropriate cases, when the consent of the parent or other custodian cannot be obtained, nctvithstandinq the provisions of the Act cf t!arch 3, 1901, as amended (31 Stat the placement of homema ers in the home to maintain the child and h.is or her sibli~gs er to assist the parent or other careta.ker in discb.argi.ng b.is er her responsihilities to the child 5) day care for the c.!l.i.ld and his or her siblings 6} counsel.ling services for the child and his or her family 7) medic al e val u a ti on and/or em er e c. cy t= eat :n en t of the child by a quali!.ied physician; and Enrclled Origi 39 (8) other appropriate services or reso~ces available in the community b) ihen an investigation indicates that a child has been left alone or with inadequate supervision and a thi.rd- party placement cannot be made, the Divi.siot is authorized to make a telllpora.ry cust~dial placement of the child: PROVIDED, That 1) notice is left for the parent er custodian which shal.l state the procedure for reclaiming the child 2) efforts cclltinu to locate the paJ:ent 3 the child is re"turned forthwith u~on the reguest of the parent or custodian, unless there is additional evidence of immediate dange.r to the child and Police ac"tiou. is taken pursuant to D.C. Code, secs. 16-2309 (3) or as amended by tb.is act; alld (4) a complaint a.lleqi~g neglect i~ filed with t~e superior Coa:t of the District of Colu~tia A) at the end of five (5) days if the parent or castodian fails to c1ai~ the child vit~iD that time, or (B) immediately npon t~e discovery of adclitionai evidence of :im~ed.iate danger to the ch.ild c) ihen an investigaticn made pursuant tc section 1Qij or 105 of this act indicates that a child i~ an aDu~ed o~ a neglected c!:U.ld a~d •hen it ~as bee~ determined that the \ Enrolled Original "o c.hila ca~no~~e adequately protected by a..c.y of the services set forth in subsections (a) or Cb) of this sectic~ or by any oth~r services, the Chief of the Divisicn is authorized to 1) remove the child with the consent cf the parent, gaardian.&amp;amp or other persoc. actitg in lccc ~arentis 2) request the coqioratioc. Ccuns&amp;amp;l c! the District of colu:bia to petition the Family ~ivision of the Superior Court 0£ the District cf Columbia for a finding of neglect and, where appropriate, the r.~moval of the chiJ.d; and (3) request the ~olice to ~emove the chiJ.d vhen the con.sent of a parent, go.ardia.n or othe~ castc:diat! cannot be obtained and the need to protect the child does not allow sufficiac.t ti~e to obtai~ a court order. Sec. 305. Au thori t v to Provide r!ed ic:a 1 Ca re ihen the Department of Bc.~an Resources has physical custody oi a child pursua~t to subsecticn (t) or (c) of sec~ion 304 of this act or pursuan~ tc t.c. Cede, sec. 16- 2313 or 16-2320, it may 1) authori%e a medical and psychiatric evaluation and/or emergency =edica.l, surgical, denta1, or ~sychiatric treat:ent at any time; and (2) authorize non-e~ergency medical, surgical, dental or psyc~iatric tt'~at2ent, or aotcpsy, Yhen reasonatle Enrolled Origil::uil. 41 efforts to consu.lt the parent have been made tat a ~arent cannot!be consulted ITI.E IV H!Gt.ECT ~gocE!DIHGS sec 01. Short !itle 'this title may be cited as the "Neglect froceedinqs Amendment Act of 1S77 sec. 402. Right to Coansel Section 16-210~ cf the District 0£ Columbia Code is amended ~y a) striking the he.~dillq and all reference thereto in chapter 23 of titie 16 of the Di.strict cf Colambia Code and i~sertinq .in lieu thereof the follcwing S action 16-23 04. Right to Connse.l; Pa.rt y Sta. tus b) striking subsection a~d inserting in lien thereof the f olJ.cvinq b 1) ib.en a child is alleged to be neglected or tt'b.en the teimi.nation of the ~arent and chi.ld relationship is under consideration, the parent, guardian or custodian of the child name~ in the petiticn er in a motion to terminate i.s entitled to be represe~ted by counsel at a.ll critical stages of the proceedings, and, i! financia.l.ly unable to obtain adeqnate representaticn, tc have ccuusel appointed in accordance llit.h rules es~atlis.hed b7 the Sll.perior Couri: of t ie tis"tl:ict of Cola:ntia OJ.led Origi:al 42 n(2) If the child has been living vith·a person other :than the parentr sue~ person shal1 receive notice of th.e neqlect or the termination proceedings and, if t.he chi.ld has been with them for twelve (12) months er more, such person(s) may, upon his or her request, be designated a party to the proceedings: PROVIDED, That if the child has been living with such peJ:son less than twelve (12) months, upon such person's request the judge may, at his or her discretion, dasignate the person a par~y tc the proceedings: PROVIDZ:D, l'urther That such p_erson shall net te a party in those parts of the p~oceedings vhich pertain to the determination of neglect as defined in t.C. Cede. section 16-2301. If such parent or other perscn par~y to the proceedings is financia.lly lllla~le to c~tain adequate representation, coansel shall be appoi~ted in accordance vith rules established by the superior Court ct the District of Co1um.bia. The Division shall in every case involving a neglected c.l:U.1d which tesults in a judicial ~rcceeding, i.ucladinq the ter:ination of the pa~ent a~d chi1d rel.a.tionship pursuant to subchapter III of this chapter, appoint a guardian ad litem vho is an attorney to represent the child in such proceedings. The guardian ad litem shall in generai be charged vit~ the representaticn c£ the c~ild's best interest sec. 403. Visitation Section 16-2310 of the District of Columbia ~de is amended by a) deleting the 11 at the end of su.bsection b) of sncl:l section, adding "and that" in liea thereof and adding a uew subparagraph (3) to read as follovs 3) uo alternative rescurces c:r arrangements a.re available to the family that would adequately safeguard the child vithont requiring removal {b) addi.nq a new subsection (d) tc read as f ollovs: n(d) ihenever a child has been p1aced in shelter care, the child's pa.rant, quard~an er custcdia.n shall be pe.rm.itted v-isita tion a.t least wee kl! unle s.s it appears to the judge that such vis.itaticn rights would crea~e an imminent danger to or be detrimental to the vell- beinq of the child, in v~ich case, the judge ~hall either prescribe a schedule of visitation rights er crder that v i sitation rights not =e allowed Sec 04. Notice and Placement Section 16-2313 of the District of Colambia Code is amended by adding to the end thereof the f ollovinq nev subsection (f f) The depar-tmen't. or agency ha vi.ng cus-:ody, pursuant to a shelter ca.re order, 0£ a child alleged to be a neg.lacted Cllld shall give Ilotice ic ay l::e oral, o= any -r El:lrolled OrigiDal 44 change in the placement of the child to the chiid 1 s parent, the child's guardian ad litem and the child's fester parent, if any, at least forty-eight (48) hours prier to the change .in placement, except that in the case cf an emergency, notice shall be given no later than twenty-four (2 hours xcludinq Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays) after the change. Botice need not be given tc the pa.rent where the Division has found that visitation voald be detrimental to the child or the Division has determi..Ded that the parent should not be apprised of the child's lccation. Open the request of anr person entitled to notice ande.r this subsection, the department or aqe~c1 having legal custody of the child shall a£ford an opportunit! fa an admi.nistrative hearing to review the proposed cb.a.nqe in the placement of the child, except that the department er agency need not conduct snch a hearing if the requester doEs not gua.lify as a party pu.rsua.nt to o.c. Code, section 16-2104 Sec. 405. Physical and ~ental a:i~atic Sabsection (e) of sect.ion 16-2315 of the District c! Cclamtia Code is amended to read as fellows: n (e 1) At anr ti.:iie following the fi.ling of a petition which alJ.eqes a neglected c~ild as defined by o.c. Code, section 16-2301 (9) {C} the Oivisicn may, on its own ~oti.on or th.e .motion of a.ny p.a.r-ty, £er ;cod cause s.b.ovn Enrolled Origil 45 order the mental or physical examination of the parent, guardi~n, o~ custodian of the child vhcse atility to care for the child is at issue 2) Following an adjudicaticn that a child is neglected, the Division may, on its c~u mo~icn or the motion of any party, order a mental or ~hysical examination of the parent, quardian, or custodian of the child whose ability to care for the child is at issue. n (31 The .Division may o:der additional mental examinations to be performed Y independent ext:erts upon a shoving by any party that a prior examinaticn is inadequate } !he resu.lts of the mental or physical examination shall not ~e ad.:tissitle evidence in the fa.ctfind.ing b.earinq unless tha a.l.legaticns contained in the petition set forth fac"t.S vhich support a petiticn pursuant to o.c. Code section 16-2301 (9 C 5 he resu.lts of the :ental or physical e~amination shall be admissible at a dispositional hearing. n(6) The results of the mental or physical examination shall not te admissible as evidence in any criminal t=~cceeciinqs Sec. 406. Predisposi-tion S1:udy and Feport Section 16- 2319 of the District of Columbia Code as amended by the Enrolled Original Prevention of Child lbuse and ~eglect let of 1977, is fnrthes: amended by addinq the following new subsection (c c 1) The report to the Di visicn ill neglect cases shall include, but not be limited to, the fcl.iovinq i.n£o rma ti on Cl) the specific harms intervention is designed to alleviate B) the plans for alleviating these harms including specific services, the proposed providers of the services reco u1ended and the actions the pa rent, guardian, or custodian should take to a.lleviate these harms CC) the estimated time in which the goals of i.ntervention ~ay be achieved or in which it will be knovn that the goals may not be achieved; aDd D) the criteria ~o be used te deter:ine that intervention is no 1onger necessar1; aDd 2) If the remova.l of the c!lild :rem his parent, guardian, or custodian is recommended, the repo~ shall also inc.lllde 1) the recommended type ot placement B) the reasons vhy the chi.ld cannot be protected in b.is or her. b.ome; lt[C) the likely harm the child will s.uffer a·s ·a· resul-t. of tlle saparaticn frc:n his or her pa:ent, Enrol1ed Origilla: 47 guardian, or custodian and recommended stefs to be taken to llil1imi.%e this ha rm and D) the plans for ma.iDtainiDg contact betveen t.b.e parent and child through Viti.ta tion right.s in order to ma.x::imize the rent-chiJ.d relation~hip consistent with the vell-bei.nq of the child sec. 407. Dis~osition of Child ihc is Neglected 4 Delinquent, or In Need of su~ervisie~ Section 16-2320 of the District of Col~mhia Code is amended by a) striking the at the end cf snbparagraph (3) of subsection (a) and adding the fol.loving language: ne:cept that no child shall be crde~ed placed cat.side ~s or ~er home anless t~e Division finds the c:.hild ca~not be protected in t!J.e home and there is aD availatle placement likely to be less damac;ing to the c!Uld than the child's ovu home. It shal.l ~e presu:ed that it is generally preferable to leave a c!l..i.ld in his or her own heme b) strikiDq subparagraph (5) of sutsecticn (a and inser~ing in lieu there~f the f ollcving language 5) T.he Di vision illay make sue h other d.isposition as is not prob..ibited by law and as the Division deems to be in the best interests of tbe child he Division sha.ll have the aathority ~o (i) order any public agency o: tle District o! Coluabia to p:ovide any service Ez:rolled Origillal. 48 t~e Division determines is needed and which is within such aqencr.•s leqal aathority and {ii) order any ~rivate agency receivinq public funds for services to families or cb..ildren to provide any such services when the ~ivision deems it is .ill the best interests of the child and vi-thin the scope of the legal obligations cf the agency c) adding at the end of sabsecticn (a) the follovinq nsw su!:pa.ragraph (6 6 erminate the pare~t and child relationship for the purpo_se of seeki.nq an adc-ptive placement for the ch.i.ld pu.rsnant to sa:chapter III of this c.h apt er d) adding to the end thereof nev subsections (f) and (g) to read as follows Cf) In its dispositional order the Division sha.l.l address the matters set !ortb. in section 16-2319 (c) 01 accepting, modi£ying, or rejacting the ~lan su~mitted pursuant thereto. If tha plan is rejected er major modi=ications a.re made, tAe agency charged with service responsibility shall within ~ll.i=ty {30) days su~mit to t~e Division aDd to all parties a plan ~hich add=esses the ~at~ars delineated in section 16-2319 (t he agency responsibile !or providi.ng the ser7ices shal.l ~romFtly report to t ie Division aJlC. all parties i it is u.oa!:lle for Enrolled original 49 whatever reasons to provide the services delineated in the plan g he department or agency tc vhom the leqaJ. custody of a child has been transferred parsuant to subsection (a) of this section shall give Dctice, which may be oral, 0£ any change in the placement cf the child to the child's parent, the child's gua.r:dian ad litem and the child's £aster parent at least ten (10) days p~ior to the change in placement, except that in the case cf an emergency notice shal.l be qiven no lat than twenty-four (2 hours (exciudiDq Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays) after the chanq e. tlotice cf a change ill p lacemEnt .ce~d not be given to the parent _when the judge has determined that visitation voa.ld. be detrimental tc the child or t!le. jadqe has deter~ined that t.!le pa~ent should not :e aF~rised cf the cnild's location. Open the request cf any ~erscn entitled to notice under is suhsaction the deFart~ent er agency naving legal cus~ody cf the child shall affcrd an opporttmity for an admiDist?=ative heariDg tc .review the proposed change in the placement of the child. Except in the case of an emergency, t~e hearing shall be held and a decisioo rendered prier to a change in t!ie ~lacement. 19 Sec OS. Providing for Review of Ois~c~iticnal orders StL~c.l:.a.pter of cb.a~ter 23 of title 16 is amended by ZXlrol.led Original so (a) renumbering sections 16-2323 through 16-2337 as sections 16-2324 throuqh 16-2338, respectively. {b) add.i.uq thereto a nev section 16-2323 to read as follows 16-2323. Review of Dispositional Crders a) ihen a child has been adjudicated neglected and a dispositional order has been entered :y the Division, the Division shall hold a review hea.ri~g 1) at least every s.i 6) mcnths tor a child under the age of six {6) yea.J ho is ccmmitted to the custody of an aqeney, department, or insti tuticn 2) at least every su (6) mcnths fer a child of any age who is committed to the custody of an agency, depart.men t, or ins ti tntion .tut has not cee n ccmmi t'ted for longer than llfO (2) years 3) at least every year for all ether chil.d.re.n lt least ta 10) days prior tc each review hearing the Division or the depart~ent, agency, or institution responsible for the supervision of the services to the child and his parant, guardian, er custodiall shall submit a repor~ to the Division ~hich shall inclade, cut not be ll:iited to, the following :D:lior:iaticn aJ1 t'.c uuae OrJ.§&amp;gt;!D r t 51 nc1) the services provided or offered to the cili.ld a.nd hi~ pa re.n t. guardian or other custcdian; n (2) ally evidence of the a:elicraticn of the condition &amp;amp;hich resulted in the findinq of neglect and any evidence of new problems which vou.ld adverse.ly affect the c!l.ild 3) an evaluation of the cocperaticn of the parent, quardian or custodian with the tivisicn or the appl.icable department, agency, or instituticn; n (4) in those cases in which the custcdy of the child has been vested in a department, agency, institution or person other than the _pa.rant A) the exte.nt to which visitation .has occurred and any reasons why visitation has net occurred or has been infrequent CB) the estimated time in which the child can be returned to the home, a~d C) whetb.er t~e agency bas initiated or intends to initiate the f.i.l.i.ng by the corForaticu Coansel 0£ a motion requesting the ter~i!lation c.f the parent and child relation.shiF and any reasons why it dces not intend to initiate the filing 0£ such a motion; a~d 5) such other infor~ation as may te reqaired by rules of the supe-rior Cou:t of tb:e tist:ric~ of Cola::ibia 52 n (c 1 notice of a review heari.nq under t.his sectiou shal.l !e given t.o all parties and their attcrneys of record as prescribed by rules o.f the Superior coart. of the District of Columbia. n (d f the Oivisicu fi.nds that the co=a:i.tment of the cn..i1d. to a depai:t~ent, agency, instituticn er person other tlia.11 the pa.:ent is no longer necessary tc safequa.rd the vel.fare of the cnild, the Division may crder 1) the c~i1d returned to the home and the provision of supervisicn or ather services; or n (2) a.ny other disposition authorized by section 16-2320 (a} Sec. 409. Court Cost and E~penses Secticn 16-2325 of t~e District of Columbia Code is amended tc read as follo~s a) If, at tlle dispositional heari~g er thereafter, t~e Division finds, a£ter due notice and a hearing, that the parent or other person legally obligated tc care for and snpport a child subject to proceedings ander this suhcnapter is financially ab.le to pa1 t!:ie Divisic12 may c-rder him or b.er to pay all of or part o.f the costs cf 1) physical and menta.l exami~atic~s and treatment of the child ordered by the Division 2) except in neglect cases, a rea~cnabl: cactpensat·ion for the s~vic.es and related expenses cf l!!arclled Origiilal 53 counsal appointed by the DiVision tc reFresent tile child; a.nd n-(3) in neqlect cases, a reascllble ccm i=ansa ti on for tile services and related expenses ot ccansel a~pcinted by the Division to represent the parent or person b) Payment under t!U.s section shall be made as prescribed by rules cf the superior ccurt cf the District of Colu.m..bia. n Sec 10 ermination of 'Parental Sights Chapter 23 of title 16 of t~e District of Columbia Cede is amended by adding to ~e end thereof a new S~bc.tiapter III to read as fol.lows Su.bc.hapter ll I=roceedi.n gs aegardi.ng be erm.i.na tion oi Parental Rights of Certain Neglected Children "Section 16-2351. Purpose of the sutchapter; Construction of Provisions a) Tb.e general purposes of th.is subchapter are ~o 1) ancouraqe stal:lil.ity ill t.be lives cf certain children who have been adj~dicated neglected and have been removed from tile custody of their parent by providing judicia1 procedures for the per:anent ter~icaticn of the par~nt and child relationship in the circums-tances set for:.h in tnis sabchapter 54 2) ensure that the consti t ational tights of all parties are recogni:ed and enforced in aJ.1 ~rcceedin9s conducted pursuant to this subchapte.r vhile en~uring that the fundamental needs ·cf children are not subjugated to the i.llterests of others: and 3) increase the op port uni ties fer the prompt adoptive placement of c:.b.ildren for whcm parantal rights have been terminated. 11 b b.is subchapter shall be liberally cc:nstrued to promote the general purposes tated in this section Section 16-2352. Definitions a As used· i.n th.is su.bchapter, u.t.les~ the context otherwise requires: 11 (1 parent and child relaticDshif' includes all rights, powers, privileges, immuniti~s, dutie~ and o.b.liqations exis~ing under la bet~een a parent and child, including rights of inheritance he words a~ply equally to every c~ild and every i:arent regardless of th~ marital status of the parents cf the child C 2 termination of the E'are ~t and child. relationship' means the adjudication that a child. is free from tha cnstody and central of either c: beth c! his or her l.iving pa.rents by means oi a cell.rt order that cc~p letaly se-~ers and e-.xtillguishes 't.he pare.n a-.nd child re·lationshi SS b) The terms found in this subcbapter ~hich are defille4 in section 16-2301 of this chapter shall be given the same definition herein. nsection 16-2353. Grollllds for Terminaticn c~ Parent and Child Relationship n (a) 1 judge may enter an order fer the termination of the parent and child relationship when the judge finds from the evidence presented, after giving due consideration to the interests cf a.ll parties, that the termination is i.n the best interests of the child b) In determining whether it is i~ the chiJ.d 1 s best interests th.at the parent and c~ild relationship be terminated, a judge sha.11 consider each of the fol.loving factors: n (1) the child's need for continuity of care and caretakers and for timely integration i~tc a ~table and permanent hoae, takinq in~o account the ditferences in the development and the concept o! time of children cf different ages 2) the physical, mental and e~oticnal health of all individuals involved to the deg~ee that such af£ects the welfare of the cll.ild, the decisive consideraicn being the physical, mental and emo~ion.a.i needs of the child 56 3) the qua.J.ity of the interaction and intereiatioush.ip of the child vit.h his er her parent, sibl.ioqs, relative and/or caretakers, i~cluding the foster parent; and n (ti to the extent feasible, the child's cpinion of his or her own best interests in the matter Section. 16-235 aotions a} A motion for the termination of t.he parent and child relationship may be filed by the District of Columbia government or by the child t!i~ough his er hEr legal representative {b) 1 motion for the termination cf the ~aren't and c:~d relationship may be filed only when the child who is t.he subject of the motion has been adjudicated negl~cted at least six {6} months pti.or to the filing of the motion a~d the child is ill the court-ordered cu.stcdy cf a department, agency, institution or person other than the farent; except that the motion for termination may be filed i~mediately n (1) upon an adjudication t.hat the child was abandoned: or 2) when, despite reasonable effcr~s, the parent could not be iocated for the factfindi~g hearing and durinq the thres (3) months ptior to the hearillg. Enrolled Original. 57 c} l motion for the termination cf the Farent and chiJ.d relationsip shall include but not ~e limited to 1) the name, sex, date and ~lace of birth, and current placement of the child; parent 2) the name and title of the petitioner 3} the name and address of the c:l1ild's "Cq) a plain and concise statement of the facts and opinions on ~hich 'the termination of the parent and child relationship is so~~ht 5) a speci.fication as to the health of the ch..ild 6) a. statement as to the general. prcspects for o.r the barriers, if a.ny o tb.e adq:ticn cf the c.hild; and 7) a statement as to the varicas efforts taken by the moving party to locate the ~arent of the child d ihen any facts reqllirad parsaa.nt to subsection (c) of this section are not knovn to the mcvinq party, if he or she shall so state in the ~otion, er en a mcticn by any party, for good cause shown, t.he judge may direct the fili~g 0£ a bill of particulars to inzo the ~cving party of the precise nature of the allegations cc~tained in the motion for tAe te~:i.ria..ti..on of the pa.=ent a~d child relaticnsnip SS "Section 16-2355. consideration of Ter:inaticn of the Parent~a.nd Child Relationship at Review Bearinqs a) lfter a child adjudicated neglected by the Division pursuant to this chapter has been committed by the Civision to the custody of a department, aqency er institution for more than eighteen (18) months and no heari~q en a motion for the termination of the parent and child relaticnshi~ has been held vith.in the precedi.ng twelve (12 acnths, the Di vision sha.ll, a.t a reviev hearing, determine why a motion to terminate the parent and ild relationshi~ has not been £iled b) 7or each cllild v l:a.o remains in custcd. y for thr2e (3) years or more, the Division shall, at each annual review hearing, determine vhy a ~otion to terminate the parent and child relationships has not bee~ filed Section 16-2356. Parties "Parties to a proceeding for the terminaticn of the parent and child relationship shall be the child, the parent of the nailled child, aJld the. aqe11cy having the legal custody of the child he j adqe may at his or her discretion, name on his or her ovn mcticn or in response to a moticn £or joinder or i:ltervention, join additional ~a~ties to a pxoceeding to terminate the parent and ~ild rela~icnship Section 16-·23:57. Notice Enrolled Orig!:u 59 11 (a) ii.hen a mo ti en to term.illa te the pareD t and child relati~nship is filed, a jadge sha.ll ~rcmptly set a time for an adjndicatory hearing and shall cause notice thereof to be given to all parties. 11 (b) 1 judge sha.ll direct the issuance tc and personal service apon the child's parent of a sammots together with a copy of the motion to terminate the parelrt and child relationship. 11 (c) ihen it is ap~opriate to the proper dis~csition of the case, a jadqe may direct the service of a summons upon otner persons d) If a personal. service llilder this secticn cannot be effacted, then notice shal.l be made ccnstruc:tive.ly pursuant ~o rules of the superior Court of the tistrict cf Columbia Section 16-2358. Cooduct of Bearings a) l.ll hearings a.lld proceedi..tlgs c~ a moticn to terminate the parent and c~i.ld rela~ioc~hiF shall. te held by tne judge, without a jury b) All hearings and tlroceedings held FursuaDt to this subehapter shall. be recorded by appropriate ~eans c) Except in hea.rings 1:.o declare a perscn in contemFt of court, th.e general public sha.ll be e:xclcded from hea.rings and proceeci.:lgs a=ising pursuant to ~his su~chapte.r. only persons necessa.ry to sac.b. hea:i.ngs a.nd Froceed.i.ngs shall l::e Enrelled Original 60 admitted, but a judqe may, pursuant to rules of the Superior coart bf the Di.strict cf Columbia, admit such ether persons as have a proper interest in the case er the wcrk of the Division on the condition that they refrain frcm divu.lqinq ill.formation identiLying the child involved in the proceed.ill.gs or memters of his or her fattily d) I! a judge finds it is in the test interests of the child, he or she may temporarily e%cludE the child from any proceed~g. Onder no circumstances, hcvever, may counsel in the case be excluded Section 16-2359. Adjudicatory Searing a l judqe sh.all oe_gin the ad judicatory heari.ng or determining whether all parties are present and whether proper notice of the hearing has been given. If the parent has been given proper notice bat has failed tc appear the judge may proceed in his or her absence b) l judge shall hear evidence F=eseotad by the moving party and the burden of proof shall. rest u~cn the mcving party c very party shall have t.!le rig.ht tc t:rese.n"t evidence, to be heard in his or her o"n behalf and to cross- examine witnesses called by another party d} All evide~ce which is releva matetial, and competent to t~e issues before the judge shall oe ad~i~~ed. Em-oiled Original 61 e) Botwithstandinq the t=rovison.s c:f D .c Code, secticms 14-306 and 1~-307, ne~ther the hustand;vife privilege nor the physician/patient privilege shall be a grou.nd for excl~ding evidence in any t=rcceeding brought llJlder th.is subchapter. nsection 16-2360. Disposition Azter !erminaticn a) If a judqe finds that suf£icieDt grcunds exist for the termination of the parent and child relaticns.hi the judge shall so order and decree and shall vest the leqal custody of t.b.e c!iild i.n a dep.aJ:tment, a 9enc1 er ins ti tu ti on b) The dep art;nent, agency or insti tu ticn to wlllch a chi.ld is committed a£te.r _the ter~inaticD cf the parent a~d child relationship pursuant to this su..bchapter shall. be responsible for seek~q ~he prompt adoptive placement of the chi.ld and, if an adoptive placement has net been made within th..ree (31 months, the department, agency, or institution sha.ll list t..b.e child on all appropriate local, regional and national adoption exchanges. I! an adcFtive ~lacement has not cee..n made wi~hin six {6} months of the termination, a hearinq shall be ~eld and with~ every six (6) months thereafter the department, agency or instituticn shall. report to the Division on its ei!orts tc secure an adoptive placement, including but not l.i.mi-eed tc the following in·for:ra ti on Ez:rolled Original. 62 1) the extent to which an adc~ticu has been explored vith the c:.hi1d's foster parent an~ any reasons vby a..n adoption by the foster parent is net ap~rc~riate 2) a1l adoption exchanges with which the child has been listed and the date of each listing; and 3) the limitations placed on the families to be considered for the adoption of tbe child c he i.n.formati.cn provided pursuant to subsec:tion (b) shai.l b~ provided to the guardian ad litem at least ten (10) days prior to a reviev heari.Ilg. n (d} A notice 0£ a review hearing shall be given as prescribed by rules of the superior Court cf the District of Col~mbia to the child's guardian ad litem. lny person with vhom the cb..i.ld has been living for six (6) mcnths er more shall be given notice cf hearings and shall u~cn his or her request be joined as a par~y to a review hearing e) If the OivisicJl ii.J:.ds that the defartme.nt, agency or institaticn vested with ~he custcdy cf the chi1d is not making suff.icien t efforts to secure an ado ~ti ve placement for the child or that i~appropriate limitations have been placed on potential adoptive families, the ~ivisiou ma1 order such add..iticna1 effcr~s as it deems a~propriate or ~ay order that the i~position of inappropriate li:itations be el..i ina ted or il1a y trans.fer t!le pover to c:on~ent to an Enrolled Or!g!llal 63 adoption together vith the vestment of legal custody to any other l.icensed chi1d placement agency Section 16-2361 ffect of Terminaticn Decree a) An order terminating the parent and child relationship diiests the pa.rent and the child of all legal rights, pave.rs, privileges, im:unities, duties and obligation~ wit!l. respect to each other, except the right of the child to inherit f rc~ his or her parent he rig~t of inheritance of the child shall be termi~ated cnly by a final order of adoption. n(b) ihen a..11 order ter~atiJlq the ~arent and c..b..ild relationship has been issued, the parent vhcse rights have been ter~i..11ated shaJ.J. not thereatter be entitled to notice of proceedings for the adoption of. t.!le child l::y a..11ctner nor shal1 such parent have any right to otject to the adoption or otherwise to participate in the proceedings Section 16-2362. Decrees a very order of the Division terminating t~e parent and child re.lationship shall be in vriting and shall recite the findings upon v~ich such o:der is tased, inclading findings ~ertaill.inq to the cow:t's jur~sdicticn b iotvithstanding t!le provisions of t. c. Code, section 16-2329 as renambered by the Erevention of Child A..bo.se ar.d. Neglec.t let cf 1977, a.ll orders terminati:ig t.:i.e \ \ EZlrolled Origi:la1 64 parent ud c:.hild relationship entered pursuant to this subcnapter shall not be final and effective antil the time for ~otinq an appeal has expired and, if a notice of appeal has been eutared, the order shal.l not become effective until the date of the final dispcsitiou of the a~~eal Section 16-2363. Confidentiality cf Seccrds he provisions of sections 16-2331 and 16-2332 of this chapter, as renumbered by the ?reventicn of Child Abuse and Beglect let of 1977, sha.ll apply to all juvenile case records and juvenile scd.al records as defined therein vhi~h are created pursaant to the proceedings under this subc:hapter Section 16-2364. On.lawful Disclosure "ihoever vill.fally discloses, receives, makes use of, or knowingly permits the asa of informatic~ ccncerninq a child or other person in violation of sectic~ 16-23E3 of this subchapter shall be quil~y cf a misdemeancr and u~on convic:tioo ~ereof shall be fined not ~ere than two hundred aJld fifty dollars (S250) or imprisoned !or net more than ninety (90) days, or both. 1 violaticn of this section sha.l1 be prosecuted by the CorporatioD ccunsel cf the District of Colamhia. nsection 16-2365. Termina~ion Dacrees c~ Other J urisdict icns E:lrc1led Origi.a2! 65 "If the pare ut and chiJ.d re.la tio ns hi i: has l:een termi~ted by jadiciai decree in ancthex juri~dicticn that decree, un.less it is against the pnbJ..i.c policy of the District of Columbia, shal.1 have the sare f crce and effect ill the District of Co.lum~ia as to matters within the jnrisdiction of the Cistrict of Columbia court sec. 41i. This act shal.l take effect i:ur!uant to the provisions of section 602(c) 0£ the Dist.rict cf Columbia Se.lf-Government a..nd Governmenta.l Raorgani:aticn Act. f 1 Do"et No: 2-48 t_tJ n a.w tlf!dM1¥1 Secretary to the Cou:ic:il g JUt. f1l7 Q Dl.aa.pprcvec:i in pa.rt lle!e:n:c:e I 1 i i I 8 JUL 19T L/{:J l I r L l ·i DoC"ame:t Budget Ac oc.s o. c amp;c:ud wit!:i.out Ma.yor's Sign&amp;amp;tu.re Sec:ret:Lry to le Cou.:tc:il Council Reena.c:ei.ent: o VOICZ VO Secreta y to th.e Cou:c:il 0 aou. c.u.r. von c::nu•C\ amp;»au f n: I I I 1 c c:r c ac11 us I I I -a c c s•aoi I i t I TUCA I I I I .ii M.A.50~ I I F o\3..DY I I I I II MOO Z. o. I I 3 .A 1:1 y I I I I ii MOOR I I C:U 1 Q: i I I I !I ROI \ I I ·oIXON I I I I II £.:CU ION I I tM•m:u• Ve&amp;amp;e 3 LI Reena.ct::e:.t roved LI Ma.yor1 s V'et:o S1U:2.i:.ed SW:imitted. to tlte Conp-es s: Sena.te Ac:t:.c:c Resolution Nw Oer I I 11 s \.ta uI;'i c I I I I I I lf W'TT SON I I I I I I I II ~VINTZ I I I I I I I ii I I I I I I I I I II I I I I I r I amp; v I Sec:eea.ry to t!:i C.:iw:.c:il Sec:reca.ry to ~e Council esiciet:.t 0£ the ti. S. Sccreta.ry to t!le Ccu Lc:il Haase Action lesolution Nu er Cle!'k ci ~e Hc:us e i \ I \ cketNo 2 4_8 First llea.&amp;amp;i Action: 5/17 /77 W VOIC: VOTE: Adoctee unanimCW Cl.tV LeR..l4~1 Secrec:&amp;amp;rr to t:ie Co~ LJ ltOLL CAl.L VOTE uo•u I C I I i c:1v C C• I u•c I I 1 c:i cu i •re i I 1 TtJ'CXZ3. I I I I !l~ON I f I I ii s:i A trr i :i c I I I I ~y I I I I !I MOO t.Z. o. I I I I II \\~ 5'0N I I I I 3.A:a.3.Y I I I I MOOIU J. I I I I ii W f I I I I Cl.A..O..te I I I I ii :a.ou_o I I I I I I I I O!XCN I I I I ii s~c r cN I I I I II I I I I l:-ila laa v A 9ft&amp;amp r Q VO.tel: VOTZ: Sec-ecary to b.e Council \ Q ltOI t. c u.l. VOTZ: II MASON II &amp;lt;.1.CC.R.Z o. I :17'L: SON 11 MCOE.Z I !I I ii 5/ 31/77 VOIC:Z VOTZ: Adooted Unanimouslv 0 aoLL CA.l.l. VOTZ l I I I I ~U..SON I I I ·p l. r lt;C I I I I Ttrc:.t I S t l I I I I :j CC Z i. I i I I 1~·r~cN I I I I £ I I I I IMCO I I I I l f-:Z I I I I I cu I I i I :1 ot..o I I I I I I I I DIXCN I I I I ·j s:,c z N J I I I I I I I 7 Y'~lci I l I I I r I</search-text>
  </meta>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>102</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>104</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>105</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>106</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>106a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.06a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>106b</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.06b"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>107</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>108</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>109</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.09"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>109a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.09a"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>I-A</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>151</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.51"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>152</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1301.52"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>II</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>201</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>202</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>203</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>204</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>205</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>206</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>207</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>208</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>209</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1302.09"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>III</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>301</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>301a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.01a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>302</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>302a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.02a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303a</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.03a"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303b</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.03b"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303c</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.03c"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303d</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.03d"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>303e</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.03e"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>304</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>305</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>306</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>307</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>308</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>309</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.09"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IIIA</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>331</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.31"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>332</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.32"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>333</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.33"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>334</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.34"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>335</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.35"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>336</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.36"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>IIIB</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>351</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.51"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>352</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.52"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>353</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.53"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>354</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.54"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>355</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.55"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>III-C</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>371</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.71"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>372</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.72"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>373</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.73"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>374</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1303.74"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>V</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>501</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.01"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>502</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.02"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>503</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.03"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>504</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.04"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>505</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.05"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>506</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.06"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>507</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.07"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>508</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.08"/>
    </section>
    <section>
      <num>509</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1305.09"/>
    </section>
  </container>
  <container>
    <prefix>Title</prefix>
    <num>VI</num>
    <heading/>
    <section>
      <num>601</num>
      <codified:stub doc="D.C. Code" path="§4-1306.01"/>
    </section>
  </container>
</document>
