<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-25">
  <num type="law">2-25</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-09-28</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-25.pdf">D.C. Law 2-25</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3718</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-25 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-136, which was referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 14, 1977 and June 28, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on July 8, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-56 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>( \ J COUNCIL OF THE DISTRICT OF COLOMBIA NOTICE October ll, 1977 D.C. LAW 2-25 "Advanced Life Support Act of 1977" Pursuant to Section 412 o f the District of Columbia Self-Govern:lllent and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of ColUll\bia adopted Bill No. 2-136 on first and second readings June 14, 1977, and June 28, 1977, respectivel y. Following the signature o f t.he Mayor on July 8, 1977, this legislat.ion· was assigned Act No. 2-56, p~blished in the JUly 22, 1977, edition of t he o.c. Register, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c l) of the Ac t. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Co~gressional Review Period has expired and, therefore, cites the following l eg i s lat ion as o. c. Law 2- 25, effective September 28, 1977 j STERLING TU ·tER Chairman of~~e Counc il (Vol 24, o.c. Register, 817, July 22, 1977) \ gt C LAW z-zs IN THE COUNC[L OF THE DI STRICT OF C~L UM81A September za, 1977 To a mend the Good Samarit a n Act of the District of Columbia, to e s tablish a prog ram for the certification of eme r gency medical technician/paramedics. and fo r other pu rposes BE IT ENACTED SY THE COUNCIL OF THE DISTRI CT OF COLu~eIA That this act may be cited as the "Advanced Life Support ~c t of 1977 Sec. z. The Act to relieve physicians of liability for ne gligent medical treatment at the scene of an accide nt in the Di str ict of Columbia approved November a, 1965 (79 Stat. l 302; o. c. Code s ec 2-142) is amended to read as foll ows a) Any person who in good f ai t h r enders emergency medical care or assis tance t o a n injured per s on at t he s cene of an accident o r o t her e mergenc y in t he Ois tr ict of Col umoi a outside o f a hos pi t al wi t hout t he expectati on o f receiving or intending t o seek compensation from such injured per son for s uch se rv ice. s ha ll no t oe li abl e in civil dama~e s for any act o r o~is s ion not cons titut ing ross ne 9l igence. i n the course of rende ri ng such care or s s istance I r l I I Zzlrollod Orieil::al 2 b) In the case of a person vho re nders ecer9ency aed.i.cal care or assistance in circucstances described in subsection (a) of this section and who is net licensed or certified by the District o1 Columbia er by an7 state to pro•ide 11edical care or assist ance, tbe ll11ited immQO:it:r provided in subsection (a o t this secti sball apply to snch person: PROVIDED That the pe r so n shall relillg uish the direction of the ea.re of tbe injured ~erson vben an appropriate person licensed or certified by tbe District of Colambia or by any state to provide medical care or assi stance assumes respoosil&amp;gt;ility tor the care of the injured person. tech11ic:ian/para111edic v bo, in good fait h. and parsaant to instructions either di r ectly or via telecom::unication frog a licensed physician, renders advanced emerge ncy aedical ca.re or assistance to an inju.red person at the scene of &amp;amp;.II accident. or other e:ier geocy or in transit from the scene of ao accident or emergency to a hospital shall oot be liable a c:i.Til daa1a&amp;lt;Jes for any ac:t. or 011issic11 no.t constituti:ig gross ne&amp;lt;Jligence in the course of rendering sue~ ad,anced e:ergency medical care or assistaoee d) 1 licensed physician vbo in good !aith gi ves eaer&amp;lt;Jency medical instructions either directly or via 3- tele communication to a certified eaer;ency ae dical technician/para:Dedic for the purpose ~f pr~~idlng a~ianced eaergency medica~ care to an in jured person at the scene of an accident or other emergency or in transit !ro:zi the· scene of an accident or eiergency to a hospital sball not be liable in civil da:11a9es ~or any act or clllissien no.t constituting gross negligence in the coarse of giving such emergency medical instructions. ace&amp;gt or the purposes of t.liis section, the ter:D •emergency medical tec!Lc.i.cian/paraaedic' means a pezson who 40 has been trained in advanced emergency xedical care, employed in that capacity and certi.fied bJ the appropriate o n 9overnoental certifying authority in the District. of Columbia or in any state to 1) carry out all phases of basic life support; 11 (2) administer drugs under the written or oral authorization including via teleccieanication, of_a licensed physician 3) adlti.nister intraveneus ~elations under the written or oral authori:atioa, including tia telecommunication, of a licensed physician; and 4) carry out, either direct.17 or via telecocmunication instructions from a licensed physician I Z:zrolled Origia~l -4- certai:n other pha.ses of advancei life SUFPOit as authoriied I bJ the appropriate governmental certilyiDCJ aatbcrity sec. 3. The District of Columbia regulation entitled "1 Begulation to tstablisb Standards fer l =bulances an d Hedical personnel and to l!rovide ftJr ?heir Certi.fication approved December 13, 1977 (aeg. 72~29) is anended as f ollows a) by striking "Coa:missioner" vha re ver it appears and inserting in lieu t hereof "ea1or b) by adding to the end of 11ectie11. 1 the folloving nev definiticn f Emergency ned!cal Teccnicia n/ Para~edl.c• means a person vho possesses .a valid Emergency aedical Teclutlcian aramedic's certificate issued pursuant to t~is regalation c) b y adding a nev subsectiea (c) to section 2 to read as follows c lo perso.i firm cer;:oration association or government agency shall advertise or disse11.inate ·infor mation to the public that Ecergenc:y lledic:al Teciinician/Paraaedic asb!llance service is cffered anles s tbat service is, in !act, provided by aergeacr aedical Technician/Para.m.edics i~ mobile inten.siv units, as defined by the aayor parsuant to subsectio c) of section 4 of tbis reqalation, on a continuous twecty our (2Q) hour I I Olled Original 5- per day basis. I! advertising or i nfcr"c:a ticn "regarding Z•ergenc1 eedical Technician/Paranedic a ~bula nce ~ervice appears on aAY vehicle it may only appear en t~ose mobi.J.e intensive care unit •ehicles, as detilled by the 11ayor pursuant to subsection (c) ot section q c! this regulation, 11.tilized on a continuoas .tventy-four (24) hear per day basis to provide service d) by adding to section 3 the follcving nev subsection (kl k) The 11ayor may el!tahlish additic_nal J cense r equiremen ts !or an a m.balance ser?ing as a mobile intensive care onit, as defined by the ~ayer pursuant to sobsec:t.ion (c) of section q of this regulation, including aaditional fees for such a license e) by adding to section 4 the f cllcving nev subsection (c c) The 11ayor, vith the ~ssistance of the District of Colunbia Advisory Com~ittee en Emergency aea..i.cal Serrices, is authorized in his or her discretion to promulgate regulations speci..fying additicoal equipment and ebicular requirements for an ambulaoce ~ervin9 as a mobile intensive care ani t i J (f) by amending section 6 as follcv r~l.lcd Originul -6 1) subsections (a) through (h) are rodesigna ted as paragraphs (a 1) tlirc:ugh {a 8 respectively 2) the heading "lcibulance Per.5onne1. 1• is aJ1ended to read as fol.lows Emergency lledical technicians and Emergency aedical. Tec:hnician/Paramedic.s i 3) the terms "licensing licen.5ed and aucense" are stricken and the terlls "certi.fyiog certified and certificate respectively, are iaserted ill lieu thereof q) a nev subsection b) is added to r ead as follows b 1) The !layer, vithin thirty {30 Jays of the effective date of this subsectic shall v ith the assistance of the District of Columtia J.dvi!ory Coomittee !or EillergencJ aedical. Services prcmulgate rules and regulations establishing standards aad Frocedures for the certification of Emergency lledical 'Iecbnician/ Pua1:1edics such standards and procedures shall ine.lude: a reqaire:ent f or the Satisfactory completion Of a training C~lltSE in eDergency catdiac and noncardiac care, approv'd by the .nayor, coasi$ti ng ot not less than !our hundred (QOO) hours of I I \ r 7- classroo= and pr act ical ins~ruction, including, but not li=ited to, instruction in i) all ~bases o! basic life s upport, and J ii) the administration of drugs and intravenous sol utions a ad er t l:e vri tten .and oral aathoriza ti on, either directly or via telecc:i cunlca ti on, of a licensed phjsician IB) a require itea t !cir the initial and t he continual dete rmination of skills t l:rougb .oral P,tten a nd practic:a.l en rlnations C) provisiens prescribing the li!a ~npport services vbic~ car be ~roTided by ?ce~gency !adical Technician/Par amedics including tbcs11 services vbi ch -require the supervision b y talecccmunication of a licensed Fhrsiciaa D) proTisions for t~e .coctin uity of eaergencf =edical care and assista11ce acro:ss sta~e borders including a provision for t he reciFrecal r eco9nitio11 of medical personnel certified oz liceased by another jurisdiction: E1IOVlltD, T.bat t .his section shall not be construed t o allo w such personnel t o Ferform any services •hlch they are not licensed o r certified bJ t he pare ot jurisdic~ica to perfor and \, \ 1 l \ I Enrollod OrieiDQl 8 l provisions fcir the rene va l denial, suspension and revocation ot certification 2ROVID?D, That an examination f or tbe r eneval cf the certification of an !aergency Hedical Technician/Pa ramedic shall be requ ired at least ever y tvelve (12 mon ths 2 o applicant aay be ce.rti.fied as an Z:aergency edica l Technician/Para1J1e die anless the' applicant has satisfied al. l conditions fo r certificaticn as an ae.rgency l!edical technician as required pursua nt to subsection (a) of this section 3) During t he fractical fCr~ion of t~ e training program specified in subparagraph (1) of subsection {b) of this section, the 1J1ergency 11edical teehnician/Para1J1edic t rainee shall be s upervised f continuously by a physician or by a registered nurse g) by ame nding secticn 7 to read as f ollovs section 7. The l!ayor i s hereby aiithor ize d and directed to pi:cvide upon the payment ot sucn fees as be or she may establish and to approve cour ses of s~udy and training designed to 1) prefare intei:ested persoos for those oral vritten and practical examinations I l r equired for certification as an Emergency eedica 1 Tee!l11ic:ian: z:ergency Medical Tecbnician for certi!i catioa as an tnerqeucy aedieal technician/Paramedic and El:lrollod Original 3) as3ist a certi fi ed E:er9enc7 ~edical Technician or a certified E~ergency aedical Tec~nician/Paraaedic in improving a nd apdating his or her sld.ll.s, and in pi:epating a certified :E11ergenc7 aedicaJ. Technician/Paramedic for the e%amination for t~e reneva.l of his or her certification h) by deleting the vcrd s "of $2.00" wherever they ap.Pear 1:n sections 3 (j 6 (a 8} and e cl of llegalation 72-29 4lld insertill!J in liea thereof the vords "in an amount determined ~J the !ayer and (i) by amendiDg section 9 as follovs 1) by inserting the vords or person certified" after the vord "licensee" wherever it appears 2) by insertillg the words "or certificate" after the vord "licens e" vberever it appears; 41ld t ~1 \ \ { Ellrollod Ori~inal -10 3) by inserting the vord s 11oc r 2 erqency Medical Technician/Para11edic as the case may be after the vo.tds 1•~11erqency !Sedical lechrician" vherever they appear. Sec. II. Section 2 of the District of Colui:il:ia E111;iloyee Joo-Liability let as ac;eJlded by ~he "lledical Em lo7ee Protection Act of 1975 11 effective !larch 2E, 1976 (D.C. I.av 1~59) is turther amended by l.Jlsertinq after t he vords "nurses, nursing assistants but befcre the vords •physicians' assistacts" the folloving l~gcase e11ergency medical technician emergenc1. 2edical technician/paramedic See. s S11bsection (a) of section 9 of the "District of Colu111bia Oni!ora Narcotic Drug let a roved June 20 1938 (52 Stat. 790; D.c. Code sec 33- 409(a is uiended by inser~ng a.:fter the vord "nurse" the vcrds certified e•ergency medical technician/paramedic Sec. 6. This act shall take effect as Ercvided in section 602(c) of t he District of Columtia Sel!-Gov~rnment and Governmental Reorganiz ation let 2- 136 tlocJ&amp;lt;ct ~o nnc P.ucU:g A&amp;lt;t!~a Tune 14, 1977 [}9 VOlCC: VO't':S Adopted Unan {}))JJ.11.M&amp;gt; Y2 Sec Cil.r co Qe Co~ LJ S.OU. C~ VOT:l I •H t I 4 e iot.-cat I 1 t I a..a S t t i \ T11C1&amp;lt I I I I ii MASCN I I I I s A C I I I I I J I I q .i.&amp;lt;COAZ l l I I I M Wll..SC::i I I I I &amp;lt;U I \ I I I I 't ~{COP I l I I ·I n I I I I I c t..l \ I I I I 4 0~ I I I I l I I I I 1 Di:tC=\ I j I ii s 1 I I I I I I I 1 Z:ai•Wu f 1 I LJ VOlC VOT U ira I I r t I c t i I I CS lll.•C'\ 1 1 1' I kt nc gt I i M gt SON I jSr ti r~C I ~1.CCJ.Z I p c;o; 3..A 1 lt;COU I· J. I J!w o. Ct l a: I t 3.Q.w.J 1 I icrc I I s c u J t J \.a M :r. 7 1 S.c:ooOl to tb.o C.o U n-t. An&amp;amp;t or Uqea.cy Act Tune 28, 19 77 LJ !\OU. CA 11'0-.Z: i I I t I o t l I t I r. I Ci:\i IC I J Tuc::c:i. l I I I •JM,i.SCN 1 I I I .t i..u G I I I I HA Y I I I I q tee 0. I I I I :1wu soN I I I I I !I .L~:l 'f I I I :l~lCO J. I I I I 1rcr"t"Z1 I I I I I C1-L,-C.CZ I I I I 'f ll.OL..A..U: I I I I I I I I I oao~ I I I I :l ~JC:cz 1 I I I d I I I I ;c_.i n.a \ amp « I i j I l J.2('Appnvo•i f l)U&amp;amp;~p:&amp;lt;&amp;gt;Y~ Q Ilh"J&amp;gt;provod £ rt ue.nc.ce .Doc:um lt e..dstt N 2- 13 6 E:c..c C.ve S•cn-:a.ry. il. C t gt;.Lctad '°"ti.aw yol s Sip.at amp;ro S4cret:l-:y to le Cawicil LJ JI.OU C\il VOW f TC r f C D t't l I i&amp;lt;t2.ur&amp;lt 4 VI I .aY-'I r ro r l a..1 1 T jc;A I I I I .1 AS ON I I I l Js gt wi J4 C 1 I I I HAS.i I I d M CO l C J I dW"!r c~ I I I I I 3A I I I I J MCQ3.Z I I I I j W TZ I I I I I CU t!&amp;lt I I I l a o A t J I I I j i I I I I ·oi:xo I I I it s c s l I I I I I I I I I x 'e d•e t e1• A.~u I lt;cttoa t!-t e ~t,ic LJ u c AP eoi 0 lU.yor Volo S i:d hu leA oi C.1 t1 Jt g.w~ S•c:r•ta.ry 10 CowiC.:1 S.-t a A c!:ion R..uotvtl.oa. N~~z HOQse Ac n olut;!C"Q. Nu.r b e r </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
