<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-30">
  <num type="law">2-30</num>
  <meta>
    <stub/>
    <effective>1977-10-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-30.pdf">D.C. Law 2-30</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3723</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-30 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-72, which was referred to the Committee on Advisory Neighborhood Commissions. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on June 28, 1977 and July 12, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 5, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-67 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text>COUNCI L OF THE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE November 3, 1977 D. C LAW 2-30 "Advisory Neighborhood Coilll:lissior.s Additional Notice Act of 1977 Pursuant t o Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self-Gover:unent and Governmental Reorganiza tion Act L 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No 2-72 on first anc second readings June 28, 1977 and July 12, 1977, respectively Foll owing the signatu~e of the Mayor on ~ugust 5, 1977 this legislati on was assigned Act No 2-67, published in the August 19, 1 97 7, editi on of the D.C. P.egis~er, and transmitted to both P.ouses of Congr ess for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 6C2(c l) of the Act The Council of the District of Coll.l!:lbia hereby gives notice that the 30- day Congressional Review Period has expiree and, therefore, cites the following legi slation as 0 C. Law 2-30 effective October 26 1977 Vol. 24, D.C. Register, 1455 August 19, 1977 r i i L 5 D. c LAh' Z-30 IN TH~ COU~CIL OF TH~ D IST~iCT OF COLU~S lh October ?b 1977 To provi j e fo r addi t ional nctice re~uirem~nts t o Advi sor y igh,ornocd C o issions fram certain governr•e nl l a:}enci es Th3t t'li s 3C t :nay oe ci t'?d a&amp;gt; the "Adv iso r y lt;ei 9 nt gt; r'1000 Cor.1 i ss ion ~d dit.i cn &amp;lt;'l l :Jot. ice c t of 19 77 f f ·2ct iv e Oc t.o:&amp;gt;e r 10 197 J Law 2 11 is d:r,i.;r·oe :J as llo~s: r~1 t ~e res~~t s•c t.icq l!(C) is redesigna t.ed ~s saction 1 3 {C)(l th e fol l owi nJ new ~dr ag r ls ar v a~dad t o c tiC'l 1 3 c 2 J The Al coho lic 5~ v e rage ont.rcfl o!l r C s na l l pro vi de eac h 3ffect ed Adv isory ~e i l~ o r hood Co~~ission b y ma i l #ith a not.ice o f p~ndin~ original applicatio ns fo r prev i o us ly unissue::l liouo r licens.e s in c luding tr ans fers f o r Re t ailer s License Clas s A, or Reta il e r s L icense Class wit i n t he oounaari es o f e a ch aff~cted ollea Original -2- Ad vi sory Nei ghborhood commissicn at lea st thirty (30) days prier to any hearioq 2t which any s uch application 2ay be scheduled fer ccosideration. The Alcoholic Beverage Contrcl Eoard shall publ ish ancually iii tbe District of Cclumtia Jiegister on or near the first day of Noveiter er after tha t date ith good cause publishe d vi t b such nctice, a list of those l icensees ~i th a Eetailer•s licenss Class A, or a Retailer s Licer ~e, Cla~E C, liguor license hicb will e xpire on the 1st cf January of the ne.xt year 3 The Department of Ecooo ic tevelcpiieii t shall ensure that each affect ed AdviEcty Neighborhood Co~missioo is provio ed regularly ty mail with a current list of ap?licati cos icr cco~truction and der.olition permits withio the t ouocaries of that &amp;amp;d visory Neighborhood ComDissicn. 11 and (c) the fol lo i;ing ne subsection (g} is added to section 16 9) All materials literatur€ ne w ~letters or letters proouced o r paid for ty tbe fu nds allocat ed to the Advisory Nei9bborhocd Ccmaissicns m~st bear the fol lo ing sentence Tbi s itat e:i:i al was printed by Aovi sory Neighbor hood co~~issic insert t he Enrolled Original 3- aooro2riate Advisory 1: e i o hbo r h c cd Cctttti ssicn n ucber) and paie f or by District c1 Cclu1bia tax revenues' l. 0 type of at least ten t 1 C) i:ci ot s II Sec. II This act shall take effect as i:r cvioed for acts of the council of the District of Cclorlia in section 602 (c) of t he District of Colum~ia Self-GoverL»ent aed Gcvernmental &amp;amp;eor9anization Act, aprroved DeceEber 2 1~73 (87 ~tat 8 1 4 o. c. Cod e, sec. 1- 147 (c 1) l Docke t No: 2- 7 2 \ 6/28/77 !Xt VO!CE vor Adopted Unar:irnously (l abs.} Hardy CU{ztaw tlluiw Sec:eto.T to cle Cc=cil L I ROLL CALL VOT I I I l Y.OCitZ, J. f I I I 1 lX I I f I I J I I I If .ROW I I I I N f I I I 1 J I I I 11 £ AC I il I I H I I r r I Secretary :o i::t~ Co\::ic~l LI VO!C VOTE; Sc.c:'eta to t c CO'Q l.c:,l I RC L CALL VOT lt r .r 11 MCO J c l Z I r I i OJ r r I I ll I I I I XCN" I I I I 1£-:Ac z I I I I I I I I I I x \ J °-1 •r.t v o I Fital R•ac!i lg o 0 Hge:&amp;gt;c:y A ct 012: 7 /J 2/7 7 IN vo:c van: }\::io;&amp;gt;tecl U a:u:nou~ly Cf~ I cv yvi.4 Sec a.ry to ~e. Cow:i;cil f .RO L CAL VOT cew C.I\ \ I t f I COio t C I t 1 1 w c 1 lt I C T J t a.f T c CZ ;t I I I I llMASC1' I i I I ii \J Ji.SG I l I I I t:J 111~ I I I J MCC:U I I I I !I W:l..SOl I I I \ I I I 1MOO J. I J I v;:N I J I J I C gt ¥"2 I I f OLA I I I I 1 I I I l I nrvnN I I I U ir c z WN I I I I ii I I I I r z,J c ii 1 Docket No: 2- 72 P escnte d to ~e Y..ayor: JUL 2 2 1877 Actio:lc! t.'ie M~vor: 5 AUG J77 {3 Ap;irove&amp;lt L I DiU gt;:ove&amp;lt L I Dinpi&amp;gt;rove~ L r•r i.eCe:ezee Doc l e::t Bu.Cgct Ac cr.s c!cd wit.'lc\!t NLayc J Sig~r e xec1:f..ve Ste!"e ta ry, D. C Sccre y :o ie. Co c!l I f VOICE VCT Sec:e to C t CC\ C!l LI ROLL cu vo7 c:o CJL c lf• I •Tr I 1-&amp;lt;f I I c:oul't Cioo slll c I TI I 1 IJ:oc t I i I v. I a,J TUCi:&amp;lt;LR I l I I A.SON I F OY I I I I R MOC:&amp;lt 1 I 3.4 y I I l I MOC I l cLJ gt;c I I I I 1-0 l 1 DOCOI' I I I I s 0'\l I V6.t P e s e ed to th e Prc:sii!c t; LI Ree=c=e:.t &amp;gt;.p;irov ec I I w ygr•s Vote Sus:.ai=e&amp;lt Sub:r..itted t:&amp;gt; t.:le Co~gruSl SEP 7 Se~tc M:ion R.e s olutic Ni e Sccrt:a:-y o t 5cr..a.tc I I II s gt lt n c I l I I I I I ilWU.SCX I i I I I I 1 Wl r I I i I I I I I I I I I I I I \ Xe 1 c i l S ec!'et.a..ry :o t.~e Cc~.cil S cc.rcta.ry to c Cci ctl P:-esic!e t:.t ol ~e C. S. 11 \,j 91i l ,\+l 1 Cle:k 0£ t!i e Ho:!se</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
