<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-33">
  <num type="law">2-33</num>
  <heading type="short">Hearing Aid Dealers and Consumer Act of 1977</heading>
  <meta>
    <effective>1977-10-26</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-33.pdf">D.C. Law 2-33</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 3726</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-33, the “Hearing Aid Dealers and Consumer Act of 1977,” was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-39, which was referred to the Committee on Public Services and Consumer Affairs. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on July 12, 1977 and July 26, 1977, respectively. Signed by the Mayor on August 17, 1977, it was assigned Act No. 2-79 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF TEE DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA NOTICE November 3, 1977 D. C Law 2 -3 3 "Hearing Aid Dealers and Consumers Act of 1977 Pursuant to Section 412 of the District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (PL 93-198 the Act, the Council of the District of Columbia adopted Bill No. 2-39 on first and second readings July 12, 1977, and July 2 6, 1977, respectively Following the signature of the Mayor on August 17, 197i this legislation was assigned Act No. 2-79, published in the August 26, 1977, edition of the D.C. Reai ster, and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for a 30-day review, in accordance with Section 602 (c 1) of the Act. The Council of the District of Columbia hereby gives notice that the 30-day Congressional Review Period has expired and therefore cites the following legislation as D. C. Law z-33 c~r c:ct~er zo 1977. s~~c~ Chairman of the Council (Vol. 2 4, D. C. Register, 17 9 9, August 2 5, 1977 c l .\ 2-33 1cr E 26, 19 77 i st.:ibl i sr std'1·:lJ r 1s 21n l procedur.:r, to pror c: u~~rs of Ile.Jr in 3 i 1S As usej in t'1is Jct, the ter 1 auciologist" means any p~rson whi 35 :3t least d 'la st r '3 ·1 e r e i i u :1 i o 1 o y :in 1 e t t r J i r r. ts of of the r:c~-ni ssion on Li censure t rJC':ice t gt;e 1--e ·J lin Arts 2 J f i t i n in s e 1 l i n; o f ri 0 a r i n c; a i J s 2 in t lo s e JClPt3tio~ or sa l e of ne3r in~ 1i1s j 1~1ril'1 Ji1 7!~ans any Jear3 gt;la in:;i: ru E'1t o r i c s i n e :1 r o f r t:1 i: n r t e c 1; r o s e i: 1 i i .1 r z- attachments or accessories of that wearable instrument, excluding batteries, cords or earmolds. Enrolled Original (4 hearing test evaluation" means a written statement, based on testing conducted by an aucJiologist, otolaryngologist or a medical technician directly supervised by an otolaryngo l ogist. The statement shall include· the fo ll owing information: \A) the ear or ears to be fitted 8) the type of earmold C) the gain (amplification) of the hearing aid 0) the minimum and maximum po~er output of a hearing a id E) the frequency response of the hearing a.idi (F) the results of pure tone and speech audiometry; and (G) the date of the hearing test. This shal l not prevent an audio1ogist or otolaryngologist from recommending a specific make and model of hearing aid 5 medical clearance" means a written stat~ment b~sed upon a medical examination by an otolaryngologist, that concludes that the patient may benefit from a hearing aid and that there are no ~edical cond ition s to contraindicate tha use of a hearing aid. Tt1e statement must i r.c 1 ude the date of the medica l examinat i on ollcd O:igiD 3 6 Office" means the Office of Consumer Protection of the District of Columbia 7 otolaryngologist" means a physician 1 icensed in the District of Columbia who specializes in medical problems of the ear, nose and throat 8 person" means any individual, partnership, association, organization or corporation 9 registrant" means a hearing aid dealer wno engages in the practice of fitting and selling hearing aids and who h~s registered pursuant to section 4 of this act lO sell" or "sale" means any transfer of title or of the righ~ of use by sale, conditional sales contract, lease, bailment, hire-purchase or any o~her means, excluding ~holesale transactions of dealers and distributors ll telephone option" means an option available on hearing aids which enables the wearer to hear the electrical sign~l on the telephone 1 ine rather than the acoustic si9na1 produced by the telephone 12 used hearing aid" means a hearing aid which has be~n worn for any period of time by a buyer or potentia l buyer. E lrolled Original -4- Sec. J. POWERS ANO DUTIES OF THE OFFICE OF CONSU~ER PR:JTECTION. The Office shall 1 } issue and renew certificates of registration to en gag~ in the business of fitting and selling of hearing aids, as provided in section 4 of this act; and (2) implement and enforc-&amp;lt the provisions of this act by utilizing the powers, procedures and sanctions of the Office~ 3S provided for in sections 4 and 6 of the "District of Columb i a Consumer Protection Procedures Act approved July 22, 197 O.C. Law l-76) and the regulations of the Off ice. Sec. 4. REGISTRATION a) It is unlawful for a person to engage in the pr3ct ice of fit t i ng and selling of hearing aids without haying first obtained a ce'rtificate of registration f.rom the Office under the provisions of this act b) Nothing in this act shall prohibit a corporation, p~rtnership, trust, association, or other 1 ike organizat i on m~intaining an established business address in the District of Columoia fro m engaging in tne business of fitting and sei1ing of, or offerinq for sale, hearing aids at retail wit~out a certificate of re~istration: PROV!OED, That any ~nd 311 s uch fitting and sel 1 ing of hearing ~ids is E.!lrolled OrigiDaJ 5- conducted by individuals who are registered pursuant to section 4 of this act. Such corporations, partnerships, trusts, associations, or other 1 ike organizations shall file annually with the Office al ist of all individuals holding val id certificates of registration who are directly or indirectly employed by them c) Each person desiring to obtain a Certificate of Registration from the Office to engage in the practice of fitting and selling of hearing aids shall make an apolication to the Offic The application shall be made upon a form and in such ma~ner as the Office shall provide. It shal 1 set forth 1) the name and business address of the app1 icant A) if an individual, the na~e under which he or she intends to conduct business 9) if a partnership, the name and business acdress of each member thereof and the name under which the business is to be conducted C} if a corporation, the name of the corporation and the name and business address of each of the officers of the corporation. Any applicant who intends to conduct business under a fictitious name shall file with the application a copy of the registration of that fictitious name 2) the place or places, including the complete address or addresses, where thP. business is to be conducted; and {3) sucn further information as the Office may prescribe. Enrolled Original (d) The Office shall act upon an application for a certificate of registration within thirty (30) days after receiving the application. Each application shall be accompanied by an applicat i on fee, which snall in no event be refunded. If an application is aoproved by the Off ice, upon payment of a registration fee, the applicant shall be granted a certificate of registration to be valid for a period determined by the ~ayor of the Oistrict of Co lu mb i a. The certificate shall be conspicuously posted i n the place of business o f the registrant. In the case of l oss, mutilation, or d~struction of a certificate, the Office s:ia11 issue a duplicate certificate, upon proof of facts and ~ayment of a fee e If a registrant maintains more than one place of bus i ness within the District, he or she shall appl y f o r and procure a duplicate cert i ficate for each place of business. Enrolled O~iginal -7- [f a registrant has a change of address of place of business, he or she shall notify the Office within fifteen {15) days of such chan;e f) Certificates expire on the date determined by the ~ayor of the District of Columbia. An unexpired certificate may be renewed by applying to the Office on the form pr~scribed by the Office and the payment of a renewal fee. Late applications for registration or renewal shall be an ~doitional amount. The Office shall act on an application for renewal within thirty (30) days after receiving the apol ication g) The Office shall not pr~vent an aoplicant for a certificate of registration from fitting and selling of hearing aids pending a determination of the initial apol ication with in six (6) months after the effective date of this act h) No physician or audi?logist m~y r~gister .under this act to sell hearing aids for profit i) The Mayor of the District of Columbi~ is authorized to fix and changa from time to time the period for which any certificate of reg i stration author i zed under this act may be issued. The ~ayor of the District of Columbia is authorized to set and c~ange from time to time th~ amount of any fees p r~vi d ed f or i n sect ions 4(J) and 4(f) of this act e- Sec. 5. SPECIAL PROVISIONS a} No registrant shall fit, offer for sale, or sell a hearing aid to a person unless, within the preceding three (3) months, the person has received a medical c learance after an examination by an otolaryngologist ~nd a heuring test evaluation b} No registrant shal l sell a hearing aid not conforming to the hearing test evaluation required without prior consultation and written approval from the signer of the hearin; test evaluation c) Sections S(a) and 5(b) of this act do not app ly to l) the purchase of an identical hearing aid within t~o (2) years of the date that the purchaser receives the origina l aid; and (2} the purchase of pdrts, attachments or accessories of the telephone des1gned to aid the hea r ing-impaired d) If a prospective hearing aid user has a bona fide religious bel i~f which precludes him or her from having a medical examina~ion as required in s~ction 5(a of this act, t h~ prospective hearing a i d user may wa i ve the medi ca l ex~mination requirement: PROVICED, That he prospect i ve -9- hedring uid user signs the following statement, printed in ten (10)-point type My religious beliefs require that I waive the medical examination and the hearing aid evaluation required by the 'Hearing Aid Dealer and Consumers Act of 1977' for the purchase of a hearing aid. I voluntarily waive the medical examination, notwithstanding the fact that I have been advised by HEARING AID DIS?ENSC:R' S NA that my b~st health interest ~ould be served if I had a medical evaluation by a physician who is an ear specialist No registrant shall seek to induce a prospective hearing aid user to execute such a waiver e) No otolaryny~logist or audiologist making recommendations pursuant to sections S(a) and S(h) of this act shall have a direct or indirect ~embership, co- owners~ip, or proprietary interest in a business which is controlled by or which employs a registrant for the purpose of fitting and selling of hearing aids for profit f) No hearing aid shall be sold to any person unless ~ccompanied by a thirty (30) d~y money -back written Enrolled OrigiD&amp;lt;l 10- quarantee providing that if the customer returns the hearing i d within thirty (30) days in the same condition as when purchased the customer shall be entitled to the return of th~ cost of the hearing aid and accessories as i~emized on th~ bill provided ~ursuant to section 6{a) of this act, but in no case shall the hearing aid dealer be permitt9d to retain a service charge greater than five percent (5 of tna cost of the hearing aid and accessories and th~ cost of the earmold g) No registran~ or agent thereof shal l visit the home or sna1 1 te l ephone any potential buyer for the purpose of ind~c i ng a sa l e of a hearing aid without having obtained, prior to the visit, the ex~ress wr i tten consent of the bu yer to that v i sit. Any consent shall c l early and conspicuously s~ate that the buyer is aware that the sel l er may attempt to se l l a hearing aid during the visit sec. 6. MINIMAL PROCEOU~ES a) Each he~ring aid sale shal l be accompanied by a receipt that includes 1 t he name, address, and signature of the purchaser 2 } t he date of cons ummat i on of t he sa l e; Enrolled OrigiDal -11 3) the name and address of the regular place of business, the number of the certificate of registration, and the signature of the registrant 4} the make, model, serial number, and purchase price of the hearing aid; {5) a statement as to whether the hearing aid is "new" or "used 1 o) the complet~ terms of the sale, including A) an itemization of the total purchase price, including but not 1 imited to the cost of the hearing aid, the ear~old, any batteries or other accessories, and any service costs; and (8) a clear and precise statement of the terms of the trial period and the terms of any guarantee or warranty. including disclosures made pursuant to sec~ion 7(a)(3){H 7 the title and address of the Office, with a statement that complaints which arise with respect to the transaction may be submitted to the Office 8) the original of the written recommendation 9) the fo ll owing statements in ten (lO)-point type or larger A This hearing aid wi1 1 not restore normal hearing nor will it prevent further hearing loss Enrolled OrigiDal -12 B No hearing aid may be sold to you without a prior medical examination C A return visit to a physician who is ~n ear specialist or audiologist after the purch~se of this aid will help you in best adapting to it and (10) if the hearing aid sold has a telephone option, a statement that the telephone option will not work on all telephones and a statement indicating the types of telephones upon which it will work b) Each registrant shall keep records for every customer to whom he or she renders services or sells a hearing aid, including l) a copy of th receipt as specified in subsection {a} of this section 6 2) a record of servic~s provided 3) any corresoondence to or from the customer; and (4) any waiver forms, as provided under section 5(d) of this act. Such records shall be preserved for seven (7) years after the date of the transaction c) Each registrant sh~ll post conspicuously in large print at his or .her place(s) of bus iness and mak~ ava ilabl e for i nspection at any sale a retail price 1 is t showing a ll h~~ring aid models for sa l e 13- Sec. 7. GROUNDS FOR REVOCATION ANO SUSPENSION a) In addition to those practices prohibited under section 5 of the "District of Columbia Consumer Prot~ction Procedures Act effective July 22, 1976 (O.c. Ldw 1-7&amp;amp the Office may dP.ny the application for a certificate of registration or may suspend or revoke the certificate ·of re;istration of any hearing aid dealer issue~ pursuant to this act or may refuse to issue a rene~al if it has been ~etermined by the Office or a court of competent jurisdiction that such registrant has l) made a material false stat~ment or conc~aled a mat~rial fact in connection with an appl ic~tion for a certificate Z) had a certificate of registration issued under this act revoked or _suspended previously; Enrolled Origir.31 {3) been guilty of fraud or fraudulent practices or has practiced dishon~st or misl~ading advertising, including but not l imi~ed to advertising a particular model, typa, or kind of hearing aid when the offer is not a bona fide effort to sell the product so offered as advertised 8) advertising that a hearing aid is a new invention or involvos a rew mechani~al 14- engineering, or scientific concept ~r principle in hearing aid capability C) aovertising that a hearing aid will be beneficial to persons with hearing loss, regardless of the type of hearing loss 0) advertising that a hearing aid will enable persons with a hearing loss to consistently distinguish and und~rstand speech sounds in noisy situations; Enrolled Orieinal (E) representing that the services or advice of a person 1 ic~nsed to practi~e medicine or of a person 1 icensed as an audiologist will be used or made available in the selection, fitting, adjustment, maintenance, or repair of hearing aids when that is not true F} using ~r incorporating in any title or designation the words "doctor c1 inic clinical audiologist hearing aid audiologist or any other term, abbreviation, or symbol G) wearing any costume, which would tend to give a false impression that one is being treated medically or t~sted by an audiologist HJ representing, advertising, or implying that the heuring aid or repuir is guarant~ed, Enrolled Origin~l 15- without a clear and concise disclosure of the identity of the guarantor, the nature and extent of the guarantee and any condition or limitations i!llposed stating or implying that the use of any hearing aid will restore hearing to a normal level, preserve hearing, prevent or retard progression of a hearing impairment save a person from deafness, or any other false or misleading m~dically or audiologica11y unsupportabl~ claims regarding the efficacy or benef i ts of a hearing aid J) representing or imp lying that a hearing aid is or will be "custom made made to order prescription made or in any other sense especially fabricated for an individual person ~hen such is not the case; and {K) representing that -a hearing aid has a telephone option, unless it is clearly and conspicuously disclosed that the telephone option will not work on al 1 types of telephones 4) been grossly negligent in the fitting, sel li ng, or repairing of any hearing aic; Enrolled Original -16 5) failed to comply with any other provision of this act or any rules or regulations promulgated hereunder; and (6) direct l y or indirectly giving, offering to give, permitt i ng or causing to be given, money or anything of value to any person ~ho ~dvises another in a professional capacity, as an inducement to influence such person, to have sue~ person influence others, to purchase or contract to purchase any product so l d or offered for sa l e by the re3istrant, or to influence an y person to refra in from dealing i n the products o f compet i tors. {b For the purposes of paragraphs (3 4 5 and 6) of subsection a of th i s section 7, the act i ons of any em~loyee of a hearing aid dealer shal l be attributed to and deemed to be actions of such hearing aid dea l er. Sec. 8. SEVERA8IL!TY The prov i s i ons of this act are severab l e, and if any provision, sentence, clause, sect i on or part is held i ll e~al, inval i d, unconstitutional or i napplicab l e to any p~rson or c i rcu~stances. such holding sha ll not aff ect or i ai r an y o f t h remaining provis ions, sent ences, c l ~us s, s ~ct io ns o r parts of th i s act or its appl i cat i on to other p ~rsons or circumst~nces. I t is ~areby aec l dred t o b~ t he Enrolled Origi~aJ 17- legislative intent that this act would have been adopted if such i1leg~l, invalid, inapplicable or unconstitutional provision, sentence, clause, section or part had not been included h~rein and if the pP.rson or circumstanc~s to which the act or any part is inapplicable had been specifically exe~pted. Sec. 9. EFFECT!VE DATE. This act shall take effect pursuant to section 602(c) of the 'istrict of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act. Docket No z 3_9 Tulv 12, 1977 @ VCICZ VOTZ: P.dootec T.J;:anirr: ous lv (2 a!:s Winter, Mason CJ aou. CA t. VO Z: cautte.1.w CA 1 c 1 f i 1ii t e 2v.-c C••c C 1 4-11 £ a c C••c" 1 1 1 uc·:e I I I I :I ~t sc~r I I I :J s I I I LJ r I I I I :1 lt;!CC z. c. I I I j !I i"1 SON I I I I I I I it {CC Z. I I :JI t I ii i z-r I I I C I I I I :j OU I I I 'I I I I .cz::c I I I I 11 s c z i I I I it I I I amp;&amp;amp l t a T a;l:Jw.J..tL~ CJ VC!C:Z VO Z: Q OU. C..u..L VOTZ: 3 I c t f CCi J 1 i S•ceg c e Cci c I· Tulv 25 19 77 vo.tc:z VC Z: Adopted Unani.-nous ly (2 abs Dixon, Mason LJ tCt CA.Z lCTZ: I J'9 lj;y .A \..o!X.~d LO I I I I I I I i I I I l l J I i P~ese:ted to the ~Ca7or: A_U_'G_s 19_7_7 Ac:t'icn o! t.~e tavo 1 7 AUG 1977 n·cve Q Z:l sa cved; Q Oi.s&amp;amp;pp:"Oveci i:1 ?a.:t tue:-e:c:e oc:u::te:t Su.diet Ac:;oru. Sec eQ.:y :c ~c C.;1 cil xecu:i Se ca r, C. C Secee:a C.;r c:il Q VCIC:Z VCTZ: C:=UJllC C U t •rc J w:.C:.\t 1"1 I P I i a \l:it c&amp;gt t!:Jll r i I I TCC I I I I I ~t.1..SON I C i I I I I :1 ~{CC:.Z i I I .3 i I I I :I tcc:.z I c I I I I l :toI.A I I CN' I I I I !I s z I 111i lll:l: a \. l s a iese ea e esicie I I i s I I i I i ;j 11 c i I I I r I I I I I :1 i I I I 'I I I I :t c tr Sec::oe::a c e C t l Ecusc A c:i 1.es.:itut 1 e I I I I 1977 I I l I I I</search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
