<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<document xmlns="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/dc-library" xmlns:codified="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codified" xmlns:codify="https://code.dccouncil.us/schemas/codify" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" id="D.C. Law 2-50">
  <num type="law">2-50</num>
  <meta>
    <effective>1978-03-10</effective>
    <citations>
      <citation type="law" url="./docs/2-50.pdf">D.C. Law 2-50</citation>
      <citation type="register">24 DCR 4806</citation>
    </citations>
    <history>
      <narrative>Law 2-50 was introduced in Council and assigned Bill No. 2-153, which was referred to the Committee on Government Operations. The Bill was adopted on first and second readings on October 25, 1977 and November 8, 1977, respectively. There being no action by the Mayor, it was assigned Act No. 2-106 and transmitted to both Houses of Congress for its review.</narrative>
    </history>
    <search-text> COUNCIL OF T HE DISTRICT OF COLL'MOlA NOTICE Marc!l 16, 1978 D. C. Law 2-50 "Dis trict of Columbia. Bca~d of E lections and Ethics lulditional Com?~sation Act of 1977" Pursuant to Section 412 of the Di strict o Colum:.ia Self- Gove rnment and Cover=enta.l Reorganization Aci L 93- 198 the ,i.ct the C ouncil of the District of Columbia. adopted Bill No. Z- 153, on fir st a.nd second r eadings October 25, 1977 a!'ld November 3, 1977, respe ctively. E'ollowing e xpiration of. the ten-da y ier iod proviced t!ie Mayor, i!'l which no a ction was taken, pursuant to Section 404 (e) of t.'fte Act, this legislation was assignee Act No. 2-106, published in the ~ecember 16, 1977, edition cf th e D. C. Re giste and t ransmitted to b oth Hous es of Congres s ior a 30-d.ay r eview, in accordance w ith Section 602 (c l) o£ th e Act he Cou:tcil of the District o! Cokmbia. hereby gives :lOtice tha t the 30-cia.y Cong ress iona l review p eriod ha s expi r ed and, t gt;1erefore, cites the !allowing legislation a s D. C I.aw 2 -50, effective March 10, 1978 j__J S T.ER.LING TLCKER Chdrm.a.n cf b:e Council (Vol 2. 4 D. C. Register, 4806, December 16, 1977 Z r \ CH l t97 J f gt;t'ovi E a •altionol cc;np-e ris ti n f gt;r t tie n.;t ir n of is: r ict 0f Co lu iA r d of ~l~ct i ons ~n J t:ti tS 1 r1~ fo r o~~er ~u rposQs l977 '1 h&amp;lt istri c t. of C.olu11~ ta t o ;iati on31 poll tic l Jt1 11 en t; or'S c l JC"I m oer of t~a ~ocrc, uxcluoin'] t. t&amp;gt;a JMri~d ~c~~ally workuo on tha service of t~o uar1 not to ifc O -t: he S.um o f t welve t. t&amp;gt;o uS)tH1 d r five :iv mJ r od &amp;lt;J o ll i rs gt; l 2 5 JO er ~r. nu z 12) The Chairmao shall r e ceive compensation at the r a te of one hundre~ doll ars (SLOO) per day for each eight- hour hour) period actually ~orked on the service of the 3oard. not to exceed the sum of twenty-six thousand and five nu~dred (S26.SOO) per a nnum Sec 3 This act sha 1·1 beco;ne e f feet i ve pursuant to sec~ion 60Z(C)(l) of the "District of Columbia Self- Government and Governmental Reor~anization Act ap?roved Decemb e r Z4 19 73 8 7 Stat Bl4 o. c Code. sec l- l 47(c l PROVIOEO o HOWEV~R o That t he additional payment authorized by this act shall not be available until January l l 97,3 Doc~e o: 2 53 7i::t u&amp;lt \c=c Oc tober 25, 1977 f.P VO!C VOT~ Ado:)terl Ur,anLiiOl!sly (2 ~bs B2r.-y Wilson Cf~i&amp;lt;J ,Jr-t.1.0 JLv rn Sec-:e.t:l O-f :o t!:ie Cct icil co lt 1oO C l c J 4 I I 1 c ¢1.1 C lt I lA 1 .L.J,.f c~cn I 1.?r t .l T I Y. f 4&amp;gt;-J TUC&amp;lt I I I I M gt;.SCN I I j I .l S li D'XC) I I I u; 1 1 1 1 ~Meo gt o 1 1 t 1 n wu.so i 1 r r 1 3 U I I I I l i.cooa r. d 1 I I 1v ln I I I f I CLJ KZ i I I I or °' i I I I ll I I I J z:cc i; t r 1 1· 11 s:tc Z~:s1 1 1 1 1 r 1 1 X t l i f r lt;ct a t I I VO!CZ vo I I 3.0 LL CAL VO 1,1 c ° 1 c l 1 ~it lt;ti 1 t I f ii c C\ c tr I f'C I I I 7 c I l C.~ON l I !15 i!.Dl.'c J iY! I n tCCl lt c. l I pru SON I I I j lt;cc I l· I I I C lt c I :p•.Ot gt;3.A I I l I I I XON l E C:CZ I I j L VOICE VOT Adopted 'NHson c:o.t c c lt c I to• f a,;J v lt;.J v 4 I T I \l,.c I il'&amp;gt r i f i -roe I i I I ~M cr I l I I f i \.t.i' l OL'iC I l I I I i a i I J I I l&amp;gt;ICO::t I I I t 1t"·V!l..SCN I I I I I I I I lt;co I T I J ·I amp I I I I I 3 J.J cw~~z i I l OL j I I I :1 I I I I CZ:&amp;lt lt; J l I I I I I f I I j r I c lt gt l t 7 1' I Sec:.e f :o &amp;lt;l::ic ccket 2-153 tiDY 11 1277 11"if- a.u) 1 f p r.J ScC et4 l t:t ~c Ceunc t 8 NCV 1977 I I YO!CZ '10 Z hereby certify that Council Bill 2- 153' was presented to the !Ja7or of the District of Col1.llllbia on November 11, 19 77 and that 1 t!'ie Ma7or neit!'ier approved nor disapproved the bill within the ten day period specified in Section 404(e) of the District ot Co lumbia Self-Goverr.ment anc! Gover=e nt:ll. Reorganization Aot, Public Law 93- 198 of December 24, 1973 PJ llarti.n K- Schaller, Executive Secre&amp;lt ar;r, D. C November ,9, 1977 Se te .A.c ca 3.4sotut!c 1 Zie gt C. Uw ~o P:'c-ridcs o e r.i. S o,w·,p C~e~k e! c </search-text>
  </meta>
</document>
